A hit!
Strike!
Awesome!
Even though I haven't come through on my client's request...
I'm still invited to her birthday part.
I'm feeling a little embarrassed.
What are you saying?
You were just acting wildly and saying,
"Asako-san from Strawberry just invited me!"
But of course!
Strawberry is the hippest comedy duo around right now.
Imaoka Jirou (28)
Comedian
Fujimori Asako (37)
Strawberry is the taste of love!
This is Mouri!
I've come as your guest tonight...
What happened, Asako-san!?
A man suddenly came inside from my balcony, and I...
Asako-san!
Hey!
Zombie...
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
A popular male and female comedy duo...
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
This happened a week earlier.
A member of the popular comedy duo Strawberry, Fujimori Asako-san...
Came to the Mouri Detective Agency with a request.
Numata Keisuke?
He's an ex of mine from when I first came to Tokyo fifteen years ago.
We broke up quickly on account of him being a hateful bully, but...
You mentioned that, soon after Strawberry won the
Spring Manzai Grand Prix and was becoming popular...
He called me nonstop asking for money.
When I refused, he began harassing me.
Harassing?
He rifled through my mailbox...
And I started to feel someone was following me at night.
A few days ago, I found scrape marks
near the keyhole on my front door.
That's a cute pendant.
This is my pill case.
Pill case?
Yeah.
I've had a weak heart since childhood...
So I keep my medicine in this and have it on me at all times.
How unforgivable.
To think he'd harass a vulnerable lady like you.
I see.
So you accepted her request of tracking down that Numata.
Yes.
I did my best investigating, but wasn't able to uncover his address.
I told her to change her lock to an anti-picking design, but...
Perhaps Numata took notice of it and decided to break in by force.
Asako-san, there are bruises on your arm.
That man grabbed me...
Asako-chan!
Hisamatsu Minoru (60)
Manager
I was so worried!
Are you all right?
Hisamatsu-san!
This is the manager of Strawberry, Hisamatsu-san.
What happened?
A man suddenly burst in, wielding a pistol...
I was so frightened...
Take off his mask.
Yes, sir.
No!
It can't be!
Jirou!
Why!?
Why Jirou!?
Jirou...
It's a model gun.
Can you please tell me in detail the situation
from when Jirou-san entered the premises?
Yes...
Today is my birthday.
I invited Mouri-san, who's been helping
me, over with his family for a 7:00 dinner.
Hamburger patties...
And this?
It's fruit punch.
I prepare it for dessert.
It happened when I was cutting the strawberries.
I heard the sound of glass breaking.
I'll kill you!
No!
Stop resisting!
You're Numata, right!?
Shut up!
NO!
At that moment, Mouri-san and the others came to visit.
It'd be best if you put something cold on it.
Thank you.
Inspector, according to the call log, a little
before the victim snuck into this room...
He called someone else at 6:45.
K?
All right, go find out who this is immediately.
Yes, sir!
Say, did you not invite Jirou-san today?
He said he was meeting with someone today.
Why did Jirou-san do this?
Do you have any idea?
None...
Hisamatsu-san...
You?
That...
Actually...
Jirou's been planning to quit doing comedy with Asako-chan.
No way...
Although Jirou entered the comedy arena soon after high school...
He was too cute and timid on stage.
It didn't go well for him.
But Asako-chan insisted that Jirou had
talent and teamed up with him anyway.
After ten years of hard work, they had finally made it...
But as things got tough, Asako-chan's heart became worse.
She'd take long breaks from the stage and TV
shows, and often missed her reaction cues.
It seems Jirou couldn't stand that.
Come to think of it, in one of Asako-san's rehearsals I attended...
Jirou!
Hi, Jirou!
Wow, that was impressive!
No good, no good!
You missed your feedback timing three times!
What were you doing?
I'm sorry...
My chest was in pain...
Who cares about that?
We're pros!
Now, now...
Asako-san went through a lot and was just tired.
I can't bear with this!
Why don't you just quit?
Did he really tell her to quit?
Yes.
Speaking of which, I've read some things in magazines...
Oh, like this.
"Partying with an anchorwoman"...
"Dating an idol"?
Looks like he was a womanizer.
Asako-chan and Jirou were not only comedy partners, but also lovers.
But soon after they became popular, that Jirou...
I couldn't stand it either, so I reprimanded him last week.
But...
You're disbanding the group!?
Yeah.
If Asako's like that, we can't continue doing comedy.
I don't want her to hold me back anymore.
Asako-chan's been looking after you all
this time, how dare you say that!?
That's neither here nor there.
Well, what will you do after disbanding?
With my looks, I'll be successful even solo.
I'd rather that woman not come with me!
You...
Regardless, I have no intention of doing any more comedy with Asako.
She already jumped the shark.
Hisamatsu-san, you should persuade her to quit too.
'Kay?
It was Asako-chan who brought success to Jirou...
Why did Jirou-san carry so many rubber masks?
Looks like he was planning a solo show using those rubber masks.
Solo show?
A kind of comedy where you switch masks constantly.
He showed me for a bit, but...
I couldn't say it was funny even if I tried.
Inspector!
I found out who the victim was calling.
A locksmith.
A locksmith...
You mean someone who could unlock
your doors when you've lost your keys?
That's right.
But, according to them, the call was
dropped soon after they answered.
They thought it was a wrong number.
Also, I've inquired with the second floor resident of this apartment.
He said that at 6:50 when the weather forecast was on TV...
The victim was climbing up the emergency staircases.
Is that so?
Yes.
He said he's often seen the victim
and Asako-san rehearsing in the park.
He's absolutely certain.
Did the victim wear a zombie mask at that time?
No.
He probably put on the mask after reaching the balcony.
Glass shards...
What's wrong?
Hey!
Stay in a corner and be a good kid!
Wait!
There's something on Jirou-san's pants!
Those are cockleburs!
They probably got stuck on him somewhere!
Asako-san, did you go anywhere else today?
No, I was home all day.
But...
Inspector!
Regarding the truth of this case...
I, the Great Detective Mouri Kogoro, have figured out everything!
As Jirou became ever more popular and pampered by fame...
He viewed Asako-san as a burden.
However...
He feared his fame would plummet
should he ditch her too noticeably.
That's when he thought of a plan.
A plan?
Asako-san was targeted by a stalker named Numata.
Jirou used that fact.
He disguised himself as Numata and snuck into this room.
And by giving Asako-san a shock...
He hoped her heart condition would
worsen and she'd be forced to retire.
What!?
Jirou wouldn't do something like that...
But, while thinking along these lines, everything makes perfect sense.
The reason why Jirou wore a zombie mask, used a model
gun to break the balcony window and snuck in...
Was because he was planning to break up with you.
No way...
But, in the end, Asako-san resisted and stabbed him with a knife.
Inspector...
The correct description is: "The knife accidentally stabbed him."
Asako-san didn't know he was Jirou.
That's why she resisted.
This is self defense, no matter how you look at it.
I see.
Uncle's deductions make sense at a glance.
But...
As I thought.
He made a call to the locksmith at 6:45...
And someone witnessed him climbing the stairs at 6:50.
Judging from the time, he probably made the call around here.
Found it!
It was the cockleburs here that got on Jirou's pants.
The grass has been disturbed.
Did he part the grass to find something?
I see!
So it was like that!
Asako-san...
My condolences on your unfortunate loss, but...
We still need to take your statement, so
if you would please come to the station.
Yes.
Conan-kun...
Where have you been?
Somewhere.
So it is...
Just as I thought.
What's this now?
You little glutton.
Cool, this iciness is diving right into my teeth!
Now, if you'll come along...
Yes.
Inspector...
Could you spare a minute to hear me out?
What else've you got?
What I just described was the staged scenario.
The true scenario has yet to be revealed.
The true scenario?
Right.
The one in which Asako-san feigned self defense...
And proceeded to murder Jirou-san...
That scenario.
What now?
What are you saying?
Asako-san...
The man named Numata Keisuke...
Never existed in this world, right?
That's nonsense.
Didn't I show you a photo?
You only needed to present a random old photo and fabricate a story.
As such...
You constructed this fictional Numata character...
And acted as if you were afraid.
You led me to think that Jirou-san
with a zombie mask was Numata...
And likewise had me deduce it was a justifiable act of
self-defense when you retaliated and stabbed him.
Please stop this nonsense!
Besides, if Jirou hadn't worn a zombie mask and snuck in here...
Nothing would have happened!
That was all a product of your design.
Asako-san...
At around 6:00 PM, you actually met
with Jirou-san in the park, did you not?
No...
I was making dinner right here.
You said you were making fruit punch.
Ran, go take a bite.
You're good at cooking, no?
Tell me what you think of it.
Well?
It's a bit too sweet, and too cold.
I think she refrigerated it for a while after adding the syrup.
But this...
Right.
If she was really making this right before the incident...
It shouldn't have been this sweet and cold.
In other words, Asako-san...
Put the half-prepared punch in the fridge...
And went to the park to meet Jirou-san.
How can you be so sure?
The cockleburs.
They're on Jirou-san's pants.
Although you'll rarely see cocklebur plants in Tokyo these days...
It just so happens that some can be found in that very park.
Not to mention, I also saw cockleburs on
Asako-san's sneakers at the front door.
In the park, you lied to Jirou-san about
having lost the key to the apartment.
The cockleburs likely got on the two of you
while you were searching in the grass.
The reason Jirou-san called the locksmith
was to have them open the door.
But, with those two being lovers, Jirou
should've had a spare key as well!
I instructed her to change the lock in order to frustrate the stalker.
That was all part of Asako-san's plan, though.
It's likely she didn't give the new spare key to Jirou-san.
And afterwards, you proceeded with your final plan.
What's wrong?
Heart attack?
Where're your pills?
I forgot them in my room...
It'll be too late if we wait for the locksmith...
Jirou, listen...
The glass door on the balcony is unlocked.
Please take the emergency stairs...
Geez, always causing me trouble!
As Jirou-san climbed up the emergency stairs...
You got there first by taking the elevator.
Then, you unlocked the door with your key.
Asako?
Why?
After you murdered Jirou-san...
You took out the half-ready hamburger
meat and fruit punch from the fridge.
Even if that was true, we still lack evidence.
The bruise on Asako-san's left arm.
If he were to grab her left arm with his left hand...
His thumb print should've been on the outer side of her arm.
The bruise doesn't match!
That stemmed from her grabbing it with her own right hand.
And our next piece of evidence is the zombie mask.
Look carefully.
You can see tiny glass shards on the inside.
What?
It's true!
If Jirou-san had worn the mask and snuck inside...
The shards would never be inside the mask.
In other words...
You broke the glass after you had killed Jirou-san...
And only then put the zombie mask on his body.
That's what transpired.
The one who could've done all that...
Asako-san...
It could only be you.
Asako-chan...
Jirou...
I couldn't forgive him.
I also happened to overhear his conversation with Hisamatsu-san.
After Hisamatsu-san left the room, Jirou said...
I can finally put an end to being Asako's boyfriend.
It'll be a brand-new start for me!
We worked so hard as a couple...
And our efforts finally paid off!
Yet Jirou wanted to keep that fruit to himself and leave!
I can't forgive that!
Asako-san...
This was delivered just now.
It's for you.
"Are you having fun at your birthday party?
"Congratulations, you're getting a ring as my present.
"I'll cease being your comedy partner and boyfriend...
"Instead, let's get married.
"I feel bad having to tell you to quit comedy, but...
"Take care of yourself and start a brand-new life with me.
"Strawberry will always be inside our hearts, everlasting."
No way...
Jirou...
I'm sorry...
Jirou!
I'm sorry!
People's feelings sometimes go astray
and lead to irreversible consequences.
This too...
Was one such tragic case.
Did he confess to you?
That he loves you.
Why's that?
I think to worry about someone is an act of loving someone!
They were here not long ago?
The culprit who killed this person.
Next Conan's Hint
Pickup truck