Good morning.
Good morning...
Hey, what's with that sloppy appearance?
If you're calling yourself a detective, you need to be more presentable!
But it can't really be helped...
I was on a stakeout all night.
Geez...
At least do your necktie properly.
It's fine!
I just finished my report, so...
I'm heading home to get some sleep now...
Hey, stop moving!
Yes, ma'am!
That's good enough!
I'll fix it myself later...
Thank you very much.
I'll see you later!
Geez...
Hey, Takagi-kun?
Wait up!
That bastard Takagi, he's gotten too bold lately.
I hear they've been eating together more and more often.
There are even unconfirmed reports that they've kissed...
What!?
Without my permission!?
Well, the reports are still unconfirmed...
Hurry and get confirmation then!
You're a detective!
Hey, what should we do?
Shiratori...
About Takagi and Satou's relationship!
You're the chief executive of Satou
Miwako's Absolute Line of Defense!
Why don't we just leave those two alone?
They seem to love each other.
And, I've entrusted someone else with the
position of chief executive, so please excuse me.
Hey...
Shiratori!
What happened to that guy?
According to our informant, Shiratori-san got himself a girlfriend.
What!?
They say it's a woman who looks just like Satou-san.
Who on earth is it!?
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Kobayashi-sensei has encountered a case.
And her bodyguard is Inspector Shiratori?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Baby I need you
Yes, I understand.
So all I have to do is not go out by myself at night?
Yes.
Please try your hardest and refrain from going out after 21:00.
Lately, there have been a number of
snatching incidents in your neighborhood.
Oh, that was on the morning news.
They said it may have even been a female culprit.
Yeah.
But, why are you...
Why are you always calling me like this?
Because I worry about you...
Is it annoying?
Oh, no!
It's not annoying at all—it's really helpful!
I'm glad to hear that.
Well then, please be careful.
All right.
Thank you so much for calling.
Hey...
We've been trying to tell you that we've
finished cleaning the rabbit cottage.
So you guys were the ones in charge
of the summer cleaning this week.
Great work!
Could it be that call was from Inspector Shiratori?
Yeah...
But how'd you know?
It's so easy to tell!
Sensei, your face is all red!
It's... It's nothing...
It's nothing like that!
And?
Did he confess to you?
That he loves you.
Why's that?
Guess not.
Don't you remember Inspector Shiratori before?
Remember?
Well, perhaps you two already met when you were kids!
Now that you mention it...
When I first met him, it didn't feel like it was actually the first time.
As if a secret drawer had been opened in my mind.
Then, here's a hint: bookstore!
Bookstore?
Regarding Inspector Shiratori's rescuing Kobayashi-sensei from
shoplifters at the bookstore when they were young...
The inspector said he'd relay the story to her
himself and asked us to stay quiet, remember?
That's true.
Well, it seems that he's seeking the right
timing in order to move Sensei's heart.
Irritating, isn't it?
Could it be!?
The book "Thirty Criminal Mistakes by the Fiend of Thirty Faces"...
It's coming out today, isn't it?
Yeah...
Good, since I forgot to reserve a copy, I need to get it today!
In that case, you better hurry up and buy it.
The bookstore you frequently visit is closing
early today so they can watch the fireworks.
Really?
Then I have to hurry.
Oh right, speaking of fireworks, are you going as well?
Yup!
We're meeting at Conan-kun's place at 6:30 and going from there.
Huh, that's rare...
I thought you'd be meeting at Professor
Agasa's place and going with him?
The professor is helping a friend move, so he can't come.
Then, is Detective Mouri going with you?
Uncle said he was going to watch the
fireworks while drinking with neighbors.
And Ran-neechan is at a summer karate camp.
We're the only ones going.
Is that bad?
Of course, it's bad!
She's so late, geez!
If we don't hurry, the fireworks are going to start!
Well, she'll come eventually.
Sensei!
Kobayashi-sensei!
Hurry up, hurry up!
You're late!
Sorry, sorry...
I got delayed when buying the book...
The first round has already started!
Geez, we would've been on time if we'd gone by ourselves!
You can't.
Kids shouldn't go out by themselves at night.
There's been a snatcher around here recently, so you have to be careful.
Well, did you hear that from Inspector Shiratori?
Yeah...
Inspector Shiratori is all over her!
Well, he thinks I'm not that reliable...
So he was just worried about me.
However...
I think to worry about someone is an act of loving someone!
That so?
Is that right?
Yeah, definitely!
But...
Even if that's true, I wonder how he'd be as a boyfriend?
He's a police officer...
I have to worry about him chasing down ruthless criminals...
But it might be fun listening to some crime stories!
You know, I really do love mysteries...
Right?
Everyone's gone!
The night fair is packed!
Ayumi wants to eat some cotton candy!
They have goldfish scooping too!
Sensei isn't here.
I did tell her we were taking the shortcut...
Hey, now...
Where is everyone?
Edogawa-kun?
I don't think they'd be here...
Where could they be?
That's right, maybe I should text Inspector Shiratori.
"Inspector, here comes a case...
"Five children have vanished like a puff of smoke!"
Just kidding.
Listen up, just hand it over!
Or I'll kill you!
Someone's arguing with someone else...
Could it be... the snatcher?
Call the inspector!
But if I'm wrong, I'd just be a nuisance...
I wish Edogawa-kun and the others were here...
That's right!
The kids could be the ones that got involved in that!
Anyway, I need to check it out.
What!?
Who was that person just now?
No way...
Kobayashi-sensei's pretty late.
Geez...
Hey, you guys.
I'm gonna go get Sensei.
You guys wait here.
Yeeesss!
Uhm...
Hello?
Are you all right?
Sensei!?
No way...
Why...
Sensei!
Don't come near!
If you do, that person will...
Gone?
Sensei...
They were here not long ago?
The culprit who killed this person.
POLICE HQ
Come on, Sensei.
Don't be so nervous!
But this is the first time I've come to such a place...
Kobayashi-sensei, you've been called
here as a witness regarding the killer.
It's not like you're the murderer who's going to be interrogated.
Why don't you just try to relax?
That's true.
As for me...
I'm here so often that I've tried all
the dishes on the cafeteria menu!
You eat too much.
Mi~wako!
Yo!
Taking these kids to questioning?
Huh?
What's with your appearance?
You're even wearing glasses.
An image change?
Oh, no...
"Oh, no..."?
Hey, are you not awake yet?
Hurry and wake yourself up!
Kyaa!
Did you just shriek "kyaa"?
What was that for, pray tell?
"Pray tell"?
Miwako, do you have a fever?
You're mistaken, Yumi-san.
This person is...
Satou-san!
So you brought the kids.
Huh?
Shouldn't the teacher be here as well?
As I was saying, this is...
Teitan Elementary Class 1-B's homeroom teacher...
And also the key witness to this murder case.
This is Kobayashi Sumiko-sensei.
Please don't mistake her again.
Well then, let's proceed to that room and go into greater detail.
Yes!
No way...
Uhm, is there someone here who looks like me?
Yeah, though I honestly don't see any resemblance.
Well, maybe a little... bit?
Uhm, are we going to the interrogation room?
No, it's just a meeting room.
I see.
You sound disappointed.
No, I was just a bit interested.
Could it be...
That's the girlfriend Shiratori-kun is obsessed with?
Although I heard she's a look-alike...
To think she'd resemble Satou-san this much!
I was surprised too.
Especially the first time I saw her.
I know, right?
But her speaking manner and personality...
They're Satou-san's complete opposi... oww!
Who's the complete opposite of me?
No...
He means Miwako's a natural detective and is man-like!
Huh?
What do you mean?
Whatever.
The three suspects for that murder case are already here.
Let's start the interrogation.
Roger!
Seems like as soon as Shiratori-san moved out of
their way, those two went right for the finish line!
Well, seeing that now I can no longer incite
Shiratori-kun to obstruct those two...
I feel a little desolate.
Meeting Room
I see.
To recap, you we're separated from the
children en route to the fireworks festival.
When looking for them...
You overheard someone arguing with someone else.
As you went in the alley to check on them...
You witnessed the culprit fleeing.
Furthermore, upon hearing your
scream after encountering the victim...
Conan-kun ran over to the scene, is that right?
Yes.
Allow me to confirm this.
The body you found was...
This Sumida Akira-san, is that correct?
Yes.
I think so.
And, do you remember what the culprit
was arguing about with Sumida-san?
Yes... I heard a little, but...
The sound of fireworks drowned out most of it.
However, I did hear the female culprit bellowing loud and clear.
It was in between fireworks.
She said, "Listen up, just hand it over, or I'll kill you!"
I see.
That's why I'm guessing it's that same female
snatcher who's been appearing lately.
No, that snatcher was arrested on the same evening.
But, why do you think the culprit was a woman?
Was it because of her interjection?
The ending "-wayo" is used by women.
I saw the fleeing culprit's silhouette!
She had a full figure.
Her long hair was tied back, and I think she was wearing a hat.
There's no doubt.
Did you not see the culprit's face?
No, it was too dark.
But the culprit probably remembers Sensei's face.
Why is that?
Because I wasn't the only one who went to the
crime scene after hearing Sensei's scream.
What now?
Don't tell me...
Right, Sensei?
Yeah...
The culprit seemed to be staring at me from afar.
But when Conan-kun arrived, she was gone.
That's dangerous.
The culprit may come after you to silence you.
Don't worry.
The Detective Boys shall stay at your house!
We won't let the culprit lay one finger on you!
Everyone...
No, that's not necessary.
You will be protected by me, Shiratori Ninzaburou.
With my entire life.
Yes...
Sorry to interrupt your little drama...
But do you not have any questions for the
rest of us that arrived after Edogawa-kun?
Well, I guess...
I might as well ask if you saw anyone suspicious fleeing the scene.
We didn't, but...
You sound like you don't care!
Oh, no...
Did Agasa-san see anything then?
Wasn't he with you?
The professor didn't come because he was helping a friend move.
Move?
I just remembered, right before I heard those two arguing...
I saw a moving truck or something like that driving past the alley!
Really?
Yes.
The walls blocked my view, so I couldn't tell its model, but...
I did see a large "09" on the side of the truck.
Say, why does it have to be a moving truck if there are numbers on it?
In general, those that print their phone numbers on
their trucks are either moving or shipping companies.
If the truck was parked there for a while, it's possible
that the driver also saw those two arguing.
I'll have someone investigate it promptly.
Then, can we go home now?
Yeah, you guys can leave now.
But Kobayashi-sensei, please stay with me for a little while.
We happen to have three suspects here for questioning...
All of which lack alibis and may have held a grudge toward the victim.
If you remember the culprit's voice, would you please identify it?
Sure.
But before that...
Well...
Well, what is it?
Want me to go to the restroom with you?
Ayumi knows where it is.
I see...
Then, I'll tag along.
Well, I'll be back soon.
Please take your time.
Heeey.
When a lady's using the restroom, it's impolite
to say, "Please take your time"!
It's like you're hinting Sensei's having...
Idiot!
I wasn't insinuating anything when I said that!
Well?
What did she do for a living?
This female victim.
She was a pawn shop owner.
Wait a minute!
This is a woman!?
Yeah.
This shirt seems to button right over left, so it's for women.
And the name "Akira" can be used by men or women.
I see.
Well, it seems she was often mistaken
for a man and would get angry at that.
But conversely, a lot of people were angry
about her vicious way of doing business.
Sorry for the wait.
Huh?
Those kids aren't ready yet...
So the restrooms in the police HQ aren't anything special.
Of course.
Just kidding.
Why can't I meet her?
Well... there are reasons...
What reasons, you're not answering my question!
It's just not a good idea...
There really is!
Someone who looks just like me.
I think her name was...
Satou Miwako-san.
How nice...
I had wanted to be a policewoman too.
Damn, that bastard Takagi's flirting around again.
With our Miwako-san!
Soon after Shiratori dropped out, he started to run amok!
Yeah, that guy was the chief executive of
Satou Miwako's Absolute Line of Defense!
But I guess Shiratori's got some skill too.
Yeah, to find a chick that looks exactly like Satou.
I wonder if that look-alike is around here?
He simply settled for that Sensei.
Guess so.
Kobayashi-sensei, sorry for the wait.
What's wrong, Sensei?
Sensei?
The suspects are...
The ex-leader of a Ladies racing gang...
A restaurant owner...
And a former hero of Koshien.
It looks like I'm being hated.
"Am I just a substitute for Detective Satou?" she may think.
It's a lie.
Actually, I came here just to see you.
Next Conan's Hint
Bellowing
Look Forward to the Next Episode