An encounter with this young girl is what inspired
Inspector Shiratori to become a police officer.
The Inspector initially thought Detective Sato was that girl...
But it was actually our homeroom teacher,
Kobayashi-sensei, that was his girl of memory.
That Kobayashi-sensei then came across a murder case.
The victim was a pawn shop owner, Sumida Akira-san.
She was said to have angered many people
with her vicious business practices.
From Kobayashi-sensei's response to Inspector
Shiratori's questioning, we obtained three clues.
The first being the angry voices of the culprit and the victim.
The second being the stationary truck near the
scene, possibly from a moving company.
And the third...
Was the silhouette of the culprit witnessed by Kobayashi-sensei.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Inspector Shiratori and Kobayasi-sensei.
What will the outcome be of the case and their love?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
As—I—said!
I was watching TV at home alone!
There was a soccer match I couldn't miss.
Kagitani Kikuna (25)
If it hadn't been for that, I would've gone to
the culprit's place and killed her myself!
You really hated her that much?
Yeah.
I needed money real bad, so I had to temporarily
pawn my late mother's ring out of desperation.
I didn't have enough money to buy it back in
time, so I went to beg her for more time.
But that woman was wearing my mother's ring and said...
"Oh, about that cheap excuse for a ring, I already sold it.
"This one may look similar, but it's different.
"And it's worth twenty times more," without any hint of shame!
See!?
How could I not want to kill her!?
Well...
Uhm, Inspector?
Takimoto Ryouko (31)
Are you thinking I was the one who killed her?
Oh, no...
But, on the day she was killed, I heard you took a day off from
the restaurant you work at and slept alone at home, so...
But it couldn't be helped.
My cold's gotten a lot worse lately.
And?
What's your relationship with the victim?
We heard you really hate her...
I do not particularly.
It's just that I bought a 500,000 yen antique plate from her.
But it started smelling weird, so I hired an appraiser to check it.
It turned out to be a replica, only worth 300 yen!
Not to mention that odor turned out to be cat food...
And she'd only been using it as a dish to feed her cat.
I don't bear a grudge against her at all!
Yeah, I did borrow some money.
About five million yen from that woman.
I finally secured a way to return it and we set up an agreement,
but now that she's dead, I guess I can't repay her, huh?
Kodama Ryuusuke (27)
As proof, at the time that woman was killed...
I had just polished off a bottle of premier
champagne at home and got really drunk!
But even the day before the murder...
The victim was heard storming into your
apartment and demanding her money back.
That was just for show, for show.
That was just an excuse for her to see me.
Too see the former hero of Koshien!
Well, since I injured my left shoulder prior
to being drafted, I wasn't able to go pro.
Nobody seems to remember me anymore.
In other words...
That chick was really into me!
Got it?
Looks like we recorded the three suspects' voices perfectly.
Yeah.
Now all we need is for Kobayashi-sensei to check the voices.
Well, if the culprit is female, that last guy is probably unrelated.
Say, what kind of person is that Kobayashi-sensei?
I heard from Yumi that she's got Shiratori-kun in a fever.
She's a teacher in Conan-kun's class at the elementary school.
It seems they had a chance meeting recently during a case.
I thought I was sure Shiratori-kun loved
someone from within this headquarters, but...
I guess I was wrong.
That was you, you!
Anyway, can you introduce me to that Sensei?
I think it's best if I don't.
Why can't I meet her?
Well... there are reasons...
What reasons, you're not answering my question!
It's just not a good idea...
Wow, there really is!
Someone who looks just like me.
I think her name was...
Sato Miwako-san.
How nice...
I had wanted to be a policewoman too.
Damn, that bastard Takagi's flirting around again.
With our Miwako-san!
Soon after Shiratori dropped out, he started to run amok!
Yeah, that guy was the chief executive of
Sato Miwako's Absolute Line of Defense!
But I guess Shiratori's got some skill too.
Yeah, to find a chick that looks exactly like Sato.
I wonder if that look-alike is around here?
He simply settled for that Sensei.
Guess so.
Kobayashi-sensei, sorry for the wait.
What's wrong, Sensei?
Sensei?
"This one may look similar, but it's different.
"And it's worth twenty times more," without any hint of shame!
See!?
How could I not want to kill her!?
This was the voice of the first suspect, Kagitani Kikuna-san.
And the next one...
Not to mention that odor turned out to be cat food...
And she'd only been using it as a dish to feed her cat.
I don't bear a grudge against her at all!
That was the voice of the second suspect, Takimoto Ryouko-san.
And the next one would be the third suspect, Kodama Ryuusuke-san.
Well, since he's a male, he probably isn't relevant to this.
But just in case...
If he was irrelevant, then just forget about it.
Is that so...
Then, after hearing the voices of the two
women, did either of them sound familiar?
Did one of them have a voice similar to the
culprit's bellowing you heard at the scene?
For ease of reference, I've chosen the parts
where they were most emotionally excited.
Sensei?
What's wrong?
Didn't you hear the culprit's voice?
I don't think either of those voices matches the culprit's.
What I heard was a deeper, intimidating woman's voice.
Is that so...
So, you need to either find a new suspect...
Or locate and interview the passengers of the vehicle
resembling a moving truck that drove past me at the scene.
About that truck...
We couldn't locate it.
We couldn't find any trucks with a big "09" printed on the side.
No way...
Is it possible that you misread the numbers?
If they were partially blocked by the wall,
then a 5 could be mistaken for a 9.
Just because they're alike, doesn't mean that I would mistake them!
Not me!
"Not me"?
Well...
It's possible the employees happened to stop
their truck for reasons unrelated to business.
Of course we also thought of that and pressed them, but...
Even after also interviewing people living in the vicinity...
It seems no one ordered a moving or a shipping truck to come.
So, you mean...
I was only making up this information so that I
could have fun fooling around with you police!?
No, not at all...
Regardless...
I've already told you what I saw and heard.
I'm going home.
Allow me to drive you home...
In case you encounter the suspect.
I'm fine.
I can at least take care of myself.
So would you stop bothering me?
Excuse me.
Shiratori-san...
Sensei!
Inspector Shiratori, I think it's best if she has escort.
Since Sensei was spotted by the culprit.
Yeah...
Chiba-kun, can I leave that to you?
But, are you sure?
Well...
It looks like I'm being hated.
Kobayashi-sensei, please wait up!
Hey, you!
Why would Sensei be mad at you?
Did you say something bad?
Dunno...
There's only one reason it could be.
Kobayashi-sensei may have seen Detective Sato earlier.
Kobayashi-sensei saw Sato-san?
In addition, if she happened to hear rumors about
your infatuation for Detective Sato...
Sensei will definitely suspect you.
"That Inspector Shiratori was only being nice
to me because I look like Detective Sato.
"Am I just a substitute for Detective Sato?" she may think.
No...
She was never a substitute...
Kobayashi-sensei is my girl of destiny.
But you also once mistook Detective
Sato for your girl of destiny, didn't you?
I won't deny that...
Wouldn't it be better if you told her already?
That Kobayashi-sensei is your girl of destiny from childhood,
that you saved in that bookstore from those shoplifters.
Of course I want to tell her the truth, but...
I just can't seem to find the right timing.
Yo, Inspector-in-love!
How'd it go with the suspects' voices?
She heard them, right?
Yeah...
But they don't seem to match what she heard.
Is that so...
Well?
Where's this teacher that's been giving Shiratori-kun butterflies?
Well, Sato-san wants to meet her no matter what...
Shiratori-san?
Uhm...
Looks like it isn't the right time... for this...
See you!
Yeah, see you!
Sensei, see you!
See you!
It's dangerous to run!
I know!
Sensei doesn't look good.
I guess she still hasn't heard anything about
being Inspector Shiratori's girl of destiny, huh?
Well then, how about I tell her?
You can't!
It's not romantic unless he tells her himself!
Even if you say so...
If this keeps up she'll never be able to know!
Well, it's not so bad, is it?
Unlike some big liar who's been hiding
his identity from someone he loves.
Hey...
But...
Why can't we match the culprit's voice?
Yeah...
They said the only ones who hated Sumida-san and
didn't have an alibi were those three people.
Three people?
We only heard two people's voices.
Re-mem-ber!
The third suspect was a man.
The culprit's voice that Sensei heard
sounded like a woman, so he was skipped.
Besides...
Kodama Ryuusuke-san, the guy who got skipped, was a
former high school baseball star that lit up the Koshien.
But because he injured his shoulder, he went undrafted.
Looks like he's now working at a host club.
He still didn't give up his dream...
When he was off work, he practiced with a
baseball club team to give it one last shot, but...
He recently completely broke his shoulder,
forcing him to quit the club team.
You know a lot.
I asked Detective Takagi about it afterwards.
And, how about the other two?
Let's see...
The first suspect, Kagitani Kikuna-san, is a freelance worker.
She's the ex-leader of a ladies racing gang.
But because she caused a serious accident, she lost her license.
A ladies gang leader?
Yeah.
It's said that if she calls for it, a hundred people will gather to her.
Then, isn't she the culprit?
Who can say?
I heard that during her trial, she needed
a lot of money to pay for compensation.
And the last person?
Takimoto Ryouko-san is the manager of a small
restaurant, and the daughter of an entrepreneur.
It seems she was trying to get back the money
she had lost on some counterfeit plate...
And had spent quite a fortune on lawyers in an
attempt to sue the now-murdered Sumida-san.
Well, she skipped out on sleep to consult
with her lawyers, so she caught a cold.
She was also wearing a mask on the day
she was called to the police station.
Mask?
I see!
She was wearing the mask in order to disguise her voice!
I thought of that at first as well...
But masks these days are thin enough to preserve one's voice.
And it didn't sound like her voice was obstructed.
But, the culprit Sensei heard had a woman's voice.
If one of the two female suspects is the culprit...
Doesn't the woman with the mask sound extremely suspicious?
That's the thing I'm bothered about.
If she only heard the voice, how can Sensei be sure it was the culprit's?
Of course she can tell.
Because that woman yelled "Listen up,
just hand it over, or I'll kill you-wayo!"
And Sensei said that the fleeing culprit had a full figure.
But the victim, Sumida Akira-san, was a woman too.
Perhaps the "I'll kill you-wayo" was said by Sumida-san.
That's true...
Threatening to kill someone could cause
the opponent to retaliate out of fear.
Beyond that, with regards to the truck with the
"09" that Sensei saw leaving the scene...
Why can't we find it?
The truck the Professor called when he helped his
friend move the other day didn't have numbers on it.
Did you see the truck?
No, but I asked him...
Whether it had numbers on the side or not.
But the truck belonged to a company called
"OSAKA NICO-NICO TRANSPORTATION."
It was the company's name, not numbers,
that was printed largely on the side.
Company's name?
Professor also said...
That the truck driver got lost because he wasn't
familiar with Tokyo and his GPS wasn't working right.
It was already past 8:00 PM when they could
finally start the moving—it was a real hassle.
Hey, Genta-kun.
You look like you're thinking hard about something.
Did you realize something?
No.
My cavity's been hurting so I'm pressing it.
Cavity?
You've been saying that since before summer vacation.
I didn't want to go to the dentist...
Geez...
Don't trick us with that pose, just go to the dentist already.
I see.
Could it be...
Inspector Shiratori?
What are you doing here?
I said I have nothing else to tell the police.
But...
We investigated further afterward...
But we could only conclude that no one else
other than those three could be the culprit.
So I'd like you to listen to their voices one more ti—
That's not necessary.
Didn't I say so already?
None of their voices is the same as what I heard from the culprit.
Or do you think I'm telling a lie?
It's a lie.
It was a lie when I said I'm here to have
you confirm the suspects' voices again.
Actually, I came here just to see you.
To clear up your misunderstanding.
I didn't misunderstand anything...
Looking good!
Go, Inspector Shiratori!
The truth is, when we met during that
earlier case, it wasn't for the first time.
I had met you long before.
You were the girl who scolded the shoplifters in that bookstore.
Bookstore?
Shoplifters?
Yeah.
I was deeply moved by that girl.
That's why I decided to join the police...
After seeing how brave you were.
Brave...?
Police...?
Well?
Do you remember?
No, I'm sorry, but I don't remember.
And, about that girl...
It wasn't me—perhaps you mistook me for Detective Sato?
No, that's...
Well, please excuse me.
Wait...
Sensei!
Well, Kobayashi-sensei.
I'll be heading home now, so would you please lock up when you leave?
Yes.
Thank you for your work.
Thank you as well.
Hello, Teitan Elementary School.
Sorry for the late call.
I'm with the police, is Kobayashi-sensei there?
This is Kobayashi.
But I have nothing else to say to the police.
No, the truck you saw with the 0 and 9 on the side has been found.
We took some photos and were hoping you could identify them.
All right.
If you would please send them to me at a later date...
Oh, no, the confirmation is needed immediately.
I've already asked the security guard to let me inside the school.
Is that so?
Then come to the staff roo—
How about the music room?
The truth is, I graduated from here and
used to be in the brass band club.
It felt nostalgic when I looked around the room.
Oh, is that so?
I'll come to the music room then.
Great, I'll be waiting.
He's an old boy here?
I wonder when he graduated?
Perhaps...
We were in the same class?
Huh?
But the music room was renovated last year, and
the walls and desks have all been replaced.
What's there to be nostalgic about?
Besides, his voice just now...
Where have I...
If you can prove that Sensei's testimony was correct...
Maybe she'll open her heart to you!
Who's there!?
Was someone there.
Yeah, a suspicious shadowy figure was watching us.
Next Conan's Hint
Giraffe