On the night of the firework festival,
Kobayashi-sensei witnessed a murder case.
Listen up, just hand it over!
Or I'll kill you!
Are you all right?
The victim was a pawn shop owner, Sumida Akira-san.
From those who may have held a grudge against
her, three suspects were found to have no alibis.
However, despite Kobayashi-sensei overhearing
quarreling between the culprit and the victim...
She was unable to select a voice that matched
the bellowing from the recorded voices.
Kobayashi-sensei was also acting strangely.
For some reason, she seemed to be avoiding Inspector Shiratori.
It appears she misunderstood his relationship with Detective Satou.
To resolve the misunderstanding, Inspector
Shiratori visited our elementary school...
I had met you long before.
You were the girl who scolded the shoplifters in that bookstore.
I was deeply moved by that girl.
That's why I decided to join the police...
After seeing how brave you were.
No, I'm sorry, but I don't remember.
And, about that girl...
It wasn't me — perhaps you mistook me for Detective Satou?
Well, please excuse me.
Wait...
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
We're double solving the case and the love problem!
And news about Kid has also flown in!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Your precious trump card...
Seems to have gone to waste.
It's because you kept her hanging and
didn't say anything until it was too late!
And why'd you change the story?
The reason you joined the police...
Wasn't because you saw Kobayashi-sensei stand up to the shoplifters...
But wasn't it because you received the sakura
decoration made from straw wrapper after that?
Right, right!
"The sakura is the symbol of police officers in Japan...
"Determined, kind...
And a dignified flower of justice."
Isn't that what Sensei said to you?
Well...
I thought it'd be better if I said I resolved to
join the police after witnessing her bravery...
Perhaps, upon hearing words like "brave" and "police"...
She couldn't help but relate those to her look-alike Detective Satou.
I'll go clear it up!
Don't.
It won't do you any good to make excuses now.
She wouldn't want to hear you speak, right?
Then, what should I...
There is only one way.
If you can catch the culprit that Kobayashi-sensei saw...
And prove that Sensei's testimony was correct...
Maybe she'll open her heart to you.
No, but...
But, among those suspects, none of their
voices matched the one Sensei heard, right?
Still, she did tell us that she saw the
culprit's silhouette as they ran away.
All she could tell was that the culprit had
breasts and her long hair was tied back.
Besides, the moving truck with the large "0" and
"9" printed on the side has yet to be located.
Remind us who the suspects were.
Let's see...
The ex-leader of a ladies gang, the
foul-mouthed Kagitani Kikuna-san...
A small restaurant manager who
caught a cold, Takimoto Ryouko-san...
And the former hero of Koshien who injured his left shoulder and
currently works at a host club, Kodama Ryuusuke-san, these three.
But as of now, based on Kobayashi-sensei's
testimony, the culprit has not yet been identified.
Then, are you saying that Sensei was speaking nonsense?
Kobayashi-sensei would never talk nonsense!
No...
Then, all we have to do is deduce from this.
What made Sensei mistake the facts?
Mistake?
Yeah.
Mistake.
Conan-kun!
What's wrong, Conan?
Was someone there.
Yeah?
A suspicious shadowy figure was watching us.
Was that our culprit?
It could be.
It seems the culprit saw Sensei's face after all.
Idiot.
The culprit wouldn't know where to find her just by seeing her face.
I bet it was some camera brat who likes
to take candid photos of little girls!
Well, it won't do us any good to stay here, so let's go home!
Kobayashi-sensei said she was staying late
tonight to prepare some teaching material.
So even if we wait, she won't be leaving anytime soon!
Hey, Conan!
Wait for us!
Conan-kun!
Wait, you guys...
Hello, Teitan Elementary School.
Sorry for the late call.
I'm with the police, is Kobayashi-sensei there?
This is Kobayashi.
But I have nothing else to say to the police.
No, the truck with the 0 and 9 on the side has been found.
We took some photos and were hoping you could identify them.
All right.
If you would please send them to me at a later date...
Oh, no, the confirmation is needed immediately.
I've already asked the security guard to let me inside the school.
Is that so?
Then come to the staff roo—
How about the music room?
The truth is, I graduated from here and
used to be in the brass band club.
It felt nostalgic when I looked around the room.
Oh, is that so?
I'll come to the music room then.
Great, I'll be waiting.
He's an old boy here?
I wonder when he graduated?
Perhaps...
We were in the same class?
Huh?
But the music room was renovated last year, and
the walls and desks have all been replaced.
What's there to be nostalgic about?
Besides, his voice just now...
Where have I...
Prepare to brace yourself.
Damn...
The hell...
Who the hell are you!?
Police HQ First Division, Criminal Investigation Section 3...
This is Assistant Inspector Satou Miwako...
Kodama Ryuusuke-san.
The police!?
You aren't a teacher!?
The real teacher...
Was under Inspector Shiratori's care in the hall...
And was switched out.
Then, you're saying you knew I was going to be here?
Yeah.
Based on Kobayashi-sensei's testimony.
Cut the crap!
All that "the culprit is a woman" and "I saw a truck with "0" and "9"...
Wasn't that all just nonsense spouted by that damned teacher!?
It's not nonsense!
She just thought she saw a woman!
Right.
The silhouette of your elbow pressing on
your injured shoulder while running away...
Looked just like a woman's chest.
Furthermore, because a female snatcher was lurking in that area...
It's no wonder that she imagined the culprit to be a woman.
Besides...
That woman looked just like a man.
If Sensei heard a man and woman arguing...
And then mistook the body she found as that of the man...
She would easily believe the culprit was the woman.
Is that reasoning correct?
Yeah.
It would be hard to think the bellowing was really from the victim.
Well...
It seems you also cut your long hair to try to deceive us.
Also, what Sensei saw on the side of the truck at the scene...
Weren't the numbers 0 and 9, but the alphabet letters O and S.
The name of the OSAKA NICO-NICO TRANSPORTATION
company had been painted on there in romaji.
The walls obscured them enough to look like numbers.
That truck was hired to move the furniture of Agasa-san's friend.
Earlier, we confirmed with the truck driver...
About the fact that you and the victim were seen entering that alley.
One more thing: as for you knowing Kobayashi-sensei
happened to be an elementary school teacher...
It was because I yelled out "Sensei" as I arrived on the scene.
When a child calls someone "Sensei," the first thing
that comes to mind is an elementary school teacher.
As a result...
You searched the nearest elementary school to find her...
And aimed to silence her.
Yeah...
I was going to mess her up before she remembered anything else...
And threaten her not to give any more testimonies.
Because I don't deserve to get thrown
in the slammer for killing that devil.
But, didn't that "devil" loan you five million yen?
Yeah, that's right!
It costs money to pursue one's dreams.
Medical bills for my shoulder, trainer fees...
Despite her looks, that woman was a high school baseball fan.
She knew about me and had high hopes.
But, soon after she learned that my
shoulder was completely busted...
She changed her attitude with the flip
of her hand and treated me terribly.
Even though I still had a chance to become a
batter, she demanded payment every day...
In the end, she told me to bring my personal
seal and sign a life insurance policy!
Then, what the victim said about "Listen up, just hand it over" was...
Yeah, it was my seal.
She was planning to take out a life
insurance policy on me and kill me!
That's why I killed her before she could do me in!
So I could go on pursuing my dream!
It was self-defense!
Criminal Law, Article #36.
An act unavoidably performed to protect the
rights of oneself or any other person...
Against imminent and unlawful infringement is not punishable.
An act exceeding the limits of self-defense
may lead to the punishment being reduced...
Or may exculpate the offender in light of the circumstances.
These are the provisions of self-defense.
At the time of the crime, you used a
bladed weapon with the intent to kill.
So none of these circumstances apply.
Not to mention, turning a bat which fulfills
dreams into a weapon to silence peopled...
Earns you no right to talk about dreams at all.
Criminal Law, Article #235.
A person who steals the property of
another commits the crime of theft...
And shall be punished by imprisonment for up to ten years.
Was it really you...
At the bookstore back then!?
Did you finally remember me?
Since long before these children were born...
I have been...
In love with you.
Yes!
Sappy...
Now, now.
Hey, Conan-kun.
Is she the teacher who gave Shiratori-kun butterflies?
I swear I've seen her face before...
It's yours, yours!
Don't tell me, you didn't know that when you two switched!
Shiratori-san!
Care to join us for lunch?
No, I'll have to pass this time.
Because I have this.
Well, excuse me.
I bet that's Kobayashi-sensei's homemade bento!
Homemade bento...
Satou-san...
Satou-san!
Would you like to make me a bento?
Would you... like... a bento...?
If you're gonna buy a bento at the store, get one for me too!
You can choose the style!
As long as it stuffs my belly, I'll like it!
Yes...
Takagi-san...
Fight!
Did you see it?
The news about Kid this morning!
I did, I did!
He sent out another notice, right?
Yeah, his target is a big jewel owned by Suzuki Jirokichi...
Kirin's Horn.
It has plant seeds from tens of thousands of years ago mixed in...
A valuable piece of amber!
But that notice was quick.
Regarding the amber that was discovered at the old temple...
Wasn't it just last week?
Well, since they had it advertised on TV
and in newspapers every single day...
Even Kid would take the bait.
But wait...
Do kirins have horns?
They do!
Two small ones.
You're talking about giraffes.
The kirin in question is said to be completely covered in golden scales...
Is shaped like a deer, has a cow's tail and a horse's hooves.
Growing from its dragon-like head is a single horn.
It's a divine beast from Chinese mythology.
azure dragon
white tiger
Then, it's akin to Seiryuu and Byakko!
Well?
Have you been summoned again?
No, I haven't heard anything yet...
How about it, Edogawa-kun?
Looks like you're having another duel with Kid!
Do you have a strategy prepared?
Oh, no...
Just Conan again?
How nice...
Ayumi and the others wanna duel with Kid too.
It can't be helped.
Conan-kun's the one who chases Kid away every time.
May I please have a word with the Detective Boys too?
What is this?
Care to share your enthusiasm?
Why are you asking them?
Huh?
Haven't you heard?
Advisor Suzuki Jiroukichi announced it at the press conference today.
He's seeking assistance from the entire Detective Boys.
No way...
Why?
Mr. Advisor...
I'm not sure what to think about placing
children at the site of Kaitou Kid's attack.
Can't you tell from that guy's advance notice?
"On the night of the next full moon at 7:00 PM...
"I'll be paying a visit to receive Kirin's Horn—Kaitou Kid.
"PS. This time, let us cease the child's play...
"And engage in battle as adults."
How conceited, he revealed his own weakness.
When he says "as adults," he means not to invite children!
That means Kaitou Kid is weak against children!
Weak against children?
Exactly!
Even a master of disguise like him can't appear as a short child!
The kids at the scene would only be a nuisance!
If that's the case, then our strategy is
to invite an entire crowd of children!
I see...
Beyond that, the full moon he mentioned is two nights from now...
The day that mountain temple will be directly hit by the typhoon.
The intense rain will prevent him from using his trademark hang glider.
With his wings clipped, Kaitou Kid is nothing more than a baby!
I'll lead the Detective Boys and make a
grand arrest in front of the TV camera.
It'll be a perfectly beautiful chapter to adorn my autobiography!
They suit you all so well!
Those Detective Boys parkas.
Thank you!
Well, allow me to introduce myself.
Shinkai Juri (37)
Reporter
I'm a reporter, Shinkai Juri.
Pleased to meet you.
And sitting next to me is my cameraman, Masui-san.
Masui Shougo (41)
Cameraman
Nice to meet ya!
And sitting up front is...
Let's see...
Hisumi Isao (38)
Soundman
Hello.
I'm the soundman, Hisumi.
Oh my, I'd heard that the soundman was a young boy...
They couldn't get in contact with him,
so they called me at the last minute.
Don't tell me that just because the typhoon's
coming, he just chickened out like that?
That youngster...
It's really pouring now!
I've been waiting for you, Detective Boys!
Well?
How're the clothes I had made for you?
You had these parkas made for us, mister?
Yeah!
I thought you'd look more like a detective group with matching clothes.
Thank you!
We really like them!
Well?
Where is this Kirin's horn?
From the looks of things, there's a big pillar in the middle....
At the four corners are white, black...
Green, and also...
Red pedestals, that's about it.
Copper pedestals.
The color paint flaked off and the top looks bumpy.
There seems to have been a statue here, but it's been removed.
Look, look!
There's something like a keyhole!
It's true!
Wait!
Hey!
Don't touch things at will!
Inspector Nakamori!
You should've warned the kids that the pedestals
have a mild electrical current running through them!
Kids only learn through pain.
Well?
Where's the horn?
I'll show you right now...
By using these white, black, red, and green...
Four keys I'm holding!
Inspector Nakamori, I require the assistance of your subordinates.
No problem, but...
Be sure to turn off the current!
Shut off the power for a bit.
Understood.
So you use the colored keys on matching pedestals?
Yeah.
What's that sound?
It's the sound of the electrical current in the pedestals being shut off.
After each beep...
The green, red, white, and black pedestals,
in that order, will cease to be electrified.
Inspector, your signal.
All right.
What was that sound?
One, two-and...
Ah, that's...
Three!
The central pillar!
It's splitting!
And inside...
That's...
This is the Kirin!
How rad!
Then, the yellow jewel on its head is...
Yeah, must be the amber they call "Kirin's Horn."
Pretty!
Now, come get it if you dare, Kaitou Kid.
Right here, right now...
I'm gonna catch you!
Damn it!
If there was just one keyhole, I could guard it by myself...
Then, Ayumi and the others will guard them for you!
Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
It must mean that Kaitou Kid and any of his accomplices...
Are still here, that's what!
Next Conan's Hint
Sparrow
Look Forward to the Next Episode