Kirin's Horn.
Found by Advisor Suzuki Jirokichi inside
a mountain temple on a Kirin statue....
It's a horn made of amber.
After hearing the news, that grandiose
Kaitou Kid dispatched his calling card.
The advisor invited us Detective Boys,
who he believes Kid cannot disguise as...
Along with a TV station's live broadcasting crew
to capture Kaitou Kid with great enthusiasm.
The Kirin statue was hidden in the central pillar of the room.
In order to reveal it, four keys need to be inserted into
the pedestals' keyholes in each of the four corners...
And must be turned all at once.
Now, come get it if you dare, Kaitou Kid.
Right here, right now, I'm gonna catch you!
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
The vanishing treasure and Kaitou Kid.
Only the Detective Boys will seek them out!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Good.
Close it.
Yes, sir!
As you can see, if the four pedestal keys
aren't turned at the same time...
No one will be able to see the Kirin statue.
In other words...
So long as that guy doesn't steal the keys
from me and split himself into four people...
He'll have no means of stealing it.
Could it be that the creator of this device is...
That's right, the Master of Tricks from the Bakumatsu...
Samizu Kichiemon, right?
Yeah...
There's writing on the base of the pillar.
"One who desires to acquire Kirin without depending on the
correct method must devote themselves to changing...
"Samizu Kichiemon," it says.
Did you figure out the meaning of this?
No, not yet.
But it's all right so long as I have these four keys in my hands.
It won't be stolen.
Optimistic old man.
If we assume that guy has three accomplices here...
I'm afraid that all he needs to do is cut the
lights and steal the keys for an easy heist.
That's true.
And if Kid were to tamper with these hastily affixed
lights, it seems the power would instantly go out.
Yeah...
And he'd instantly have cut off the pedestal's electrical current too.
It'd be a relief if I could have someone guard the four
pedestals even when the lights go out, but...
I can't know if my subordinates have
been switched with Kid's underlings.
I can't trust those three from the TV crew either.
Damn it!
If there was just one keyhole, I could guard it by myself...
Then, Ayumi and the others will guard them for you!
Kid has no way to disguise as us!
We're the ones you can rely on the most.
Plus, if just the four of us managed to protect the
treasure from Kid, we can rub it in Edogawa-kun's face.
That's true!
But is that all right?
If you touch the pedestals before the
power is shut off, you'll get shocked.
It's fine.
As long as we don't mess up the order.
After the beeps, the power will turn off to the
order of green, red, white, and black, right?
Yeah, don't get confused.
Now, it's just ten minutes before Kid's announced time!
Will Kid really show up at this mountain temple
where the Detective Boys are lying in wait?
Now, let's all go catch Kid!
Conan-kun and the others are really on TV!
How nice...
Why didn't you go there too?
Uncle Jirokichi rejected us over the phone!
"This time I'm only inviting children.
"No one that Kid can disguise himself as!"
So he said.
Take a five minute break!
We'll be going on standby three minutes
before showtime, so I'll be counting on you.
OK!
Roger that.
Then we'll go on standby too.
Right!
Hey, where are you guys going?
To guard the pedestals!
The question is whether or not you'll guard the keys, old man.
There's no need to worry.
With the keys nailed to the wall like that, that guy can do nothing at all.
It's my victory!
A blackout?
Don't get flustered!
A blackout is to be expected.
Rain and wind...
Someone opened the window?
Are you getting this?
Yeah, but in this darkness, there's nothing...
And the audio?
We're picking it up for now...
Could it be!?
This sound...
The pillar!?
Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
Hang in there!
Kirin's...
Kirin's Horn...
It's gone!
Conan-kun...
Conan-kun!
Open your eyes...
What are you doing!?
Why aren't the lights back on!?
Calm down!
Everyone, stay where you are!
Wait, what happened?
Did Kid come?
Who knows...
They're on!
Hey, hey, hey!
Kirin's Horn...
It's been stolen!
Impossible!
The four keys are still pinned to the wall!
How in the world did...
I don't know yet how he did it, but...
During the approximately one minute long blackout...
He, or his accomplice, ran around in the dark...
And got to the four pedestals with the keyholes, that much is certain.
This is...
I have obtained the Kirin's horn
Kaitou Kid
Kid's card!
When did he!?
Inspector!
There's a card on this pedestal too!
Here too!
There's one here as well!
All four of them?
Inspector!
The breaker at the main temple was rigged.
The blackout likely resulted from that.
Inspector, over here.
It looks like small time-bombs were set
on all of the temple's storm windows.
That damn Kid...
He didn't just cause the blackout to create darkness.
He also blew out the windows to let the wind
and rain into cause such commotion...
And escaped during the confusion!
At any rate, take this youngster who
was attacked by Kid to the hospital.
Bring a car around!
And have the rest of the cars pursue Kid!
With this typhoon, he can't use his hang
glider, so he couldn't have gotten very far!
But...
According to the report that just arrived...
What!?
Due to a landslide, the roads are closed!?
Hey now, if that youngster was given poison or something...
It wasn't poison.
Look, a stun gun.
It seems as if Edogawa-kun was knocked out using this.
I see...
That guy took out this lad, his toughest opponent, first.
I'm sorry...
Don't "I see" me!
It's all because you made a huge fuss to the
media about that jewel you found last week.
You provoked that guy before you had a proper security detail.
It was a month ago.
It was a month ago that I heard that the magnificent piece of
amber known as "Kirin's Horn" was sleeping in this temple.
I purposely delayed the announcement
until I had obtained ownership of it.
The premise that this senile fool had gotten caught up in
the moment of having found bait to hook him with...
And that yours truly foolishly challenged him to a duel without
having arranged a sufficient security force — was actually planned.
Then, these lights that seem hastily affixed...
That's right.
I was aware those could be manipulated to cause a blackout.
And I already noticed the stupid trick he set up on the storm windows.
The weak electricity running through the four
pedestals, and calling the Detective Boys here...
It was all part of the scheme to confuse and
entice him into coming to this musty old temple.
The wood on the windows that looks rotted and easily broken...
And the wall that looks like a single strike could knock it down...
They have steel inside.
Furthermore, on the two doors that serve as entrances and
exits, I set up locking mechanisms and hid sensors in them.
They're designed so if they're forced
open, a piercing alarm will go off.
Since we didn't hear that sound, it must mean...
That Kaitou Kid and any of his accomplices...
Are still here, that's what!
They're...
Still here?
Kid is?
Now, Inspector Nakamori...
It's your turn.
Other than the children, go ahead and pinch everyone's face...
Before that, there's something I want you to clear up for me.
How did Kid steal that amber horn from the Kirin statue?
Before the blackout, you nailed the white,
black, red, and green keys to the wall.
And in the four corners of the room...
Are white, black, red, and green pedestals with keyholes, which
the keys needed to be put into and turned at the same time.
Otherwise the statue of Kirin hidden in
the central pillar shouldn't be revealed!
Even if Kid somehow made spare copies of the keys...
How could he accomplish that in the darkness, where
neither the pedestal nor the keyhole were visible?
If it's just light, couldn't it have been the kids?
They have lights on their watches.
Since they said they'd protect the pedestals,
that guy probably relied on their lights.
We didn't turn on any lights!
It's true we were blocking the keyholes like this, but...
Haibara told us not to turn our lights on, even if the lights went out.
And...
While you were blocking them, no one came?
This keyhole...
Something's shining.
This is...
Fluorescent paint!
Inspector!
This keyhole also has fluorescent paint!
Don't tell me, could it be...
As I figured, there's fluorescent paint on the tips of all four keys.
It probably got there when they were put in the keyholes.
Then, with just the tiniest bit of illumination on the keyholes...
Yeah.
He handed the keys off to his accomplices in the darkness, who put
them into the lit keyholes and turned them at the same time...
And thus Kirin's Horn was stolen.
Isn't that right?
Kaitou Kid-san!
Me?
Isn't that the case?
It's an obvious fact that the keys Kid used
weren't copies, but these keys right here!
Which means you purposely nailed the metal hook
holding the keys with little force for easy access...
And after using the keys, you returned
them to the wall - the only possibility!
Then why don't you try pulling the hook off?
They aren't so easily moved!
You simply secured them better after use, didn't you?
If you're going to go that far, then just search me!
After all if I'm Kid, then I should have Kirin's Horn on me!
Yeah, even if you hadn't suggested it, I was planning on doing th—
Wait.
Why not allow the Detective Boys to conduct the searches?
If the inspector and advisor are Kid and his accomplice...
There's the possibility you could rig the search to deceive us.
That's right!
You can relax if it's us!
There's no way we could be Kid's accomplices!
That's true, but...
Though, we'll also search everyone else, is that OK?
"Due to certain circumstances, we will
be switching to another program.
"We apologize for the wait."
The scrolling ticker has been saying that for a while...
It's not starting at all, huh?
But, I wonder what that strange sound was?
It was hard on the ears, right?
Huh?
Was there a sound like that?
What did you say?
Despite the fact you've searched everyone here, are
you saying you still couldn't locate the Kirin's Horn?
Yeah.
We figured it may have been slipped onto us...
So we even checked our own clothes and Edogawa-kun's
pockets, but nothing came out.
How odd.
The space between the window bars is such that Kirin's Horn can't be
pushed through, so even if he had an accomplice on the outside...
He wouldn't have been able to pass it off.
As—I—said!
Kid has already escaped.
Hurry and open the doors so we can chase after him!
But...
That's true...
Since the sought-after jewel is gone, it's
natural to think Kid wouldn't still be here.
But I just don't get it.
The reason why he had to knock out Kudou-kun.
Well, taking out a bothersome opponent would
be considered an overwhelming victory, but...
If you merely put them to sleep, you won't get
the satisfaction of rubbing it in their face.
Was there some other reason?
What also bothers me...
Is Samizu Kichiemon's statement carved into this pillar.
"One who desires to acquire Kirin without depending on
the correct method must devote themselves to changing."
In other words, those who want to get Kirin's
Horn without following the right steps...
Must go with the flow.
The correct method likely refers to the keys.
But what is the "flow"?
Wind?
The flow of the wind?
No...
The reason the wind's coming in is
because Kid broke the storm windows.
That's right!
Why did Kid open the windows in the first place?
Since he already caused a blackout, there's no point
in further confusing us with the wind and rain.
Even if Inspector Nakamori is right and that Advisor Suzuki is Kid...
He'd have to take off the keys affixed to
the wall within a minute in the dark.
Handing them off to accomplices without any light...
Turning the keys at the same time without a signal...
And making the stolen jewel disappear
as if by magic, is it even possible?
Also, whether or not Kid even had any accomplices is doubtful.
Calling a number of accomplices to this locked room...
There's a chance that one of them may get caught.
I'd definitely avoid a risk like that.
Ah, can't do it.
I'm not good at this.
You'd definitely say something like this, right?
"You can't even figure out something this elementary?"
Like a sparrow, you'd chirp and chatter...
About that vast knowledge of yours.
Sparrow...
About this paragraph...
Perhaps the word "sparrow" could be a hint.
Why?
Most of it has faded, but the kanji for
"sparrow" is carved in that red pedestal.
Really?
Red sparrow...
Suzaku!?
It's true!
You can see the kanji for "sparrow" on top of it!
Then, maybe there was a sparrow statue attached to the top!
It's not a sparrow.
"Red" could be "vermilion".
If the faded word above the kanji "sparrow" had been "vermilion"...
It would form the name of a legendary
creature among the four Divine Beasts...
Suzaku, right?
Suzaku
Vermilion Bird
Suzaku is...
Something you see in games...
A red bird like a phoenix?
Yeah.
And facing the red pedestal on the right
side, the white pedestal must be for...
Byakko.
Byakko
White Tiger
And further to the right is this black pedestal for...
Genbu.
Genbu
Black Tortoise
Further to the right again, the green pedestal that
is also to the left of the red pedestal earlier...
There's no denying that a statue of Seiryuu had been there.
Please hold on a second.
Isn't Seiryuu written as "azure dragon"?
That pedestal's color is green, no?
The kanji for "azure" was originally used to represent the
color of plants as seen in lush mountains and trees.
Seiryuu
Azure Dragon
Seiryuu's original color was actually meant to be green.
The four divine beasts each have a direction they protect.
Suzaku is the south.
Byakko is the west.
Genbu is the north.
And Seiryuu is the east.
And in the center location would be...
That Kirin, they say.
Then, this paragraph written by Samizu
Kichiemon at the bottom of this pillar is...
The "aftercare" or backup plan in case the keys are lost or stolen.
The "one who desires to acquire Kirin without
depending on the correct method" refers to...
Those who want to get Kirin's Horn without using the keys.
And the next part, the "changing" from "must
devote themselves to changing" means...
The flow of time or the changing of places.
As for the "devote themselves" part, we probably can
take it to mean "to go with the flow and let it be."
Then, by just waiting and not doing anything,
the Kirin would appear from the pillar?
No.
If the four pedestals in the corners of this room
are Suzaku, Byakko, Genbu, and Seiryuu...
Wouldn't it have something to do with the
colors and directions that each represents?
That's true.
I think it may be asking us to perform some action in
accordance with a particular order for the four pedestals.
But colors don't have any order.
Then maybe it has something to do with
the order of east, west, south and north?
But, we say "east-north region" here in
Japan, so shouldn't north come after east?
I think the order should start with north!
Since north is on the top in all maps.
It looks like we can't decide on an order going by only directions.
Be it going clockwise or counter-clockwise,
they will still flow continuously.
That's true.
If only Suzaku, Byakko, Genbu, and Seiryuu had an
order attached to them, it might have worked...
I bet Conan-kun would know something, but...
He's been sleeping like that the whole time.
In any case, as far as revealing the
Kirin statue from the pillar goes...
It has to be done by either inserting the four keys into the
four pedestal keyholes and turning at the same time...
Or without the keys, by doing something to the four pedestals in
some kind of order - there doesn't seem to be any other way.
And Kid doing that during the one
minute blackout seems impossible.
If he had accomplices, there had to be some sort of a signal.
So let's first determine that.
How can we determine that?
There is a way.
The people who filmed the evidential VTR...
The TV crew.
Kudo-kun.
Until you open your eyes...
The rest of us will have no choice but to do our best.
Although it was supposed to be a young staff member...
If you're going this far, then you're suspicious too, cameraman!
Don't sleep forever, just lend us some knowledge.
White...
Remove the lock from that door at once!
It's you, isn't it?
Magician in the Moonlight?
Next Conan's Hint
Genta's 10-Yen-Sized Bald Spot
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Pun on pronounciation
of "bald" and "bold"