Aiming for the big jewel known as Kirin's
Horn, Kaitou Kid passed on a notice.
Kirin's Horn was protected by a security
mechanism crafted by Samizu Kichiemon...
And could not be removed unless four keys
were turned simultaneously in four pedestals.
We Detective Boys ended up safeguarding the four pedestals, but...
In the dark, Edogawa-kun was knocked
out, and Kirin's Horn suddenly vanished.
The four pedestals represent the legendary creatures...
Suzaku
Vermilion Bird
Suzaku...
Byakko
White Tiger
Byakko...
Genbu
Black Tortoise
Genbu...
Seiryuu
Azure Dragon
And Seiryuu, the four Divine Beasts.
Perhaps Samizu Kichiemon's statement that was carved
in the base of the central pillar containing Kirin's Horn...
Has something to do with this.
It looks like we Detective Boys have no
choice but to solve this mystery ourselves.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Kaitou Kid's been trapped in the room.
But who would've thought he'd disguise as—!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What?
You want to review the video and audio from the blackout?
We want to see whether you caught any odd lights or sounds.
That's a good point.
Since, in that darkness, turning the four keys in the
pedestals together would warrant some sort of signal.
Let's confirm that with the VTR.
A blackout?
Don't get flustered!
A blackout is to be expected.
It's the sound of the storm windows breaking,
and the rain and wind rushing into the temple.
Ayumi was surprised, so I put on my hood.
Me too!
I did as well.
Watch it quietly!
Are you getting this?
Yes, sir.
Those are our voices.
Yeah.
Seems it.
This is the sound of the electricity in the pedestals being cut, right?
Could it be!?
It's the sound of the central pillar rising and Kirin being revealed.
So that's the light from the stun gun...
Conan-kun?
A light came on.
Ayumi turned it on.
I was worried because I heard Conan-kun's scream.
And after that...
Kirin's...
Kirin's Horn
It's gone!
It seems the jewel had already been stolen by this point.
They're on!
Looks like there weren't any strange sounds or lights after all.
At the absolute most, there was the light from the stun gun
that knocked the lad with glasses out, and his scream.
But, before his scream, there was
already the sound of the pillar moving...
But if that sound was a fake that Kid recorded...
And if we assume Kid had finished passing out
the keys to his accomplices during that time...
Then, since we left the pedestals because of Edogawa-kun's scream...
It's possible for them to turn the keys at the same time.
That's true, but...
Until you heard that scream, were you guys really
protecting the keyholes on the pedestals?
Yeah, we protected them.
We spread our arms like this.
We leaned against the pedestals and blocked the keyholes.
Speaking of which, who protected which pedestal?
The one I protected was...
That black pedestal.
And I was in charge of the green one.
Ayumi's was that white one.
And finally, I had this red pedestal.
But weren't you scared?
Because even if there was a blackout, electricity
was still running through the pedestals.
Yeah, that's why...
Hey, old man!
This floor...
It's rotten here and there, but are there
iron plates inside like with the walls?
Yeah.
But as far as under the floor, the ceiling, and the four corners go...
I didn't touch them since there were already
complicated mechanisms installed.
Well, there's a wire mesh surrounding
the crawl space, so there's no escape.
Uhm...
If you're saying Kid has accomplices among
us, I know someone that's suspicious.
It's the guy in charge of the audio.
Although it was supposed to be a young staff member...
He suddenly got replaced for no reason.
I told you, that's because they couldn't get in touch with that guy.
If you're going this far, then you're suspicious too, cameraman!
The person who's really in charge of the camera for
this program was a junior of mine from college.
But a pro like you somehow took over!
What're you saying!?
He's the one who called and asked me to substitute for him, saying
he lacked the confidence to do a live broadcast fresh out of college!
That's what I heard too.
Since Advisor Suzuki was all fired up and even
purposely prepared matching parkas for the kids...
That's why they replaced him with a pro.
"Purposely," you say?
I had those made only because your TV station
told me it'd be more thrilling that way!
And the one who called me and recommended an apparel company...
Wasn't it you, Miss Reporter?
Me?
I know nothing about that.
Say...
Did you also call us Detective Boys here
because someone else told you to?
No, it was written in the postscript of that guy's advance notice.
"This time, let us cease the child's play and
engage in battles as adults," it said.
That's how I realized that guy was weak against children,
and the reason why I called in the Detective Boys.
It's true that if the calls reaching the
TV station staff were all Kid's doing...
It would mean he was purposely trying to exclude young people here.
If so, I wonder why he wrote that on
the postscript of his advance notice?
Judging from the advisor's character...
Isn't it easy to predict that he'd call us, the
extremely young Detective Boys, here?
And besides, this case is full of mysteries.
It's baffling that the stolen jewel hasn't been found anywhere.
The same can be said to the four keys nailed to the wall by the advisor.
If he really nailed the metal hook holding the keys with little force...
Then upon returning the keys, he'd have to make
a loud noise in order to nail the hook firmly back.
Yet I didn't hear anything like that in the video.
Maybe the fluorescent paint on the keys and keyholes were faked...
And he really used the keyless method
described by the statement on this pillar?
Geez...
Don't sleep forever, just lend us some knowledge.
White...
Conan-kun, you woke up?
You're too loud.
We're keeping it a secret that you've woken up?
Hey, why is that?
You fool.
This is the first time Kid's ever knocked me out.
How can I get up without knowing the reason?
By the way, what was that "beep" sound?
That's the sound of the electrical
current in the pedestals being cut off.
In the order of green, red, white, and
black, each sound means it's been cut.
That's why the inspector asked us to protect
each pedestal as we hear the sounds.
Also, can you tell me the position of Kid's cards on the pedestals?
The position.
On the red pedestal, it's taped right above the keyhole.
And on the green pedestal it's a little
higher up — I can see those from here, but...
I can't see the black or white ones.
The white one is the same as the red one, it's right above the keyhole.
The card on the black one is even higher than the green one.
I see.
That's how it is.
Then, can you guys surround me so no one can see what I'm doing?
This posture is really starting to hurt.
That's right...
And you can see things that you shouldn't.
Ah, no...
That was an accident...
Pervert.
Idiot, I'd have stayed quiet and kept looking if I were a perv—
Conan-kun!?
I've got it.
The reason why Kid knocked me out.
Really?
And of course...
Kid's identity.
He's one of those people!
Can you inform someone from the riot squad for me?
That because the person Kid disguised as is currently
being confined somewhere in this temple...
They need to tell the squad on the
outside and let them start the search.
But which member should we tell?
That's right...
If one of Kid's accomplices disguised as a squad member...
No, Kid doesn't have any accomplices here.
Kid stole the amber horn from the Kirin statue all by himself.
With the help of four unsuspecting underlings!
Four underlings...
You mean...
Remove the lock from that door at once!
Let us pursue that damned Kid!
No, I will not open the door.
Why?
I still have a feeling that guy is lurking inside this room.
He's still eagerly waiting for the door to be opened.
That's how I feel!
You're right.
It won't do if you open the door.
Because his escape has been hampered beyond his expectation.
With no accomplices here in the room, I'm
sure he's breaking out in a cold sweat.
No accomplices, you say?
Hey, hey, did you forget?
There's no other way than to insert the four keys in the
pedestal keyholes and turn them simultaneously.
Including Kid, there had to be at least four people to do that.
Not to mention that the four keys...
They were affixed with this metal hook
before the crime by the old man like this!
The keys don't matter.
Because Kid didn't use them!
Look here...
Didn't I say all keys and keyholes have fluorescent paint on them?
But you don't know when the fluorescent paint got there, do you?
That's right.
Even before the blackout, the keys and the keyholes...
May have had paint applied by Kid!
That may be true, but...
Can the Kirin statue be revealed without the keys?
It's written on the base of the pillar, isn't it?
"Those who desire to acquire Kirin without depending on
the correct method must devote themselves to changing."
This is the "aftercare" left by Samizu
Kichiemon in case the keys are lost.
It means that those who want to get Kirin's Horn
without using the keys must go with the flow.
What "flow" is this?
The four beasts.
The pedestals in the four corners
represent the legendary divine beasts.
This green pedestal is Seiryuu.
The white pedestal is Byakko.
The black one is Genbu.
And this red pedestal is for Suzaku.
But do the four divine beasts have an order to them?
The seasons.
The seasons?
Azure Dragon
Seiryuu represents spring.
Vermilion Bird
Suzaku is summer.
White Tiger
Byakko is autumn.
Black Tortoise
Genbu is said to represent winter, and...
If "must devote themselves to changing" means
to hand ourselves over to the flow of seasons...
Then we must entrust our bodies in the
order of spring, summer, fall, and winter.
Entrust our bodies?
In other words, to press our bodies against the pedestals like this!
Next up, Haibara-san.
Alright, Yoshida-san.
Last is Genta-kun.
The pillar is...
Moving...
It's closing...
It's closed!
Now do you see?
Even without the keys, the pillar can still be raised and lowered.
But the blackout was only one minute.
Are you saying that Kid ran around the room, affixed his
cards and leaned against the pedestals, all without a light?
It wasn't Kid.
We were the ones who leaned against them.
We were asked to protect the pedestal keyholes
in the order of green, red, white, and black.
Isn't that right?
Inspector Nakamori.
No...
Mr. Magician in the Moonlight?
I see!
If they were protecting the keyholes...
They would have to press their backs against the
pedestals while keeping an eye on their surroundings!
Hey, hey!
How did the cards get attached then?
You had us do that, too!
When the windows broke and the rain
and wind came in, we put our hoods on!
The sticker cards were stuck to our backs and hidden by the hoods.
You had them attached by making us lean against the pedestals!
As proof, the position of the cards corresponds
to the height of the child who was guarding it.
So they do...
Perhaps Kid used the reporter's voice to call Advisor Suzuki...
And by recommending a merchant that makes these
parkas, he was able to set this trick up himself.
But I'm amazed that you've managed to lean against the
pedestals in that darkness without mistaking the order.
From what I could see from the VTR, there didn't seem to be any signal.
It's the sound.
This guy said it himself.
"In the order of green, red, white, and black, we'll hear
sounds of the electrical current being cut off..."
"So we need to wait for the sounds and
protect the pedestals in that order."
But I never set up any such sounds...
Didn't you hear those?
They went "beep, beep"...
And were harsh on the ears!
Did you hear something like that?
No...
Not at all.
Mosquito sound.
After the age of 20, human ears begin to deteriorate and
it becomes difficult to detect high frequency waves.
You played the sounds only children could hear in
order to instruct them on the order of the pedestals.
Even if there was a sound, it wouldn't be
questioned if nobody says anything about it.
That's why you got the young TV staff members out of the way, right?
To prevent them from hearing the sounds.
You didn't tell us about the mosquito sound part at all.
Sorry...
But, where is Kirin's Horn then?
About that...
It was in the hood of my parka.
His plan was to pretend to take me to the hospital
after I was knocked out by the stun gun...
And then slip away with the jewel from there.
Well, I realized it soon after I got up because of the jewel's weight.
As for the fluorescent paint...
You applied them soon after you got the keys from
the advisor who wanted to show us the Kirin statue.
Since you applied the fluorescent paint to the keys first...
Of course the keyholes would have paint on them after use.
In that case, where's the real inspector?
I think he was knocked out by the stun
gun and is somewhere around here...
Open the door!
That's Kaitou Kid disguised as me in there!
Why not let him in?
But, what if he's one of that guy's accomplices
that's come to help aid his escape?
If he had planned that, he would've done so earlier.
I see.
All right, open the door.
How's this, Kid?
I've tagged all of the adults except for you!
With this, you can't disguise as anyone.
Because the one without my seal on their face...
Is only you!
And just like that, your number is up!
Well, well...
I wonder about that.
Genta!?
Spotlights, now!
Find him!
The one without my seal on his face...
He must be Kid!
But, Inspector...
Everyone has a seal on their face.
We can't locate Kid's presence anywhere!
How's that possible!?
Then, where the hell did he go?
He couldn't possibly disguise as a child...
Hey!
Help me out here!
Genta-kun?
What's with that hole?
I don't know!
Someone grabbed me when it got dark...
And pulled me into this hole!
Come to think of it...
While Kid was disguised as Inspector
Nakamori, he was touching the floor.
He probably set some simple explosive device
back then and opened a hole in the floor...
And escaped under the floor using Genta as a plug.
All right, Kid's under the floor!
Open the door now.
Got it.
Genta, stay there and don't move!
If someone grabs your leg, let us know by shouting at us!
Hey, do you see him?
No, not yet...
Wait, hold on...
Genta's 10-yen bold spot should've been...
Kaitou Kid!?
I'll return this to you.
It's not the jewel I'm seeking anyway.
When did you...
Where's Genta?
Sleeping under the hole.
Soundly.
I see.
You only wanted to prove you could even disguise as a child.
Bingo!
For Kaitou Kid...
Nothing is impossible!
Later!
Wait.
You forgot something.
That squad member is Kid!
Get him!
What!?
Kid!?
Once I hide in the forest with this disguise, they'll be
unable to tell me apart from the other squad members!
Kid located!
The position is six kilometers west of the mountain temple!
It's Kid!
He's here!
How!?
How did they find me!?
Just returning the favor for knocking me out.
I'm gonna make french fries from potatoes
dug at the farm to go with my beer!
Inspector, about the body...
Doesn't it look like he's pointing to himself with his index finger?
He's probably using his face to tell us about the culprit!
Why are there injuries on his forehead too?
Next Conan's Hint
Scarecrow
Look Forward to the Next Episode