Mejiro-san!
Good evening, we've come out for a field trip!
Ran-chan!
You're here early!
How amazing!
So many autumn vegetables here.
You put in a lot of effort, even during weekdays.
Mejiro Misa (45)
Office Worker
I just manege to water and harvest them after I get back from work.
It's convenient when it's so near, isn't it?
Who did it?
Who sabotaged my insect net?
Taguchi Shinichirou (51)
Salaryman
And I worked so hard to set them up just for my vegetables!
It was your doing, wasn't it!?
I dunno.
Nakamura Takehiko (73)
Unemployed
But thanks to that, my patch can get the sunlight it deserves.
If only that annoying old-timer weren't here...
Don't throw your weeds into my field!
I know nothing of it.
Inoue Marie (26)
Office Lady
Don't make me repeat myself!
Knock it off already!
Shut up!
Didn't I just say I know nothing of it?
He even managed to flood my patch the other day.
Seems like that old man brings nothing but trouble.
Sorry about all this.
You're here for a field trip, not for this nonsense.
Say, would you like to help me with my harvest next time?
I'll share some of my organic vegetables with you.
Nothing delicious about vegetables with
so many bug-bitten holes in them!
What's with this farm?
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
A murder case at the rooftop farm.
Scarecrow Kogoro takes the stage today!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Dad, you're all fired up!
I'm gonna make french fries from potatoes
dug at the farm to go with my beer!
Just don't pop a hole in the roof.
That's...
The old man from the other day?
Too late.
A forehead wound as well?
The deceased was Nakamura Takehiko-san, 73 years old...
A senior who lives nearby.
The estimated time of death is approximately 10:00 AM.
When you guys arrived at this rooftop farm,
Nakamura-san had already collapsed, is that right?
Yes!
It was around 11:00 when we found him.
By the way, what's with that getup?
My daughter and I came here to help with Mejiro-san's harvest.
Very well.
Is Nakamura-san one of those who rented a patch?
Yeah.
Because he's been causing various troubles to those around him,
the other renters have nicknamed him "Annoying Old-Timer".
I see.
It's worth investigating to see if this has anything to do with the case.
Blunt force trauma to the back of his head was the cause of death.
Looks like he hit his head on the corner of that water tank.
So he collapsed facing upwards?
There are shoe marks indicating he slipped.
Why is there a wound on his forehead?
It looks pretty recent.
Perhaps something else hit his head?
Maybe he was washing his hands by the drain
but accidentally hit his head on the faucet.
Taken by surprise, he staggered back and slipped
on the floor, causing him to fall on his back.
What do you think?
Maybe that's why the towel fell on this side of the drain.
What's with that smudge?
According to the investigator's report...
It was the same material as the paint on the fence handrails.
It probably was hung over the handrail.
Did this man carry two towels?
There was a cell phone next to the body.
Go find out whether this belonged to Nakamura-san or not.
Yes, sir.
As for entering or exiting this rooftop, there's the elevator...
The emergency staircase is undergoing maintenance, so there's
no means of accessing the rooftop via the stairs at the moment.
Which leaves the only access point as the elevator.
There doesn't seem to be a taller building around either.
The windows of this building are all iron-barred.
As such, there's no way for anyone to climb
out of the window and up the rooftop.
Check the security camera in the elevator to see
whether anyone entered or exited the rooftop.
Understood.
To confirm whether they're related to this
incident, let's interview the farm renters.
Yes!
Takagi.
Bring in the relevant parties.
Understood.
Regardless, this body is striking a strange pose.
What is it?
This pose...
Could this be!?
Mouri-kun, what's wrong?
Inspector, about this body...
Doesn't it look like he's pointing to himself with his index finger?
Well, I can't say that it doesn't, but...
Couldn't it be that the pose was a coincidence
stemming from his tripping and falling down?
Ran!
About the rooftop farm renters we met the other day...
Who else was there other than Mejiro-san!?
Well, there's the salaryman Taguchi-san,
and the office lady Inoue-san, I think.
Inspector, some suspects have the kanji for facial parts in their names!
Mejiro-san contains "eyes".
Taguchi-san has "mouth".
Prior to his death, Nakamura-san probably
used his face to tell us about the culprit!
Are you serious?
But, we can't tell which part of the face he's pointing to as of now.
Was it the eyes, or the mouth?
What do you police have to tell us?
This morning, Nakamura-san was found dead at the rooftop farm.
That annoying old-timer?
My, now my patch can finally return to peace.
I feel as if a burden has been taken off my chest.
It's these three, correct?
Yes.
And when I went to the farm the other day, I heard that
Nakamura-san was bringing trouble to all of them.
Mejiro-san had her patch flooded.
Taguchi-san had his insect net sabotaged.
Inoue-san had weeds thrown in her patch.
And there may be further examples of his troubles beyond these.
The grudge against him built up, and finally...
Wait, that old man was killed!?
Don't tell me you think we did it?
Now, now.
We've yet to establish this as a murder.
We're only bringing you here as voluntary
material witnesses to gather information.
With our estimated time of death for Nakamura-san being 10:00 AM...
Please tell me where you three were and what you were doing.
Let's see...
Let's start from the renter of the patch diagonally across from his...
Mejiro-san, if you please.
I work in the office on the first floor of this building.
Since I hadn't finished the management tasks from
yesterday, I came to work today at about 8:30 AM.
Where were you at 10:00?
It wasn't until 11:00 that Ran-chan and her family were due to come
help with my harvesting, so I was working in the office until then.
Can anyone else verify that?
With today being Saturday, no one else
had reason to be there besides me.
Because Mejiro-san is working in this building,
she'd have easy access to the rooftop.
Maybe his finger was pointing to the eyes...
Then, how about the renter of the patch right next
to Nakamura-san's, the salaryman, Taguchi-san?
Before noon, I went to the home center alone to buy some mulch.
I was planning to come to the farm this afternoon.
Can anyone else verily that?
If the clerk from the home center can remember me...
Oh, right!
I have the receipt.
Here you go.
A receipt issued at 11:00 AM can't be used as an alibi.
Oh, dear...
Could the dying message be referring to the mouth?
Then, what about the renter across from
Nakamura-san, the office lady Inoue-san?
Because it's my day off from work, I woke up pretty late.
Around 10:00?
Well...
I think I turned on my TV and watched it half-awake, but...
I don't think anyone else can attest to that.
I live alone.
Although Inoue-san's floor is right below the rooftop...
Her name doesn't contain any kanji for facial parts.
It doesn't look like anyone has a sound alibi.
I would like to ask everyone to come to the
scene and answer a few more questions.
The annoying old-timer managed to
bring us trouble even after death.
Be it an accident or a murder, he
deserved it as far as I'm concerned.
He chose to hit his head and drop dead...
Yet he still managed to drag us into this, how annoying indeed.
Yes?
I see.
Understood.
Inspector...
The cell phone belonged to Nakamura-san after all.
There was an incoming call with no caller ID at around 10:00 AM.
It seems to be from a prepaid cell phone number.
We don't know who made that call yet.
Look into it just in case.
Got it.
What should we do about those three?
Looks like their attitudes and testimonies
didn't change even after viewing the scene...
Inspector!
We've checked the footage of the elevator security camera.
Nakamura-san ascended the rooftop at 9:00 AM.
And, until 11:00 AM when Mouri-san and the
others arrived, no one else came to the rooftop.
Which means, other than Nakamura-san,
no one entered or exited the rooftop.
Nothing appears to be suspicious.
In other words, this is an accident prone to senior citizens.
After working on the farm, Nakamura-san came to wash his hands.
Just then, his cell phone rang, and he slipped out of carelessness...
Hitting the back of his head on the corner of the water tank!
That was the sequence of events.
But didn't you also mention that the body's
strange pose was supposed to mean something?
No, no, no, I was merely exploring one possibility!
When he slipped on the floor, he thought "I'm a goner!"...
And as a result struck a pose, that was all.
And the forehead wound?
While he was falling down, he hit his
head with the cell phone in his hand.
Right, let's conclude this case as an accident.
Something's bothering me.
There are two suspicious points:
One being the wound on Nakamura-san's forehead...
And the other being that another towel was on the
ground despite there already being one around his neck.
Ran-neechan, if you touch anything from
the scene, the police will get mad at you!
The support stake fell on the side, so I...
This...
I see.
So that's how it was.
We're finally released.
If it was an accident, they should've told us so from the beginning.
My day off has been wasted thanks to this.
Uncle, do me a favor.
Damn!
Inspector...
Among those three people...
There lies a true culprit who murdered Nakamura-san...
And made it appear to be an accident to lead the police astray.
What are you...
Didn't you also say this was an accident a moment ago?
I was only telling a lie to lower the culprit's guard.
Regardless, please gather the suspects here.
You're presenting your deduction posing like that?
Does my pose have any relevance?
What is of concern here is the truth behind the case.
Man...
What is it now?
Geez.
In order for it to look like an accident, the culprit
who killed Nakamura-san employed a certain trick.
A trick?
Hey, hey, are you sure?
Why are you still saying that?
I realized there was a trick after noticing
Nakamura-san's forehead wound.
That wound cannot be inflicted by slipping on
the draining floor and falling on one's back.
Rather, something flew over here and hit his forehead.
But...
Didn't we determine that there were no other
buildings in range for objects to be thrown from?
Yes, and that is how we were deceived.
The kid from my agency discovered
something of interest in the cabbage patch.
Hey, Conan!
Here it is.
When I pieced together all the shards, it formed a brick.
This...
Someone opened a hole in the middle.
The brick pieces were scattered around the border
of Nakamura-san's and Inoue-san's patches.
That flew over here and hit Nakamura-san in forehead.
The reason it's in pieces is probably
because it hit the paving stones.
Flew over here?
From where, exactly?
The brick didn't fly across the building, but flew up from below.
From below?
The towel was dropped between the handrails and the drain, right?
I was intrigued by that.
There was already a towel around Nakamura-san's
neck, yet another towel was present on the floor.
Come to think of it, that man put his initials on his towel, but...
That one doesn't have those.
Inspector...
Do you remember there being paint from the
handrail on the inner side of the towel?
I did receive reports to that effect, but what about it?
That paint smudge appeared to have been scraped against something.
The towel was hanging over the handrail, while a force
made it rub against the paint and fall on the ground.
What do you mean?
The culprit threaded a rope through the hole on the brick...
And hung it over the handrail on the rooftop.
The towel was probably hung between the handrail and the rope.
And when Nakamura-san approached the handrail...
The culprit pulled the rope hard from the floor below!
Nakamura-san slipped because of the impact...
And hit his head on the water tank that
was placed strategically by the culprit.
The flying brick hit the paving stone and
smashed into pieces around the patch.
Although the culprit retrieved the rope by pulling on it strongly...
They left the towel at the crime scene.
The purpose of the hanging towel was to obstruct Nakamura-san's view.
It disabled him from seeing the brick hanging in place.
In other words, the culprit who killed Nakamura-san...
Inoue-san...
It was you!
What!?
Me?
Why?
I see.
The only one who could employ this trick is
Inoue-san who lives directly downstairs.
Her window's directly below the draining floor.
Furthermore, Nakamura-san left us a dying message.
After hitting his head on the water tank,
Nakamura-san realized that you set him up...
And left a message implicating you as the culprit.
But Inoue-san's name doesn't contain kanji for facial parts, does it?
That's not it.
Nakamura-san's finger wasn't pointing to anywhere on his face...
But was pointing to the floor below.
In other words, his dying message was that
he was killed by Inoue-san from downstairs.
It's true that with such a set-up, it was possible for her
to injure Nakamura-san's forehead and make him fall.
But how did she manage to lure
him into approaching the handrail?
That's right!
Are you saying I yelled at him?
If I did that, I'd be suspected by my neighbors!
It was simple.
You merely used the prepaid cell phone.
Inoue-san confirmed over the phone that no one
else but Nakamura-san was on the rooftop.
She then thought up an excuse to lure him
into coming near the hanging towel...
And pulled the rope from below.
But that...
You've merely deduced that I was the only
one who could use the trick you conceived.
The dying message part was also hard to buy.
Do you have any evidence?
Concrete evidence!
You said this before you came up the rooftop.
He chose to hit his head and drop dead...
Yet he still managed to drag us into this, how annoying indeed.
At that time, the police had yet to explain
anything about Nakamura-san's cause of death.
The only one who could say that was the
culprit who employed the trick, Inoue-san.
Detective Chiba!
From the elevator's security camera, did
you see Inoue-san appearing after 10:00?
No, she wasn't in the footage even once.
Which means Inoue-san didn't come out of her room after that.
In that case, we should find it in her room.
The rope used to kill Nakamura-san.
Takagi...
Yes, sir.
Do you consent to us searching your room?
You don't have to search there.
Just like the private eye said...
It's in my room.
I didn't have time to get rid of it.
Yes, it was I who did it!
I killed that bastard of an annoying old-timer!
But, just because he was causing trouble doesn't mean you can...
Trouble?
It wasn't just trouble!
I put my heart and soul into growing my vegetables for months...
But they all wilted because of the bastard's chemical!
And that old geezer—!
Huh, they were supposed to be vegetables?
They were growing so horribly that I figured
them for weeds and applied herbicide to them.
I grew those vegetables from seeds left
by my father after he died from illness!
How dare that old-timer insult me like that!
I couldn't forgive him!
They said that long ago, when Inoue-san was a
child, she lived with her father who was a farmer.
Since her father died of illness, maybe growing vegetables
was the only way she found to cope with the ordeal.
Huh, I think I forgot something...
Uncle, hang on to being Scarecrow Kogoro for a bit longer, will you?
A necklace for ¥50,000?
Maybe it's a birthday present for someone.
You won the free hotel stay coupons!?
Hey, Mom isn't wearing anything around her neck!
Then, why don't you wear a collar?
Next Conan's Hint
Cola
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Punning on "Hey" and
"Cola" in Japanese