By the way, Ran...
The long weekend is coming up, isn't it?
Let's see...
Monday the 11th is Health and Sports
Day, so it's a three day weekend.
Well, well?
Are you taking us somewhere over the long weekend?
Nope, was just asking.
That so?
Hey, if we don't hurry, we're going to miss the raffle.
You're right.
If you're going to the raffle, take my wallet.
I've saved up quite a few raffle tickets.
Got it.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
The difficult Auintie's birthday is coming up.
October 10th
Kogorou cooks up the Perfect Present Plan!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It's true.
There are almost twenty raffle tickets in here!
I wonder what he bought...
Maybe the receipts are in his wallet?
I do see receipts, but...
They're all snacks to go with his beer.
Here it is.
50,000 yen!
Beika Jewelry Shop...
A necklace?
Don't tell me, Dad...
Are you going around supporting some bar waitress!?
Maybe it's a birthday present for someone.
Birthday?
Mine's still a ways off...
If it's not for Ran-neechan, that leaves...
That's it!
October 10th is Mom's birthday!
October 10th
That's it for sure.
He was checking the date a while ago.
I bet Dad must've remembered Mom's birthday!
Yeah, and so did I.
Because you'd always mention it at the school's sports event.
October 10th is my mom's birthday.
I'm gonna win first place and give the red ribbon to her as a present!
As you'd say.
Then, the reason he gave us his wallet and
had us intentionally find the receipt...
Was him asking us to arrange a situation where
it'd be easier for him to give it to Mom?
Pretty smooth, Uncle.
But, what should I do to ensure they meet each other?
You could invite them out to eat together as usual.
This isn't "usual"!
It's gotta be special!
Then, how about...
Something like that?
*****************************
Grand Prize: ONLY Brand Large Screen TV
1st Prize: Shizuoka Sea Side Hotel Stay for Two
2nd Prize: Beginner's Golf Set
A hotel stay for two...
All right!
What!?
You won the free hotel stay tickets!?
Even better, it comes with an exquisite dinner!
What tremendous luck she has...
It seems it's fine if I bring Conan-kun along so long as I ask...
So the three of us will go this weekend, all right?
Of course...
Be sure to bring everything you need to bring!
A hotel in Shizuoka, next weekend?
Is this another scheme to pair me up
with that mustached old man?
Bingo!
Absolutely right!
Sorry, but I have an appointment to meet
with someone for work next Monday.
Say...
How do you think Dad was able to get
so many tickets to win the hotel stay?
It's because he spent 50,000 yen to buy a necklace...
For a certain someone's birthday present!
But I guess it's too bad.
It can't be helped if you already have an engagement.
Wait a second!
If it's Shizuoka we're talking about, it'll be perfect!
The person I'm meeting Monday is from Shizuoka,
and I was actually supposed to meet her there.
Then, we'll meet you next Sunday at the Shizuoka Sea Side Hotel.
Sensei, you're supposed to meet your client right here...
Isn't it fine?
Since I'm taking the trouble to go and meet her personally.
October 10th
Well?
I'm here at the hotel.
What should I do now?
Just relax for a bit before dinner time.
I think Dad will be giving you the present before or right after the meal.
And then, maybe the two of you can spend
the night together in his room?
The two of us?
And what will you do?
Conan-kun and I will spend the night in your room!
Right, Conan-kun?
Looks like someone's here.
I have to go.
Mom.
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
Oh, Kokubu-san...
Our meeting was scheduled for tomorrow.
My husband came with me and we ended up having a fight...
Kobuku Akiho (28)
Client
Sorry and all that, but...
Mind making an exception and letting me stay here tonight?
I don't mind sleeping on the sofa...
But...
Prior to tomorrow's settlement negotiations, wouldn't it be best if...
You discussed everything with your husband?
l-already-said I don't wanna be near that dork!
But aren't you the one with the stalker problem?
The amount of consolation money...
The terms of the out of court settlement...
This is Kisaki, the attorney, speaking.
Is this Kokubu Akiho-san's room?
Yes...
This is Akiho's husband, Takehiko.
Your wife came to my room, number 306, a moment ago and fell asleep.
I'll be going out and won't return until 11:00 PM.
Would you mind coming by to get her at some point?
Kobuku Takehito (30)
Akiho's Husband
I think she'll cool off after she's slept off her drunkenness.
Yes, I understand.
My, Miss Attorney.
During tomorrow's negotiations, I trust you will take good care of us.
Hino Midori (51)
Opposing Party in the Negotiations
Since it appears to be true that my son has been following
this woman, we'll pay the extent of the settlement fee.
But this all started because that former race queen
tricked and toyed with my son's feelings...
And I have a few words to share with her about that.
Well, that's for tomorrow.
And naturally, you didn't bring your son along, correct?
Given that it was a stipulation for the in-person negotiation.
No, I didn't bring him.
But, who knows whether he's followed me here on his own or not.
Hino Seiji (26)
Midori's Son
Geez!
We haven't seen each other in so long...
And you couldn't wear something sexier than this?
Oh?
It seems you aren't surprised at my showing here.
Yeah.
Judging by the way Ran was talking, I expected
a certain old lady would be coming along.
Ran...
Apologies, but would it be all right if I left now?
Now, now...
Since we're all already here, let's just enjoy this exquisite dinner!
This old guy...
Is he even planning to give her a present?
This food is really delicious, isn't it?
Yeah.
It really is!
Definitely unlike a certain someone's cooking.
That reminds me!
The last time the three of us had a meal together...
It was my birthday...
Wasn't it?
Yeah...
That so?
In any event...
Isn't this restaurant a little warm?
What's this?
Mom isn't wearing anything around her neck!
Yeah...
I haven't found an accessory I like yet...
Then, why not try a collar?
Just like the one your cat's wearing.
Bear with it!
He says things like that, but...
I bet he's just teasing you and will wait until right
before your birthday passes to give it to you.
Hey, Dad!
He's out.
There's only an hour left of my birthday.
Sorry, but I'll be heading back to the room.
Of course, I do mean my room.
Geez!
Kokubu-san...
Looks like she left.
But what was all that about?
The necklace that man bought...
Could it be he's being duped by some woman?
Huh?
Guess I don't have a choice.
Really...
This is the worst birthday.
I'll ask again, why should I apologize to her!?
Because you didn't give her a certain something!
It's fine.
There are still three minutes left.
Huh?
Is Mom asleep?
Yes, who's there?
It's me, I've got something to tell you.
Can't it wait until tomorrow?
It has to be today!
Please, let me in!
Geez...
What is it?
Why are you dressed like that, idiot!?
I was taking a shower!
Got a problem?
Well?
What do you want to talk about?
If it's about that mustached old man...
I have nothing to...
Kokubu-san!?
Hang in there!
Kokubu-san?
Kokubu-san!
The estimated time of death is between 10:00 and 11:00 PM.
The cause of death was blunt force trauma.
She was struck in the back of the head with a blunt object...
But, we have yet to locate the murder weapon.
And?
Are you and the victim acquainted?
Well, Attorney...
Kisaki Eri.
She was a client of mine.
Her name is Kokubu Akiho-san.
She was dealing with a stalker problem.
We had planned to conduct a settlement
negotiation in this room tomorrow.
Why was she in your room?
She's staying in this hotel with her husband,
and the two of them had a dispute earlier.
That's when she said she wanted to stay in my room...
And passed out here.
Naturally, I gave her husband back in their room a call.
I told him I'd be out of the room until 11:00 and asked
him to pick her up when it was convenient.
And judging by the fact she wasn't here
when I returned shortly after 11:00...
I was fairly sure that her husband had taken her back.
Hold on a second, please!
Are you absolutely certain that there was no
body here when you returned to this room?
Yes.
The door to this room is auto-locked.
Without the keycard, no one could've come in from the outside!
Beyond that!
The window is such that no one could pass through!
When you came back the room, there wasn't a body...
And yet after taking a shower, you claim a body suddenly appeared.
That makes this a locked room murder!
It is now an impossible crime!
Or, perhaps...
The truth involves you returning to the room
and having an argument with the victim...
And you killing her in a fit of anger?
Then, while you were showering in order to rid yourself of the blood
that had splattered on you, Mouri-san inconveniently arrived.
If that were so, wouldn't I have refused to let him in?
Precisely!
Utilizing reverse psychology you invited
the great detective Mouri-san inside.
All in order to make a simple crime appear impossible!
Look now...
Regardless, the possibility remains that
you have a weapon concealed on you.
I'll call a female officer to conduct a full body search!
That won't be necessary.
I already completely stripped her in the
bathroom and checked her thoroughly.
Completely stripped her!?
Yeah.
She was only wearing a bath towel, so that's all I had to remove.
No, no, no, what I'm saying is...
That's sexual harassment!
It's fine.
We're a married couple.
But living separately.
Married...
But your name...
Kisaki is my mom's maiden name.
She only uses it for professional purposes.
My, so you're his wife!
I'm finally able to meet you!
Finally?
You see, every time Mouri-san is with a beautiful woman...
I mistake her for his wife.
Idiot!
You talk too much!
But, in that case, your statement would
be considered a familial testimony...
And can't be admitted into the investigation.
On the other hand, we'd have to consider the possibility
that you two conspired together to destroy any evidence.
Hey, hey, Yokomizo...
Because if that isn't the case, we can't
really explain this locked room mystery.
Ah-le-le?
There's even a blood stain over there.
Look, the bottom of the bedsheet.
Blood?
But why isn't there any blood on the carpet below?
Could it be that it was stained as the bed was moved?
In order to hide the body...
That's possible...
If the culprit concealed the body by
moving the bed and then lay next to it...
They could've moved back the bed and revealed
the body as I was showering...
And escaped this room unnoticed.
But, if you hadn't gone to shower, they wouldn't
have been able to use that trick.
Yeah.
If you had gone to bed a drooling mess like
usual, they'd have been all out of luck.
Drooling?
Say, aren't you talking about yourself?
That mess wasn't from drool.
It was from cola, right?
See, there are spots on the carpet in front
of the refrigerator that seem to be cola.
And on the lid of the can sitting on top of the fridge...
I can still see a pool of cola.
Is that true?
Yes...
I decided to drink it after I came back, but it sprayed all over me.
I forgot I had put it on the refrigerator.
But...
Don't you usually only drink water, tea, or coffee?
All that was inside was that carbonated drink.
Well regardless, if the body was hidden under the bed...
There must have been at least two culprits.
Why's that?
One person lifting and moving something
this heavy would be pretty back-breaking.
And there aren't any skid marks on the carpet.
There are blood stains by the foot of the bed.
The large ones were likely from the blunt force attack, but...
What's with these small ones that are
equally spaced and gradually fade?
Inspector Yokomizo!
Shortly before the time of the crime at 9:30 PM...
We've discovered that several calls were made to this room!
Is that so?
Wasn't it the victim's husband who was asked to come pick her up?
One of the callers was from the victim's
room, 309, so that must be true...
But another caller was from Room 302.
Room 302?
Hino-san's room...
You know them?
Yeah.
She's the mother of the stalker I told you about earlier.
But, what was her reason for calling?
My wife!?
Who...
And, why?
We're currently investigating that.
But, why did you not pick your wife up?
I did call and say I'd pick her up, but...
She bellowed that she wouldn't let me even if I came over.
That's why I thought...
That it'd be best, with apologies to the attorney,
for her to keep my wife in her room for the night...
And that I could come by in the morning if she had cooled down.
And, what was the cause of your argument?
Well, it was...
About this, right?
Conan-kun!
A bunch of mini cars!
I've loved cars since I was a kid, and lining them up helps me feel calm.
But...
How was this the cause of the fight?
Because, see...
The side mirror was tossed on the floor.
A car-loving man wouldn't do something this violent, right?
Then, your wife did this?
Yeah...
She told me to quit this childish and disgusting stuff and threw it.
Say...
Which one of these cars is your favorite?
Well...
The beloved car of the legendary actor, James Dean...
This Porsche.
By the way, was it only you and your wife in this room?
Yeah...
My wife's the only one I'd let see this kind of hobby.
That woman was...
Well, I always figured one of the foolish
men she deceived would eventually kill her.
On that note, it's my understanding that you called the victim.
Yeah.
I was calling the attorney to see if we could change the
time of our negotiation tomorrow just a little bit.
But I was shocked when that woman picked up the phone.
Why did you aim to change the time?
The golf appointment I have with a friend got moved up.
Going to play golf so soon after your stalker
of a son's settlement negotiations?
Why not?
After all, there's a good golf course nearby.
By the way, are you staying in this room by yourself?
Yes, that's right.
Can't you tell this is a single?
This room...
Has another occupant.
Because these cigarette butts don't have lipstick on them...
And the filter...
Is still damp.
It's true!
Is that right?
That's enough, Seiji!
Get out here!
So that's your stalker so—!?
I told you my son was only deceived!
But, you were instructed not to bring your son here, were you not?
Well, he happened to be here because he's touring
with his friends on their bikes tomorrow morning.
Then, show us that bike!
Right here.
Look.
A road bike, huh?
But, why did you hide your son?
I thought that woman called the police to arrest my son, so...
Incidentally, please share with us your whereabouts
and actions between 10:00 and 11:00 PM.
I was drinking with Mama.
If you think we're lying, verify it yourself!
We were at the hotel lounge on the uppermost floor!
In Attorney Kisaki's room...
Her client Kokubu Akiho-san was murdered.
There are three suspects.
Akiho-san's husband, Kokubu Takehiko-san.
Ahiko-san's stalker, Hino Seiji-san.
And his mother, Hino Midori-san.
The person who murdered Kokubu Akiho-san...
Should be among these three.
Something's under the pillow.
A present?
Gotta lower then raise the expectation for a surprise...
Why can't I find the key to solving this case?
Well, since this special day only comes once
a year, I'll let Uncle show off this time.
Next Conan's Hint
Health & Sports Day
Look Forward to the Next Episode