Found within Uncle Kogorou's wallet
was a receipt for a 50,000 yen necklace.
It seemed to be birthday present for Ran's mother,
Attorney Kisaki, who was born on October 10th.
October 10th
After learning of that, Ran displayed he tremendous
lottery luck and won the hotel stay prize from it.
As a result, we ended up sitting at a fancy
dinner table in a sea-side hotel, but...
Uncle didn't seem to plan to give her the present,
and even fell asleep due to his drunkenness.
Attorney Kisaki became irritated and returned to her room.
Just before midnight and the end of the birthday...
Ran tried to get Uncle to deliver his present at any cost.
But soon after we barged into the room,
we discovered a murdered female body.
That woman was Kokubu Akiho-san, a client of Attorney Kisaki
who requested a negotiation regarding her stalker problem.
Kobuku Akiho (28)
Client
The body wasn't there when Attorney Kisaki returned her room...
But was said to appear out of nowhere while she was taking a shower.
Looks like the culprit moved the bed
and hid under it along with the body.
Accompanied by Inspector Yokomizo, we began questioning
all of the hotel guests with connections to Akiho-san...
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Fulfill Ran's wish, Uncle...
With your famous deduction but without sleeping!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
My wife!?
Who...
And, why?
We're currently investigating that.
But, why did you not pick your wife up?
Kobuku Takehito (30)
Akiho's Husband
I did call and say I'd pick her up, but...
She bellowed that she wouldn't let me even if I came over.
And, what was the cause of your argument?
Well, it was...
About this, right?
A bunch of mini cars!
I've loved cars since I was a kid, and lining them up helps me feel calm.
But...
How was this the cause of the fight?
Because, see...
The side mirror was tossed on the floor.
A car-loving man wouldn't do something this violent, right?
Then, your wife did this?
Yeah...
She told me to quit this childish and disgusting stuff and threw it.
Say...
Which one of these cars is your favorite?
Well...
The beloved car of the legendary actor, James Dean...
This Porsche.
That woman was...
Well, I always figured one of the foolish
men she deceived would eventually kill her.
Hino Midori (51)
Opposing Party in the Negotiations
On that note, it's my understanding that you called the victim.
Yeah.
I was calling the attorney to see if we could change
the time of our negotiation tomorrow just a little bit.
But I was shocked when that woman picked up the phone.
Why did you aim to change the time?
The golf appointment I have with a friend got moved up.
Going to play golf so soon after your stalker
of a son's settlement negotiations?
This room...
Has another occupant.
Because these cigarette butts don't have lipstick on them...
And the filter...
Is still damp.
It's true!
Is that right?
That's enough, Seiji!
Get out here!
Hino Seiji (26)
Midori's Son
So that's your stalker so—!?
I told you my son was only deceived!
But, you were instructed not to bring your son here, were you not?
Well, he happened to be here because he's touring
with his friends on their bikes tomorrow morning.
Then, show us that bike!
Right here.
Look.
A road bike, huh?
Incidentally, please share with us your whereabouts
and actions between 10:00 and 11:00 PM.
I was drinking with Mama.
If you think we're lying, verify it yourself!
We were at the hotel lounge on the uppermost floor!
It certainly appears that the mother and son
were drinking together from 9:00 to 12:00.
And it seems they both left once to go to the restroom.
But it was at different times, so the two
of them couldn't have moved the bed.
Well, it's getting late now.
Let's continue the investigation at dawn...
And, where do you propose I stay?
Why not just stay in Mouri-san's room?
You two are a married couple.
But living separately, I should note.
Well, this was inevitable.
Something's under the pillow.
A present?
Uncle had it prepared after all, didn't he?
But why didn't he give it to her yesterday, on October 10th?
October 10th is my mom's birthday.
I'm gonna win first place and give the red ribbon to her as a present!
Don't tell me, Uncle...
You can't raise it and then lower it.
Gotta lower then raise the expectation for a surprise...
Raise and then lower...
Lower and then raise?
I see, so that's how it was...
The culprit utilized that to move the bed so quickly.
Without anyone's help, they did it single-handedly.
October 11th
Hold it, hold it!
We finally had the chance to stay at a hotel as a family!
And this is a buffet!
So why are you sitting at different tables?
It was I who sat down first.
Doesn't that make the one who purposely sat
at another table that mustached old man?
It can't be helped.
I have a lot on my mind.
Such as how I'm going to prove the innocence
of my wife, who has become a murder suspect.
Dad!
Ran, don't be fooled.
There's no telling what he's up to.
Mom!
He's checking the time.
And then checking the present.
Because that moment is approaching...
He's starting to raise the expectation of the receiver, I see.
Well, might as well put Uncle to sleep and solve this case quickly!
Damn...
At such a critical moment...
Why can't I find the key to solving this case at all?
Damn it!
Well, since this special day only comes once
a year, I'll let Uncle show off this time.
It looks like a dish is being brought out!
How amazing.
Something so heavy is being moved by a single person.
It's not amazing.
With there being tires on the bottom...
It's easy for a single person.
Tires on the bottom?
Hey, what kind of dish is this?
Take a look.
Sausages!
They look good!
The ketchup...
Hey!
What are you doing!?
It's all right, I'll just bring another one out.
Geez.
Huh?
The ketchup marks look like dot-dot-dot!
Isn't it incredible that the marks are evenly spaced?
Idiot.
It's nothing incredible at all.
Because the ketchup on the tire will leave a mark on the
ground as it rolls, the result is the evenly spaced...
Wait.
This mark...
Where have I...
I see!
That's what happened!
You finally got it.
Ran!
Call Yokomizo now!
Have him gather the suspects in the
room where the crime took place!
Then, does that mean...
Yeah, I figured it out.
The trick behind that locked room
murder, and the culprit why devised it!
Mouri Kogorou's deduction show is about to begin!
Sorry, Mouri-san.
It took us a while to get here.
Because by the time Ran-san had contacted us...
These three had already checked out of the hotel.
So why did you call us here?
I thought there wasn't anything left to talk about.
I bet they still feel...
Suspicious toward us.
What's this about?
Don't we have an alibi?
From 10:00 to 11:00, the supposed time of the crime...
My son and I were drinking in the hotel lounge!
But it seems you both left to use the restroom once.
But separately!
And each was only for about ten minutes.
Also, the corpse was in the room where that attorney was staying.
When the attorney came back at
11:00, the woman's body wasn't there.
And if the body was discovered around midnight after she
was taking a shower and let Detective Mouri in the room...
Then, isn't this a locked room murder!?
That's true.
Since the doors are auto-locked, you can't get in without a keycard.
If my wife was in the room, she could
have opened the door for me, but...
When you returned to the room, my wife wasn't there, right?
Right...
No.
She already was in the room.
Your wife, I mean.
Already killed and hidden under the bed.
Under the bed?
It can't be...
And then the culprit moved the bed during Eri's shower...
Revealing the body and fleeing this room immediately.
Moved the bed?
But how?
Please wait a moment.
Is this all right?
Without doing your usual thing...
Usual thing?
This thing!
Just like that!
The hell was that?
Say!
Can you tell us how the bed was moved?
That's right.
Before I returned to the room...
If the culprit had killed Akiho-san...
Concealed the body under the moved bed...
And then hid themselves next to the body...
I probably couldn't have noticed them when I came in.
And while I was showering...
It's possible that they moved the bed back in order to
reveal the body, and then escaped the room, but...
It's a herculean task for a single person to slide
a bed that heavy without leaving drag marks.
Even if Akiho-san who was sleeping in my room was killed
by her husband, Takehiko-san, when he came to get her...
He would have been by himself.
As for the two of you who knew Akiho-san was in my room,
you could've moved the bed by working together, but...
At the time of the crime...
There was no point in which you were both gone.
That makes it impossible.
Under such circumstances, how did they move the bed and who did it?
Mr. Detective?
By putting tires under the bed.
Tires?
I see!
Seiji-san had a road bike.
He must have utilized the bike's tires!
Utilized them...
How did he do it?
It wasn't a bike!
Isn't it obvious?
It was the person with toys that could easily be placed under the bed.
By toys, do you mean the mini cars?
Yeah, that's right.
A single person can lift a bed one corner at
a time and place the car under each leg.
With tires under each of the four bed legs, it would
be easy for a single person to slide the bed.
The one who lined up the mini cars even in a hotel room...
Takehiko-san!
Was it not you?
The proof is the small blood tracks near the
leg of the bed that are evenly spaced.
It's likely that the mini car tires ran over the bloodstain
on the carpet while you moved the bed.
My guess is you've already disposed of those mini cars, though.
But, Mouri-san...
If he had just placed the bed on top of the mini
cars, it would've slipped off while being moved!
That's true...
So you didn't figure it out, Uncle?
I don't think a man who likes mini cars so much
would do anything like that to damage them.
Because he was so proud of them when he showed me!
Back then...
Say...
Which one of these cars is your favorite?
Well...
The beloved car of the legendary actor, James Dean...
This Porsche.
The car that James Dean drove...
The Porsche 911!
Porsche 911?
But the car that James Dean drove was...
The Porsche 550 Spyder.
A convertible.
I see!
He could've stuck the bed leg into the opening where the seats are!
That would certainly stabilize it!
That's why you couldn't show the 550 Spyder to Conan-kun.
Because the bed leg broke the seats.
But, why didn't Takehiko-san leave immediately
after the murder instead of using that trick?
Because if Eri had discovered the body
immediately after returning to the room...
He'd be the first suspect since she had
asked him to come and pick the victim up.
That's why, after killing his wife...
He held the door open using a stopper and returned to his room...
Before coming back with his mini cars and deploying his trick.
He figured that if it seemed to be an impossible
crime, it would divert attention away from him.
But...
That trick couldn't be used if the
attorney hadn't been in the bathroom!
That's why...
It was a lucky break for you!
But...
Waiting under the bed with a body on such an off chance...
That's true.
No one in their right mind would do that.
Encouraged from a few drinks, perhaps?
I don't think so.
Speaking of drinking...
Whenever Uncle comes home from drinking,
he has something he usually shouts.
"Ran, bring me some water!"
That's true, but...
Why are you bringing that up now?
The reason why one gets thirsty after drinking is that a
dehydration reaction occurs as the body breaks down alcohol.
You already knew I was coming back to the room around 11:00.
You could've assumed that I was going for a drink with someone.
That's why...
You put only carbonated drinks in my refrigerator...
And shook up every single can.
That way, once I had opened it...
The contents would spray up and force me to take a shower.
Well, since we still haven't found the murder weapon...
Why don't we examine the glass ashtray in
Room 309 where Takehiko-san was staying?
It seems all of the rooms have those ashtrays.
If he took the murder weapon with him to make
it seem like an extremely impossible crime...
He would have to switch it with the one in this room.
A short time later...
A luminol reaction test on the ashtray in Room 309 proved positive.
It was Akiho-san's blood.
Takehiko-san also confessed to the crime.
The motive was the mini cars.
He had heard that Akiho-san, a former race queen,
liked mini cars, so they hit it off and got married.
But she laughed and said it was all a lie
to lure a wealthy man like Takehiko-san.
What pushed him over the edge...
Were her final words.
Say, did you figure out?
The meaning of that birthday present I gave you.
The 550 Spyder?
That was the beloved car of a famous movie star, right?
A car that can't be bought unless you're rich.
In other words, it means I only married you because of your money.
I can't wait to inherit it after your death!
That was quite a present, huh?
Yeah, I wouldn't want to get something like that.
My, I think it beats getting nothing.
Well, I'm heading home.
You aren't going back to the hotel?
It's already 11:00!
It's fine.
I've already called a taxi.
See you.
Don't leave.
Although there's only an hour left, it's still your birthday.
Why don't we celebrate, just the two of us?
We'll send Ran and the brat off to another room...
And return to the time when we were lovers.
This is a little something from me.
Well, since you're an adult, I guess you won't be
thrilled to get something trivial like a birthday present.
May I ask...
Whose birthday is it?
Why, yours of course!
Same as Health & Sports Day!
Speaking of Health & Sports Day, it
used to be on October 10th, right?
That's right.
But now it falls on the second Monday in October.
Don't tell me Dad only remembers Mom's
birthday through Health & Sports Day?
It's because you always said it at the
sports event when we were kids!
"Today's my birthday, so I can't lose!"
October 10th is usually a bright and sunny day, so
schools used to hold their sports event on that day.
What the...
I purposely lowered and then raised it!
So it was all meaningless?
Lowered and then raised it?
That's why you were so cold to Mom!
You didn't need to lower her expectations...
In any case...
I'll gladly accept these spoils of war.
You clumsy detective...
And the next day...
Hey!
What in the world is this!?
The contents of the present!
I thought it was a necklace...
But they're prayer beads!
Is he telling me to die?
That man!
The manager at Poirot asked Dad to buy those prayer beads...
It looks like he brought the wrong thing along by mistake...
There it is!
Uncle, that's too big of a mistake...