What exactly does that mean?
Sunday
"Constructed an aquarium in the house."
Nishida-kun is a famous aquarium designer.
Perhaps he has a huge fish tank in his house.
Aku.... Akurimu?
Then, does that mean it's a new type of ice cream?
It's "a-ku-a-ri-u-mu".
It means aquarium.
An architect who designs aquariums.
The house of a person who makes aquariums?
I wonder what the house will be like...
I'm nervous!
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
In the house with the aquarium...
Even the fish are involved in the case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
NISHIDA
DESIGN OFFICE
Maybe he isn't home?
That's strange.
We definitely agreed on 12:00...
Professor Agasa?
Oh, Imura-kun!
Imura Kousuke (32)
Nishida's Assistant
It's been a while!
Is Nishida not in?
He promised to show me the interior of his house today, but...
So that's why the kids are here too, huh?
Good afternoon.
I'm Nishida's assistant, Imura.
Hello!
Nishida probably went out to buy something.
Here, I'll get us in with the spare key.
Here, come in.
Thank you, Imura-kun.
By the way, your clothes...
Did you come back from a trip somewhere?
I went to tour Guam.
I left there last night, and...
Only arrived in Narita just this morning.
I'm a little behind on sleep.
Awesome!
This is fantastic!
A pirate ship!
This fish has a pointy mouth...
That's the Caribbean Longsnout.
It's part of the family of butterflyfish who live in the Caribbean sea.
Caribbean Sea, huh?
What's this?
There's a fish with weird markings on it.
Oh, that's a species of pufferfish that lives in the Indian Ocean.
I wonder if there are Indian eels...
So pretty!
These are really rare!
Black clownfish!
Those are from Australia.
Look at that, Ai-chan!
All the pretty fishes!
Yeah, just like jewels.
You're romantic for a change.
I wonder exactly how much an aquarium
spends per month on just the electric bill.
They're certainly living jewels, aren't they?
You're really...
Hey, there isn't anything in that tank.
Genta-kun, what happened?
The roof fell down!
There's no helping it.
This glue doesn't dry easily so don't touch the miniature.
Yes...
That's right!
Chocolates from Guam, anyone?
Gum chocolate?
What's that?
It's Guam—Gu-a-m.
Me, I want some!
Before that, go wash your hands.
Yes!
Wow, this is spacious.
How nice!
What was that?
Hey, what happened?
Conan-kun...
Nishida-kun!
Sensei!
No way...
Are you two all right?
Yes...
Imura-kun!
Hurry, call for an ambulance!
Yes!
It's regrettable, but...
He's already gone.
It's best to call the police as well.
This person...
Has a mark like an insect bite on the nape of his neck.
What exactly...
What's that?
You can't stay here.
Just a little...
Come, let's go.
Hang on!
Just a second!
In short, at 12:30 PM today...
You discovered Nishida-san's body
submerged in the bath tub, right?
That's correct.
What's the condition of the body?
There are no conspicuous external wounds.
Cause of death is drowning.
Judging from the extent of the rigor mortis...
Nishida-san likely passed away Friday night.
With today being Sunday, that gives us two days.
There's a bottle of brandy and a glass on the work desk
He went to bathe after drinking?
As he was drunk...
He probably fell asleep while bathing and drowned.
I suppose so...
Nishida-san is a strange person, isn't he?
Well, Nishida-san entered the bath at night, didn't he?
But he didn't even turn on the light
and bathed in complete darkness.
You're right!
If he entered the bath on Friday night...
The light should be on, but...
Hey!
Say, don't you think this is suspicious?
That's glue on his fingertips, isn't it?
It looks that way.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Even though applying glue onto the miniature...
Is a very delicate job that requires the
use of the needle of an injector...
Nishida-san didn't make any mistakes at all.
Normally, when one is drunk...
It would be impossible to do something this demanding.
We should have forensics determine exactly
how drunk Nishida-san was when he died.
Yes, sir.
Could you conduct the test to determine the
level of alcohol content in his blood first?
Roger that.
Also confirm Imura-san's alibi since he has a spare key.
Understood.
My apologies, but...
Could you tell us where you were on Friday night?
Isn't it an accident?
This is merely a formality.
I was on an overseas trip in Guam on Friday night.
I was shooting on both Friday and Saturday night, so...
The shooting range should have a record of it.
Incidentally, when did this trip start and end?
I left on Thursday night...
And returned to Narita this morning.
I believe you can confirm that with my passport.
Please.
Excuse me.
I see you left Guam on Saturday night.
Thank you for your cooperation.
You're not supposed to touch!
I thought it should be dry by now...
Geez, Genta-kun...
Hey, hey, he said the glue didn't dry easily, didn't he?
I wonder how long it'll take to dry...
That's true.
This is a special type that can dry in water, so...
It'd probably take about 12 hours or so to completely dry.
12 hours?
The glue on the body's fingertips wasn't dry yet...
If Nishida-san died on Friday night...
It is strange that the glue hasn't dried.
Conan-kun, this is bad!
What is it, Ayumi-chan?
All the shrimp are dead!
I thought they weren't keeping anything in this tank?
The shrimp are there to control the water quality.
I wonder why they're dead.
Huh?
The shrimp here are a different species from the ones over there.
The lower part of their legs are white.
The water quality and environment of
every tank seems to be different so...
The species are probably placed in them accordingly.
Could it be...
Ayumi!
There are live baby jellyfish.
It's true!
Baby jellyfish!
Jellyfish?
I see.
So that's how it was.
This wasn't an accident...
But an ingeniously planned murder!
Inspector...
The blood test report is in.
The alcohol content in Nishida-san's blood was 0.40%.
0.40%?
Usually, that's the state bordering unconsciousness.
The fingerprints found on the glass matched Nishida-san's.
With this, we can conclude that we were right.
Nishida-san went to bathe even after he
became drunk and eventually drowned.
An accident due to carelessness.
I suppose so.
That's why I advised Sensei not to drink so much!
Hold on.
Nishida-kun didn't drink any alcohol before he died.
On the nape of Nishida-kun's neck...
There's a small red spot that resembles an insect bite, isn't there?
That's the mark left behind from an injection.
First, the culprit snuck up on Nishida-kun,
who was working on the miniature.
He used chemicals to put Nishida-kun to sleep.
Afterward, he used the injector...
And injected the alcohol directly into his blood-
stream through the nape of Nishida-kun's neck.
In doing that, alcohol would be detected in the body's blood...
Making it look like Nishida-kun was drunk when he died.
Afterward, the culprit submerged the
unconscious Nishida-kun in the bath tub...
And drowned him.
Isn't that so...
Imura-kun?
What about me?
Confess.
I already know you're the culprit that killed Nishida-kun.
I was in Guam on Friday night when Nishida died.
No, that's false.
Nishida-kun wasn't killed on Friday night.
It was probably on Thursday, during
the day, before you left for Guam...
That you killed Nishida-kun.
That's why the bathroom light wasn't on.
Sunlight was already flooding in through the large windows.
That caused you to simply forget to switch on the lights, didn't it?
What are you talking about?
Didn't the police say Nishida's time of death was Friday night?
That's where your trick comes in.
You cooled the body to delay the time of death, didn't you?
Cooled the body!?
The glue on the body's fingertips has yet to dry.
It's because, under low temperatures,
it's difficult for the glue to dry.
Since the body was cooled, the glue couldn't dry.
It's true that the time of death can be
delayed by cooling the body, but...
How do you cool the body?
Before I explain the method...
I have to first explain about the tanks in this house.
Tanks?
Now, a question for the kids...
In the tank with the pirate ship miniature...
There were Caribbean Longsnout from the Caribbean Sea.
Do you know why?
"Why"...
And for the tank with pufferfish from the Indian Ocean...
Why was the miniature of the Taj Mahal placed there?
I see.
The ocean that the fish is from in the tank
is represented by the miniature inside.
I see!
There was a movie that told the story of
pirates in the Caribbean sea, wasn't there?
That's why the tank with the pirate
ship has fish from the Caribbean sea!
The Taj Mahal is a famous temple in India.
That means fish from the India Ocean are kept in that tank, right?
Then, the tank with the pyramid has fish from the desert?
Not quite.
Those fish are likely from the Red Sea, which is in Egypt.
The Opera House is a building in Australia, so...
That's the tank for fish from Australia.
That's right!
And the miniature that was supposed to be placed in this tank...
Is that clock tower from Sapporo.
Sapporo?
In other words, the fish that were supposed to be
kept in this tank were not tropical fish, but instead...
Fish from the sea around Hokkaido.
Probably those from the Sea of Okhotsk.
I see...
But, how exactly is that related to the case?
Try touching the glass of the tank.
It's cold!
Like ice.
The Sea of Okhotsk is a cold sea in the north.
To house the fish that come from there...
It's necessary to keep the temperature of the tank low.
In other words, there should be a cooler in
that tank to lower the water temperature.
This should be it, right?
Imura-kun used the cooler to cool the water in the bath tub...
So as to keep the body's temperature low.
Hence delaying the estimated time of death.
What'd you say!?
Look carefully inside the tank.
There's evidence showing that the
cooler was used to cool the body.
Could this be...
A contact lens?
Yes, that would be Nishida-kun's contact lens.
The contact lens case in the washroom is empty.
As for why the contact lens would be in the tank...
It was probably...
Imura-kun, who returned from Guam this morning...
Came to this house before we arrived.
This is because he had to put the cooler, which had been
used to cool the body, back in its original place with the tank.
However, on the cooler bar that was in the bath tub...
The contact lens that had dropped out
from Nishida-kun's eye was stuck on it.
Not noticing that, Imura-kun returned the cooler to the tank.
Hence the contact lens that was stuck on the bar fell into the tank.
All the shrimp in that tank died because you took away
the cooler and allowed the water temperature to rise.
Shrimp are highly susceptible to changes in water temperature.
I didn't come to this house this morning!
I came in for the first time with you,
Professor, when I met you at the door.
Do you remember the newspaper, Imura-kun?
Newspaper?
When you saw the mailbox full of newspapers,
you didn't appear to be very surprised at all.
That's because you knew that Nishida-kun was dead, right?
You acted as though you met us at the door by coincidence...
And let us in to discover the body.
That's absurd!
That's just your wild guess!
There isn't any evidence!
Well, let's show you the evidence.
Tome-san?
Will you please conduct the test Conan-kun requested just now?
Roger.
A gunpowder reaction!
A gunpowder reaction?
When you fire a gun, gunpowder will fly in all directions.
Later, once sprayed with nitrous acid, the
gunpowder on clothes and furniture will react...
And turn a purplish red.
Oh yeah...
Mister, you said when you left Guam on Saturday night...
You were firing guns at the shooting range, weren't you?
When you returned the cooler to the tank...
It must have touched the gunpowder on your clothes.
Excuse me.
Damn it!
Why did it...
I thought it was perfect!
The alibi that you worked so hard to create has
become the evidence that revealed your crime.
Why?
Why did you kill Nishida-kun?
I thought you respected him!
I did, until five years ago.
He was a genius aquarium designer.
I really...
I really respected him.
Until five years ago?
What exactly does that mean?
Nishida stopped coming up with designs five years ago.
He'd used up his talent.
That's why, in the last five years...
All of his works were actually designed by me.
By you!?
Right...
I have been Nishida's shadow.
But I was fine with that.
Under the name of the genius designer,
as long as I could design what I liked...
I was content being merely a shadow...
Because I respected Nishida.
But then...
When Nishida discovered talented
people from the younger generation...
He discarded me and used them instead.
I couldn't forgive him!
I had dedicated so much to him,
and yet he cast me aside so readily!
If he was going to abandon me...
Then I decided to abandon him instead!
Or so I thought...
One Week Later
The fish were so cute!
They were so pretty...
The big shark was really cool!
Those shoals of sardines were great too.
Instead of that...
I'm hungry...
Now that you mention it...
Oh, it's already 2:00 in the afternoon.
Let's go eat something.
All right!
What would you like to eat?
Unagi!
Sashimi would be nice!
I wanna eat sushi!
Hey, hey...
Now you're eating the fish you just said were cute?
You don't say...
Who would have thought of a bird?
Why are you guys here again?
We're here to pray for love oracles.
Nine?
Not a bird, but a monkey.
Nine...
What exactly is it?
Next Conan's Hint
Button
Look Forward to the Next Episode