One!
Teitan High School
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
Nine!
Ten!
One!
Two!
I surrender...
Osu!
You're in top shape as always!
Kazumi-senpai!
Tsukamoto Kazumi (18)
Former Karate Club Captain
What brings you here?
All the studying and exams made my body feel sluggish.
Mouri, care to be my opponent?
Yes, with pleasure!
Please don't hold back.
Of course!
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
At the shrine, the Rooster Man appeared...
Along with the mysteries of the festival's nine monkeys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Ranburi Shrine
Second Rooster Day
This place is totally bustling!
They're selling all kinds of rakes!
As expected of a Rooster-Festival.
This is my first time here, and I never thought it would be this big!
Regardless, what kind of rake did you come to buy?
Aren't those rakes supposed to bring prosperity to businesses?
Well...
You see, Ran's preparing for an upcoming karate tournament...
Yeah!
It's to help me win again.
The rakes in the Rooster Festival have that sort of effect?
They do.
A long time ago, after Prince Yamato Takeru won his battle...
He went to the shrine to give thanks on
the day of the Rooster in November.
He then happened to lean his weaponized
rake against the pine tree of that shrine.
This gave birth to the Great Rooster Festival...
And the open-air markets set up for the
event are called the Rooster Market.
Conan-kun, you know a lot.
On a related note, some say the stars suddenly brighten
on the night of the Rooster in a certain November...
Bringing forth the Bodhisattva.
Some also say that the Rooster Markets originated from the
farmers' Harvest Festival — just to name a few theories.
That's why the rake's become a lucky talisman.
They say it will "rake in" victories at war, and
bring better fortune and business prosperity.
And I suppose all of that was on TV, too?
It was on the evening news...
Ran!
It's here, it's here!
The Ranburi Shrine's specialty...
"Lovely Fortunes!
These fortunes only appear during the yearly Rooster Festivals...
They perfectly describe the ideal type of girl for the boy you like!
Sonoko, you're taking this too seriously.
It's just one of those fortune tellings.
Didn't you know?
Sawako-chan in Class C...
She followed what the fortune said and confessed
her feelings, and everything's gone well!
Really?
What are those two doing?
Who knows...
All right, fortunes GET!
Now, let's see what Kyougoku-san's ideal type is...
Shinichi's ideal type...
Come to think of it, back then Shinichi...
I have things I want to ask you and to tell you as well.
So wait for me, will you?
Shinichi...
But if my deduction's correct...
I suspect...
That what we would like to ask each other is one in the same.
Did you know, Shinichi?
What I wanted to ask you was, "What do you think of me?"
And if it's the same...
Then maybe...
Could it be...
Gah...
So it's come to this.
Oh, you're not opening it?
I'll do it when I get home...
No way!
Hey, wait!
Let's see, what's this...
Shinichi-kun's ideal type is...
"The one who captures this high-strung old soul is
a woman who displays the virtues of Old Japan.
"Gaudy fashions and tomboyish conduct is prohibited!
"If you persist and appeal to him as a proper woman...
"The distance between you two shall be shortened without limit!"
Got that?
But, that...
Does it really matter that much?
Things like high-strung and old soul type...
Well, Shinichi-kun often notices those itsy-bitsy details.
You could say he's sensitive and high-strung, right?
That's true...
And he doesn't really care about fads and fashion...
So I guess he'd be an old soul type?
Say, Madam, you just casually admitted it, didn't you?
That you love Shinichi-kun!
That's not it!
I mean...
Sure, sure!
Confirm it yourself later on.
About the ideal type for the detective you love!
I'm going to the restroom for a bit!
Geez...
Hey...
Thief!
Ran!
Catch that guy!
Tomboyish conduct is prohibited!
Geez...
Why didn't you take him down with karate as usual?
Sorry...
Well, as long as you aren't hurt, it's OK.
There wasn't anything important in that purse anyway.
Hey, what happened?
A snatcher, a snatcher.
Someone cut my purse's shoulder
strap with a knife and ran off with it.
The culprit was also wearing some kind of mask.
A mask?
A Firebreather mask.
A Firebreather mask?
That was on the news last week...
The Rooster Man has made yet another
appearance at the Rooster Festival.
Following his appearance last week on the
First Rooster Day at Sandei Shrine...
We learned yesterday that, on the
Second Rooster Day at Ranburi Shrine...
The Rooster Man
REAPPEARS!!
The Rooster Man reappeared wearing
his trademark Firebreather mask
The Rooster Man
REAPPEARS!!
****************
Where Could the Rooster Man Be?
The Number of victims having their
belongings stolen is escalating.
Ranburi Shirine
In addition, this snatcher was nicknamed the "Rooster Man" from
his appearances at Rooster Festivals and his cocky thieving acts.
Approximately 160-170 cm tall
Wears Firebreather mask
Male in his 20s or 30s
He is expected to strike again.
According to the police, on the Third Rooster
Day set to occur at the end of this month...
Security and vigilance will be heightened.
But...
There are about thirty Rooster Markets at shrines in Tokyo alone.
In the entire Kanto Region, there are at least fifty.
Can they really catch him?
But, Sonoko said to me:
"I'm going to get my revenge, so you definitely have to come
with me to the next Rooster Festival at Ranburi Shrine."
Why does she think he's going to show up at that shrine twice?
Not sure.
But she seemed to have a lot of confidence.
Maybe she thought he'd try to outsmart
everyone by visiting the same place!
Well, I suppose appearing at a place he's
already struck once would be unexpected, but...
Then, you can go by yourselves!
I'm not going.
Such a hassle.
That's true.
Who would be interested in some Rooster Man?
Third Rooster Day
Huh?
What's wrong, Ran?
You rarely wear long skirts!
It's just kind of cold today...
So I thought it'd be best for me to wear this...
And look at you, Sonoko.
You're dressing more maturely than usual!
Really?
Well, in any case!
Let's go get our revenge!
Hey, you know where the Rooster Man is?
Not that!
I mean let's draw another one of those!
By revenge... you meant that?
Lovely Fortunes?
I'm going to draw a good oracle this time!
That's defeating the purpose of the oracle!
The Rooster Man!
The Rooster Man came again!
For real!?
He really came?
What's with the daypack?
It's the Rooster Man's.
The Rooster Man threw it at people who were chasing him!
And, where did the Rooster Man go?
He escaped that way, toward the park.
Hey, Conan-kun!
Is the bag he stole from Sonoko-neechan here?
This bag is mine!
So that means this wasn't a copycat?
Bloodstains on the daypack's shoulder strap?
Hey, where did the Rooster Man come from?
There.
Near where those people are gathered.
Hey, are you all right?
Hang in there!
We just called an ambulance!
Hey, was this person attacked by the Rooster Man?
Yeah.
I suddenly heard a groan, so I looked over here.
That's when I saw the guy wearing a Firebreather mask
leave this person's side and start running away.
That made me think he resisted when the Rooster
Man tried to rob him, and got stabbed in retaliation.
It's not the Rooster Man...
It's Monkey...
Monkey?
Hey, hey, what was that?
What do you mean by monkey?
Weren't you stabbed by the Rooster Man?
Seems like he's trying to say something...
But no voice...
Nine?
Hey, hang in there!
Not Rooster, but Monkey...
Nine...
What exactly is it?
Nine monkeys...
What was this man trying to tell me?
I see.
He's called the Rooster Man because of his cocky
act of robbing at the Rooster Festivals, huh?
But this time he also tried to rob someone of their life.
This is no cock-and-bull show anymore.
Regarding the victim stabbed by the Rooster Man...
We've discovered his identity.
A resident of Haido City, Masuko Shirou-san, age 21.
He's a high school graduate applying for
Touto University's Literature Department.
I heard the victim was taken to the hospital,
but has he regained consciousness?
Oh, no.
Inside the daypack we found the victim's bag as well.
We confirmed his identity from his driver's license inside.
And, what's the victim's current condition?
Fortunately, the wound was shallow.
While he lost consciousness from the physical
pain and mental stress of being stabbed...
The doctors say he should regain consciousness in time.
And?
Why are you guys here again?
For revenge, revenge!
Several days ago at this shrine's Second Rooster Festival,
Sonoko had her bag snatched by the Rooster Man.
That's why we were staking out this Ranburi Shrine!
I deduced that he'd try to outwit everyone and reappear here.
No, you only came here to draw another oracle...
Of course, I've succeeded in getting my bag
back from the Rooster Man's daypack.
Oh, no...
We can't return that to you yet since it's evidence.
But, this does prove it wasn't a copycat crime.
Yeah.
At this moment, we're gathering victims from the
First and Second Rooster Days to come confirm it.
Though I suspect this Rooster Man from
the Third Rooster Day is the same culprit.
But, our only clue is that he was
wearing a Firebreather mask...
There's more.
Even though we're saying that the person who was
stabbed here was a victim of the Rooster Man...
He told us, "It wasn't Rooster, but Monkey."
Monkey?
Also, he showed me nine fingers just like this.
So the culprit must be someone
related to monkey and nine, right?
Monkey and nine...
Nine monkeys...
Nine
Monkey
Kyuu... saru...
Nine
Monkey
Ku... saru...
Kusaru
Perhaps the culprit is rotten!
Well, his character has likely gone bad...
But this is no time for puns!
Inspector!
We've apprehended the Rooster Man!
Really?
Yeah, but...
There's three of them.
Three?
The people who chased after the fleeing Rooster Man
saw him take refuge in the park's public restroom.
They then reported it to us.
Then, by the time you received the report and made your way
here, all these bystanders had gathered around the restroom?
And when you guys ordered those still inside to come out...
Only those three men did, is that correct?
Yes.
According to witness testimony, there's no doubt
that the Rooster Man entered the men's restroom.
After escorting those three out, we searched inside.
Inside, we found a bloody knife, a down jacket...
And a Firebreather mask discarded in the utility closet.
That's why we believe it's safe to assume
the Rooster Man did enter the restroom.
And, according to the onlookers...
Before we arrived, no one else entered the
restroom due to the fright of the incident.
As such, the Rooster Man can't be anyone but those three.
I see.
Well then, may I have a word with you one by one?
About your names and purposes for coming here.
My name is Hino Tatsuo.
Hino Tatsuo (45)
Shrine Visitor
After I bought this rake at the Rooster Market, I stopped
by this restroom on my way home to relieve myself.
My stomach's been acting up lately...
Look, I even brought my medicine.
Was it you!?
The Rooster Man!
Because your face looks just like a monkey's!
It certainly looks like a monkey's face.
Hey, hey, aren't you looking for the Rooster Man, not a monkey?
The person who was stabbed said it!
"It wasn't Rooster, but Monkey."
But it wouldn't be about his face, would it?
The Rooster Man was wearing a Firebreather
mask, so his face shouldn't have been visible.
That's true...
I didn't come for the Rooster Markets...
I was only here to street-pass communicate with other gamers.
Street-pass communicate?
It's an in-game feature that allows gamers in
close proximity to exchange items and maps.
Since a lot of people gather for the Rooster Festival...
I figured I'd be able to get a lot of exchanges.
See?
I was able to communicate with ten people.
That's why I went to the restroom to check it.
In any case, what's your name?
We haven't asked you yet, right?
Sarukawa Hisami (20)
Part-time Worker
It's Sarukawa Hisami.
Saru means monkey!
So you're the Rooster Man, huh!?
Sonoko!
But, no one calls me "Saru"!
My first name is Hisami, and since Hisa can be
pronounced as Kyuu, people call me Kyuu-chan".
Hisami
Kyuu-chan
Kyuu?
Before the victim lost consciousness, he conveyed these clues:
kyuu
"Monkey" and the number "nine"!
But I don't think the victim would know the snatcher's name.
That's true...
My name is Mizunoe Shinji.
Mizunoe Shinji (32)
Company Employee
On my way to buy a rake for the company
I work for, I stopped by this restroom.
Since I wasn't able to come and buy
one on the Second Rooster Day...
Actually, I meant to buy it on the First Rooster Day, but...
Before I could, the Rooster Man happened
to snatch the bag with my wallet in it.
Then, you're also a victim of the Rooster Man?
Yeah.
I can only afford lunch boxes bought from
convenience stores these days thanks to him.
Since I'm broke...
I had one today too.
I believe I still have the receipt...
Huh?
Where'd I put that receipt?
If he's a victim, we should be able to confirm that immediately.
Yes.
We probably can if we search the Rooster Man's daypack.
Is there anything in your bag that can confirm it's yours?
Like a license or identification card?
If you want those, I think my bankbook is still in there.
Please make sure the Shin in Shinji is the
same as Shin from the Jinshin War.
Jinshin War
All right, go check this immediately.
Yes, sir.
It seems you're not connected to monkey or nine, huh?
I'm a monkey according to animal fortune-telling.
Animal fortune-telling...
Old school...
That was what, centuries ago?
By the way, I know you were targeted
during the Second Rooster Festival, but...
What kind of rake did you come to buy?
That's...
They're here to draw oracles called "Lovely Fortunes".
Lovely Fortunes?
What could that be?
They're oracles only available during the Rooster Festivals.
I have one on me right now.
Huh?
There's a button mixed in with my change.
Where did this button come from...
Ran!
Catch that guy!
Hey, what happened?
A snatcher, a snatcher.
Could it be that this button is from the Rooster Man's clothes!?
Remember, the Rooster Man bumped into me, right?
At that time I must have picked up this button
and put it in my wallet along with my change!
But, couldn't the button have been on the ground before that?
But if that's true, then it's important evidence!
If one of those three people has an article of
clothing that matches the missing button...
That person has to be the Rooster Man!
If it's possible, we'd like to search your homes immediately.
Is that all right?
Yeah, that's fine with me.
Me too, as long as you explain everything to my mama.
I don't mind at all if it'll clear my name.
Well, take a picture of the button immediately and
send it to the investigation teams for confirmation!
Yes, sir!
How strange...
Ran having picked up a button from the Rooster Man's
clothes should have been a shocking revelation...
But these three didn't show any signs of anxiety.
The Rooster Man...
He appeared at the Rooster Markets, put on a Firebreather mask...
And would snatch people's bags or belongings before getting away.
His crimes up until now didn't involve hurting people, but...
Tonight, on the Third Rooster Day...
He finally stabbed and injured the high school
grad, Masuko Shirou-san, with a knife.
Inside the daypack left by the Rooster Man were belongings
he'd snatched from victims, indicating it wasn't a copycat.
Masuko-san, before losing consciousness, left
a message with "monkey" and "nine".
What on earth do they mean?
Among the three suspects, does the Rooster Man really exist?
This case...
Doesn't seem like it will end that easily.
The victim knew about the culprit's identity.
That's why it was actually the ninth monkey!
What?
You know who the Rooster Man is?
This is weird.
Ran-neechan hasn't answered her phone for a while!
Next Conan's Hint
Oracles
Look Forward to the Next Episode