We decided to visit the Rooster
Festival held at the Ranburi Shrine.
What attracted Ran and Sonoko were "Lovely Fortunes":
romance oracles available only during Rooster Festivals.
But the Lovely Fortunes weren't the only
thing to appear at the Rooster Festival.
Along with them was a snatcher nicknamed the
Rooster Man, donning a Firebreather mask.
He snatched and took with him Sonoko's bag.
Then, we revisited the Ranburi Shrine
during its Third Rooster Day, but...
The Rooster Man reappeared again...
And stabbed and wounded high
school graduate Masuko Shirou-san.
Before Masuko-san lost consciousness, he
murmured, "It wasn't Rooster, but Monkey."
Then, he proceeded to present me nine fingers with both hands.
What on earth did he mean?
Inside the park's restroom where the
fleeing Rooster Man took refuge...
There were three men.
Hino Tatsuo-san.
Sarukawa Hisami-san.
Mizunoe Shinjisan.
Was the Rooster Man among these three people?
After learning that the button found in Ran's wallet...
May have been left by the Rooster Man when he
bumped into her on the previous Rooster Day...
The police decided to search the three men's houses, but...
This case...
Doesn't seem it will end that easily.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
A mysterious shadow is approaching Ran...
The identities of the nine monkeys and Rooster Man will be revealed!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What?
You didn't find anything?
So there weren't any clothes at those three's
houses that matched the missing button?
No.
And since we didn't have a search
warrant, we could only look around.
Yet we didn't even spot any clothes with that type of button.
We also asked the family members of those three, but...
They didn't recall any clothing that suddenly went missing.
So the odds of it being disposed of after the crime are low?
Yeah.
Which means it's likely the button Ran-san
picked up was only on the ground by chance.
Is that so...
Beyond that, according to people in their homes...
Hino Tatsuo (45)
Shrine Visitor
Hino-san had gone on a trip to Sendai with
his family on the First Rooster Day...
Sarukawa Hisami (20)
Part-time Worker
And Sarukawa-san was working his shift at the time
of crime on the First and Second Rooster Days.
Mizunoe Shinji (32)
Company Employee
They also testified Mizunoe-san had gone to Nagasaki
on a business trip on the Second Rooster Day.
Not to mention he had filed a theft report from when he
was robbed by the Rooster Man on the First Rooster Day.
I see.
In other words, none of these three people would have been able to
commit crimes at the First, Second, and Third Rooster Festivals.
In addition, we received word from the hospital just now.
They reported that the victim Masuko
Shirou-san has regained consciousness, but...
And?
He says he doesn't remember being stabbed by the Rooster
Man nor leaving any message about "monkey" and "nine".
Is that so...
He doesn't remember?
What's that supposed to mean?
Inspector, we found it.
Inside the Rooster Man's daypack,
we found Mizunoe-san's bankbook.
So it was there?
Yeah.
The bankbook was inside someone else's bag,
so it took longer than expected to verify it.
Someone else's?
Yes.
We had the victims of the First and Second Rooster
Festivals come and verify their bags, but...
Most of the things inside the bags didn't match.
Now that you mention it...
There was a handkerchief in my purse that I didn't recognize.
And the oracle that was supposed to be inside wasn't there.
Isn't that the one called "Lovely Fortunes"?
It was in another person's bag.
I think it said, "The one who captures
this high-strung, old-soul type is..."
Stop!
No need to blurt out what it says!
High-strung, old-soul type?
But, why were the belongings all mixed up?
The Rooster Man must have taken
everything out of the bags he stole...
And then got them mixed up when
he hastily stuffed them back in.
And...
The victims from the First and Second Rooster Festivals...
Did they confirm those were their bags stolen by the Rooster Man?
Yeah.
In other words, there's no doubt that it was
the same culprit for all three incidents.
So this clears us, right?
Yeah.
The jerk who spread rumors about the Rooster Man hiding
inside this restroom is probably in this crowd of onlookers.
It certainly seems that way.
And it appears none of us could have been present
at the First, Second, and Third Rooster Festivals.
Then, we're going home.
You don't mind, do you?
My wife is probably worried.
Well, that's all for today.
Out of the way!
Move it!
It's strange.
Ignoring the fact that the contents of
the stolen bags were mixed up...
Why was he carrying them all with him to begin with?
If he was caught carrying them, they'd serve as proof
that he wouldn't be able to talk his way out of.
And those three's reaction to Ran's declaration that she might
have found the Rooster Man's button also bothers me.
If one of them were the Rooster Man...
Normally they would've broken into a cold sweat
wondering if they'd lost the button even if they hadn't.
Cold sweat...
Sweat...
I see!
Because that man was running and sweating...
That's why he tried to hide it for fear of being noticed.
Wait.
Even if that person is the culprit, it wouldn't be
possible for him to be at all three Rooster Festivals.
In that case, there should be another
Rooster Man outside of that person, but...
The Rooster Man's daypack had the stolen
bags from all of the Rooster Festivals.
And what's with the "monkey" and "nine?
Just what did that message mean?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Such a grim face.
I was just thinking about what "monkey" and "nine" could mean.
Monkey and nine...
Dad!
Why are you here?
I heard on the news that the Rooster Man
reappeared at the shrine you went to.
So I got worried and came to pick you up.
It was all over the news!
That the guy who was stabbed left
behind a message of monkey and nine.
If I were to play the word game of "kyuu" I'd say...
Myna Bird
Kyuukanchou.
Ambulance
Kyuukyuusha.
Table Tennis
Takkyuu.
Baseball Stadium
And there's yakyuujou too!
But I can't think of any stadiums with "monkey" in their name.
Speaking of baseball stadiums...
Why does Koshien Stadium carry the name "Koshien"?
Was there a place called Koshien near that stadium?
There is.
I think there's Koshien Station.
That's not it.
The station was named only after
the completion of Koshien Stadium.
And because of the year that
Koshien Stadium was completed...
What about the year it was finished?
I see, that's how it was.
The victim knew about the culprit's identity.
That's why it was actually the ninth monkey!
Well, let's go home.
I almost forgot!
I need to pick up the clothes from the cleaners!
Dad, please take Conan-kun and Sonoko home without me.
Leave that kind of thing for tomorrow!
But Dad, isn't your friend's wedding tomorrow?
Let's see...
The cleaners was...
Hey, geezer.
You gonna bump into us and just go on your way?
I'm sorry!
If you're really sorry, hand over your wallet.
Don't worry...
We'll only take enough to cover our drinks!
If this is a shakedown, I'm reporting you to the police!
Young miss, you've got some guts!
Isn't she a cute one?
You wanna play with us?
Bastards...
"The one who captures this high-strung old soul is
a woman who displays the virtues of Old Japan.
"Gaudy fashions and tomboyish conduct are prohibited!
"If you persist and appeal to him as a proper woman...
"The distance between you two shall be shortened without limit!"
I'm just saying that crime is bad, you know...
What's with you?
What's this, a fight?
Hey, let's go.
Watch your back!
Thank you, you saved me.
No problem...
Tomboyish conduct is prohibited!
Act proper, act proper.
What?
You know who the Rooster Man is?
Then, you figured out the meaning of the monkey
and nine that the stabbed man left behind?
In fact, the stabbed man knew the person who stabbed him.
That's why he said, "It wasn't Rooster, but
Monkey," and showed me nine fingers.
Then, wouldn't it be the monkey-faced Hino Tatsuo?
If they're acquaintances, they should know each other's face.
But...
That person has nothing to do with "nine", right?
In that case, is it the man named Sarukawa Hisami?
If I recall, his nickname is "Kyuu-chan".
If they're already on a nickname basis...
I think the victim would've said his nickname
or just, "The culprit is Sarukawa" instead.
But the only remaining person is named Mizunoe Shinji, right?
What's he got to do with monkey and nine?
Say, the kanji 酉 that denotes "Rooster" Day
is borrowed from the Twelve Branches, right?
Then, "Monkey"?
Let's see...
It's 申, also means "to be called".
Wait, it's the same character as "Shin" in Mizunoe Shinji!
But, there's no "nine" in there!
We were talking about how Koshien Stadium got its name, right?
That's because the stadium was completed in 1924,
the year of Koushi, so it was named "Koshien".
The year of Koushi?
It's the sexagenary cycle.
Composed of Kou, Otsu, Hei, Tei, Bo, Ki,
Kou, Shin, Jin, Ki —
these Ten Stems...
And Shi, Chuu, In, Bou, Shin, Shi, Go, Bi, Shin,
Yuu, Jutsu, Gai —
these Twelve Branches.
This stems-and-branches counting system forms a 60-year cycle.
Since Koushi came from the first stem
"Kou" and the first branch "Shi"...
It is thus the first year in each of the 60-year cycle.
Because the stadium was completed in
that year, they named it Koshien, right?
And what's the name of the ninth year?
The ninth year in the cycle will be after...
Koushi, Occhuu, Heiin, Teibou, Boshin,
Kishi, Kougo, Shinbi, so it's...
Jinshin.
Jinshin as in "Jinshin War", right?
And aren't there native-Japanese reading for those too?
For example, Hinoeuma.
Let's see...
The Japanese reading for Jinshin is Mizunoesaru.
Mizunoe!?
Mizunoe Shinji!
Exactly the same!
As proof, that Mizunoe guy was going to show his receipt
from the convenience store but didn't, right?
That's because he was chased as the Rooster Man, and the
receipt in his pocket got wet from his running and sweating.
If he had shown the wet receipt, it would've
been proof that he had been running.
And the things the Rooster Man threw inside the utility
closet of the park restroom where he took refuge...
Were only the knife used as the weapon, his
down jacket, and the Firebreather mask.
I see.
He prepared a change of clothes beforehand,
but he didn't have time to change his pants.
But wait!
That Mizunoe guy had been on a business trip and couldn't have
been at the Second Rooster Festival, according to Detective Takagi.
Furthermore, he filed a theft report because his bag that had his
bankbook was snatched by the Rooster Man on the First Rooster Day.
Of course.
Although the Rooster Man who stabbed Masuko-san
at today's Third Rooster Festival was Mizunoe...
The Rooster Man on the First and Second Rooster Day...
Was actually Masuko-san!
I think perhaps Masuko-san was blackmailing Mizunoe-san?
Using the bankbook he had snatched as leverage.
It probably shows illegal dealings or embezzlement.
He may have threatened him to pay or risk having it revealed.
Then, is that why Masuko-san brought the daypack with all of
the things he had stolen during the prior Rooster Festivals?
Yeah.
Perhaps that Mizunoe guy tactfully asked him to bring them with
him along with the bankbook as a condition of the transaction...
Setting here as their meeting place.
He'd kill Masuko-san after his arrival...
And he'd leave behind all of the stolen items while
running away dressed as the Rooster Man...
So that he wouldn't be suspected due to having
an alibi for the Second Rooster Festival.
I see!
Since that stabbed Masuko-san was trying
to apply to the literature department...
And all the bankbook had was a name and address, the
"monkey and "nine" conversion easily came to mind!
In that case, could it be that the reason he claimed to not
remember anything after waking up in the hospital was...
When he was stabbed, he was mortified so he blurted out
"monkey and "nine" to point out the person who stabbed him.
But when he regained consciousness and thought it through...
He realized that he'd be exposed as the Rooster Man
should the meaning of monkey and nine be revealed.
Thus he decided to stay quiet.
But we have no evidence...
If only someone had picked up anything the Rooster
Man dropped or something along those lines...
That's it!
The button Ran picked up after she bumped into
the Rooster Man at the Second Rooster Festival!
If they found the clothing that's missing that button at
Masuko-san's house, wouldn't that work as evidence!?
Since the Rooster Man on the Second
Rooster Day was Masuko-san!
And, if we could make that Masuko guy confess and
spill the beans about Mizunoe, it'd be case closed!
You two are amazing!
A great deduction!
That's the Deduction Queen and Sleeping Kogorou for you!
It's nothing!
Piece of cake!
But somehow...
It feels different...
Anyway, let's tell Detective Takagi about
the button and have him investigate!
We'll find out if there are any clothes that match
the missing button at Masuko-san's house!
I may have sent too much to the cleaners...
What!?
You gave the button back to Ran?
Why?
Wasn't that evidence!?
Well, at that time it hadn't been confirmed as such, so...
And she said it may have been from your
clothes and wanted to take it home to check.
Hey, don't tell me...
In order to get rid of the button, that
Mizunoe guy would go as far to attack Ran!?
But if it's Ran, there's no need to worry!
She's really strong!
Uncle, this is weird.
Ran-neechan isn't answering her phone!
Wallet...
Found it!
This is it!
If I can just get rid of this button...
I'll never be suspected!
Mizunoe-san...
Right?
That button...
Yeah, that's right.
This belongs to the one I failed to kill today...
The button of the Rooster Man!
The Rooster Man you failed to kill?
But wasn't that person stabbed by the Rooster Man?
I'm telling you that the Rooster Man was that high school grad!
That bastard...
He found out about it from the bankbook he stole from me...
That I'd been embezzling funds from my company.
Well, since there were multiple deposits per month for
the same amount going to a nonexistent company...
I suppose it would've been impossible to go unnoticed.
That was indeed the fake company's
account I used for embezzling.
That bastard...
All because he said he'd return my bankbook
but didn't know which bag was mine.
That's why I told him to bring all of the
stolen bags so I could check for myself.
All so I could disguise as the Rooster Man for a night.
Too bad it seems he survived, but I know he won't say anything.
Since he's just a wimp who kept saying that he tried to relieve his
stress from studying for entrance exams by snatching purses.
Odd, isn't it?
Why do you think I'm telling you all of this so openly?
Miss...
It's because you're going to die here.
Right here, right now.
Ran...
Ran!
It'd be best if you turned yourself in.
Because as of now, no one has died yet, but...
If you commit further crimes...
Begging for your life?
I suppose you don't wanna die, huh?
You're still at an age where you've yet to enjoy love life.
And you still have an unopened Lovely Fortune in your wallet.
It's unopened?
Don't tell me, Sonoko...
She snatched my oracle and pretended to read it back then...
But she was only reading hers?
While we're at it, why don't I read it to you as a parting gift?
"To capture the heart of this brilliant-minded
man, just be yourself exactly as you are.
"Even if you try to pretend and act cute,
beware that he'll immediately see through it.
"Stay true to your natural and pure self...
"And if you keep pressing onward and
holding onto what you believe...
"Your feelings will certainly be delivered to him."
There you go!
Ran-neechan!
As expected, there was no need to worry...
But, what was that showy move just now!?
"Rounding Heel Kick"!
Kazumi-senpai taught it to me a while ago!
Really...
This man is actually the culprit...
Yeah, we know.
But Ran, wasn't tomboyish conduct prohibited?
That was your oracle, Sonoko!
Mine was...
Let's see...
"To capture the heart of this brilliant-minded
man, just be yourself exactly as you are.
"Even if you try to pretend and act cute,
beware that he'll immediately see through it.
"Stay true to your natural and pure self...
"And if you keep pressing onward and
holding onto what you believe...
"Your feelings will certainly be delivered to him."
This one's so good!
Trade with me please!
No way!
But well...
I guess girls need to stay strong after all!
Maybe I should take karate lessons too!
You're to strong!
No Sonoko, you need to act proper!
Delicious!
Awesome!
Miyake-san!
This is...
An imitation of the seven wonders, isn't it?
Those two look like they're hiding something.
There are only three of the seven wonders left.
Is something still going to happen?
And what's with that man?
Next Conan's Hint
Fire
Look Forward to the Next Episode