Hiroshima, Hiroshima.
My name is Mouri Kogorou, a renowned detective.
We have just arrived at Hiroshima.
Standing next to me is my daughter, Ran.
Hello, my name is Mouri Ran.
And this freeloader...
No need to call me a freeloader...
My name is Edogawa Conan!
The purpose of our visit to Hiroshima this time...
Isn't about solving tough cases.
Koshiji Naoto (45)
Director
Even a great detective needs a break.
We're here today to tour around famous
sightseeing spots in Hiroshima...
Yatsukawa Kouji (27)
Assistant Director
And treat ourselves to the beautiful
sceneries and local cuisine specialties.
Kamisuwa Mikihiko (52)
Nichiuri TV Producer
This is our idea of an R&R, where we relax our bodies and
minds from the stress of wrestling with taxing cases!
Kitamura Yuuichi (32)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Producer
What's wrong?
Excuse me, my stomach's been acting up for a while...
I shall title it, "The Great Detective's Vacation:
The Hiroshima-Miyajima Gourmet Food Tour".
Be sure to tune in!
Good, cut!
Camera, how was it?
Hamada Yukinari (40)
Cameraman
Yes, everything went well.
I've recorded some great footage here.
And the sound?
Shimokura Kazuya (25)
Soundman
No need to worry, Koshiji-san!
Good job!
Mouri-san, you really are a great detective.
Miyake Fumie (28)
Makeup Artist
That was truly impressive!
Is that so!?
Truly, truly!
You didn't look like you were new to this at all!
Really now?
As such, we joined Nichiuri TV's travel program
as guest stars and came to visit Hiroshima.
Kitamura-san?
Hey, hang in there!
Are you all right?
Kitamura-san!
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
The seven wonders in Miyajima, Hiroshima.
The town scenes are real, but the case is a mystery!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It's from Sonoko.
A video call?
Hi, Ran!
What's going on, Sonoko?
Didn't we agree to meet on site?
You're still at home!?
Well, you see...
I still can't decide what I should wear.
This autumn-like one-piece dress with red leaves?
Or the one with a matured look...
This?
I think either one fits you perfectly.
Because she said, "If it's on TV, then I have to go."
She was supposed to come with us as a "relative", but...
Sorry for the wait.
How is Kitamura-san doing?
I apologize for the inconvenience.
I gave him some stomach pills to take...
So I think he'll get better if he rests for the day.
Let's continue our filming as planned.
Understood.
Hey, what happened, Ran?
Looks like it's time for our departure, so I'm hanging up.
Hurry up and get here!
I'll be there soon!
Sanyou Main Line
But, it must be tough for you to work as a producer...
Having to come along for all these filming sessions.
No, no, I don't usually come along.
But this time we have none other than
the Sleeping Kogorou-san as a guest.
Isn't that right?
Yeah, that's the reason why!
I'm honored!
It takes about 25 minutes from Hiroshima
Station via the Sahyou Main Line...
To arrive at Miyajimaguchi Station, the
entryway to Miyajima some would say.
After walking from the station for a few minutes, passing
the conger eel rice and red leaf buns specialty stores...
One arrives at Miyajimaguchi Pier, where the ferry terminal is.
Miyajima
It takes only ten minutes by ferry to reach the
Itsukushima Shrine, a world heritage site, in Miyajima.
I can see it!
World Heritage Itsukushima Shrine
Miyajima is said to be a deity in the
form of island and is awed by many.
That's why they build toriis and
Shinto shrines in the sea instead.
During low tide, people can even walk straight to the Big Torii.
They perform court dances to worship the deity there, don't they?
National Treasure High Stage
I wanna see them!
Delicious!
Fried oysters are the best!
Conger eel rice, scrumptious!
Hand-formed tempura, that hit the spot!
Delicious!
Oyster Rice Ball
Awesome!
Conger Eel Bun
Miyajima Traditional Crafts Center
Delicious!
Daigan Temple
Itsukushima Shrine Museum
The red leaf buns were delicious!
What's wrong?
Geez, who the hell put salt in my drink!?
Salt?
What do you mean by that?
How should I know?
While we were filming, I put my
drink over there with my bags, and...
Wasn't that just a joke?
But that was pretty mean for a joke, wasn't it?
If I recall, the person who was near the bags was Kamisuwa-san...
Hey, hey, cut it out.
Why would I do something that childish?
That man wearing a coat...
Do you know him?
No...
I see!
Could that guy be...
Yatsukawa!
Head to the next scene!
We're on a tight schedule!
Yes, sir!
Start the rehearsal now!
Well then, now that my stomach is getting
empty, let's head over to that place.
Hey, hey...
What did you want to say earlier?
If I recall, it was two weeks ago...
Some guy kept poking around asking about us staff members.
That guy earlier looked a lot like him.
So that man followed them all the way to
Hiroshima and mixed salt with the canned coffee...
But for what exactly?
And also...
It's just a rumor, but...
They said someone related to the TV
station is running an illegal casino.
Illegal casino?
Because of that, Kamisuwa-san and
Koshiji-san have been jumpy lately.
Red Leaf
Bun
Misenya
Oh, a long-established red leaf bun shop!
Red leaf buns originated right here in Miyajima, right?
Looks tasty!
Welcome to our shop!
Hello there!
What kind of red leaf bun do you recommend?
What I recommend is...
This "Misen's Seven Wonders" flavor assortment here.
Ayase Yayoi (22)
"Misenya" Owner's Daughter
It's been receiving very high praises!
"Seven wonders" flavor, huh?
Say, say, what are Misen's seven wonders?
They're legends about Misen, a mountain
that stands tall in the center of Miyajima.
Misen
Ever since Master Koubou's training, the fire he
ignited has kept on burning for a thousand years...
The "Eternal Fire".
When the Master left his tin staff
standing, it grew roots and became...
The "Plum Tree of the Tin Staff".
The salt water inside the rock's hole goes
up and down in synch with the tides...
The "Ebb-and-Flow Rock".
Etched with scriptures in the Master's calligraphic writings...
The "Mandala Rock".
Said to be claps from a goblin living in Misen...
The "Sound of Wooden Clappers".
Even on sunny days, dew dropped as
if there had been a rainshower...
The "Dewy Cherry Tree".
The mysterious balls of fire appearing
on the sea surrounding Miyajima...
Called Dragon Fire, was watched over by the
tree atop Misen — The "Dragon Fire Cedar".
Imitating these seven wonders, we've created red leaf
buns with matching flavors and sell them in assortments.
This one is plum flavored.
That'd be the Plum Tree of the Tin Staff.
Cherry fillings.
The Dewy Cherry Tree, right?
And the Eternal Fire has a spicy hot flavor!
How interesting!
Cut, OK!
Young miss and boy, you two were good!
Aren't you awesome, Conan-kun?
Your debut as a child star!
I've acted as a child "star" many times, you know.
This is...
My, how nostalgic!
Have you guys been here before?
Yep.
It was in autumn two years ago.
We were here to collect information for another program.
It's been a long time!
I heard you guys were coming again, but I couldn't wait
and ended up putting these on display two weeks ago.
That guy, he was...
Look, that guy!
Ayase Shinroku (27)
Yayoi's Brother
Wasn't he the man earlier?
You know my big brother?
He's Yayoi-san's...
Brother?
Your brother's been missing for two weeks?
Yes...
In fact, in autumn two years ago...
My parents entered a forbidden entry area in Misen...
And slipped and fell to their deaths.
But my brother and I felt suspicious about their passing.
Knowing Misen like the back of their hands, my
parents would have never just fallen and died.
My brother searched the vicinity persistently...
And then discovered that thing.
That thing?
Something shiny, like a piece of a beautiful accessory.
It had the shape of a flower.
Half a month ago, my brother said he
finally knew what it was and left home...
And we haven't been in contact since.
Mouri-san, I beg of you!
Could you please find my brother?
My apologies, but our filming schedule is very tight.
Is that so...
Why would Yayoi-san's brother stalk the Nichiuri staff?
Wait...
Two years ago, in autumn...
Didn't Koshiji-san and the others come to Miyajima?
Could it be related to the accident two years ago?
Senjou Hall
This is strange...
What's wrong?
Well, Miyake just called me...
But I didn't set my ringtone to something weird like this.
That's the sound of wooden clappers...
Well, why not take the call?
Oh, that's right.
Hello, is this Miyake?
What's wrong?
Answer me!
Hello?
Where could Miyake-san be?
In such a short time span, she couldn't have gone far.
Miyake-san!
Are you all right!?
That's good, she wasn't hurt badly.
This is...
Are you all right?
Yeah, it was nothing...
Why were you there?
I happened to see that man — the one
who looked like Yayoi-san's brothers.
My brother?
While I was chasing him, a rock suddenly fell from the stone wall...
So it's not only the salted canned coffee...
This practical joke has gone really bad.
But they're the same, right?
As the seven wonders.
The assistant director Yatsukawa-san
had salt mixed into his canned coffee.
The cameraman Hamada-san had his cellphone
ringtone changed without his knowing.
The makeup artist Miyake-san was
injured by a rock with patterns.
Those are in accordance with Misen's seven wonders...
The Ebb-and-Flow Rock...
he Sound of Wooden Clappers...
And the Mandala Rock, aren't they?
You're right!
That's a good catch, kid.
Acting like you know everything!
It's only three of the seven wonders, no?
Coincidence, mere coincidence!
Is that so?
Maybe there's more...
There is.
The assistant producer Kitamura-san had a necktie...
With cherry blossom patterns, right?
Now that you mention it...
Yeah, it was a lousy tie with an out of season pattern.
One of the seven wonders, the Dewy Cherry Tree.
In that case, could it be...
That the guy's stomachache...
Was also the work of someone!?
By someone, do you mean Yayoi-san's brother?
No way...
But, why did he target us?
Does nothing come to mind?
It'd be best if we also asked Kitamura-san, right?
I know that.
Kamisuwa-san!
He's not answering.
Is he sleeping?
To be on the safe side, I'll have the hotel staff check on him.
Is that right?
So he was sleeping after all?
Then please tell him to call us when he gets up.
Thank you for your help.
There are only three of the seven wonders left.
Is something still going to happen?
And that man...
Is Yayoi-san's brother behind all of this?
Wait...
Her brother went missing two weeks ago.
That picture was also put up two weeks ago.
Could it be...
Her brother saw that picture and...
What now, Kamisuwa-san?
Our plan for today?
We'll be touring around Daishou Temple, and that's it.
In that case filming will be our first priority.
Let's talk about this again tonight.
My apologies, Mouri-san, but please comply.
Understood.
Then, let's head over there.
Yes!
Daishou Temple
Cut!
Good, OK!
Great job, guys!
One more scene and we're done.
Those two look like they're hiding something.
I better not take my eyes off them.
Kannon Hall
Next, spiritual training where you shed your
present life's impurities in the dark...
A tour around the Ordination Platform!
Ran-san, Conan-kun, if you'd please!
So we're the only ones going down?
I don't think I can handle this...
It'd be bad if I took my eyes off those two.
Hey, show us some courage, boy!
Go, go!
Go for it, Ran-chan!
Now, off you go, off you go!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Don't go first without me!
Let's go together, Conan-kun!
We're finally out...
And with that, we've wrapped up our schedule for the day.
I look forward to working with you again tomorrow!
Thanks for the hard work...
Huh?
Where's Kamisuwa-san and Koshiji-san?
Somebody, come here!
What was that?
Kamisuwa-san!
Koshiji-san!?
This...
He's still breathing.
Yatsukawa-san, call for an ambulance!
Kaji... there...
What did he say?
Kaji... there?
Was someone there?
The culprit!?
Koshiji-san, one more time!
It's no use.
He just passed out.
This is...
A cellphone strap?
A tin staff!
An imitation of one of the seven remaining
wonders — the Plum Tree of the Tin Staff?
Did the culprit drop this?
It's him...
I saw the man we spotted during the day running over there.
You should've told us that sooner!
Could he be trying to escape by the ferry!?
Will I make it?
Excuse me!
I'm sorry!
Where's the ferry?
We were too late...
Hey, look!
It's that man!
Damn!
We were so close!
This is bad!
That Misenya shop is on fire!
What!?
By "kaji", he meant "fire"?
Someone!
Anyone!
Hurry!
Did you bring water?
Hey, hurry up!
Yayoi-san!
Are you all right?
Yes...
Is this from Kitamura?
Kamisuwa-san, sorry for inconveniencing you.
Now's not the time for that.
Koshiji's been attacked, and Misenya's on fire!
Koshiji-san was!?
And what do you mean on fire?
It's Kitamura-san, who's resting in a hotel in Hiroshima.
Kamisuwa-san!
This is bad!
Before the fire broke out...
People around here saw a man that resembled her brother!
What was that!?
The culprit must be that bastard.
Her elder brother?
He assaulted Koshiji-san, and then torched his own home...
"Gourmet Tour Detective Solves the Case—On the Spot!"
Yayoi-san!
The rest of us might be attacked again!
I'm not about to let culprit run amok anymore.
It's my turn to retaliate!
Next Conan's Hint
High-Rise Apartment
Look Forward to the Next Episode