In order to participate as guest in a travel program
for Nichiuri TV, we came all the way to Hiroshima.
But strange incidents befell the TV staff members...
After we befriended the shopgirl Ayase Yayoi-san from a
long-established red leaf bun shop known as Misenya...
We learned that these incidents were in accordance
with Misen's legendary seven wonders.
Furthermore, the identity of the mystery man
that'd been harassing the TV staff members...
Was determined to likely be the older
brother of Yayoi-san, Shinroku-san.
Two years earlier, an incident involving Yayoi-san's
parents had them fall to their death at Misen...
Does it have something to do with the TV staff members?
What's more, the director Koshiji-san was attacked...
And the Misenya shop was set on fire.
Was everything the work of Shinroku-san?
Or was it...
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
The seven mysteries will be revealed.
We'll learn the surprising culprit at the end of our trip!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Miyamoto Kenichi (55)
Hiroshima Police First Division Inspector
I'm Miyamoto from the Hiroshima Police.
Uhm, may I ask how Koshiji-san's doing?
His condition?
He's unconscious and in critical condition.
No way...
How awful!
The culprit must be that bastard.
Isn't that so, detective?
No, we can't conclude that...
Mouri Kogorou-san, is it?
I've heard a lot about you.
Thank you.
Bu culprit...
Do you mean Ayase Shinroku-san from this Misenya shop?
Pardon me, but you're Ayase-san's little sister, right?
Have you seen this before?
That's...
My brother's!
It seems this was dropped at the scene
where Koshiji-san was attacked.
Right, kid?
That's right.
And, the cause of fire?
We can't fully establish that yet, but the point of
origin was at the boundary of the adjacent store.
There weren't any inflammable materials
there, suggesting this was probably arson.
Inspector!
Around the time the fire broke out, people in the vicinity
witnessed a man resembling your brother around here.
In that case, it really was...
Her elder brother?
Ayase Yayoi (22)
"Misenya" Owner's Daughter
He assaulted Koshiji-san, and then torched his own home...
No way!
That's a lie!
My brother wouldn't do something like that!
Yayoi-san...
It's true.
Even if we assume Shinroku-san was the culprit...
What reason could he have to burn his own home?
Is something wrong, kid?
Speaking of fire, isn't this another imitation of
one of the seven wonders —
the Eternal Fire?
It's true!
The seven wonders, again?
What's this about?
No, I still think it's just coincidence, but...
I see.
In other words, regarding your parents' deaths...
Your brother suspects that the TV staff members, who happened to
be around at the time of the accident, had something to do with it.
And as such, he imitated the seven wonders and caused all of this.
It was only a possibility.
However...
I confirmed with Yayoi-san earlier, but...
Her parents' accident happened the day after we left.
In that case, her parents' accident
had nothing to do with Koshiji-san.
But, Shinroku-san mistook the whole
thing without knowing this fact...
In any case, regarding Ayase Shinroku-san's whereabouts...
It will be the first priority for our police's investigation.
Brother, where could you be?
Although he's currently in hiding...
We can't say for sure that Shinroku-san is the culprit.
Leading us to believe so...
The real culprit might be among those people.
But, at the time Koshiji-san was attacked...
Hamada-san, Shimokura-san, and Yatsukawa-san were
with us during the tour of the ordination platform.
Miyake-san was with Uncle.
And Kitamura-san called us from the
hotel in Hiroshima during the fire.
It takes ten minutes to arrive at Miyajimaguchi by ferry.
It then takes a further 25 minutes to arrive at
the hotel in Hiroshima City by bullet train.
He couldn't make it in time even if he were to
attack Koshiji-san and hurry back to the hotel.
In that case, it looks like the one without
an alibi would solely be Kamisuwa-san.
Come to think of it, that time...
there
Kaji... ita...
This is bad!
That Misenya shop is on fire!
What!?
By "kaji", he meant "fire"?
Looks like he thought "kaji" meant something else.
Wait, it was impossible for Koshiji-san to
have known about the fire at that time.
In that case, the "kaji" blurted out by Koshiji-san was...
Could it be!?
Kid...
Will this photo be of assistance?
Thank you very much.
I happened to have one more copy on hand.
Since the ones I put up on display all got burnt.
Could it be that the target of the fire wasn't meant to be Misenya?
Atomic Bomb Dome
The next day, we returned to the city of Hiroshima...
Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park
And met up with Kitamura-san who was resting in the hotel.
Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum
I deeply apologize for the inconvenience I caused yesterday.
Are you all right?
Yes, good as new.
About your stomachache, do you have
any idea who might've done this to you?
You mean the Seven Wonders imitation?
Kitamura Yuuichi (32)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Producer
I just heard about it and was appalled.
As far as I could recall, there was that lunch I had during filming...
Kamisu Mikihiko (52)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Could it be that someone tampered with his lunch?
What concerns me more is what we should do from now.
Yatsukawa Kouiji (27)
Assistant Director
Uhm...
I know that Koshiji-san is in a bad state right now...
And I understand that I shouldn't be saying this, but...
What, just spit it out.
I think this is a once-in-a-lifetime chance for us!
"Gourmet Tour Detective Solves the Case—On the Spot!"
We're guaranteed to get high ratings!
Hamada Yukinari (40)
Cameraman
I completely agree.
I'd feel unsettled if we did nothing.
That's right.
Miyake Fumie (28)
Makeup Artist
Shimokura Kazuya (25)
Soundman
That'd be a disgrace to Koshiji-san.
Please allow me to also regain my reputation.
I beg of you.
Understood.
I'll negotiate with the higher-ups myself.
Yatsukawa, take on Koshiji's role for the time being.
Yes, sir!
As you can see, Mouri-san...
There's a slight change of plan in our
program, but can you still help us out?
If it's decided, please count on me!
What's that?
Great!
Let's do this!
I'm counting on you, Hamada-san!
Leave it to me!
Could it be...
If Shinroku-san truly believed that the TV staff who visited Miyajima
two years ago had something to do with his parents' deaths...
It's logical to assume that he imitated the seven wonders of Misen
where they died, and launched his attack on the staff members.
But, the ones who came to Miyajima two years ago...
Were only Koshiji-san, Kitamura-san, and Miyake-san.
Since Yatsukawa-san wasn't even there...
Wouldn't it be strange for the culprit to imitate the
Ebb-and-Flow Rock wonder and put salt in his canned coffee?
That really was strange...
Well that's... because he's part of the staff.
There's a saying that goes, "He who
hates Peter harms his dog," right?
That's right, exactly what you said!
Are you saying the next target could be me?
It's also possible that I'm the target.
Regardless of who the culprit is...
They are likely to imitate the remaining
wonder of the "Dragon Fire Cedar"...
And make their next heinous move, no doubt about it.
We then decided to meet up with
Shinroku-san's friend in Hiroshima City.
Shukkeien
Miniature Scenery Garden
Well...
I haven't seen Shinroku-kun for over half a year.
Rainbow Arch Bridge
After his parents died, Shinroku-kun went off the deep end.
Unable to leave him alone, Yayoi-chan quit her collage
program in Osaka and came back to Miyajima.
Was that person really the culprit?
Come to think of it...
The high-rise wasn't there.
Could it be?
Hiroshima Castle
About Shinroku-kun?
Well, I don't know too well...
Hey, hey.
I have a question about two years ago, can you tell me?
What is it?
I see.
So that really is how it was.
No good!
Kamisuwa-san isn't here!
Where?
Where could he be?
Yayoi-san?
Kamisuwa-san!
Yayoi-san...
What...
A dragon pattern...
The last of the seven wonders...
The Dragon Fire Cedar's imitation?
Kamisuwa-san's cellphone...
Was he attacked from behind while he was on the phone?
So, did you see the culprit?
No...
When I arrived here, Kamisuwa-san was already on the ground.
In that case, why were you here?
Someone called me, claiming to be calling on behalf of my brother.
Saying that my brother wanted to talk to me about the truth he
just learned, and that he wanted to meet at Hiroshima Castle.
A proxy, huh...
Is that really so?
Are you suspecting Yayoi-san?
If the brother's motive is to avenge his parents' deaths...
We can assume that the sister shares the same motive.
No way...
So I'm next!
Since Kamisuwa-san didn't even come here to film
two years ago and was still attacked regardless...
If this is a case of an indifference assault,
the rest of us might be attacked again!
Are you saying it won't be just salt for me the next time!?
Since it's an indifference attack, indifference!
Damn, what a son of a bitch!
I'm not about to let the culprit run amok anymore.
It's my turn to retaliate!
What did you say!?
Koshiji-san and Kamisuwa-san are...
Dead!?
Are you sure!?
We just received word from the hospital.
My condolences.
It can't be...
So the culprit really was this Ayase Shinroku guy?
Yes, we just finished paperwork seeking his arrest.
That son of a bitch!
Even Kamisuwa-san is...
He's already under our protection.
It was exactly as Mouri-san deduced.
The culprit is right here!
No way...
It can't be!
So it was you?
Dad?
Actually, I have no idea what's going on either...
So this is the famous "Sleeping Kogorou" pose?
Kitamura-san, the culprit behind all these incidents was you.
By leading us to think Ayase Shinroku-san imitated Misen's
seven wonders in order to avenge his parents' deaths...
You managed to carry out your crime scheme.
Your target was the director, Koshiji Naoto-san.
The plan was to murder him.
What was that?
What do you mean by that?
Allow me to explain.
First, why did he want to make Shinroku-san into his scapegoat?
That's because, regarding the death
fall of his parents two years ago...
It was you, Kitamura-san, who was responsible.
No way!
In the autumn of two years ago,
after the filming session ended...
You remained at Miyajima alone due
to mountain-hiking being your hobby.
I heard it from Conan.
Isn't that right, Miyake-san?
Yes.
While climbing Misen, you entered the forbidden entry area...
And were reprimanded by Shinroku-san and Yayoi-san's parents.
I don't know what happened during that time, but...
Their parents fell to their deaths as a result.
Shinroku-san searched the vicinity and picked up
something resembling a piece of an accessory.
That was actually the zipper decoration
on the jacket you were wearing.
It's the exact same as the thing on the bag you're carrying right now.
Conan!
Here!
Here you go.
The zipper on Koshiji-san's jacket!
It's true...
It's the same thing!
Two years ago, Koshiji-san happened to borrow that jacket from you.
I recall that he said, "Lend me that
jacket, I feel like I'm catching a cold."
That zipper decoration was discovered
by Shinroku-san at the accident site.
Kitamura-san, you dropped that, didn't you?
Tell us what happened then.
It was an accident!
We argued a little bit, and then suddenly...
I didn't know they'd end up like that!
We'll have the police thoroughly question
you about the details of that incident.
It was two weeks ago that Shinroku-san realized
the origin of the object he had picked up.
Quite possibly after looking at the photo from two years
ago that was put on display by the souvenir shop owner.
So, is that why Shiriroku-san thought Koshiji-san
had something to do with his parents' accident?
Right.
As a result, Shinroku-san went to Tokyo to verify his suspicions.
Isn't that right, Shinroku-san?
Ayase Shinroku (27)
Yayoi's Older Brother
Yes.
It's exactly as you said.
After arriving in Tokyo...
I started to investigate that director named Koshiji-san.
Soon afterwards, this guy said he'd let me
meet Koshiji-san, and wouldn't let me down.
The one who approached you was Kitamura-san.
Yes.
Then he called Shinroku-san to Hiroshima
while the filming was taking place...
And confined him in this room.
The person who imitated the seven
wonders and attacked Koshiji-san...
And burned the photos that could become evidence...
Was actually Kitamura-san disguised as Shinroku-san.
But, wait...
Kitamura-san had an alibi, didn't he?
Kamisuwa-san called this hotel and received
confirmation that he was sleeping...
And during the fire, Kitamura-san called back too.
The "Kitamura-san" the hotel staff member
saw when she stopped by and checked...
Was actually Shinroku-san who was given sleeping pills.
By shaving off his mustache and changing his hairstyle...
He could make sure that she wouldn't be able to
tell them apart when the police question her.
On the other hand, Kamisuwa-san
suspected it was Kitamura-san's trick.
The high-rise wasn't there.
Right.
About that high-rise that can be seen outside the window...
It wasn't in the video call last night.
I've found out what this was about.
Yes, that's right.
There's another hotel branch of ours
near the Miyajimaguchi ferry terminal.
The interior was almost the same as this.
In other words, the hotel itself was also a double.
After he crossed the sea by ferry, he immediately
checked in to that particular nearby hotel...
And promptly called Kamisuwa-san to establish his alibi.
However, there is a difference between the two hotel rooms.
It's the color of the curtains.
Although this one is sky blue, the one at
Miyajimaguchi was peppermint green.
That's why he couldn't close the curtain.
But because of the contrasting night sceneries...
Kamisuwa-san discovered the trick that had been used.
And then...
Hello, is this the Red Leaf Hotel?
The reason he smashed the cellphone was to prevent people
from noticing Kamisuwa-san had made a call to the hotel.
He then called Yayoi-san out, in the hope that...
He could frame her with the crime.
What was that!?
It looks like there had been a rumor about
someone running an illegal casino.
Well, Kitamura-san, wasn't that about you?
About Koshiji-san's final message...
Fire there
Kaji... ita...
He actually meant "casino" and "Kitamura".
Koshiji-san had already noticed your true color.
My guess is that he asked you to turn
yourself over to the police, right?
But instead, you tried to put it in Kamisuwa-san's
head that Koshiji-san was the suspicious one.
That's why during filming, the atmosphere between
Kamisuwa-san and Koshiji-san was unsettling.
Could it be that after murdering Koshiji-san, you also planned
to frame him with the crime of running the illegal casino?
About that casino...
I was only trying to have some fun at first, but...
Suddenly everything was blown out of
control, and I had no way to quit anymore!
I just couldn't help it!
You couldn't help it, so you assaulted
Koshiji-san and Kamisuwa-san...
And decided to frame Shinroku-san with the
crimes you committed, ruining his life?
Do you think you can get away...
With such an egocentric excuse!?
I almost forgot to say this.
Neither Koshiji-san nor Kamisuwa-san is dead.
I just received a report from the hospital that both of
them have stabilized and are responding to treatment.
It was all part of my instruction.
I apologize for lying to you all.
But the reason I did that was to allow the real culprit to
lower his guard and proceed to frame Shinroku-san.
Afterwards, Koshiji-san and Kamisuwa-san
steadily recovered from their injuries...
And Shinroku-san reunited with Yayoi-san,
rejoicing in each other's well-being.
Delicious!
This Hiroshima-style okonomiyaki is awesome!
The beer is awesome too!
One more!
But, I wonder what will become of the program?
Hey, hey, they'd better have it broadcast!
This is my first time I'd be able to see
myself making a great deduction!
Indeed, since you're always asleep, you Sleeping Kogorou.
I wonder where Sonoko is now?
Speak of the devil...
Sonoko, where on earth are you...
What are you doing, Ran?
Hurry and come here!
This island is so soothing!
Island!?
It's really awesome in Miyakojima!
She mistook the name and went to Miyakojima instead...
All right, cut!
And what every kid likes...
The "Masked Yaiba" show is also produced here!
I just watched it last week...
The back of the body is soaking wet.
Given that the rain already stopped, why?
This is a murder case disguised as suicide!
Next Conan's Hint
Fountain Pen
Look Forward to the Next Episode