The rain stopped!
You're right.
There's the company where the Higashiyama-san
we're visiting works — Orion Planning.
This "Orion Planning"...
What kind of company is it?
They specialize in the planning and production
of commercials, events, and TV programs.
And what every kid likes...
The "Masked Yaiba" show is also produced here!
I just watched it last week...
After being dragged there by Genta and the others.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
A falling incident occurred right before our eyes.
Reveal the alibi trick that hit our blind spots!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Uhm...
I have an appointment with Higashiyama-san
from your publication's planning department.
Sunagawa Nanae (27)
Event Planning Department Employee
You must be Mouri-san.
Higashiyama told me about you.
Let me call him now...
Higashiyama-san already told me to
call his extension after I arrived.
His extension number is 423, right?
Yes, that's right.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Let's see...
Four, two, and three.
Hello, who is this?
Is this Higashiyama-san?
This is Mouri.
Oh, Mouri-san!
Sorry for the inconvenience of having you call this late.
No problem!
You don't have to apologize.
I shall go meet you right away.
My office is at the annex behind the building you're in...
What's wrong, Mouri-san?
Just now...
Someone was falling when I looked out the window!
What'd you say!?
The deceased was the event planner at
this company, Takahata Fujihiko-san.
So he fell to his death?
It looks like Takahata-san's office is on the sixth floor up there.
He likely fell from the window there.
I see.
But, why are you here?
I was invited here by Higashiyama-san
who also works for this company.
Yes.
Higashiyama Toshio (38)
Publication Planning Department Employee
Regarding our newest project, the
planning for a mystery puzzle book...
I have many things to consult with Mouri-san about.
It looks like the only two people who remained in the
office tonight were Higashiyama-san and Sunagawa-san.
Let's begin by visiting Takahata-san's office on the sixth floor.
Yes.
The back of the body is soaking wet.
Given that the rain already stopped, why?
The elevator is...
Undergoing maintenance?
Oh, no...
We just finished checking—you can use it.
Is something wrong?
Well, it's just...
We will probably ask you some questions afterwards,
so would you please remain on the premises?
All right.
Is Takahata-san's office all the way in the back?
Yes.
You still sweat a lot as usual.
Even the collar of your shirt is soaked in sweat.
Is that so?
There's a bandage on Sunagawa-san's finger.
There wasn't one when we arrived.
When was she injured?
Looks like it's locked.
Because Takahata-san had the keys himself...
The probability of this being a case of suicide is high.
Suicide?
That Takahata-san?
No way.
What do you mean by that?
That arrogant, overconfident man committing suicide...
It's just unthinkable.
Looks like there's no doubt he fell from here.
Inspector!
Look at this!
What is it?
*******************************
My talent has reached it's limits.
Embarrassing myself further
is not something I want.
I shall thus end my life.
Takahara Fujihiko       |
This is...
Takahata-san's suicide note?
So unbelievable.
Ah-le-le?
Hey!
What are you doing!?
That place is all wet!
What?
You're right!
Say, when did the rain stop tonight?
If I recall, it started raining around 7:30...
And it stopped about 8:00.
When we arrived at this building, it was around 8:20, right?
Hold on.
In other words, you mean more than twenty minutes
before Takahata-san fell, the window was wide open?
Takahata-san's back was also soaking wet.
Did Takahata-san open the window and stand
with his back against it long before his fall?
That's very odd.
Inspector!
We found this object stuck on Takahata-san's suit.
What is that?
Huh, I think I've seen that somewhere before...
That's...
Something we use on the Masked Yaiba show.
That's right.
It's a scale from the monster's costume.
Why was something like that there?
I just watched the Masked Yaiba show a while ago.
When Yaiba's ally, Laser Police, fired his laser gun...
The monster went "pushuu" and fell all flat.
I wonder why that was?
Hey!
What the hell are you talking about?
Hey, tell me why!
That monster was actually a balloon.
From Laser Police's laser gun, an infrared ray similar
to the one used in TV remotes comes out.
When it hits the sensor on the monster...
A mechanism causes the air to release.
That's awesome!
The air comes out of the balloon and flattens?
Hold on!
The top of the overhang isn't wet.
As I thought...
What's going on?
No, no-no-nothing!
Inspector!
This is a murder case disguised as suicide!
What did you say?
First, the culprit placed the inflated monster
balloon atop the overhang outside the window.
They then put Takahata-san to sleep using
sleeping pills or something of the sort...
And placed his body out of the window on the balloon.
The culprit left the room after their setup.
But, wasn't the door locked from the inside?
Elementary.
All they had to do was leave the window of the next room open
beforehand to ensure an escape route via the windows.
I see.
After that, once they fired the remote gun
at the monster from the adjacent room...
Takahata-san's body would slip down without hitting
the overhang and leaving suspicious marks.
The overhang beneath this window
appears to have not been rained on.
This is proof that the culprit placed the
monster balloon before it rained.
I see.
And they would've tied a rope or something
to the balloon for easy retrieval, right?
You're awesome, Uncle!
What a great deduction!
Of course it is!
The culprit left the room after setting up the trick.
But it rained before the culprit could execute it,
causing the back of the body and the floor to be wet.
So this suicide note was also faked by the culprit, right?
Can you tell me where you usually keep the balloon?
In the storage room on the first floor.
Any employee is authorized to enter.
So the culprit is an employee of this company?
Chiba!
Somewhere in this building lies the
monster balloon and the remote gun.
Search every corner of the premises and find them!
Yes, sir!
Say...
How far can the infrared ray from the remote gun reach?
It could only reach...
About five or six meters.
In that case, we can narrow down the
location of the room used by the culprit.
Let's see.
There's the meeting room next to this...
And the office rooms on the fourth and fifth floor below us...
And their adjacent meeting rooms, that's about it.
Totaling five rooms, huh?
But, since the office room keys are only for their respective owners...
Other people won't be able to just enter at will.
In other words, it means that only one of the meeting
rooms on the fourth, fifth, or sixth floor is possible.
Are the interiors of the meeting rooms the same?
Yes.
Inspector, judging by the distance, it's
possible to move from one window to another.
All right, Takagi.
Go to the security room and check out
who entered and exited the building tonight.
Yes, sir!
Now then, would you please tell me
your whereabouts for the night?
A little while before it rained, I was talking on the
phone with a client in my office on the second floor.
By the time I hung up, the rain had stopped.
When was it that you heard about our visit from Higashiyama-san?
Around 7:00.
It was before the call from my client.
I received a call from Higashiyama-san's office.
How did you know it was from Higashiyama-san's office?
The extension number showed up on
the screen, so there was no mistake.
And after that, Mouri-kun and the others came?
Yes.
At the time Mouri-san called Higashiyama-san's extension...
I was on my way to the reference room to return some materials.
Right here.
Because I was busy organizing papers in the room...
I didn't notice the commotion where Mouri-san was.
Or, by lying to us...
You went up the stairs to the fourth floor immediately,
entered the meeting room, and made Takahata-san fall.
But the stairs are right next to the elevator.
She would've been spotted by the maintenance men.
That's right.
After you finished organizing the papers, what then?
Because I cut my finger on some paper, I
returned to my office to put on a bandage.
It wasn't until then that I noticed
Mouri-san's voice outside the window.
I decided to go out and check, and there I
saw Higashiyama-san coming out of the skyway.
So this is the room where you received Mouri-kun's call, right?
Yes.
I've been working in this room the whole night.
There was no doubt Higashiyama-san was in this room.
I called his extension myself, after all.
Not to mention the phone is nailed to the wall and can't be moved.
In order to go from this room in the annex building
to Takahata-san's office in the main building...
You would need to go across the skyway on the second floor.
And in order to take the stairs from there,
you would have to walk past the elevator.
If you could go confirm with the maintenance technicians...
They should be able to testify that I didn't walk past there.
Can you reach the main building by going outside?
You'd need to enter the main entrance where the security guard is.
So no matter which way, it's impossible to avoid being seen.
Is there any way to change the extension number?
There are no functions like that on the phone.
In the office on the second floor of the
main building, there is a central switchboard.
You can only change the number from there.
I see.
Mister, do you practice archery?
Yeah.
I practiced a little, way back in school.
Higashiyama-san is so good, he even won the
championship at the Metropolitan Tournament.
Wow, that's impressive.
Oh, no, it was nothing like that.
According to the security guard's testimony...
Takahata-san returned to the company at 7:10 PM.
Afterward, the only people entering the
building were Mouri-san and the others.
The maintenance technicians
started working on the elevator at 7:00.
They witnessed Takahata-san going up the stairs.
So the technicians didn't witness
Sunagawa-san or Higashiyama-san walking by?
Correct.
They said that no one else passed by other than Takahata-san.
Inspector!
I've retrieved the monster balloon and the remote gun.
Where'd you find them?
There are garbage chute openings at the landings of each floor.
I found them stuffed inside.
It was in the one between the third and the fourth floor.
So the culprit really did use those.
And...
Here's one more thing.
This item was dropped on the overhang of
the meeting room window on the fourth floor.
A fountain pen?
According to the forensic
investigators, it wasn't dropped yesterday or today.
I think this has nothing to do with the incident, but just in case.
No, that's not it.
This fountain pen is the crucial key to solving this case!
I see, I've got it!
The culprit who killed Takahata-san was...
That person!
What is it, Mouri-kun?
Huh?
He isn't here?
What's this?
It's me, Inspector.
Mouri-kun!
Where on earth are you?
This is the extension number from Higashiyama-san's office!
Inspector...
Can you switch to speaker mode?
Understood.
Are you in my office?
I apologize for letting myself in.
But, in order to solve this case...
It was necessary.
Did you figure out the truth behind this case?
Yes, I've figured out everything.
Takahata-san returned at 7:10.
It then started to rain at about 7:30.
In other words, the culprit visited Takahata-san's
office between those times and put him to sleep...
Setting up the balloon from the Yaiba
show as their trick, and left the office room.
But before they could execute the trick, it started to rain...
Causing the body and the floor to
be rained on and their trick exposed.
Why didn't the culprit make
Takahata-san fall soon after it started to rain?
That's indeed strange.
That's because the culprit wanted to secure a solid
alibi of being at a distant place during Takahata-san's fall.
Isn't that right...
Higashiyama-san?
The culprit who killed Takahata-san...
Higashiyama-san...
It was you!
What are you saying, Mouri-san?
I received your call at my office in the annex building.
How am I supposed to have killed Takahata-san!?
Higashiyama-san...
Where do you think I'm making this call from?
By "where"...
You can't mean...
Mouri-kun!
Why are you there?
Did you really call us from that meeting room?
Yeah.
But the extension number is 423!
Extension numbers are not assigned to the phone
machines themselves, but to the phone lines.
In other words, they're assigned to the
modular cables attached to the phones.
Higashiyama-san unplugged the cable from his office phone...
And by utilizing a long extension cable, he
replugged it into the phone of this meeting room.
By doing so, the extension number from this meeting room...
Will show up as Higashiyama-san's office number, 423.
So how did he transfer the cable
from the annex to the main building?
Higashiyama-san is an expert in archery.
Tying the extension cable and his arrow with a long string...
He shot his arrow from his office in the annex
building to the hallway window in the main building.
Then, by retrieving the line in the main building...
He was able to pass the extension
cable from the annex to the main building.
Higashiyama-san...
By using this trick, you connected your office
phone cable to the phone in the meeting room...
And waited until 7:00 when the elevator
maintenance took place to call Sunagawa-san.
All for making us think you were in your office at the annex.
And at the time I called your extension number...
You took my call at the same time you executed the
monster balloon trick, causing Takahata-san to fall.
Afterward, you reconnected the phone back to its original cable.
You then hid the gun and the
retrieved balloon in the garbage chute.
In a great hurry, you returned to your office
and pulled the extension cable back in...
Met up with Sunagawa-san like nothing
had happened, and finally came to see me.
Just hold it right there!
How on earth did I return to the annex building?
That's right.
In order to go back to the annex, you need to
go past the elevator undergoing maintenance.
By jumping out the window from the
third floor, he ran past atop the skyway.
That way he wouldn't be spotted by the technicians.
That's only your conjecture!
Where's your evidence?
Evidence!
The extension cable I'm using right now was found inside your office.
I know nothing about such a thing!
Higashiyama-san...
Something about you stood out.
You sweat a lot...
So you've been wiping your sweat nonstop.
After absorbing the sweat, your aqua-
colored shirt collar turned a deep blue.
But, is that really sweat?
Someone dropped a fountain pen on the
overhang above the window of this meeting room.
When it rained, ink that leaked out of the pen
mixed in with the rainwater and dripped down.
Since you were trying to shoot at the monster
balloon, you had to lean out the window.
The ink then fell on your collar.
Higashiyama-san...
You were the one who did this.
That's right...
I was the one responsible.
To tell the truth...
The small factory my brother operated wasn't doing well...
So I introduced him to our company.
The company then placed a lot of orders to him for event props.
My brother was so happy.
But...
Takahata took advantage of my brother's
financial difficulties, and demanded illegal kickbacks.
My brother refused him due to having a strong sense of ethics.
And, soon after, my brother was denied payment of his products!
You could've just sued him for breach of contract!
Takahata anticipated this and snuck in addendums to their contract.
In the end...
My brother was deep in debt...
And committed suicide.
No way...
That's...
Why I murdered him.
Using the props he planned for the event...
And I thought everything'd go well...
I thought by making the famous
detective Mouri Kogorou my witness...
I'd have nothing to worry about.
If only...
If only it hadn't rained...
I'm upside down!
Uncle, you should be wide awake now...
Right?
What's that?
"Blood Spray Hitman"...
A story about a professional killer.
For some reason, he was hired to do a job in a spa town
As a result, the steam became saturated
with blood, giving him his namesake.
Why don't we try this hot spring inn's specialty...
The laketop outdoor spa?
I haven't taken a bath in three days!
Next Conan's Hint
Laketop Outdoor Spa
Look Forward to the Next Episode