Now, on top of me is a flood,
and below me is a big fire.
Who am I?
A hot spring!
Bingo!
Shouldn't the answer be a hot tub?
You don't heat up a hot spring.
Oh, but isn't not necessarily wrong, is it?
Most hot springs are heated up by
constantly burning magma, after all.
Well, that's true, but...
What's this about, anyway?
With you taking us to the hot springs, Professor.
I'm going there to do some repairs.
There's this inn owner who really liked this
invention of mine and bought a large quantity.
I've heard the guests love it a lot too, but...
Recently is seems to keep breaking down.
What did you make?
Is it something like a chair that simulates the effect
and feel of being in a hot spring just by sitting in it?
Awesome!
If it were something like that, we wouldn't need hot springs.
Well, just look forward to seeing it!
It's probably some worthless invention as always...
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
An open-air bath atop a lake...
And a sealed-room mystery before dawn.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hakone Hot Springs Kobou Inn
The current water temperature is 42.3°C.
The total sulfur content per kilogram of water is 25.7 milligrams.
This hot spring is a sulfur spring.
So cute!
It is effective for skin diseases, arteriosclerosis,
skin enhancement, rheumatism...
Who's that doll?
Nervous disorders, and sensitivity to cold...
He's Ishikawa Goemon.
If someone is to speak of Japanese
bathtubs, it has to be Ishikawa Goemon!
Wasn't he executed by being boiled in an iron pot?
When ingested, it may also have medicinal effects...
A... gainst...
Diabetes...
Gout...
Cons...
Ti...
It looks like Goemon is totally steamed up.
It seems the moving parts are worn and
water seeped into the inner workings.
Can you fix them overnight?
Yeah.
I've brought all the parts with me.
I'll make them sturdier this time.
Hey, now.
You still haven't finished cleaning?
Isn't it already past 1:00?
Please wait ten more minutes.
Geez...
I was planning to try each of the five spas here before filming starts!
Well, you could try them after filming as well.
Uhm...
Might you be the actress Natori Mishio-san?
Yeah, I am.
I knew it!
You played the role of the first generation
Kamen Yaiba's love interest, right?
You were very cute!
And so nice to everyone!
Natori Mishio (28)
Actress
Seems I did play such a ridiculous role once, didn't I?
But that was a long time ago.
Would you please not remind me of it?
She seems different from before.
She always used to be smiling...
Is she tsundere?
Sorry, kids.
She's just irritated right now because she's focused on her role.
Tanzawa Junsaku (34)
Mishio's Manager
Even I, as a manager, find it hard to talk to her.
By "her role", do you mean you're filming a drama or something?
She did say something about filming a while ago.
Oh, actually...
It's a movie to be released next year...
The supreme masterpiece of the Blood Spray Hitman series...
Titled Scarlet Wellspring
Tetsuyama Ganji (67)
Scriptwriter
Of course, the scriptwriter is yours truly, Tetsuyama Ganji.
I don't think you runts know of me, huh?
I know, I know of you!
So you're finally going to remake Scarlet Wellspring?
What's that?
"Blood Spray Hitman"...
A story about a professional killer.
For some reason, he was hired to do a job in a spa town.
As a result, the steam became saturated
with blood, giving him his namesake.
The series is that old man's debut work.
The story of the hitman protagonist is separated
into the Youth part from when he was young...
And the Old-Age part from when he had gotten on in years.
But Scarlet Wellspring is the only
title that belongs to the Midlife part.
If I remember the story, the main character
quit being a hitman due to a certain incident.
But for the sake of the hot spring inn hostess,
he decided to start helping her kill for free...
And set up a perfect sealed-room murder, or something like that.
And the Midlife part that is Scarlet Wellspring was
filmed just once, a long time ago in black and white.
They haven't been able to remake it
since they couldn't find a suitable actor.
Despite the fact that the Youth and Old-Age parts have
been remade many times using various actors and directors.
And as such...
Teradou Unpei (33)
Actor
Yours truly, the ideal embodiment of
the middle-aged hitman, has appeared!
Teradou-kun, you've come too!
Yeah.
I'd heard the heroine hostess had already arrived...
So I ditched my manager and flew here.
Before the film staff arrives tomorrow...
I was thinking I could get to know
the beautiful hostess a little better...
Stop doing whatever you like to my actress!
Besides, the role you're playing is that of a grief-stricken
middle-aged man, exhausted by the business of killing.
Not that of a skirt-chasing pervert with undisguised lust, right?
Yeah, I know that.
It's a completely different story from the
pompous showoff you played in the Youth part!
Oh, that's it!
I thought I'd seen your face somewhere before...
You're that actor, Tanzawa Junsaku-san!
Yeah...
You were the best hitman!
Would've been nice if you played the Midlife part too!
Hey, hey...
No...
I've taken a break from acting due to various reasons.
But you could be dragged back into acting.
Given that the cast could be completely changed
on a whim by our great scriptwriter here.
Yeah.
That's true.
I already have two or three actors in mind as your substitute.
Depending on your performance, a change could occur.
Of course, that goes for you as well, Natori-kun.
I suppose so.
Well, do take a nice bath in the spa...
Cleanse your body and reliably play the part of a hostess for me.
Since there will be wet scenes in the film.
What was that?
A "wet scene"...
Is that when you take a bath?
I see!
Because the body gets all wet.
Well, let's just leave it at that.
What's wrong with that man's leg?
He injured his tendon a number of years ago.
As a result, he's been walking like that ever
since, according to one documentary on TV.
Anyway, since we came all this way...
Why don't we try this hot spring inn's specialty...
The laketop outdoor spa?
What's that?
As the name implies, it's an open-air bath
made on top of a lake with a great view.
This place and Tottori's Hawai Hot
Spring are the only ones known to exist.
Awesome!
But, why is the women's bath larger?
They'll switch the men's and women's
baths after they finish cleaning at noon.
Later!
Yeah!
See you later!
Looks like it's really crowded.
The women's bath is crowded as well.
It can't be helped.
Let's make it the first thing we do in the morning!
In the morning the men's side will be the larger one.
Soaking in hot water while gazing at
the rising sun would be nice too, right?
Yeah!
That's right!
We're atop the lake exposed to the wind, no wonder it's so cold.
Let's go back to our room now!
So you've finally come around, huh?
At the laketop outdoor spa...
With the morning sun shining...
Wonderful, wonderful!
The man in the lead role?
If he doesn't please you, we can make a switch!
What's wrong, Mishio?
It sounded like something shattered.
Did something happen?
It's nothing!
Leave me alone!
Geez, why me?
It's the manager from yesterday.
You're up early.
It's only 4:30.
Got a problem, runt?
I'm back...
You're late, Conan!
How long can it take you to just buy some drinks?
It's because you had me go and buy them all by myself.
Not to mention asking for all kinds of things!
It's your fault for sucking at rock-paper-scissors.
That old man with the pipe from yesterday!
He's going to the spa so early!
Look over there!
He's crossing the bridge!
It doesn't open until 5:00 AM, right?
It's currently 4:43.
Isn't that cheating!?
We should go too!
We'll let the professor sleep in.
Good idea.
He was up late making repairs after all.
How come that old man's allowed in, but we aren't?
Well, that sensei is an honored guest.
So we made a special exception for him.
But, well...
It's only about ten minutes until 5:00.
That's true...
I suppose it's all right.
Hey, it's dangerous to run!
I haven't taken a bath in three days!
You need to thoroughly wash yourself before you get in the spa!
I'll wash myself!
That old man's clothes...
I don't see them here.
What's wrong, Ayumi?
What's going on in there?
You can't come in!
Why...
Is this old man in the women's bath?
An accident?
No, this was a murder.
Furthermore...
A sealed-room murder!
Did something happen?
I don't know.
I came to try the laketop outdoor spa...
But those kids wouldn't let me pass.
Like I said, we can't let anyone inside.
Conan said so!
Hey.
Is that person dead?
Yeah.
Already stopped breathing.
No way...
Haibara...
You contacted the police already, right?
Yeah.
Tetsuyama-sensei...
Why is sensei...
Sensei!
You can't touch him!
Tetsuyama-sensei!
The cause of death is acute subdural hematoma due
to blunt force trauma in addition to cerebral contusion.
The estimated time of death is about 5:00 this morning.
Traces of lather are on the bottom of the vic's feet.
The tiles beneath his feet also have lather residues.
Furthermore, seeing that the soap flew
over there across from his feet...
It seems that while getting out of the bath, he
accidentally stepped on the soap, slipped, and fell...
Thus hitting his head on the rocks around the bath.
There's no doubt that this was an accidental death.
But, isn't it strange?
This is the women's bath, right?
Again with this brat, huh...
I also thought that was strange, but...
When this old man arrived at this outdoor
spa, it was only a little past 4:30 AM.
It was still dark outside, so he likely
mistook the women's bath for the men's.
But, we also came here right after that man did...
女: Women
男: Men
And we could clearly see the characters for
men and women on the entrance curtains!
In that case, didn't you meet them too?
The two employees at the entrance to
the bridge from the main building!
Those two told me this:
Before the kids came, the person who went through the entrance...
Was solely this old man!
If you were the next to arrive after
the old man and discovered his body...
Then this was an accident no matter how you consider, no?
But just look there...
At the old man's collar bone.
There's a pool of water.
Look, his belly button too.
If he fell hard enough to die from hitting his head...
Then any water on his body should've been knocked off, right?
That's true.
Perhaps someone poured water on the old man
after he fell in order to wash something off?
What do you mean by wash off...
I see, the blood!
The unnatural blood spray that ended up on his
shoulders and back when he was initally struck...
After using the spa's rock to deliver a final
blow to his head, the culprit washed it off.
In order to make it look like an accident!
Hey, wait a minute.
When you found the body, there wasn't
anyone here expect for you kids, right?
Right.
There also weren't any loud noises
of someone jumping into the lake.
Which means this laketop outdoor spa...
Was a completely sealed room!
It's an impossible crime, isn't it?
So, unless we can solve that mystery first...
Yeah, that's right.
Brats shouldn't spout off pretending to be detectives!
Hey, call the forensics back here!
We're going to thoroughly investigate again!
Yes, sir!
Ow...
By the way, Conan-kun...
How was it?
You saw that, right?
Saw what?
You know, "that".
"That".
Ayumi screamed really loud, right?
Yeah, I saw.
So you really...
Did see that!?
Yeah, sure did.
It's quite natural when going to the bath...
To be totally naked and exposed.
Totally naked!?
Exposed!?
You little—!
Conan-kun is a dumb dumb dummy!
Both of you saw that too, right?
The old man's corpse.
What were you guys talking about?
I mean...
About that old man's body, we saw it too!
We peeked before the police got here...
How could that be possible?
You guys didn't come inside, did you?
We saw it from outside.
See, by going across this pathway around the spa...
Passing by the outside ventilation fan...
And climbing over this fence...
There!
You can see it, right?
Hey, you brats!
Just where did you...
This veranda is connected to a pathway outside!
What!?
Also, because this glass door wasn't locked...
I see.
Before 11:00 last night when the outdoor spa closed,
if the culprit hid in the dark corner of this pathway...
After killing the old man who came early in the morning,
they'd go through the pathway from this veranda...
And most likely mix in with the guests who were
denied entrance and clamoring about outside.
You got it.
So, for starters...
Why not pick out those who came to this laketop outdoor spa
alone, without telling anyone else, from the guests around here?
The culprit might be one of them.
And as such...
The ones who came to this outdoor spa by
themselves without telling anyone are...
Curiously, only you three people who just happen to
have connections to the deceased Tetsuyama Ganji-san.
Well, most of the guests were with their families.
The only ones staying in rooms by themselves
were Tetsuyama-san and you three.
No one else.
So, while you take out all of your personal belongings...
Please tell me your whereabouts and actions at
approximately 5:00 AM, the estimated time of death.
Let's begin with the one who is said to play the heroine
in the movie from the script Tetsuyama-san wrote...
Natori Mishio-san, you go first.
I don't know what you're getting at...
But all I have on me is this pouch with my make-up and a towel.
My room key is at the front desk.
Since we were told to turn it in to the front
desk before coming to the outdoor spa.
I was just waking up at about 5:00 AM.
I came here at about 5:30.
I heard that we can soak in the hot
water while watching the sunrise.
After all, I like hot springs.
And then?
Was the relationship between you and
Tetsuyama-san just that of actress and scriptwriter?
Yeah.
You're lying.
It seemed as if you were being wooed by Tetsuyama-sensei.
There are even rumors that you got the
heroine role by becoming the great sensei's lover!
I got this role because of my expertise!
Don't associate me with you, someone who got chosen
as a candidate for the starring role by sucking up to sensei!
"Candidate"?
It was decided that it'd be me!
Well?
You, the lead actor, at about 5:00.
I was sleeping about that time.
I came here for a morning bath just before 6:00.
My only belongings are a towel,
these cigarettes, and my room key.
You didn't turn your room key in at the front desk?
Too much of a hassle.
I also brought my key with me instead of turning it in.
After all, I only came to look for her
because she hadn't returned to her room yet.
That's why my belongings are my
room key, my wallet, and my cell phone.
At about 5:00, I was watching TV in my room.
TV at five?
You're an early riser.
Yeah.
In fact I woke up a little after four.
At about 4:30, I went to the front desk for change.
Was that change for buying canned coffee?
You're up early.
It's only 4:30.
Got a problem, runt?
We met in front of the vending machine around 4:30, right?
Yeah.
Which means...
The manager Tanzawa-san couldn't have hidden himself
here for the entire night to ambush and murder Tetsuyama-san.
Murder?
So this wasn't an accident?
Is that true?
Yeah...
Although we can't say anything for certain yet.
The culprit must be one of those three.
The culprit who murdered Tetsuyama-san.
In that case, the culprit has to be...
This woman right here!
That person was completely absorbed in their role and forgot that...
The conclusive evidence is still hidden in their own pocket.
The murderer is still here.
Right in front of my eyes!
Next Conan's Hint
Ring
Look Forward to the Next Episode