Professor Agasa took us to a hot spring inn in Hakone.
The filming for the newest movie in the Blood
Spray Hitman series was taking place there.
Tetsuyama Ganji (67)
Scriptwriter
We came across the scriptwriter Tetsuyama Ganji-san...
Natori Mishio (28)
Actress
The actress playing the heroine, Natori Mishio-san...
Tanzawa Junsaku (34)
Mishio's Manager
Her manager, Tanzawa Junsaku-san...
And the lead actor, Teradou Unpei-san.
Teradou Unpei (33)
Actor
At dawn the next day, we went to the laketop outdoor spa...
Only to discover the murderer Tetsuyama-san in the women's bath.
Judging from the circumstances, the culprit likely waited
outside the bathhouse all night to ambush Tetsuyama-san...
And after the crime, blended into the crowd.
The only guests who walked around alone the night before were...
Mishio-san, Tanzawa-san, and Teradou-san—those three people.
The culprit is likely...
To be among those three.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
One actor got caught in a pitfall.
The mysteries of the bathroom is finally revealed!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
In that case, the culprit has to be...
This woman right here!
Last night, I overheard Tetsuyama-sensei
talking on his phone in the lobby.
Saying things like you had finally come around...
At the laketop outdoor spa with the morning sun shining...
And that if the lead actor didn't please you, he could make a switch!
Surely she must've used her feminine wiles
to lure Tetsuyama-sensei here and...
I see.
That would make sense with him being dead in the women's bath.
How about it?
Were you the other party on the phone?
Yeah, it was me.
I told him that, if he came to the women's
bath first thing in the morning...
I'd take a dip with him before the other guests arrive.
But that was just a lie.
I only wanted to teach that perverted sensei a lesson
by making him wait in vain and embarrass himself.
Given that I wasn't the only actress who
was sick to death of his sexual harassment!
In other words, it seems you both
had motives to kill Tetsuyama-san.
Hey, hold it!
This guy here has a motive, too!
Five years ago, Tetsuyama-sensei suddenly
took his lead role in the movie away from him...
And he hasn't acted ever since then!
Is that true?
Yeah.
I did resent him a bit at the time...
But now I'm thankful.
It's thanks to him that I was able to experience
various things besides being an actor.
Me too.
I didn't hate him enough to kill him!
Me neither!
Inspector Yokomizo.
This was found behind a basket in the changing room.
A Japanese green tea plastic bottle?
But what's inside doesn't look like green tea.
Yes.
It looks like normal water.
Also, we found match cinders floating on
the surface of the lake near the crime scene.
Match cinders?
Why?
Uhm...
Why not have those three people meet with the employees
who were at the entrance to the bridge in the main building?
That's right.
If the culprit hid here all night, they wouldn't
have passed through the entrance yet today, no?
Because this floor is dimly lit and rather
dark until about 6:00 in the morning...
And police officers and all sorts of
people have passed through today...
We couldn't identify anyone specific.
Although we do remember Tetsuyama-sensei
coming first, and then the children came after him.
You said Tetsuyama-sensei was specifically allowed to
enter the outdoor spas before everyone else, but...
Had it always been that way?
Yeah, because sensei enjoys taking the very first bath.
So when sensei stays here, we always turn the lights
in the bath on at 4:30 AM to let him through early.
Inspector.
It appears that one of the victim's rings has gone missing.
Ring?
Yes, only an empty case was left in his room...
And the case says it's the Nichiuri TV's Newcomer Scenario Award.
You mean that ring with the soybean-sized jewel.
Right, right, the silver one.
Before giving lectures or party speeches...
He used to wear it, claiming it was
his good-luck charm for the occasion.
You can't find it anywhere?
Right.
Presumably it was thrown into the lake along with the weapon.
So you didn't find anything in these three people's room?
No, we found something in each of them.
In the ashtray of Teradou-san's room, we
found a large number of match cinders.
Matches, you say?
What's wrong with that?
I merely used the matches to light my cigarettes!
There was a glove in a bag in Tanzawa-san's room,
but for some reason there was only the left one.
It's a golf glove.
There are many people who wear it solely
on their left hand to prevent slipping.
I'm right-handed after all.
Also, in the trashcan in Natori-san's
room, there was a broken wine glass...
And on top of the desk was a script
with some of the pages crumbled.
It was for the role.
When I was reading the script last night, I got to a scene where
my character ripped out paper and threw a glass at someone.
That's why I did it without realizing.
Putting myself in character and acting
out my role is how I do business.
Put oneself in character and act it out?
I see, so that's how it was.
That person was completely absorbed in their role and forgot that...
The conclusive evidence is still hidden in their own pocket.
Inspector Yokomizo.
I've spoken with the inn employees at the front desk.
And?
They said that, at around 5:30 this morning, Natori-san
turned her room key in, which remains at the front desk.
Also, at about 2:00, Teradou-san called the employees
to his room, stating that his air conditioner was broken.
Well, turned out to be user error.
Then, what about Tanzawa-san getting
change at the front desk at about 4:30?
That was also confirmed.
They said he exchanged a 1000-yen bill for 100-yen coins.
Before we police came, was there really not even a single
person who went back to the main building from that bridge?
Right...
In that case, these three people would've
been in the main building until dawn.
And about "the culprit hiding themselves at
the laketop outdoor spa the entire night"...
That speculation from this brat was completely off the mark.
That's because...
Professor!
You're awake.
In that case, surely the culprit infiltrated
the outdoor spa from the lake...
And after murdering Tetsuyama,
they returned to the lake and fled.
All right!
Start gathering intel from the lake's perimeter-
There's no need for that, is there?
Because the murderer is still here...
Right in front of my eyes!
Hey now...
I don't know anything about this murder.
Don't worry, just pretend to talk along with my voice.
What's this?
Butting in all of a sudden!
No, I'm just...
Just saying that, despite there being surviving traces of
someone having hidden at the outdoor spa overnight...
Are you guys blind enough not to see them?
Traces, you say.
The plastic tea bottle in the changing room
which curiously contained water inside...
And the match cinders that were
floating on the lake are such traces.
To wait outside the bathhouse overnight as the wind rampages
across the lake is too cold to bear in a season like this.
Having said that, even if someone were
to enter the bathhouse from the veranda...
They wouldn't be able to bear the cold night in the
changing room where the lights and heat were both off.
There's only one way to stay warm.
Are you saying someone soaked in the hot spring?
Yes, that's right.
Judging from the fact they drank up not only the green tea
but also the water from the changing room sink as refills...
They must've taken multiple dips overnight.
Because one gets thirsty just from being in the bath.
Then, the match cinders floating in the lake...
Someone has been smoking in order to stay awake.
They must've done so at the veranda in
order to not make the spa smell like smoke.
In that case, you with the cigarettes are the most suspicious one!
Hey how, I didn't...
I only said that they were smoking...
Not that they were smoking cigarettes.
If it wasn't cigarettes, then...
Pipe...
Hold on!
If you mean they were smoking a pipe while waiting...
Yeah, that's right.
The one hiding at the laketop outdoor spa all night was...
The victim of the murder, Tetsuyama-san himself!
Then, what about the "Tetsuyama-san" who
passed through this entrance at 4:30 this morning?
That was the culprit.
They were impersonating Tetsuyama-san.
In other words, by reversing the common
sense that there'd be no reason for the victim...
To hide at the would-be crime scene for a
long period of time waiting for the culprit...
They set up a mind trick to throw us off!
Hey, is that right?
Didn't you guys let Tetsuyama-san pass
through this entrance to the outdoor spa?
Well...
I really think it was him.
The unique way he walked...
And the stern expression he had as if coercing us were
manners that could only belong to Tetsuyama-sensei.
However, this floor was dimly lit at that time.
Not to mention that person...
Was wearing a knit cap and glasses, and had
a towel wrapped around like a scarf, right?
I see.
People who knew Tetsuyama-san very well...
Such as this actor...
And that former actor...
Could have acted out the part of Tetsuyama-san, isn't that right?
Hold it!
If that's the case, this actress here is also suspicious!
If she put on many layers of clothing,
she could imitate his physique.
And by imitating a stern expression,
she wouldn't have to say anything!
She also said if he came to the women's bath first thing in the
morning, she'd bathe with him before the other guests arrived.
If her instruction was actually "to hide in
the women's bath all night," then it all fits!
That would certainly be the case.
But only if the other party on the phone
with Tetsuyama-san was really her.
"Really her"?
Are you saying she's lying?
If she hadn't said that, she would've
been unable to protect the culprit.
Because the one who saw Tetsuyama-san
talking on the phone was Teradou-san.
If Natori-san completely denied being
the other party on the phone...
Then the suspicion would fall on the remaining person.
Natori-san's manager, Tanzawa-san...
None other than you!
What are you saying?
I wasn't lying!
Perhaps Tanzawa-san told this to Tetsuyama-san over the phone:
"Natori-san will go to the laketop
outdoor spa first thing in the morning."
"If you want to see the bathing scene
of her, hide there and wait overnight."
As her manager who knows her
schedule, he could use such a strategy.
And judging from Tetsuyama-san saying,
"You've finally come around" over the phone...
He was probably nagged by Tetsuyama-san many times about this.
Of course Tetsuyama-san could've come and
hidden in the women's bath first thing in the morning.
But he was told that, if Natori-san knew Tetsuyama-san
had gone to the spa, she'd likely be on her guard.
That's how Tanzawa-san convinced Tetsuyama-san
to hide at the veranda of the women's bath...
And walked towards the bathhouse as
Tetsuyama-san himself before 5:00 AM.
Afterward, he put away his disguise in the changing room...
Fast-talked Tetsuyama-san into coming inside the spa room...
And bludgeoned him to death.
After that, you had planned to reenter
the bathhouse amid the confusion, no?
In case some of your hair had been left at the bath.
However...
The children arrived earlier than you planned.
They not only found the body and made a commotion...
But also blocked the bathhouse entrance.
You had wanted to cover up any traces of your being at
the crime scene, but you couldn't secure an opportunity.
That's why Tanzawa-san was forced to...
Hold it, you're talking as if you saw it as it happened...
But do you have proof?
Yeah, the proof is...
What are you being so sneaky about, Conan-kun?
Isn't that the bowtie that can change your voice?
Are you talking with the professor's voice?
Can't you speak with your own?
That's not it.
The professor doesn't know about the
case, so he's whispering advice to him.
I see!
Nice save, Haibara.
Don't sweat it.
I won't let them peek at things they shouldn't, like you do.
Peek?
If that's what you mean, don't worry about it.
I didn't see anything besides your butt!
Butt?
What about a butt?
Oh, nothing...
Shoot!
I accidentally said that in the professor's voice...
But, he shouldn't have known that.
Something that only the culprit should know,
but Tanzawa-san knew it nonetheless!
That's why Tanzawa-san took the first step to enter the spa room.
And that's my proof!
But if the children were blocking the entrance, wouldn't
it be natural to want to know what was happening inside?
However, the crime scene was in the women's bath.
Normally you'd let a female go in
first to check on the situation, right?
You're right.
But Tanzawa-san knew...
That inside the spa room were only
Tetsuyama-san's body and the children.
So even if he should inevitably see the children naked...
It wouldn't be a problem at all!
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
Looks like some kind of sinister aura is coming out...
You're scary, really!
Is that your proof?
Don't make me laugh.
As for concrete proof, don't you know about it too?
The thing Tanzawa-san still has on him.
It's the ring that you said on the spur of the moment
"had a soybean-sized jewel" in order to protect him.
To protect him?
Yeah.
For a ring with such a large jewel, it would
be easily detected even if it were on a finger.
You wouldn't think that the blackened
ring on Tanzawa-san's left middle finger...
Could possibly be that ring!
What now?
So this is...
Inspector, when you told him to show his belongings...
He realized that in his back left pants pocket
was the ring he had forgotten to throw away.
So he put it on his middle finger
while fumbling around in his pocket.
With the jewel hidden out of view in his palm.
But why go through the trouble for the ring?
Because when the silver on it was sulfurized, it turned black.
This hot spring is a sulfur spring.
Reacting to the hydrogen sulfide and sulfur dioxide...
The surface turned into black-colored silver sulfide.
Upon seeing the blackened silver ring,
he thought that it had to be taken off.
He wanted it to look as if he had just arrived at the baths...
So it wouldn't do if people suspected
that he'd been in the spa for a long time.
Well, though if this were a highly concentrated
sulfur spring, it would've turned black instantly.
Regardless, what an idiot.
Forgetting to throw it away...
He couldn't help it.
Because he was totally acting as Tetsuyama-sensei.
Tetsuyama-sensei always held his pipe in
his left hand, so he was probably left-handed.
That's why you accidentally put it in your
back left pocket, which you normally wouldn't use.
bathrobe     outer robe
Until you threw away the yukata, tanzen,
and weapon stained with blood in the lake...
You thought you'd put it there for a while.
You also pushed the vending machine button with your left hand...
And you referred to me as a "runt".
Which means you were already mimicking
Tetsuyama-sensei by then, right?
Yeah.
It was a hassle.
To act like such a narrow-minded man...
Was something I'd never done before.
Hey, don't tell me...
You still hold a grudge against Tetsuyama-sensei
for dropping you as the lead role five years ago...
Yeah, to put it simply, that was my motive.
The role I was denied was the middle-aged hitman from
Scarlet Wellspring, the one currently being remade.
Since I had gotten rave reviews for the Youth part...
I thought that surely I was to continue that role.
Wasn't it because he thought you were
too young at the time to play the role?
Yeah, I thought so as well.
Even sensei told me that I was too young...
That I didn't produce the melancholy vibe...
And that I needed to experience various things.
That's why I stopped acting and even became her manager.
I experienced the hard work of the underling
that I didn't have the chance to as an actor...
"Oh, this is what sensei had wanted to teach me," I had thought.
So this time, when I learned that
Scarlet Wellspring was being remade...
I called sensei to beg him for the lead role, but...
Sensei was so drunk, he didn't even
know that I was the one on the phone.
Tanzawa Junsaku in the lead role as the hitman?
It can't be him, he's too good.
Like he was in the Youth part...
If he were praised as having superb skills that
surpasses the original work again, it'd be annoying.
No matter how I pleaded, I was never
allowed to play the middle-aged hitman.
Unfortunately, not until sensei departed from this world.
Because the inspiration for my dream as an actor was the
black-and-white Scarlet Wellspring I watched as a child...
I wanted the role even if it killed me.
But, when I think of it now, I suppose I wasn't cut out for the role.
If I had truly been able to act as a
hitman immediately after killing sensei...
Then I wouldn't have made such a mistake.
Mishio.
Play the role of the hostess with all your soul.
It's an important role that will open up the breadth of your roles.
I can't.
You were the one who taught me that during the entire
filming, I need to assume the role even in my private life.
The one who ordered the hit was the hostess herself.
In order to conceal this fact, without batting an eyebrow...
She would go as far as to kill the hitman in cold blood...
This is a role...
I could never play with my soul.
All right, everyone!
Don't forget your belongings!
Yes!
We should go buy one more souvenir!
Hey, Professor...
Come here a sec.
Ever since I changed clothes after leaving the hot
spring, for some reason my butt's been hurting.
Can you check on it?
Sure.
Speaking of the hot spring, Ai-kun went
to the men's bath a little while ago.
Why?
Not sure.
She said she was looking for something...
It's a little red and swollen.
Are you serious?
That's chili pepper.
If you wash it off with water, it'll start healing soon.
Inside your underpants is chili pepper powder!
Well, there's nothing to be worried about.
A child's naked body...
Even if you see it, there's no problem, is there?
That little...
Someone, catch him!
Stop right there!
Move it!
This is bad!
This guy is Kanemura.
He's a member of that fraud group, right?
The crime scene was between this
Natsuhabara Station and Beika Station.
It's near Sugame Station.
I understand how you feel.
But you're wrong.
Next Conan's Hint
Automatic Ticket Gate
Look Forward to the Next Episode