Line Natsuhabara Station
Hey, geezer!
Hurry your ass up!
That was interesting, wasn't it?
Get a move on already!
Sorry about that.
What a rude man.
A pickpocket!
Someone, catch him!
The guy from earlier...
So he's a pickpocket?
Stop right there!
Move it!
Careful, boy!
This is bad!
Mister...
We'll take a report there.
And you too...
Hold on a moment!
Huh?
This...
After a while, we were released from police questioning.
We reboarded the Touto Loop Line, but...
Huh, what's going on there?
Three stations ahead is Sugame Station, and
an incident has already occurred nearby.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
The identity of the Friend of Justice
is actually a picture-story showman?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
This guy is Kanemura, a wanted criminal.
He's a member of that fraud group, right?
Yes.
By gaining the trust and favor of the elderly living alone.
He introduced them to fictitious investment
schemes and cheated them out of their money.
Many victims have committed suicide of filed bankruptcy.
Cause of death?
A blow to his forehead.
That's the only wound on him.
I think the culprit was pretty impressive.
Because there's no sign of a struggle.
And to beat down such strong-looking man in one blow...
Why are you here?
We saw this from the train.
Hey, Conan-kun, let's not bother them.
Let's go...
You are...
Norizuki Tokuma (75)
You guys are from earlier!
Are you acquaintances?
Yeah, kind of...
But why are you here, mister?
He's our witness for this case.
After I parted ways with you earlier, I saw that
man hitting someone with a club from the train.
That's why I deboarded at Beika Station and went to the police.
So he's the leader of the fraud group, Kiriya Teruhiko?
Was there a falling out?
Kiriya Teruhiko (35)
I have nothing to do with it!
I was only taking a walk around here!
He witnessed the scene from the train?
But...
Say, mister, where's your cane?
Since I can still move about without it, I left it somewhere.
Though it's convenient to have with me, since
people think of me as elderly and are extra nice!
A single blow to the forehead killed the victim.
And this old man said he witnessed the scene from the train...
Could it be...
How many times do I have to repeat myself!?
I didn't do it!
Then why were you around the scene?
Someone called me.
He claimed to be Kanemura's friend.
Saying Kanemura's waiting for me and to come now.
A friend of the victim?
Who was it?
I dunno.
I'd never heard his voice before.
I can't very well believe that story of yours.
It's true!
I...
I've been framed!
KIRIYA TERUHIKO (35)
SUSPECT
******************
KILLING BETWEEN COMRADES?
A picture-story showman?
That old man is?
Yeah.
I was investigating another case when I heard it from the police.
Looks like he often performs for the
kids at places like Sasanqua Park.
I see.
Well, this case is almost as good as solved.
No need for a great detective to intervene.
If only everything would go smoothly...
It's true that I met with Mouri-san here yesterday, but...
I didn't know he was interested in this case.
At any rate, he wanted you to look into
what I just said as soon as possible.
Got it.
Now to get down to business.
"The Earth is now mine!"
"I won't let you have it, Dark Lord!"
"That voice can't be..."
"Friend of Justice, on stage!"
"Dark Lord, time to face the punishment of justice!"
Ran?
"Damn you, have a taste of this!"
Having said that, the Lord's cane starts to release a black light!
Look out, Friend of Justice!
Move it, move it!
I wanna see it too!
Move it!
HEY!
What are you doing?
Anyone who comes late is at the back of the line!
HEY!
Apologize before you cry!
No matter if you're a child or an adult, you
need to follow the correct path of a man!
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
Good, you're a good kid.
Everyone, can we let this boy watch too?
Yes!
Then, please let him sit in the middle.
Thank you...
Bye bye!
See you guys later, and take care!
"No matter if you're a child or an adult..."
You need to scold whoever deserves a scolding...
But the kindness to forgive them is also important, right?
You're that miss!
You helped me during that dangerous moment,
but I forgot to say my thanks yesterday.
Thank you very much!
And I forgot to give this back to you.
Thank you!
Is Mitsu-san perhaps your wife?
I wish she were, but...
She passed away because of illness a while ago.
I'm sorry!
I didn't know about that...
No, not at all.
So you came here just for this?
No...
I wanted to ask you why you walked away without
telling your name when the pickpocket was caught.
It wasn't necessary to make myself
known with a simple act like that.
That's what I thought.
But you made yourself known as the witness
of the subsequent crime, didn't you?
Why?
Conan-kun!
Because it was a murder case.
I couldn't just pretend I didn't see that, now could I, boy?
Then why didn't you call the police right away?
Sugame
Kozuka
Sawabukuro
East Sawabukuro
Why wait until Beika Station?
Beika
I don't have a cell phone, and the conductor wasn't nearby either.
So you didn't try to get off midway?
I hadn't thought about that.
Are you done, boy?
If so, I'll be on my way.
Thanks again, young miss!
Conan-kun!
Glad you're here.
I've found out about the matter Mouri-san requested.
About the victim of the fraud group...
It seems some of them were acquaintances with that elder, Norizuki.
In addition, he is a 5-dan in Kendo.
Hold it right there!
Is Dad suspecting that old man?
Oh, no...
I don't know about that.
But wasn't the culprit already caught?
But he still denies it...
I'll talk to Dad!
Ran-neechan!
No good, I need to quickly find the truth!
Hey, there's actually one more thing
Uncle wanted you to investigate.
Again?
The crime scene was between this
Natsuhabara Station and Beika Station.
Natsuhabara
Sugame
Beika
It's near Sugame Station.
A security camera...
I should have Detective Takagi check that, too.
This is...
***************************************
Notice
We are currently undergoing renovations
and apologize for the inconvenience
Sugame Station
Not there yet.
I see...
So that's how it was.
Geez, wake up, Dad!
Didn't you say the case was as good as solved?
Why are you doubting that old man now?
I never doubted!
Then why...
I never doubted...
This beer would be tasty!
Geez!
That was punishment from God.
Witness: A-san
That man made many elders cry in despair.
Must've simply been a punishment from a friend of justice.
Mister...
That's all.
We now take you back to the studio.
Don't tell me...
He really...
Conan-kun?
No, it's going to take a little longer for that matter.
But good timing.
We've just discovered a new fact,
so could you relay it to Mouri-san?
A new fact?
Excuse me!
Mister, are you home?
Mister?
A diary...
There's one more guy in the fraud group?
Yeah.
Name's Motegi Takashi, 25 years old.
He cheated a woman, who was an acquaintance of
that elder Norizuki, out of a huge sum of money.
We're trying to locate his residence,
but we couldn't get hold of it.
Detective Takagi.
Please tell me the old man's address.
Ran?
Motegi Takashi (25)
Stop it!
That's enough!
Mister!
Miss...
I couldn't believe it, so I had wanted to hear from you directly.
So when I went to your home...
I apologize for reading this.
This is Mitsu-san's diary, right?
**************
And then I found your entry...
What's this all about?
Motegi Takashi, right?
We're with the police.
You're under our protection.
Police!?
Protection?
That old man over there intends to take your life.
Dad...
What now!?
Isn't that right, Inspector?
But I heard your order from Takagi,
that's why I issued the protection.
But I never ordered Takagi to do anything...
Norizuki-san...
You can never deceive the eyes of
the great detective Mouri Kogorou.
Yesterday, it was you who killed Kanemura, wasn't it?
Mouri Kogorou?
What are you saying?
I was a witness to that incident, you know.
That's exactly what I felt suspicious about in the first place.
You said that you witnessed the crime from the train, but...
With the railway bridge being a straight line, there's no
way you could have seen the crime scene underneath.
That's true...
Takagi.
Yes.
This thing, right?
I've borrowed this IC pass from him and had the record
checked out at the Data Center of the Touto Loop Line.
I had no reason to refuse, after all.
And what did you find out?
Before and after the time of the crime yesterday...
He entered the fare gate at Natsuhabara Station at 13:35...
And exited at Beika Station at 14:15, according to the records.
As I thought.
Because that's the truth.
No, that's rather strange.
The entering time is all right.
But the exiting time is off.
Because of the pickpocket incident, Conan
and Ran got off at Hatabata Station.
But you didn't get off.
Takagi.
What's the train's arrival time at Beika Station?
It's 14:00.
That's strange...
It's 15 minutes earlier than what the record showed.
Which means...
Right.
He got off midway at Sugame Station and committed the crime.
He then got on the next train.
Is that why there's a 15-minute loss?
That's a very interesting speculation, but...
If that were true, it would've shown up in the record as well.
Yeah...
There wasn't a record of his getting off and on at Sugame Station.
Then, why the fifteen-minute discrepancy?
I'm embarrassed to say this, but being an
elder means frequent restroom trips.
I rushed to the restroom once I arrived at Beika Station.
That's why I didn't exit the fare gate sooner.
That's the truth.
The truth was being filmed by the station camera.
You mean the security camera?
What now?
Sugame Station is undergoing renovation,
so there shouldn't be a working camera.
So you really knew.
Wasn't that exactly why you chose to commit the crime there?
One more thing.
Because many elders utilize that station, you wouldn't stand out.
In other words, you called the victim under the railway
bridge near Sugame Station beforehand...
And got off the train without being taped by the camera.
You then assulted Kanemura, and boarded the train again...
In addition to calling Kiriya to the crime
scene and making him lose his alibi.
Then how was I supposed to get off and on
Sugame Station without leaving a record?
I had Detective Takagi check out the footage
of the Natsuhabara Station security camera.
Natsuhabara Station camera?
And the suspicious actions of Norizuki-san was caught on tape.
At that time, you entered the fare gate with your IC pass...
But you backed out once and reentered.
Why did you reenter?
That's because I didn't think my IC pass went through correctly.
An elder like me is bad with machines...
Isn't that exactly what you would like us to think?
What do you mean?
At that time, you prepared not only your
IC pass but also a pre-purchased ticket.
Ticket?
You first scanned your IC pass across the machine at the fare gate.
Then you pretended to redo it, but took out your ticket...
And inserted it which was hidden in view under your IC pass.
After being pushed by that pickpocket
guy, you held onto the machine...
And retrieved the punched ticket.
Then you boarded the train, got off at
Sugame Station, and committed the crime.
You then purchased another ticket and boarded again.
When you arrived at Beika Station, you used the same
IC pass you used at Natsuhabara Station to exit.
The ticket you bought at Natsuhabara Station had been
collected at the Sugame Station where you got off midway.
Your fingerprint should still be there.
Impressive, Mr. Detective.
But I have done nothing wrong!
It's what you'd call karma...
A punishment from justice!
That's a lie!
Ran?
You scold those who deserve a scolding, but you
also possessed the kindness to forgive people.
So why did you...
It merely means that there are deeds one can never forgive.
Did you do it because Mitsu-san
died of shock from being swindled?
That's right.
That's exactly it.
It wasn't until I read Mitsu-san's
diary that I knew about the fraud.
I couldn't forgive them.
That's why, that's why I wanted to deliver
the punishment of justice unto them.
I understand how you feel.
But you're wrong.
If you had read Mitsu-san's last words...
You would've realized it.
Last words?
This...
Mr. Friend of Justice taught me about forgiving people.
That's why I decided to forgive the man who deceived me.
To this old lady who lives alone, he had been really nice to me.
His smile at that time...
I still don't think that everything he did was part of the lie.
I shall believe that he will change his ways someday.
It's unbearable to die hating someone.
Mr. Friend of Justice, thank you.
I didn't know this!
After I learned about Motegi and his gang, I was enraged...
And I couldn't see anything else except resentment.
Some Friend of Justice I am...
I allowed myself to be blinded by hatred...
And I didn't know about Mitsu-san's true feeling!
She... forgave someone like me...
She trusted me!
Just like Ran said...
There are things one cannot do no matter the circumstances.
Not as a friend of justice...
Rather, as a human.
Motegi confessed to everything...
And Kiriya was re-arrested on account
of malicious fraudulent intent.
Please step back and touch the scanner again.
What's wrong, Dad?
Must be a malfunction.
That's why I say IC is unreliable.
Say...
Isn't that the card from the rental video store?
You're right.
Uncle, aren't you the most unreliable?
Tatezato Mika.
So...
This woman is a murderer on the run,
and she wants to meet with Dad?
What...
What's that sound?
Then this incident was indeed...
The work of the kappa, wasn't it!?
Next Conan's Hint
Shoe
Look Forward to the Next Episode