Dear Mouri Kogorou-sama...
Seeing you as a great detective, I have a request for you.
A crime of murder was placed upon me eleven years ago.
Please clear my name at all costs with your great deductions.
I'll give you the details at dawn on December 19th...
In the Gunma prefecture, at Kuchibashi Village's
Koura Inn, which is near the crime scene.
Tatezato Mika.
So...
This woman is a murderer on the run,
and she wants to meet with Dad?
Yeah, that's probably the case.
"Probably the case"?
Are you sure it's all right to meet her?
That's right.
You should contact the police first...
I thought so too, and had Yamamura
from the Gunma police investigate it.
But it seems there weren't any murder
cases near that inn eleven years ago.
And that there isn't a fugitive named Tatezato Mika.
Yamamura said it's probably a bad prank.
Then why did we come?
Did I have a choice?
Since we had already eaten the retainer
fee that was sent along with the letter.
"Already eaten"?
Don't tell me the Chinese cuisine we had yesterday...
Come to think of it...
This old guy ended up ordering a lot of
expensive-looking dishes and alcohol.
Well, we're only going to determine whether or not it's a prank.
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Today marks our 600th episode!
The green legend and the kappa's curse!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Idiot!
That was dangerous!
Sorry!
But are you going to Koura Inn by any chance?
Yeah, we are...
In that case, could you give me a ride?
I'm also staying there today.
Fine, I don't mind.
Thank you very much.
Whew, you saved me!
I thought I'd walk there from the station...
But I started breathing hard midway.
You wouldn't happen to be Tatezato-san, would you?
No...
Tokubi Rokurou (42)
Painter
My name is Tokubi Rokurou.
But I think it's quite a long way from the station.
I taught at an elementary school near here a long time ago.
I liked to walk around and take in the scenery of this area, but...
It turns out I'm not as fit as I used to be.
Well, that school was shut down later...
So I quit being a teacher and became a starving painter.
Oh, that's right.
Even though you're already allowing me to ride with you, would
you mind stopping somewhere so I can visit a gravesite?
A gravesite?
So one of the kids got swept away by the river and drowned?
Yeah.
The one who died was a child named Numayama Tatsuhiko.
It seems he was swept away to a reservoir downstream.
Was that...
The murder case that happened eleven years ago?
It wasn't a murder, but an accident.
Even though it was raining hard, it seems he was
still playing in the river and got swept away.
But that was about ten years ago, I believe.
Tokubi-sensei!
Huh?
If it isn't Araiwa-kun!
So you also came to visit the grave?
Yeah, I did.
Araiwa Kazuki (21)
Tatsuhiko's Classmate
Today was the day of Tatsuhiko's death.
But for a grave, this is pretty ill prepared.
No, the real grave is somewhere else.
This is what our classmates made when Tatsuhiko died.
Instead of his remains, we buried things
that reminded us of Tatsuhiko.
Of course, I also visited his real grave.
But, why here?
It was this river flowing behind me that
swept him away and killed him.
Exactly eleven years ago today.
Eleven years ago?
So the murder case mentioned in that letter was indeed...
Letter?
How did you know he was swept away by this river?
Wasn't the child found in a reservoir downstream?
Because his shoe was found.
Tatsuhiko's shoe was caught between
the rocks at the bottom of the river.
That's why Tatsuhiko likely got his foot caught between the rocks
while playing in the river, and couldn't manage to escape.
The rain started falling harder and harder, and the flood
eventually swept him away, according to the police.
But to think he'd play in the river in December...
Which part of the river was it again?
Where his shoe was found...
It was over where the rocks are sticking out.
I think it was right here...
Is that shoe still out there somewhere?
Yeah, it was buried in that grave...
You could probably see it if you dug it up...
Hey!
No way!
Don't worry.
It's shallow.
My art supplies seem to have survived somehow...
But this sketchbook isn't usable anymore.
This incense is ruined as well.
My things were inside this vinyl bag, so they're pretty much dry.
The caps of these plastic bottles were tightly closed...
And my pillow and change of clothes are safe.
HEY!
What are you guys doing!?
Haven't I seen your faces somewhere before?
I'm Tatsuhiko-kun's friend, and I came to pray at his grave...
Pray at his grave?
What kind of grave is this!
Numayama Banzou (51)
Tatsuhiko's Father
Listen up.
My son died eleven years ago!
Just forget about it already!
Son?
So he was the deceased Tatsuhiko-kun's father?
Yeah.
He's also the owner of the inn we're all going to.
But why was the owner of the inn at a place like that?
My guess is he was keeping watch.
Keeping watch?
That inn is on high ground.
It seems that if you use binoculars from the window
in the attic, you would have an extensive view.
Not here?
There's really no one named Tatezato Mika staying here?
But she promised to meet me here early tomorrow morning...
Well, I don't see her name...
Then, have you ever heard about a murder
case happening eleven years ago?
Don't know...
"Don't know"?
It did happen.
Nohira Bousuke (45)
Guest
Furthermore...
river imp
They said the culprit was a kappa!
Kappa!?
Yeah...
There are a plethora of anecdotes about
the kappa's existence around here.
Twelve or thirteen years ago, people even
said they had really seen the kappa...
TV crews and magazine reporters even came for the scoop.
Immediately afterward, a kid drowned in the river...
People began clamoring about it being the work of the kappa.
But after that, witness reports of the kappa plummeted...
Now almost no one comes here at all.
Hold on.
The name from this letter, "Tatezato Mika"...
If you split up the characters tate,
sato, mi, ka, and rearrange them...
Wouldn't they form the characters for kappa!?
That must be it!
The kappa wanted to have its name cleared...
So it called Dad, who's a detective, to come here!
Everyone here is dancing around that stupid superstition!
If you tell any more of those made-up ghost stories...
I'll have you leave this inn!
Are you really sure?
You dropped your cell phone next to that river?
When we were at the river, I got a message from Sonoko...
And when I was typing a reply, those two fell into the river.
So it probably was at that time...
Can't we do this tomorrow?
I thought about that too, but Conan-kun said...
If the battery dies, we won't hear the phone ring
when we call and probably won't find it!
I'm almost certain it was around here.
Let's split up and search.
Hey, are you calling it?
Yeah.
There it is!
What...
What's that sound?
Hey, what's wrong!?
Kappa!
What?
Kappa?
There's nothing like that here!
It was just there!
Standing in the middle of the river and looking this way...!
So you found your cell phone?
Damn, it's starting to rain.
Let's head back.
You're right.
You saw the kappa?
Yeah...
My daughter was saying that it was at the river last night.
Well, I bet she must've mistaken a tree branch for it or something.
I'm telling you it was really there!
Perhaps it was really a ghost...
Ghost?
Let's stop this talk about the kappa here.
Otherwise that man's gonna start yelling again.
Speak of the devil.
This is terrible!
The owner is...
His body was lying on the floor of that gloomy attic...
As if possessed by the kappa, and
dragged to the bottom of the pond.
Covered in a rancid liquid that stung our noses...
And clutching his deceased son's belongings to his chest.
What?
He drowned?
Yeah, that's what the coroner said.
Furthermore, judging from the composition of water
on the victim and the water found inside his body...
He may have been drowned at some polluted
pond first and then transported here.
Come to think of it, there was that terrible smell.
Yeah.
But it looks like the culprit brought that smelly water here.
Look, this water bucket...
It has the same smell.
I see.
The culprit brought that smelly water here in the bucket...
And after they submerged Banzou-san's
face into it and drowned him...
They splashed the water all over his body, so it seems.
But, why was Banzou-san in a place like this?
It seems it was his daily routine.
Every morning after waking up, he'd come here
and keep watch over the river from the window.
That's what the people in the inn told me.
Using those binoculars.
And why was that?
It's probably because his son Tatsuhiko died
after being swept away by the river.
So, to make sure no one else met the same fate as Tatsuhiko...
He kept watch from here.
Let's see...
Oho, I can certainly see everything!
But...
If it were for his son's sake...
He wouldn't kick over the grave that his son's friends made for him.
It seems it wasn't his first or second time doing that.
There's probably something there.
Near that river, that is.
It seems that, after everyone would fall asleep,
he'd occasionally prowl around that area.
But the only thing there is the grave his friends made.
Speaking of which...
The shoe next to the body belonged to Tatsuhiko-kun, right?
But didn't you say it was buried at his grave?
Yeah.
Then I wonder if the culprit dug it up?
No, the one that was buried was his right
shoe that was caught in the rocks.
But this seems to be his left shoe.
Then...
Isn't this the shoe Tatsuhiko-kun was wearing when he was
found in the reservoir after he got swept away by the river?
So you mean one of his shoes fell off,
and the other stayed on his foot?
No, it seems he was only wearing
his swim shorts when he was found.
Only swim shorts?
In such a cold season?
That's why he was likely trying out cold-weather swimming.
That's it, it's the reservoir!
The smelly water that was all over Banzou-san's body...
It was the smell of the reservoir Tatsuhiko-kun was found floating in!
That reservoir turned into an illegal trash-dumping site...
And from that outrageous stench and view,
people in the village gave it a new name.
The kappa's dwelling...
The Hell Swamp!
The Hell Swamp!?
Then this incident was indeed...
The work of the kappa, wasn't it!?
Now look here, Ran-san...
In this scientific era where space travel is possible,
monsters like the kappa don't exist!
But!
Last night, I...
Well, can you tell me where that reservoir is?
It's about ten kilometers downstream from here.
Then I'll have forensics go there...
And compare that reservoir water to the water found with the body.
Also, I think you should search everyone's belongings.
Because the culprit would attract attention if they used
this bucket to bring the smelly water into this inn.
They'd be found out immediately due to the smell.
I see.
You're saying that in order to transport the
water, it had to be inside an airtight container.
Furthermore...
It seems like the stairs to the attic are behind the restrooms.
Anyone could go to the attic by pretending to go to the restroom.
In other words...
Someone among us in this inn could've
brought the smelly water here...
And committed the crime!
Yamamura!
What's the victim's estimated time of death?
Yes, sir!
Let's see...
Between 6:00 and 7:00 this morning.
All right!
Check the alibis of everyone in this inn!
I'm going to go through the rooms of everyone who's
staying here and look for any suspicious containers!
Yes, sir!
Wait, isn't that supposed to be my job?
I did get promoted to Inspector, after all...
Let's see...
My containers capable of housing
water with an airtight seal are these.
The big bottles of colored ink are 60 milliliters each.
The small bottles look to be about 15 milliliters,
but each of them is pretty much full of ink.
The white container is also about half full of paint,
so the only empty one is this water bottle.
But you can't drown someone in merely 100 milliliters, huh.
You see?
And would there happen to be any containers you hid from us?
I don't think there are any.
Yesterday, after falling in the river, he opened
up his luggage immediately and checked.
There weren't any containers besides these.
But why so many art supplies?
He said he's a painter.
He also said he used to be a teacher at the
elementary school that Tatsuhiko-kun attended.
That's why I'm staying here, since I was going
to burn incense at Tatsuhiko-kun's altar.
And?
At the time of the crime between 6 AM and 7 AM,
where were you and what were you doing?
I was sleeping in my room...
Until the inn personnel finished preparing
breakfast and came to wake me up.
So, were you also going to Tatsuhiko-kun's altar to burn incense?
Yes.
Many of us used to come and do it...
But now it's just me.
Then, where were you between 6 AM and 7 AM?
I woke up at 6:30 and took a morning bath.
Although I was the only one there.
The only things that could hold water are
these two 500 milliliter plastic bottles, but...
One of them isn't opened yet, and the other is still half full.
What's this?
That's a water pillow.
You put water inside and expand it, making it a pillow.
Without this pillow, I can't fall asleep.
I see, it's the water pillow!
You put the smelly water from the reservoir inside
of this and secretly transported it, didn't you!?
As proof of that, see how there's no water in here now!?
Since I was about to leave, I let the water out when I took my bath!
That's probably the truth.
That person also opened his luggage
after falling into the river, but...
That pillow was flat.
But he still could've snuck out later to bring the water here, right?
Well, that's true...
A camera, a tripod, an IC recorder, and a laptop...
What are you?
A reportage writer.
I pursue local ghost stories from various places.
So you came here because of the kappa tale?
Yeah!
But I wasn't able to gather much material.
But this sure is rare nowadays.
Instead of a digital camera, you're using a standard film camera.
It's because I used to be a cameraman.
I couldn't care less for digital things.
Well, with all of these film canisters you could've easily brought in...
The water in question!
Hey, now!
Didn't I tell you?
From before 6 AM until 7 AM, I was on
the phone with the editor-in-charge!
Isn't that a bit long?
Calling someone so early and talking for over an hour!
I wasn't able to find enough material for the kappa
story, so we were discussing what to do!
Since the printing deadline is approaching, and my camera broke!
Your camera broke?
It got soaked from the rain.
Last night when I was taking pictures outside, it suddenly—
And you're saying you caught a cold because of that?
Yeah, I had a small cold to begin with...
But it ended up getting worse...
The malodorous water Numayama
Banzou-san was drowned in...
If that was indeed from the reservoir
where Tatsuhiko-kun's body was found...
We can assume this incident occurred
as a result of Tatsuhiko-kun's death.
What is the culprit's purpose for making
it seem like a curse from the kappa?
Again with the kappa?
I swear it was really there!
This is obviously...
An alien!
I see.
So you tightly filled it in small containers, huh...
Allow me to explain to you the truth behind this case.
In the name of the Gunma Police's First Division Inspector!
Next Conan's Hint
The Color Green
Look Forward to the Next Episode