After following the instruction of
a strange letter Uncle received...
We ended up visiting Koura Inn in Gunma prefecture.
According to two people we met along the way,
Tokubi Rokurou-san and Araiwa Kazuki-san...
Eleven years ago, in the river near the inn..
An elementary school student named Numayama
Tatsuhiko-kun got swept away by a flood and died.
Could this have been the "murder" mentioned in the letter?
Then, the man that kicked over the riverside
grave made by Tatsuhiko-kun's friends...
The father, Banzou-san, was also strange in some way.
The next morning, Banzou-san was found in the attic...
Drowned in the water from the reservoir
where Tatsuhiko-kun's body was found.
Could it be the work of the kappa that
Ran claimed to have seen last night?
Or maybe...
Summer time gone How I long for you
Summer time gone Though I already know
That you'll someday come back to say your regrets —
yeah stay with me
If we continue lamenting the passing seasons...
We'll be unable to confront the mysteries of cases!
Instpector Yamamura of the Gunma police...
Will be revealing the sad truth behind the kappa!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Like the thrilling one-scene in a movie
My heart has been penetrated through
I feel my love has gone away like a dream, ta-la-ta • • baby I need you
When summer comes, I somehow long for the sea
I should've already forgotten, but my heart, Baby, just want to be there
Summer time gone How I long for you
Summer time gone Though I already know
That it really is impossible to return to that summer day from here
Summer time gone It'd be best if I laughed
Summer time gone That fool of a guy
Someday he'll come back to say his regrets —
yeah
Summer time gone...
Detective Conan is brought to you by P&G and these sponsors.
THE DREAM THE KAPPA SAW
(PART TWO)
It looks like the reportage writer just now was telling the truth.
The editor-in-charge confirmed that they were conversing
back and forth for over an hour without any pauses.
So he couldn't have drowned someone while making the call,huh?
Inspector Yamamura!
We've finished getting all of the inn employee's alibis.
At the time of crime, it seems everyone was preparing breakfast...
Say that one more time.
Uhm...
At the time of crime...
Before that.
Uhm...
The inn employee's alibis...
No before that.
Uhm...
"Inspector Yamamura"?
That's it, that's it!
Did you have something to report to Inspector Yamamura?
Well yes...
To think this hack was promoted to inspector...
Also, we have confirmed that the water
in question is a match to the reservoir.
So, was there anyone who snuck out of this inn last night?
The only ones who went out last night
was your group and Nohira-san.
He said he wanted to take pictures of the scenery
around here, and he left earlier than you guys...
Then he came back dripping wet after
you guys did, according to the report.
Mouri-san, why did you guys leave the inn?
Ran said she dropped her cell phone
by the river, so we went to Iook for it.
And then, there it was!
A real kappa!
Again with the kappa?
I swear it was really there!
Right next to where I dropped my phone,
it was standing in the middle of the river!
So, you didn't try to take any pictures as evidence?
Didn't you have your phone in your hands?
I was too scared to do anything!
In that case, why don't I try to make a picture of it?
Tokubi Rokurou (42)
Painter
If you don't mind me drawing it in
my soaked and distorted sketchbook.
Yes, the beak was bigger than that.
About this size?
Yes, yes, just like that!
That's strange.
For someone to have been drowned in a water
bucket, at least one liter of water would be reguired.
But why were we unable to locate the
container used to transport the water?
Tokubi-san's color ink bottles were full, and
he's actually painting with them now.
Araiwa-san's plastic bottle had its seal broken,
but it still had half of its oolong tea remaining.
His water pillow also didn't have any water inside.
The suspicion thus falls on Nohira-san for
having so many film canisters, but...
He has an alibi because he was talking on the phone.
To begin with, the fact that Tatsuhiko-kun was
only wearing his swim shorts strikes me as odd.
Even if he were going cold-weather
swimming, would he wear his shoes?
Also, that shoe...
There were multiple green stains on it.
Amazing!
It's perfect.
It looked just like that!
Hey, Ran!
Did you really see this kind of thing?
It was this exact scene!
Hey, let me see it too!
Hey, you're not going to say that the kappa is the culprit, are you?
No...
It's not a kappa...
This is obviously...
An alien!
Alien!?
That's right!
In this era where space travel is possible, it wouldn't be odd for
an extraterrestrial to have come from a distant planet, right?
If that's the case, why don't you tell us where
the spaceship is that it came on?
Don't...
Don't underestimate their scientific prowess!
Their spaceship may appear to be this small...
But thousands of shrunken extraterrestrials
can tightly fill it for them to travel here!
No way!
Look, you...
I see.
So you tightly filled it in small containers, huh...
At any rate, since Ran-san has witnessed this extraterrestrial
life-form whose nature remains completely unknown to us...
The culprit should be none other than this alien!
Because of that, this case will be
classified in the "Top Secret X-File"...
And kept in the dark depths of the Gunma Police HQ,
where it will never see the light of day again!
Hey, hey, are you putting it away as unsolved?
Not to mention there's no such file.
But, why did the alien have to kill the inn owner, Banzou-san?
Hey, don't go along with it...
Didn't you hear about it?
That Banzou-san had always been using
binoculars to watch over the river from this attic.
I bet Banzou-san must have seen them there!
Swarms of kappa-looking aliens playing in the river water!
That's why...
The aliens thought they'd been exposed and—
Well, I suppose it'd be easier to put this hack to sleep this time.
Hey, Yamamura?
It's just like Dad's "Sleeping Kogorou"...
Is it perhaps the kappa's curse?
Yes, kappa.
When I said that name—
kapow!—I
had a sudden burst of inspiration.
About the truth behind this case!
Even his non seguitur tie-ins are the same!
Am I... like that?
Yes.
Now, please call the remaining two suspects here.
Allow me to explain to you the truth behind this case.
In the name of the Gunma Police's First Division Inspector!
You know who the culprit is...
Araiwa Kazuki (21)
Tatsuhiko's Classmate
Nohira Bousuke (45)
Reportage Writer
And you gathered all of us here...
Could it be that the murderer is among us?
But...
Shouldn't those suspicions have been cleared,
given that you've gone through our rooms?
That's right, Yamamura.
The point of consideration in this case...
Is the malodorous water from the reservoir ten kilometers
downstream that drowned Numayama Banzou-san.
In order to drown him by putting that water
in the bucket, about one liter is necessary.
In short, the person who put that smelly water into some sort of
container and brought at least a liter here is the culprit, but...
The colored ink bottles that Tokubi-san
had were all just about full of ink...
And just now he used those inks to draw a picture.
Araiwa-san had two 500-milliliter plastic
bottles and a water pillow in his bag but...
The bottle with its seal broken still
had half of its contents inside.
His water pillow was also flat upon entering the inn.
It's impossible for the two of them to bring a liter of water.
As for Nohira-san...
He had a large number of film canisters with
him due to his job as a reportage writer.
But during the time of crime from 6 AM to 7 AM, he was conversing
with his editor-in-charge over the phone and had a flawless alibi.
With that said, which of these three
are you pointing out as the culprit?
Didn't you find it odd?
Aside from Nohira-san who has an alibi...
For Tokubi-san and Araiwa-san, if there hadn't been someone who
was familiar with the contents of their baggage prior to the crime...
They wouldn't have been able to escape suspicion.
Since we could've just assume that the water
was brought in a paper carton or balloon...
And that they destroyed the empty container after the crime
and flushed it down the toilet, feigning innocence.
That's true...
However, we were able to discern the contents
of their baggage prior to the incident.
Why was that?
Tokubi-san.
That's because...
You purposely lost your footing and fell in the river...
And by saying you wanted to check your belongings,
you spread everything out of your bag and revealed it.
It was all to set up this murder trick!
Then, could it be...
Tokubi-sensei is the culprit?
Tokubi-san called Mouri-san here with a letter
under the suspicious name of Tatezato Mika...
And en route to the inn, he stopped Mouri-san's
car and managed to get a ride with him.
He then said that he wanted to visit the gravesite of Tatsuhiko-kun,
Banzou-san's son, by the riverside before going to the inn...
All so he had an opportunity to fall into that river.
He also dragged Araiwa-san, who happened to
be visiting the grave, into falling with him...
So that suspicion could be averted from his former student as well.
But, did we tell you about the letter?
I told him about it!
That we came to this inn because a strange person called
us here whose name could be morphed into "kappa".
But...
All sensei had were these small bottles of colored ink!
How can you get one liter of water from these?
There are nine of the 60-milliliter bottles...
And sixteen of the 15-milliliter bottles.
Including the 100-milliliter squirt bottle, they total 880 milliliters.
If you tightly fill all of the containers to the
top, it would come out to about a liter.
Which is enough to put in the bucket and drown someone with.
But...
Tokubi-san was painting with those colored inks, wasn't he?
He did use many colors...
Not to mention the colors he didn't use perfectly match their labels.
He didn't use the squirt bottle, did he?
Look, it's the empty squirt bottle that
was rolling around on the ground.
Normally, water is used to dilute the colored ink.
Otherwise the ink will be too thick.
However, Tokubi-san was able to complete
that faint picture without using any water.
That's because the color ink stock solutions were only inside
the dropper attached to the lid of the colored ink bottles.
And after the crime, they were diluted using tap water.
Using tap water?
I see...
He sucked the ink into the dropper
beforehand and emptied the bottle...
Then filled the void with water from the
reservoir and drowned Banzou-san.
After the crime, he poured in tap water to mix with
the stock solutions in the dropper to provide color...
So that it would seems to just be colored ink at first glance!
Yes.
Of course, the tips of the droppers were sealed
with tape or something before the crime...
To prevent the colored ink from mixing with the reservoir water.
As proof, when he checked his baggage after falling in the
river, Tokubi-san didn't take his colored ink out of their cases.
If he had, it would've proven that inside them wasn't
vividly colored inks, but rather polluted reservoir water.
What an idiot.
If he hadn't painted the picture, he might've gotten away with it.
He didn't have much of a choice in the matter.
After the crime, meticulously cleaning out so many bottles
in such a short amount of time is by no means possible.
Some of it must remain there...
Remnants of the reservoir water inside the diluted colored inks.
That's why he purposely proposed using them to paint a picture...
In order to impress upon us that the contents of
the bottles were, without a doubt, colored inks.
Well, if we ask the forensics to check the composition
of the inks, the results should soon be clear.
That's a lie!
There's no way sensei could be the culprit!
Because...
Because sensei has never failed to visit the grave of Tatsuhiko,
who was swept away by the river, for the past eleven years!
Even after the school was shut down!
Why would sensei have to kill Tatsuhiko's father!?
Because he was his father.
Exactly because that man was Tatsuhiko-kun's father.
That's why I could never forgive him.
It's that man's fault that Tatsuhiko-kun
was swept away by the river and died.
It's the same as if that man had killed him with his own hands!
Sensei...
After school on the day before Tatsuhiko-kun
was swept away by the river...
I happened to see him in the art room.
In that gloomy room, I saw a desperate Tatsuhiko-kun who
was looking for paints that other students had left behind.
I thought for sure he wanted to paint a
picture, so I gave him a new paint set, but...
A few days after the river swept Tatsuhiko-kun
away, that man returned the paint set to me.
Since it looked as if none of the colors had been
used, I thought he hadn't painted any pictures...
So I decided to keep them as they
were, as a reminder of Tatsuhiko-kun.
But a few days ago I discovered something...
The green paint alone had been replaced with another brand!
Why only the green paint?
I dug up the grave to inspect the shoe that child had
been wearing when he was swept away by the river...
And I was convinced!
The reason why there was green paint on the inside of the shoe...
Was because Tatsuhiko-kun's whole body was painted
green on the day he was swept away by the river!
His whole body was green?
Hey, don't tell me...
That's right.
Tatsuhiko-kun was ordered by his father to disguise
as a kappa and loiter around by the river!
In order to attract customers to his inn!
Not to mention in the cold December weather!
No way...
Then, the witness statements of the kappa...
It was likely Tatsuhiko-kun, forced to be the kappa by that man.
That man stripped the shoe off of Tatsuhiko-kun's floating
body in the reservoir and hid it close to his chest...
He also replaced the green paint
before returning the actual set to me.
It was all to conceal the evidence!
That's why that man was using the
binoculars to keep watch from the attic!
To make sure that no one would dig
up the other shoe from the grave!
You're wrong.
I think Tatsuhiko-kun decided for himself to dress up like the kappa.
For the sake of his father's inn, without even telling him.
What are you saying, boy?
Because if he ordered his son to do something like
that, he'd normally just have him buy the paint!
If he'd been seen by someone while scrounging around for
paint, it might have exposed that he was acting as the kappa.
They even sell paint tubes individually, and it
wouldn't be strange for a child to buy paint.
Then why did he take the shoe off of the corpse!?
Don't you think it's for the late Tatsuhiko-kun's sake?
People might ridicule him once they find out
he died while dressing up as the kappa.
Plus it was a memento of his son.
Also, I think if it were such conclusive evidence, he would've
disposed of it instead of walking around carrying it close by.
Isn't that right, Araiwa-oniisan?
Because when Ran-neechan was telling the story of how she
saw the kappa, you thought it was a ghost, didn't you?
So you knew that Tatsuhiko-kun had dressed up as the kappa, right?
The truth is...
The day Tatsuhiko got swept away by the river...
I was also by Tatsuhiko's side.
Around that time, rumors had been spreading that the kappa was
someone in disguise since it never appeared when it was cold.
So Tatsuhiko decided that he should do it on a cold day.
I told him to stop since it had started to rain, but...
He said it was just drizzling and it would be all right...
And that I should tell the guests at the inn to
come and see the appearance of the kappa.
But as I was on my way to the inn, it really started pouring.
So I went back to tell him to stop, but...
Tatsuhiko's foot was already stuck between
the riverbed rocks and couldn't move!
When I called his dad over in a panic...
Tatsuhiko was already nowhere to be found!
So you both started looking and ended up
finding him downstream in that reservoir, huh?
Yeah...
While taking off his green-stained shoe, Banzou-san said...
Not to tell anyone about Tatsuhiko dressing up as the kappa...
Because if anyone was foolish enough to imitate him
and suffered the same fate, Tatsuhiko would be sad.
I see.
That's why he was always watching over the river.
Not only to make sure no one got swept away by the river...
But also to make sure no one would
fool around pretending to be a kappa.
No way...
No way!
But, what about the rumor of that guy prowling
around the area near the grave at night?
That's probably...
After kicking over the grave in front of his son's friends in order to
scare them away from the river, he secretly put it back together.
Even though it's just a grave made of stacked stones...
It doesn't change the fact it was an important
monument made by his son's friends.
As if in response to the wailing voice of
Tokubi-san as he was taken away...
Our surroundings were thoroughly dyed
with the sorrowful color of the sunset.
Although I wept so hard yesterday
I realize it now I listen to the song
I want to turn my feelings into words
But when I see you, my heart is unable to find its voice
Don't treat me so gently
Contrasting sceneries await us tomorrow, and I pray to God
Tomorrow is the last Time I want to remain by your side
With the last kiss, our hearts will connect even if we find ourselves apart
Tomorrow is the last Time Fulfill our dreams with me
Let's fly away on the last day - there's no need to worry, see
I'm impressed, Yamamura!
I guess becoming an inspector's rubbed off on you!
No idea what he means...
Well, since the case is solved, what do
you say to getting a drink tonight?
Sounds good!
Hey, wait a minute!
The mystery of the kappa that I saw still hasn't been resolved!
Are you still spouting such nonsense?
Hey you, knock it off.
I'm telling you I really really saw it!
Like I said, Ran-neechan...
You were so afraid that you just thought you saw it, understand?
What's this?
Talking to me as if I were a little kid...
You're just a kid yourself.
Kappa!?
It's here!
Hey, Ran!
Do something with your karate!
No way!
You!?
You're the kappa!?
Last night, when I went to the grave to
see if I could get some good pictures...
You guys suddenly showed up, I got surprised,
and ended up falling in the river.
Since your daughter kept going on about how it was the kappa...
I thought if I said the wrong thing I might be
made into the culprit, so I stayed quiet.
But...
This painting shows the body as being thinner...
The abdomen juts out, and something
like fur is coming from under the shell.
Your body looked thin because you were drenched from
the water, causing your clothes to stick to your body...
And your abdomen was jutting out because
you put something on there, right?
Yeah, my films and other things.
Then...
What's this fur thing below the shell?
I play survival games occasionally, so I like
to put leaves on my body as camouflage...
You idiot!
Well, what's solved is solved.
Detective Conan was brought to you by P&G and these sponsors.
Next Conan's Hint
Tennis Ball
Look Forward to the Next Episode (January 8th@6:00 PM.)
Our New Year
begins on
Jan.8th!
Happy New Year,
everyone!