Happy New Year, everyone!
As Detective Conan welcomes its 15th anniversary...
We're going to whoosh and swoosh
through solving more cases this year!
Please continue rooting for us!
Dad?
No way, I didn't do,anything!
Dad, an incident hasn't occurred yet!
Looks like he's simply out cold from having too much toso sake...
Figures...
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to wealth of drama.
A mystery is hidden in the tennis court.
Hit a decisive smash with shrewd reasoning!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the, intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back then gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops isn't that right? l'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Quietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
THE DEVIL HIDDEN IN THE TENNIS COURT
Sonoko's tennis coach, Gotou Takao-san,
was selected to participate in a competition.
North Karuizavva Plateau Resort Park
After being dragged along by Sonoko, who had come to cheer for him, we found ourselves in North Karuizawa.
Ran!
Let's go!
Wait, are you sure this is all right?
It's all right!
They're only doing a practice match for the competition
today, so we'll be fine if we finish before that.
Here goes!
What was that?
Gotou Takao (21)
Tennis Club Vice-Captain
Tsuchida Yuha (19)
Tennis Club Member
To think you'd bring that snotty lady
from the Suzuki Financial Group...
What the hell are you up tol?
She's only here to cheer me on.
You want to ditch me for her, don't you?
Nonsense.
Why would I care about a Iittle girl like her?
It's because she's from the rich Suzuki Financial
Group that I decided to do her a small favor.
I wonder?
I swear.
You are the only treasure that fills my eyes, Yuka.
However, it's always better to have a bigger fish to fry.
If you dare betray me, l'll never forgive you!
I wonder where Conan-kun went?
Oh, aren't you the girl who was with Sonoko-chan earlier?
Yes!
My name is Mouri Ran.
Azuma Fumihiro (22)
Tennis Club Captain
If it's about that boy, he went to the restroom a while ago.
Want me to check on him?
No, I should go myself then...
It's all right.
Only men can go in anyway.
Sorry.
Sure looks like a spacious place, huh...
That's the guy from earlier...
Uhm...
About the money I lent you back then...
About that...
Can you wait a little longer?
Ootake Chie (19)
Tennis Club Member
If you can't return it to me...
I'll be in deep trouble...
It's thanks to your support that l'm able
to participate in the competition, Chie.
But, I...
Well then, I have a match to get to.
Not good...
Such a bothersome girl.
Just shut up and keep donating money to me.
Quite the player...
I can't get my money back...
What should I do?
Boy...
Ran-san and the others are worried about you.
Yes...
Awesome!
Gotou-senpai!
What's this?
They were just fighting not long ago.
I just don't understand girls.
Senpai!
Game, Gotou!
Gotou-senpai!
Here, your honey lemon water like always.
Oh, now we're talking!
Thank you.
As I thought, Yuka knows me the best.
Gotou-senpai!
Feel free to use this, please.
Thank you, Chie.
Coach Gotou...
Keep up the great work!
Thank you, Sonoko-chan!
I'm surprised that you know my favorite color.
Because your racket is always that color, Coach.
Nice play!
Keep it up, man.
Unlike you, senpai, I won't screw things up.
Captain Azuma is such a nice guy.
If it weren't for his injury, his place in the tournament
wouldn't have been taken by Gotou-senpai.
Hey, listen.
Since you aren't up to par to be my opponent,
why don't we make it mixed doubles?
I'm gonna team up with a rookie girl and give you a handicap.
Ohf sounds good.
Sonoko-chan!
We're having a doubles match next, so come team up with me!
You mean me?!
Yeah, l'm counting on you.
That's wonderful, Sonoko!
Thank you!
He's putting us away and pairing with her?
What on earth is he thinking?
Coach Gotou!
I'm honored to play with you!
Likewise.
Yes, I'll do my best!
Don't push yourself too hard.
Sonoko-chan!
It'd be best if you took off your gloves.
Is that so?
Thanks for the advice!
Do your best!
Sonoko, go-go!
Sonoko, do your best!
Do your best...
I did it!
Sonoko-chan, keep it up.
Looks like Sonoko is doing quite well.
You're right.
Sonoko, fight!
What's wrong?
Senpai looks like he's not feeling well...
Coach!
What?
What happened?
Are you all right?
Call an ambulance, now!
Coach!
What happened to him!?
Senpai!
What is this?
The collapsed male is Gotou Takao-san, 21 years old.
He's the vice-captain of the college tennis club.
He collapsed during the practice match due to poisoning.
According to the hospital, his symptoms matched
what would be expected of aconitine derivatives.
I see.
In other words...
Gotou-san ingested the toxin lying around
somewhere with his fingers, right?
That's impossible, I guess.
Ran-san, we meet again!
Looks like it, Inspector Yamamura...
North Karuizawa is in Gunma Prefecture, so no wonder...
They didn't consider it an accident or food poisoning.
The doctors think he may have ingested the
toxin 10 or 20 minutes before he collapsed.
İn that case...
This is a murder case targeting Gotou-san, it seems.
Gotou-san is not deceased yet...
It's highly possible he was given poison
during his match and then killed by it.
Like I said, he isn't...
This wasn't an accident?
A murder?
But, how did the culprit do it during the match
while surrounded by spectators on the tennis court?
Come to think of it...
These ladies gave Gotou-san refreshments and supplies earlier.
Refreshments?
Perhaps those refreshments were laced with the poison.
Ali right, go investigate the refreshments
and supplies as soon as possible!
Yes, sir!
Hope you do your job right, Inspector...
We didn't get a positive tox reaction from the
belongings of the relevant parties, but...
The refreshment and supplies consisted of a bottle, a towel,
and racket grip tape that all came back positive for toxin.
Kitakaruizawa Plateau Resort ^ Murder Case
This, this, and that...
Inspector Yamamura, what are you doing?
You see this kind of scene in detective dramas, don't you?
I thought I should try this for once!
But you currently are a police detective!
「3 ladies provided Gotou refreshments」 →
The actions Gotou took during his break were like this, right?
「Gotou Paired with Suzuki & shook hands」 →
「Touched towel, drink, and grip tape in
that order on the bench」 →
「Wrapped hid racket with tape」
Before the match, I saw Gotou-san and
Tsuchida-san guarreling in the locker room.
Despite Gotou-san and Tsuchida-san dating, she suspected
that he's courting Sonoko-neechan because she's rich.
Hold it, what did you mean by—
I get it!
Bearing a grudge because of that, Tsuchida-san
decided to put an end to Gotou-san...
Wait, what's with this kid?
Would a police officer seriously take a kid at his word?
Tsuchida-san...
You offered Gotou-san the drink mixed with poison, didn't you!?
I never...
Although the toxin was found on the outside of the
bottle, the report showed the drink wasn't poisoned.
That so?
No...
Seeing how his palm was inflamed...
Didn't he get that by holding the bottle laced with poison?
This lady here talked to Gotou-san
alone in this very room earlier, right?
That...
I knew about that.
Chie here has been feeding Gotou-senpai
her money in order to win his attention.
To the point she even gave away her tuition fund.
Is that really true?
Yeah...
In fact, if I can't find a way to pay my
tuition, I'll have to drop out college...
Ootake-san...
So you saturated the towel with poison
and offered it to him, didn't you?
If he then wiped his face with the towel, the poison
would enter the membranes of his eyes and nose!
I didn't do such a thing!
According to the hospital, there was no
poison detected on Gotou-san's face.
That so?
Gotou-san took a sweeping victory at the
match and didn't even break a sweat.
He didn't use the towel either.
He took it off his neck and left it on the bench.
If it wasn't us, then it had to be the work of that
lady from the Suzuki Financial Group, right?
Although it seems Senpai approached
her to attempt some gold-digging...
She uncovered his intentions and flew off the handle
because she really had been lavishing him with money, no?
That's not true!
I didn't lavish anything on Coach!
I'm only here to cheer him on because I
heard he was participating in a competition.
Since Coach said he always changes his grip
tape before each game, I gave him one as a gift...
Did you say Gotou-san would change
his grip tape before each game?
Yeah...
I've got it.
The truth behind the case just hit me with a bang!
Allow me to present the solution to the tennis
court mystery at the tennis court itself!
Seriously?
In order to strap on the grip tape, you have
to first peel off the adhesive clear film on it.
If you applied toxin to the film beforehand...
You could get Gotou-san's hand poisoned because
he would change his grip tape before each game.
Inspector!
We received a report from forensics.
On the peeled film inside Gotou-san's bag and
Suzuki-san's tennis glove, traces of poison were detected.
It was on Sonoko's tennis glove too?
Just as I deduced.
Come to think of it, Gotou-senpai licked his fingers many
times because he couldn't peel off the film easily.
The culprit applied poison to the film beforehand...
And offered it to him after putting the tape back into the case.
That's why there wasn't a positive tox reaction on her body.
Right!
In other words, the culprit...
Suzuki-san...
It's you!
No way!
Hey, hey!
Suzuki-san presented the poison-laced grip tape
to Gotou-san with the intent to murder him!
Inspector Yamamura!
Sonoko would never do something like that!
She's right!
I didn't do such a thing!
When Gotou-san was peeling off the film...
He licked his fingers numerous times,
causing his body to take in the toxin.
During his play, the toxin circulated inside him...
And he collapsed when he was about to serve the ball!
This is...
So that's how it was.
Your love relationship discord is your motive.
You told the handsome guy that you were
lovey-dovey with him, but you were betrayed...
So your maiden feelings turned into hatred at some
point, enabling your murderous intent to grow.
We'll question you after we head to the station.
Wait, I said it wasn't me!
She might've had a crush on him but you're wrong!
But all the circumstantial evidence points to her.
This is a false accusation!
Looks like I have to let Sonoko clear away
any misunderstanding with her own mouth.
Geez...
Will the Gunma Police be all right?
What's she doing there?
Is she imitating Mouri-san?
Sonoko, you've got it, right?
Inspector Yamamura...
I will now proceed to reveal the truth of this case to you.
Wasn't the case already solved?
That girl over there is the culprit, isn't she?
That's right.
You applied poison to the grip tape's film and...
Gotou-san's next match started immediately
after he changed out the grip tape.
How could the poison possibly be left on the towel and
bottle he touched prior to that if you were correct?
If you put it that way...
Plus, you'd peel off the film with your fingertips...
But Gotou-san's palm was inflamed due
to coming into contact with the poison.
In other words, the poison got on his entire palm.
I get it!
Gotou-san grabbed something with poison laced all over it!
That means the culprit is Tsuchida-san!
You applied poison to the bottle, and to avoid
contact you handed it over by holding on its strap!
It wasn't me!
If the poison was from the bottle he grabbed...
He'd be unable to transfer the poison to the
towel he touched before, wouldn't he?
Then the culprit is Ootake-san!
When Gotou-san touched the towel around
his neck, the poison got on his hand and...
Why do I have to—
Incorrect.
If the skin comes into contact with poison, we
should be able to see apparent symptoms.
Ootake-san passed the towel with
her bare hands, so that's not it.
But then, where could the poison be?
I see, the tennis gloves!
The culprit wore poisoned gloves and shook hands with
Gotou-san, causing him to come into contact with poison!
I see...
Suzuki-san, the culprit is you as I suspected!
Sonoko...
Ran-neechan!
That's impossible, isn't it?
Because you're still alive and kicking after eating these cookies!
I see!
Ran-san, what does he mean?
When Sonoko was called to the doubles match...
I high-fived Sonoko and touched her glove.
If any poison were on the glove,
it would've gotten on my hand too.
And since I used that hand to eat the
cookies, I would've been poisoned too!
Is that so?
In that case, where on earth did the poison come from?
And we don't have any suspects left!
Another method remains in which one can make direct contact
with Gotou-san on the court and pass the poison onto him.
It's something a tennis player would do naturally...
And wouldn't be suspected even if under the audience's surveillance.
Azuma-san...
You are the culprit.
The captain!?
Nonsense.
I was in the stands the entire time and
didn't offer him any refreshments.
How could I poison Gotou as he was on the tennis court?
You high-fived Gotou-san a while ago.
In that instant, you forced the poison onto Gotou-san's palm.
The reason why my tennis glove had poison on it...
Was because Gotou-san's palm had already come into
contact with poison before shaking hands with me.
With that said...
The culprit was none other than you who
high-fived him before our handshake.
Nonsense.
If I were to apply poison to my hand, I
would've been in serious trouble too!
But you had your tennis gloves on.
Typically, only two balls are prepared in a match.
It's considered proper etiguette to return a
ball to the court if it flies into the stands.
But...
Since Azuma-san's glove had poison on the palm side...
He hit it with the back of his hand.
That's why, when it was switched to a mixed doubles match...
You must've been nervous to see me shaking hands
with Gotou-san after being called to pair with him.
If the investigators detect poison from my gloves and suspect
someone from the stands held the source of the poison...
Your effort would've gone down the drain.
That's why...
Sonoko-chan!
It'd be best if you took off your gloves.
You had me take off my gloves.
If I left them on the bench, they could be taken
away during the confusion of the incident.
I'm deeply impressed by your deductions.
...Or I would say that.
But where's the evidence!?
Here's the evidence, as you wish.
This ball...
When Inspector Yamamura kicked
over the ball container just now...
Only one of the balls didn't bounce at all
which gave me a strange feeling about it.
This ball has an odd rift on it.
This is...
After committing the crime, Azuma-san took off
his gloves and stuffed them inside that ball.
And in order to not have the ball stand
out, he hid it among the other balls.
He plotted to get rid of it after the commotion had died down.
If these gloves have Azuma-san's fingerprints
on them and test positive for poison...
They'll serve as the decisive evidence.
In other words, are you saying that the credit is all mine?
Yippee!
Awesome!
I'm the man!
Why would a kind man like you do this, captain?
I was supposed to participate in the competition tomorrow but...
He was jealous of me and deliberately tripped me during practice!
Unlike senpai, l'll never tumble and fall over like that.
With my leg fractured, I had to give up competing...
And Gotou took my place instead.
To think my participation was robbed
by a low-down womanizer like him...
And thanks to him, my sponsor contract
and scholarship went to waste.
He's the one guy that l'll never forgive!
As such the suspicion on Sonoko was promptly cleared.
Afterward, Gotou-san regained consciousness at the hospital and
his prognosis looked positive, according to Inspector Yamamura.
The rain lasted almost forever
Although we have a moon so blue, I still await the shining sun
open my eyes...
「My wish」 I'm a bit tired of trying to live tough
「Deliver」 My cloudy path is still long
「Deeper」 I wish for it to keep radiating under the sky
「Stronger」 With your praying voice, it should all clear up
"I want to meet you" Nothing other than that is my true answer
Shout as many times as needed! If I paint my dream alone in the sky with a full moon
Perhaps you can see it too (full moon night crisis)
Perhaps you can see it too (I want to meet you)
Deduction Queen Sonoko-san, you were wonderful!
That so?
I thought you would be made into the culprit...
I was so worried, so worried...
Ran, you really are my best friend!
With that said, it is case closed, partner!
That's right!
Right!
Ow ow!
That's too much, Suzuki-san!
Geez!
Case closed my foot!
This isn't a detective drama, you know!
Her grudge about being a suspect is indeed frightening.
Detectıve Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Ganguro
Next Conan's Hint
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE
Our ten-week long
sweepstakes is
coming to an end
next week!
We await your
entries!