As I predicted, we're lost, aren't we?
I was aware of that before you told me!
That's why I told you to turn left back there...
There's a house over there!
What?
We're saved!
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama
A gathering between fanatic fans...
The disappeared idol and the locked room mystery awaits!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Excuse me, is anybody home?
Excuse me!
Excuse me, but we were lost...
Ra—
My!
If it isn't Mouri-san!
You are...
Yatsukawa-san from Nichiuri TV?
So you are the prominent great detective Mouri Kogoro-san?
We apologize for frightening you earlier.
This is Hirasaka Reiki-sensei, a manga artist.
Could you be the author of "The Blackmagic Girl"?
A lot of the girls in my class are readers of it.
Hirasaka Reiki (28)
Occult Manga Artist
I'm honored to hear that...
Miss.
What's this "Blackmagic Girl" about?
Yatsukawa Kouji (27)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
It's Hirasaka-sensei's representative work...
A masterpiece of the occult manga genre!
The story is about the main character rising from the dead
and becoming a witch in order to avenge herself.
This lady here is Utakura Shouko-chan, an aspiring gravure idol.
Utakura Shouko (22)
Kira Fan / Aspiring Gravure Idol
I'm about to make my debut soon.
Nice to meet you!
Say, what kind of gathering do you have today?
That's right...
Seeing that even you are wearing that costume, Yatsukawa-san.
This is...
Tonight we will be holding a seance.
A seance?
You mean a ritual to summon the spirit of the dead?
That's right.
The spirit of the dead?
Of our idol, Miyahara Kira-chan!
Miyahara... Kira?
If I recall...
Miyahara Kira
Idol Actress Killed in Accident
She was supposed to star in the Blackmagic Girl movie.
"Supposed to"?
She passed away a year ago in an accident.
The movie went out of production as a result.
If it hadn't turned out like that, she would've become a top idol!
Kira-chan, why did you have to die?
Who's this guy?
Kani Yutaka (24)
Fan Club Chairman / Figurine Creator
He's the chairman of Kira-chan's fan club
and a figurine creator, Kani Yutaka-kun.
Could you be a fan of Kira-san as well, Yatsukawa-san?
Of course!
My fan club membership number is 11!
And the rest as well, then?
My name is Hoonogi Kazuo, member number 8.
Hoonogi Kazuo (28)
Kira Fan / Doctor
My occupation is doctor.
I am Izumi Maho.
Izumi Maho (22)
Kira Fan
My membership number is 120.
I'm number 53.
Mifune Ryuuichi (27)
Cameraman
I'm a cameraman, Mifune Ryuuichi.
Nice to meet you.
What's your membership number?
I'm not a member.
He's exclusively a cameraman for a cosplay shop.
A cosplay shop?
It's a shop in Akiba specializing in cosplay
costumes, prop sales, and rentals.
There's a photo-shooting corner for cosplayers in the shop.
I work as a cameraman there.
Kira-chan was a cosplay-minded internet idol to begin with.
Then, her pictures on shop homepages and
cosplay-related websites caused a huge buzz...
Prompting her to debut as a gravure idol.
As such, she caught Hirasaka-sensei's eye and was
appointed to star in the Blackmagic Girl movie.
The protagonist in Blackmagic Girl is also named Kira.
There wasn't a more suitable actress than her, but...
My deepest regrets.
Kira sama...
Why did you decide to hold a seance, then?
To be honest, weird rumors were
spreading among the fan club members.
Rumors?
They say that members who ditched Kira-chan for the
other idols would suffer from injuries or illnesses.
It's punishment for betraying Kira-chan.
An inevitable retribution!
On the internet, people are clamoring
about it being Kira-chan's curse.
A curse, huh...
Kira-chan came back to life as a witch!
A witch?
Kira in Blackmagic Girl was also
resurrected following a fatal accident...
Resulting in her obtaining her witchcraft abilities.
And she would avenge her own death against those
those that had killed her and faked it as an accident.
Kira-chan also died after falling into a lake in her car.
But to this date, they still haven't located her body.
And then there's that murder...
Murder?
My production editor, Sawanami-kun, was killed by someone...
About half a month ago.
How is that incident related to Kira-san?
The deceased Sawanami-san left a final message...
"Kira" written in his own blood.
Is that true?
I'm not lying!
Because I saw it with my own eyes!
You saw it?
She was the primary discoverer of the incident.
Don't tell me...
Kira-san came back to life just like in
the manga and caused the incident?
We don't know that, but...
That's why we decided to conduct a seance to
summon Kira-chan's spirit and ask her about it.
How ridiculous...
Hirasaka-sensei has strong spiritual perception
abilities and is well-versed in occult knowledge.
My, look at the time.
Let's commence right away.
Well then, please proceed to my meditation room.
「Meditation Room」
How did it come to this?
To the unsettled soul in the darkness...
Please respond to my inquiry.
Enlighten me with thy voice frozen in tenebrosity!
Miyahara Kira!
Please respond to my inquiry!
What!?
Oh no!
Respond to my request!
What on earth is this?
I'm in pain...
How mortifying...
Mortifying...
How painful...
Kira-chan's voice!
Unforgivable...
Unforgivable!
I can hear it from that panel...
Unforgivable...
Unforgivable!
Someone among you...
Is the culprit who robbed me of my life!
Absolutely...
Absolutely unforgivable!
I shall rise from the dead tonight...
And with my hands...
I shall wreak my vengeance!
Kira-chan's spirit!
She responded to our request!
For real...?
Dad!
Was that really the work of a ghost!?
Impossible...
It smells like explosives here.
What?
You're right.
I see, I've got it!
Explosives were planted inside the candles.
When the candles burned and shortened, it caused an explosion.
No kidding?
Something like a motor is attached to this.
What now?
This looks like it was made from
radio-controlled car parts or something.
When the motor was running, it shook the lamp stand.
So that was all a trick earlier?
That would be the case.
But what about the things that toppled over?
Look here.
What's this?
I see.
Someone tied this thread to the cups and plate holders beforehand.
By using a remote control to activate the motor
and reel in the thread, they easily fell over.
I bet props like those are pre-installed all over the place.
You mentioned someone using a remote control,
but we all had our hands joined earlier, you know.
How did they operate it?
Pressing the button on a remote control
is easy enough to be done by foot.
Isn't that right?
Hirasaka-san.
Hoonogi-san, we've been exposed.
So Hoonogi-san was an accomplice!?
It was meant to be a little performance.
But it was rather mean.
Especially that voice.
That...
How did you do that voice?
You used something like this.
By using this attachment, you can imitate
sounds coming out of a speaker.
That's why Kira-chan's panel sounded as if she was talking.
But her words weren't supposed to be like that.
Our recordings were switched to something completely different.
They were switched?
By who?
Dunno...
By Kira-chan.
Because you were fooling around
pretending to be Kira-chan's spirit.
What's more, the one who killed Kira-chan
and disguised it as an accident is really here!
Tonight, Kira-chan will come back to life...
And she will avenge herself.
How awesome!
Kira-sama is coming back to life...
The air smells strange somehow.
Let me replace it.
Who the hell switched the recordings!?
Calm down.
It must be that woman!
I'll take her by the neck and confirm it!
Hold on.
Mouri Kogoro is here.
Tonight isn't the time.
Mouri Kogoro...
If he finds out about this, I'm doomed!
Perhaps I'd be better off if I had informed the police back then!
But you stopped me!
You've got some nerve to say that.
Do you understand where you stand?
That...
Geez!
That farce did nothing but bring us trouble!
Say, I don't really know anything about Kira-san.
Could you fill me in?
She was a loyal customer at the cosplay
shop where Mifune-san works, right?
Ladies visiting the shop are usually only good at expressing
the cuteness or sexiness of the characters, but...
Kira was a natural when it came to embodying
even the dark or fatal side of a character.
Especially when I saw her cosplaying the Blackmagic Girl...
I felt her special vibe incomparable with the other girl cosplayers.
Kira-sama is God...
That's why I thought she should go further than being just a
cosplayer, and helped selling her via numerous websites.
And that's when a talent agency spotted
her, enabling her gravure debut.
What about Kira-san's fatal accident?
Exactly one year will have passed soon, but...
We had a party here back then.
Because Kira-chan had things to attend to, she
headed home earlier than everyone else, but...
She mishandled her steering on the way,
and fell into the lake along with her car.
Who else was at the party?
If I recall...
It was Hirasaka-sensei, Hoonogi-san, and Sawanami-san the editor.
Sawanami-san was the guy who got killed half a month ago?
Yeah.
What kind of incident was that?
He was stabbed with a knife by someone in his condo.
He was then discovered by Shouko-chan when she went to his place.
Why did she go to that editor's condo?
She mentioned that she's making her gravure debut soon, right?
She said they were having a discussion meeting, but...
Normally it's the editing department
that handles those meetings, right?
In other words, they were seeing each other.
Perhaps!
But what's that supposed to mean when
the victim left a dying message of Kira?
Who knows.
If you'd like, how about I call Shouko-chan
now and ask her about the details?
No, you don't have to...
Oh, Shouko-chan?
It's me, Yatsukawa.
Mouri-san said he'd like to ask you
something about Sawanami-san...
I have a slight headache.
Can we do this some other time?
Bye...
She didn't sound very well.
Why don't we just let the police handle the case?
How about the possibility that Kira-san is actually still alive?
Although they couldn't locate her body...
Her car hauled up from the lake was completely smashed.
And speaking of which...
What?
There's a baseless rumor spreading
around on the internet, and...
They say Kira-chan didn't die from the crash,
but instead from an accident during the party...
And that Hirasaka-sensei was the one who hid her body.
Hid her body?
Where?
Under the floor of the Meditation Room!
No way!
I do know for a fact that Kani was the one who spread the rumor.
Seriously!?
That guy chased after Kira's scoop like a paparazzi.
He also noticed that Kira always abided by safe driving.
That's why he thinks she couldn't
have had an accident on that road.
Kira-chan will come back to life anytime now!
Excuse me, Mouri-san.
Excuse me.
Sorry to bother you at this time.
What happened?
Shouko-san is not in her room.
Shouko-san isn't?
Since she'd said she wasn't feeling well,
I peeked into her room after a while...
But she wasn't there.
And she still hasn't returned yet.
Her cell phone isn't on, either.
From Shouko-san...
This...
I HAVE RETURNED TO LIFE
KIRA
I just got a weird message!
I HAVE RETURNED TO LIFE
KIRA
Ran-neechan, wake Uncle up.
Let's find Shouko-san.
Who's there?
Kani-san...
What are you doing?
Kira-chan came back to life!
I bet she's inside!
But it's locked and I can't open it!
So you got the same message?
Kira-chan!
Open the door!
It's true—the door's locked.
But about that door...
After the seance, didn't Hirasaka-san padlock it from the outside?
And yet it's locked from the inside now!
Is anybody in there?
Please reply if you are!
Kira-chan!
What's going on here?
Shouko-chan sent me a strange message.
Mifune-san, you too?
Shouko-chan isn't in her room, and while
searching for her we found this door locked!
Could Shouko-chan be in there?
Maho-san, please call Shouko-san again.
Yes.
I'm calling.
I can't hear a ringtone.
Let's smash the glass and unlock the door.
But...
Maybe she's not feeling well and collapsed in there!
We have no choice.
Let's do this.
It's true that it's been secured with a padlock.
What the hell is this...
Shouko-chan...
Is this for real?
Kira-sama really came back to life...
The entrance door was secured with a padlock from the inside.
That's the only window here.
It's big enough for someone to get through,
but how can one climb up there?
Wait, if I recall about the window...
It will stop opening if the switch isn't pressed continuously.
And it can't be closed from the outside.
A locked room murder?
How did the culprit who killed Shouko-san escape from this room?
She returned to life!
Kira-chan has come back to life!
It's the rebirth of the Blackmagic Girl!
Where's the key?
Only Sensei has it!
These are posters.
They look like the posters of Kira-san
from inside the meditation room.
Are you saying it was Kira-san's spirit after all?
Means that your intimidator really
was among the participants, right?
They pretended to be Kira-san, who died in
an accident, and went on a murder spree.
Next Conan's Hint
Poster
Look Forward to the Next Episode