Shouko-chan...
Kira-sama has...
Come back to life!
That's impossible...
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
An unforeseen development, a deepening
mystery, and a second locked room!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back then gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Quietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
After losing our way, we happened across a bizarre mansion.
A séance for summoning the spirit of Miyahara Kira san, an idol
who died in an accident a year earlier, was being held there.
The reason was that rumors concerning Kira-san's
curse were spreading among the fan club members...
And with the addition of a murder, it prompted
them to ascertain the cause of the events.
Although the phenomenon that occurred
during the séance were just tricks...
There seems to be a reason hidden behind Kira-san's death.
And late at night, in the meditation
room where the séance had been held...
One of the participants, Utakura
Shouko-san, was found murdered.
THE SÊANCE'S DOUBLE LOCKED ROOM MYSTERY CASE
(SECOND LOCKED ROOM)
Hoonogi-san?
This is terrible!
Hirasaka-sensei is...
What happened?
Hirasaka-sensei is dead...
It looks like he's dead!
What did you say!?
Are you sure?
No way...
Hirasaka-sensei too?
Too"?
What do you mean by that?
Shouko-san was murdered...
Inside this room.
No way...
Where is he?
Show me the place!
Because I received a strange email, I went
to visit Sensei's room to consult with him.
But his room was locked, and he didn't reply even when I knocked.
Just as I was wondering what to do, I heard a
cell phone ringtone coming from the room.
A ringtone?
Since that was from Shouko-san's cell
phone, I felt something was wrong.
So I peeked into the room from the
window went above the door and...
You saw Hirasaka-sensei dead.
Yes...
Hey, it's not something a kid should see!
Hirasaka-san!
Where's the key?
Only Sensei has it!
Damn it!
Do you have anything to pry open the door?
There's a toolbox in the utility closet at the end of the hallway.
Here it is!
Hirasaka-san...
What the hell is this?
These are posters.
They look like the posters of Kira-san
from inside the meditation room.
All of these?
Someone brought these posters from the meditation
room, ripped them into pieces and scattered around.
Why would they want to do this?
How's Sensei?
Is this...
Shouko-san's?
Looks like it.
And...
Is this the rope used to murder Shouko-san?
The victim is Utakurâ Shouko-san.
I was told she was an aspiring gravure idol.
Utakura Shouko?
The name sounds familiar.
She was the primary discoverer of the editor
murder case t hat occurred half a month ago.
That was the case Shiratori-san handled.
What?
İt seems the victim left a bloody
message of "Kira" at the crime scene.
And this is the message sent to everyone
prior to the discovery of the body.
It says "Kira" too, huh?
Does this mean it's related to the case Shiratori-kun took charge of?
I've discovered strange gadgets all over the place in this room.
Those are the gimmicks used in the séance trick.
Séance?
You mean a ritual to summon a spirit of the dead?
That's right.
Last night they conducted a séance right here.
The spirit they attempted to summon was that of an idol
actress that died in an accident last year: Miyahara Kira-san.
Miyahara Kira?
I'm not familiar with her, either...
But she's said to have been a charismatic figure that
enjoyed great popularity on numerous cosplay sites.
By cosplay, you mean people dressing
up as manga or anime characters?
Yes.
And, before her death, she was in
the gravure and acting business...
Which had her surrounded by a number of fanatic fans.
And?
Why did they conduct a séance?
Recently, weird rumors began spreading
amongst members of her fan club.
About a curse.
A curse?
Even that editor's murder mentioned earlier has
sparked rumors that Kira's curse caused it...
Prompting them to summon her spirit
in an attempt to flesh out the truth.
And?
Did the spirit come out?
How on earth could it?
It was all a hoax.
The ones who set the trick were Hirasaka-san and Hoonogi-san.
It seems their intention was to surprise everybody.
But'they said that someone else swapped the
content of Kira-san's recordings used in the trick.
I shall rise from the dead tonight...
And with my hands, I shall wreak my vengeance!
It was most likely the culprit's doing.
They pretended to be Kira-san, who died in
an accident, and went on a murder spree.
There's one more thing that struck me as odd.
I didn't detect any defensive wounds on her.
What I found on the body's neck was a ligature
mark produced by the constriction of a thin rope.
Perhaps she was drugged to sleep and murdered by strangulation?
Regardless, this really is a strange room.
This place is known as the meditation room.
Hirasaka-san would shut himself in here when
he needed to think of a plot for his manga.
Is it true that this room was completely
sealed at the time of the body's discovery?
Yes.
The only entrance to this room is through these doors.
There was a padlock on the inner side of the doors.
And the only person who owned the
key to the padlock was Hirasaka-san.
We didn't locate any key from this room as of yet.
Although there's a ventilation window above...
There isn't a foothold around in order to reach that high.
Would it be possible if they used the easels and chairs in the room?
They wouldn't reach the window even if
they climbed up the easel atop a chair.
Even if they somehow did, evidence of the
foothold should still be under the window.
But apparently there aren't any.
Plus, the window is powered by electricity.
One would have to use the switch here to open and close it.
But if you let go of your finger from the switch...
It stopped.
Same goes for closing it.
If you don't hold the switch the entire time, you
won't be able to completely shut the window.
So no one was able to escape from that window, huh?
In that case, how did the culprit do it?
Are you saying it was Kira-san's spirit after all!?
No way that can't be...
A perfectly locked room?
Is that it?
In the meditation room last night, they had tens of
posters with Kira-san on them as decorative props.
Apparently someone brought those in and scattered the pieces.
Why would they want to do this?
I don't know.
How is it, Chiba?
We suspect that he was poisoned by cyanide compounds.
Traces of those can be found in his wine.
Are you sure that this room was also locked without a doubt?
Yes.
Again, none other than Hirasaka-san had the key to this room.
I had no choice but to prop the door open.
Did you find the key?
It wasn't in the desk drawers.
The only place left to search is the drawer over there.
The drawer is locked.
I've opened it.
I've found the keys.
Looks like this is the one.
But I can't turn the key since the cylinder was
damaged when the door was forced open.
I was informed that the key was made in
Germany and cannot be easily duplicated.
It looks like in order to lock this door...
You need the key to lock it both from
the outside and from the inside.
Yes, seems so.
The other, key is probably for that padlock.
Go confirm it at once.
Understood.
What about the rope on the floor?
They won't find out until they ruh
a test and confirm a match, but...
They are confident it was the murder weapon
used to strangle Utakura Shouko-san.
What about the windows?
They are locked from the inside.
At any rate, since they are all iron-barred on the
outside, it's impossible to go through there.
A locked room here, too?
Yeah.
The window vent is only good for about ten
centimeters, making this door the only entrance.
And since the key to the door was in the
drawer in the room, which was also locked...
No, Inspector.
If we look at it from a different angle, this
locked room mystery is as good as solved.
What now?
It was a suicide.
Suicide?
The culprit who killed Shouko-san was Hirasaka.
He then returned to this room, locked
the door, and drank the poisoned wine.
I see.
It's highly probable that the one responsible for
editor Sawanami-san's murder was also Hirasaka.
But he left a dying message of "Kira" at the scene, didn't he?
That was actually written by Hirasaka.
The one who sent emails from Shouko-san's
cell phone was Hirasaka as well.
That guy did it with the intention to make it appear that his manga
protagonist came to life and repeatedly committed murder.
But he wouldn't seal this room if that were true no?
Since we'd conclude that it was suicide.
His manga series—was it the "Blackmagic Girl"?
The protagonist, Kira, is a witch.
That's why he wanted people to think it was an
impossible crime committed with the help of magic!
That kind of makes sense, I guess.
And?
Did you figure out the other locked room mystery?
No no, that one's not solved yet.
Is that so...
However, the only person with a key to
the meditation room was Hirasaka.
After the séance, I saw him locking the
door from the outside with the padlock.
No one other than Hirasaka could have entered that room.
Even if we assume it was suicide, would he really go as
far as to put the key in the drawer and lock it as well?
And why did he have to tear apart and
scatter all the posters of Kira-san like this?
Everyone...
I apologize for the inconvenience,
but I have some questions for you.
Mifune Ryuuichi (27)
Cameraman
Yatsukawa Kouji (27)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
Earlier in the day, Utakura Shouko-san
was found murdered at 1:00 AM.
Hoonogi Kazuo (28)
Kira Fan / Doctor
Kani Yutaka (24)
Fan Club Chairman / Figurine Creator
After that, Hirasaka-san was also found dead.
Izumi Maho (22)
Kira Fan
The estimated time of their deaths was approximately
between the hours of 11:00 PM and 1:00 AM.
As such, l'd like to hear about your actions
and whereabouts during that period of time.
After the séance last night the atmosphere was kind of spoiled...
Everybody went back to their rooms early.
It was about 10:00 PM.
I was in my room waiting enthusiastically
for Kira-chan to come back to life.
I didn't even fall asleep!
Maho-chan, Mifune-san, and I were chatting with
Mouri-san for a while, and left at 11:00 PM.
You called Shouko-san back then, didn't you?
Can you confirm the time?
Yes.
It was 10:40 PM.
She said she had a headache during that time.
And Maho-san went to check on her later, right?
Yeah.
I was worried, so I peeked into her
room, but Shouko-san wasn't inside.
Since my room was next to hers, I was waiting for her to
return all that time in order to give her some medicine.
But she didn't come back no matter how long waited,
so I got worried and approached Mouri-san's room...
Did any of you see Hirasaka-san after the séance?
Uhm...
Before I returned to my room, I visited
Sensei's room to have a little chat with him.
What were you chatting about?
About the recording of Kira we played at the
séance that was switched by someone else.
But I headed to my room about fifteen minutes later.
Say, what made you guys decide to do a séance?
What made us?
I told you, strange rumors regarding Kira's
curse were circulating in the fan club.
Even a murder occurred.
Do you seriously believe there are ghosts and curses?
No...
Indeed, it doesn't sound like something a normal adult would do.
Perhaps you have some other purposes you're not telling me?
That's...
Speaking of which, Hoonogi-san...
Didn't you mention you received some strange phone calls before?
No, that's...
What do you mean by that, Yatsukawa?
Well...
It was about a month ago.
We happened to bump into each other and drank at a snack bar.
Yes, hello?
What happened?
Recently, I've been getting annoying phone calls.
I wonder who did this?
Could it be..
You were being threatened by someone?
That's just...
Come to think of it Sawanami-san
also received some strange letters.
Is that true?
About a month ago, I visited his publishing
company for a magazine discussion meeting.
Sawanami-san!
Have you heard about the rumors?
Rumors?
It's been said members of my fan club that moved on to
other idols would begin to suffer from injuries and illnesses.
Among those who were injured, some
were saying they saw Kira-chan's spirit!
Such nonsense.
Are you saying Kira-chan turned into a vile ghost and
jinxed the fans who ditched her for another idol?
Not again...
Isn't that Kira-chan?
It's not like that.
It's just some tasteless prank.
Did he really say, "Not again"?
Sawanami-san was threatened by someone.
And he was later murdered.
Hoonogi-san, what about you?
I...
Please tell us the truth now.
It's true that I was being threatened.
What kind of threat?
Kira didn't die from a car acccident, but
rather in the party you had here..."
"And the one who hid Kira's body was Hirasaka-sensei," they said.
If I recall, similar rumors were on the internet too.
I think that's the work of someone who mistook them as the truth.
Sawanami-san and Hirasaka-sensei were both being threatened.
But those were just ridiculous, baseless rumors!
Despite that, Sawanami-san ended up dead!
Perhaps the intimidator is our culprit?
Could it be that you gathered everyone
here in order to find your intimidator?
With the excuse of conducting a séance.
Is that really true?
That's right.
After talking to Hirasaka-sensei, we determined:
The fanatic Kira fan—Kani-kun...
The two girls who venerate Kira's
charm—Shouko-san and Maho-san...
Along with the TV station assistant an director,
Yatsukawa-kun—they were all suspicious.
Mifune-kun was too.
Was that the reason you gathered us all here?
Really now?
"Let's scare them with the séance and watch their reactions."
Hirasaka-sensei said that.
The fact that the voice of Kira-san you
set up was swapped by someone...
Means that your intimidator really
was among the participants, right?
It's very likely the culprit in Sawanami-san's
case is also responsible for these crimes.
Could it be that Kira-san's family or intimate
friends believed in the internet rumors and...
Kira didn't have a family.
They died in a car accident when she was young.
So that's why Kira-chan was more
into safe driving than anyone else!
Seems so.
Uncle, why don't you ask them to show us
Sawanami-san's dying message of "Kira"?
Perhaps we can learn something from it.
I guess you're right.
Inspector.
Very well.
Takagi.
Yes!
Inspector!
This key is for that padlock just like we suspected.
I see.
And as for this rope found in Hirasaka-san's room...
They confirmed it was used to kill Utakura-san.
As I thought.
In that case, Hirasaka was our guy just as I deduced.
However, as long as we don't solve the
mystery of the other locked room...
Wasn't there a secret passage or something
along those lines in the meditation room?
How is something like that possible?
Mouri-san, I had them send the dying message via photo mail.
This is...
Don't tell me, that person is the culprit?
The rain lasted almost forever
Although we have a moon so blue, I still await the shining sun
open my eyes...
「My wish」 l'm a bit tired of trying to live tough
「Deliver」 My cloudy path is still long
「Deeper」 I wish for it to keep radiating under the sky
「Stronger」 With your praying voice, it should all clear up
"I want to meet you" Nothing other than that is my true answer
Shout as many times as needed! If I paint my dream alone in the sky with a full moon
Perhaps you can see it too (full moon night crisis)
Perhaps you can see it too (I want to meet you)
NEXT EPISODE
Hidden in the locked room is a sorrowful truth.
The final door is about to be opened!
THE SÉANCE'S DOUBLE LOCKED ROOM MYSTERY CASE
(OPENED LOCKED ROOM)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Ninja Arts
Next Conan's Hint
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE
The Art of getting
drunk: Ran, one
more beer!
The Art of sobering
you up: Hiyaaa!