If that person really is the culprit...
Then Hirasaka-san didn't commit suicide.
In order to prove that...
I need to solve the mysteries behind the two locked rooms!
Causing Your eyelids to swell and permeting your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
So you were the real culprit after all...
Everything will now be revealed!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
he sky I saw back the gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Quietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that fight? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
In the mansion of occult manga artist Hirasaka
Reiki-san, a séance was held during the night...
And two locked rooms murders were committed back to back.
They were related to the murder of Hisaraka-san's
editor, Sawanami Ichirou-san, half a month earlier
A dying message of "Kira" was left at the scene
Just what is the true meaning behind it?
(OPENED LOCKED ROOM)
THE SéANCE'S DOUBLE ROOM MYSTERY CASE
Say, Mr. Officer!
Did you see a Gomera badge I dropped in that room?
A Gomera badge?
I didn't receive any reports about one.
Let me look for it real quick!
Hey!
The two keys were found inside the drawer.
It's possible to throw the keys into the drawer via that window vent
But...
Is it possible for them to also put a
notebook atop those and lock the drawer?
And...
Notto mention they ripped apart Kira-san's
posters and scattered those around.
Does that mean anything to this case?
Hey, get out already.
Justa bit more!
Hold on a second!
Mr. Officer...
İt seems something is stuck in the flowers!
Let me see.
his is...
A fragment from Kira-san's poster!
Why is it on top of the flowers?
I see...
Could it be...
Ms. Investigator!
Oh, you're the kid from Mouri-san's...
Did you see my Karnen Yaiba card inside?
Looks like I dropped it when I came in last night
I didn't see it here.
Let me look for it real quick.
Little boy!
There isn't foothold in the room that
can reach the window over there.
Plus, in order to close the window...
One needs to press the svvitch without letting it go.
But, on the entrance door...
There was a padlock on the inside of it
It's impossible to lock it from the outside.
Could it be...
I see that's how it was!
I'll search for your card if you'd please.
Sorry about that!
But...
Why did the culprit have to go through all
this trouble setting it up as a locked room?
In Hirasaka-san's case, it's likely they
did it to make it appear as a suicide.
Wasn't there a secret passage or something
along those lines in the meditation room?
If it's like what I imagined...
Then this locked room...
Will be too tragic.
I've solved the locked room mystery.
But I lack evidence.
How about we conduct a search of the meditation
room to see if there's a secret passage of some sort?
Hoonogi Kazuo (28)
Kira Fan / Doctor
Something like that doesn't exist!
Not in that room.
Your effort will be wasted even if you try.
Because Kira-chan used magic to escape from the room!
Kani Yutaka (24)
Fan Club Chairman / Figurine Creator
Mifune Ryuuichi (27)
Cameraman
Yatsukawa Kouji (27)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
Isn't this room getting a little too warm?
Why don't you loosen your necktie then?
Like you always do.
utf come on...
Since the olice officers are here it'd be bad if I dressed sloppily.
Maho-san, are you feeling unwell?
Izumi Maho (22)
Kira Fan
No I'll be fine...
Wait, that person just now...
I see.
It's very likely that the culprit left some conclusive evidence.
Here, here!
Hurry up, Uncle!
Hey, what on earth did you find out?
Look, it just overthere!
Hey!
Just leave the rest to mef Uncle.
Everyone...
I hereby present to you...
The truth behind the recent incidents.
Last night, in this meditation room, we
found Utakura Shouko-san's body...
And Hirasaka-san was found dead inside his room as well.
Next to the body of Hirasaka-san, there
was the rope used to kill Shouko-san...
And her cell phone was dropped on the floor.
Judging from the circumstances, it's natural for us to assume that
Hirasaka-san commited suicide after he killed Shouko-san.
You mean it wasn't a suicide?
Right.
Most likely, the culprit visited Hirasaka-san's room...
And killed him with the poisoned wine.
They then obtained the padlock key and the room key.
After locking the room from the outside...
They killed Shouko-san in the meditation room.
Next they removed all the decorative
posters from their respective panels...
And returned to Hirasaka-san's room.
They placed the two keys, the rope used as the murder weapon...
And Shouko-san's cell phone in the room...
In order to implicate Hirasaka-san.
Do you have any proof of that?
Stuck in the flowers decorated outside Hirasaka-san's room...
Was a poster fragment we found earlier.
What?
Is that true?
It'sthis one.
Here.
This was...
On the flowers that was in the vase?
In other words...
İt follows that the culprit ripped the posters apart in the hallway,
and threw the fragments in the room through the window vent.
Why would the culprit do something like that?
I'm getting more and more confused.
İn that case, I shall demonstrate the trick for the locked room to you.
Detective Takagi!
Detective Chiba!
Yes!
What are you two doing over there?
We were preparing to reconstruct the tricks used in
the locked room under Mouri-san's instruction.
Chiba, what's that you're holding?
his is...
A jumbo-sized Kamen Yaiba movie poster.
I borrowed it from a friend who's a special effects movie maniac.
Why do you need that stuff?
That poster is the same size as the largest
Kira-san panel available in the room at the time.
The culprit used it in their locked room trick.
what'd you say?
Well then, allow us to begin the show.
First, they rolled up the poster like this.
By doing so, they have obtained a thin
tube that's about two meters long.
They then inserted the tube through the window vent
and aimed the other end at the opened drawer.
Finally, they simply slipped in the keys.
Next, they used the tip of the tube to cover the keys with a notebook.
After closing the dravver and turning the knob with the tip...
They were able to lock the drawer.
Then, the culprit...
Tore apart the posters and threw them in the room...
And finally sent the emails from
Shouko-san's celi phone to everyone.
After throwing the cell phone and the
rope back into the room, they left.
But, it only requires one poster
to accomplish this trick, right?
What reason do they/have to carry all of
the posters here and rip them apart?
Furthermore...
How did they make this meditation room a locked room?
İt was done by magic!
It's because Kira-chan has become a witch! ^
Wrong.
The culprit did not utilize magic to achieve that
İt was ninja arts.
Ninja arts?
Are you saying that the culprit was a ninja?
What I mean is not something preternatural like
the Art of Hidden Explosives or the Art of Cloning.
You see it on TV often, right?
Ninjas would use their katana as a foothold to jump over tali walls.
The culprit employed a similar technique to escape from this room.
But instead of a katana...
They made use of those tens of posters here.
Using posters?
I don't understand a bit
Very well.
I shall demonstrate it in front of everyone.
Again?
You guys are my subordinates, aren't you?
With the assistance of Detective Chiba's friend...
We've prepared matching poster sizes
with the corresponding quantity.
First, the culprit rolled up ali the posters extracted from the panels.
They stacked up the same-sized posters before rolling them up.
By doing this, they obtained four cylinders with varying lengths.
And by taping the four cylinders together...
They have created a makeshiftfoothold.
But, with just using this rolled-up paper...
Could they really climb the window that high?
If we roll the paper up into cylindrical shapes...
Their tensile strength can surprisingly
sustain the applied vertical pressure.
Detective Takagi, if you will.
Got it!
But, how did they close the window after this?
Detective Chiba.
Yes!
That's the contraption used in the sâance.
Due to the pulling force of the fishing line, the
easel will hold down the switch in effect.
Afterward...
All they had to do was return to Hirasaka san's
room and dispose of the posters...
And place the remote control back in this room
amid the confusion follovving the body's discovery.
I see.
Well then, who's the culprit?
The culprit killed not only Shouko-san and Hirasaka-san...
But also...
Sawanami-san halfa month ago.
A message indicating the culprit was left at the scene.
It said "Kira", didn't it?
As I thought, Kira-chan came back to life!
Sawanami-san was trying to point out the culprit's name.
And it is...
Mifune!
Right...
The culprit, Mifune-san...
Was you!
No way, it can't be...
If that's true, whatdoes that "Kira"
message left at the scene mean?
Sawanami-san...
Wanted to write "Mifune" in katakana...
But drew his last breath upon finishing "Mifu".
The primary discoverer, Shouko-san, saw that
and hurriedly added a vertical stroke...
Making it say "Kira".
What now!?
Such nonsense.
What reason d id she have to do that?
That's because...
She was trying to protect you, isn't that right?
What you're saying is all just speculation!
Do you have any solid proof to back it up!?
As for the proof...
You still have it on your personage, don't you?
What...
That's why, despite the fact that you usually like to loosen your tie...
You chose to bear with the heat and wear your tie properly.
The proof is hidden underneath that necktie.
Detective Chiba!
Yes!
At the time you poisoned Hirasaka-san...
The wine splashed up as the glass was knocked over...
And landed on your shirt.
You would be inconvenienced if the police
searched your personal items during questioning.
That's whyi ou ikept the shirt on andihid it with your tie.
If we have that smudge traced, we should conclude a
match to Hirasaka-san's wine at the time of his murder.
Yeah damn right!
I was the one who killed those three!
Mifune-san...
Why on earth...
It's because they murdered Kira!
The Kira I loved more than anything!
So you really were dating Kira-chan, Mifune-san?
Yeah, that's right!
That's why, although I had to conceal the trick...
İt was really painful for me to rip apart
Kira's posters with my bare hands!
But, I believe I can save Kira by doingthis, that's why...
Save Kira-san?
So it was as I thought...
I thought it was impossible for Kira, who strictly abided
by safe driving, to have had an accident on that road.
The police never gave a damn.
Something must've gone on at the party
in this mansion before her accident.
That's what I suspected!
In order to ascertain the truth...
I planted a number of listening devices all over the mansion.
I've heard enough of your secrets.
At the time, Hirasaka had given himself
over to alcohol because of his deep slump.
that night...
Hirasaka was severely drunk and got into a frenzy.
Kira tried to calm him down...
But Hirasaka forcefully shoved her away...
And...
İn order to conceal the truth, Hirasaka and
the others disguised it as an accident!
That's why you sought revenge?
Yeah!
The reason I assaulted Sawanami first
is because his guard was the lowest.
But...
I know everything.
The things you've done, Mifune-san.
But it's all right
I won't tell anybody.
Sawanami did mention that there was also a girl at the party.
He didn't tell me her name...
But I guickly realized it was Shouko.
He was just trying to cover up for his girlfriend.
And I actually wanted to kill you first!
By using your gadgets at the séance since I already
knew about them from the listening bugs!
But I changed my mind.
I could never forgive that woman who tried to threaten
me despite her involvement with Kira's death!
That's why I decided to kill that woman!
You're wrong!
You're wrong...
The girl at the party with Kira-sama that day was actually me!
Maho-san...
It can't be!
If that's true, why didn't Sawanami mention your name?
I think it's because Sawanami-san didn't know my name.
It felt like he wasn't interested in a boring woman like me.
No way...
Is that true?
Yeah...
That's why I thought she was the culprit.
Why didn't you report to the police immediately?
Because I didn't want to believe...
To think Kira-sama was really gone...
Kira-sama was my only hope to live on!
After being bullied through middle and high school...
I'd secluded myself from people, even as an adult.
But it was thanks to Kira-sama that I could live a normal life!
I happened to meet Kira-sama on the fateful day I decided
to muster the courage to visit a-cosplay shop...
Most people might see cosplay as just a pastime, but...
To immers'e in the character's imaginative
world even if it's just for a short time...
I was able to forget the painful reality.
İt was Kira-sama who taught me that
I wished everything that happened was all just a bad dream!
If I reported it to the police and made everything clear...
I would be forced to take in the cruel reality!
That was what I was scared of!
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry!
Shouko-chan...
If only she hadn't done things like threaten Mifune-san...
That was not true either...
Shouko-chan was in love with Mifune-san...
Wasn't Shouko dating Sawanami?
No...
Shouko-san told me before...
Since she thought Mifune-san was enthralled by Kira-sama...
She had to bury her feelings deep down in her heart.
Shouko-san...
I think she really wanted to help you, Mifune san...
No way...
No way!
Does that mean...
She honestly wanted to cover it up for me...
And yet I killed her with my own hands?
The reason there wasn't any defensive
marks on Shouko-san's body...
Was probably because she lost hope and gave
up struggling when you attacked her.
It's a lie':..
Lies, lies!
It's a lie!
It's a lie, a lie, a lie!
Hey, knock it off!
It's a lie!
It'sa lie...
But, why did he have to make this place a sealed room?
This is only my speculation, but...
Mifune-san wanted the police to tear down
this room by making it appear to be sealed.
He wants us to tear it down?
If we couldn't solve the locked room mystery, we'd
look into the possibility of a secret passage...
And we'd do as much as tearing up the floorboards.
By doing so he wanted the police to discover...
Kira-san's body that was hidden under
the flooring by Hirasaka and the others.
Since the police did write off Kira-san's death as an accident.
The next day, during the police investigation...
They unearthed Kira-san's body
Underneath the meditation room flooring.
And...
With that, ali the locked rooms have been opened.
The rain lasted almost forever
Although we have a moon so blue, I still await the shining sun
open my eyes · · ·
「My wish」 I'm a bit tired of trying to live tough
「Deliver」 My cloudy path is still long
「Deeper」 I wish for it to keep radiating under the sky
「Stronger」 With your praying voice, it should all clear up
"I want to meet you" Nothing other than that is mg true answer
Shout as many times as needed! If I paint my dream alone in the sky with a full moon
Perhaps you can see it too (full moon night crisis)
Perhaps you can see it too (I want to meet you)
Yatsukawa, I heard you won the Director's
Award because of your reporting the incident!
But many of my acquaintances have been killed or arrested...
It makes me feel awful.
Just cheer up.
Yes!
Please assist me with my next assignment!
Thistime, I'll be doing a report on a haunted hospital...
Filled with supernatural phenomena!
What!?
Well, let'sgo!
Let's set foot right away!
Hey-hey-hey, don't grab me!
I had enough of the occult stuff!
Indeed, we've had enough.
NEXT EPISODE
A courtroom battle between the Queen and the Madonna!
And the juror is—huh that person!?
COURTROOM CONFRONTTATION IV
JUROR KOBAYASHI SUMIKO
(PART ONE)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Painting
Next Conan's Hint
Look Forward To Next Episode