Uematsu Ryuujirou (59)
Teitan Elementary School Principal
What do you think, Kobayashi-sensei?
Have you made up your mind?
Yes.
This is a rare opportunity.
If I'm chosen to serve as a juror, I plan to accept.
Is that so?
Don't worry about class in that case, just
focus on your assigned duty instead.
Thank you for your concern.
Uhm, is that a new painting?
The chairman from the PTA donated it to us.
There's something off about the painting...
I'll be on my way.
Kobayashi-sensei!
Is it true that you've been selected to serve as a juror?
How do you know that?
Thanks to our Detective Boys information network.
What kind of case is on trial?
There's this "duty of confidentiality".
I'm not allowed to talk to you about the case!
What harm would it do if it's just a little bit?
Just keep it between you and the Detective Boys!
If I said no, I mean no!
Wait Sensei!
Just tell us!
I wonder if Kobayashi sensei can do her job as a juror?
You can worry about it after she's actually chosen.
You're right.
Being Group
Qet ctive Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
Bemg Group
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION IV
JUROR KUBAYASHI SUMIKO
(PART ONE)
Tokyo Detention Center
Your trial is approaching as we speak...
And you have not changed your
determination to plead not guilty, right?
Yeah!
Iwamatsu Toshio (35)
Defendant
I swear I didn't do it, Sensei!
Then why did you submit a confession?
I did tell the police that it wasn't me!
But they pressed me with the fact that blood was on my clothes...
You mean the victim's blood found
on your clothes upon your arrest?
Yeah.
And they mentioned the hair and stuff.
The hair and footprints left at the crime scene?
They insisted that they had all the evidence!
Was that why you signed the confession?
But I only went in there to steal stuff!
At that time, that son of a gun had already croaked.
Son of a gun?
You just refered to the victim Ishigaki-san as a "son of a gun".
Had you made his acquaintance prior to this?
No...
How is that possible?
I am here to represent you.
No matter how disadvantageous it might seem,
please tell me the whole truth without hiding.
Like I said many times, I didn't do it!
If it isn't Kisaki-sensei.
Prosecutor Kujou.
I heard you've decided to take on Iwamatsu Toshio's defense.
Yeah, I just had an interview with him.
Kujou Reiko (33)
Prosecutor
To think I'll be battling with you over
what's black or white at the jury trial...
I look forward to it.
Let's do our best.
Likewise.
Tokyo District Court
Is this the principal?
This is Kobayashi.
I was chosen!
Yeah...
And about my class per our discussion the other day...
There's no need to worry about that.
Awesome, Sensei!
Why are you guys here?
I've changed your class to a free-study period.
But these kids said they wanted to cheer you on
as well as participate in practical social studies.
I was sure Sensei would be chosen!
And?
In what kind of trial are you participating?
Duty of confidentiality! '
Well then I need to attend the information session for the jurors.
You're the first juror ever from our Teitan
Elementary School, so please do your best.
Yes, sir.
Go, go, Kobayashi-sensei!
Which of those trials is Kobayashi-sensei responsible for?
Looks like that one.
Conan-kun, Ai-chan!
Ran-neechan!
So you came to watch Mom's trial too?
Don't tell me...
This is Mom's first trial where jurors are involved, right?
And my class is on break for finals, so I'm anxious to check on her.
Right, Dad?
Her opponent is that Madonna.
I just hope she doesn't embarrass herself in front of the jurors.
The undefeatable Queen, Attorney Kisaki, versus
the Madonna of prosecutors, Prosecutor Kujou...
And Kobayashi-sensei will be'judging them?
I bet this is going to be a trial you can't afford to miss.
Why don't you go ahead?
I'll find an excuse to give the principal for you.
I'm counting on you.
Real Estate Company President Murder Case
First Public Trial
The Court is now in session.
Will the defendant please step forward.
Now, will the prosecutor please read the charges.
Yes, Your Honor.
The defendant, Iwamatsu Toshio, with the
intent to engage in theft activities...
Broke into the residence of Ishigaki Tadashi,
a real estate company president...
Located at Akebono City, Fourth District,
Block 5 through the study windows.
While searching for valuables in the room, he was discovered by
Ishigaki-shi who had returned home, and a confrontation followed.
He then pierced the victim's abdomen with a knife in his possesion.
Objection.
You mentioned "a knife in his possesion"...
But has the murder weapon been identified yet?
No, it has not been found as of yet.
Please strike the last statement.
Duly noted.
As expected of Mom!
They're just getting started.
The weapon used in the crime went missing?
The defendant was found loitering in the vicinity
of the crime scene, wearing bloodstained clothes.
After interrogation, he admitted to his crime.
The charges and applicable penal statute is murder...
Per Article 199 of the Criminal Law.
Does the defendant agree to the charges?
I didn't do it.
I'm innocent!
May I have the attorney's opinion?
I plead not guilty on behalf of my client
with regard to the charge of murder.
Not guilty...
The Court will now proceed to evidence examination.
First, allow me to draw your attention to the autopsy report.
Will the jurors please confirm it through your monitors.
What are they watching?
Maybe some images of the victim's body.
Will Kobayashi-sensei be all right?
It may be difficult for laypeople to endure...
But the task of jurors is to perceive the facts.
The cause of death is exsanguination
due to trauma on the abdomen.
The murder weapon is likely to be a sharp instrument.
The length of th eblade is estimated to be 15 centimeters.
The Court will now proceed to witness testimony.
Hara Yukie (66)
Housekeeper
You are the housekeeper hired by the victim, correct?
Yes.
I've been on the job for five years.
Please tell the Court what transpired at the time of crime.
As I was cleaning the second floor that day like I always do...
I heard something coming from downstairs.
Because the master said he wouldn't be back for his
meal after playing golf, I thought I was imagining things.
Just when I came downstairs after cleaning...
Have you returned?
Why's the window open?
Master?
No further questions.
Any questions'from the defense?
By the time you arrived at the scene in question...
The culprit was nowhere to be seen, correct?
Yes.
I only saw the master collapsed and covered in blood.
The jurors should note that the witness
is merely the primary discoverer...
And recognize the fact that she did not see the confrontation
between the defendant and the victim claimed by the prosecutor.
Tsukano Tooru (46)
Victims Brother-in-Law
You are the younger brother of the victim's late wife, is that correct?
Yes.
My occupation is director under President Ishigaki's supervision.
I understand you witnessed the crime scene
while going to consult with the victim about work.
I needed the president's prompt decision
regarding a business transaction, and then...
What's wrong, Hara-san?
Did something happen?
Tsukano-san, Master is...
President...
President!
Hara-san, hurry and call an ambulance!
Yes, sir!
Honorable jurors...
The president was my only family since my sister died.
Please deliver a severe punishment toward
the culprit who robbed him of his life!
The jurors are now free to inguire for
clarifications or details pertaining to the case.
Well then, may I ask a question?
Proceed.
It seems you didn't locate the murder weapon.
Does that mean the culprit took it with him when he fled?
We considered the possibility and have conducted a
thorough search in the vicinity of his escape route...
But failed to discover anything.
My client was placed under an urgent arrest
twenty minutes after the reporting of the crime.
It would take fifteen minutes even after sprinting
from Ishigaki's residence to the place of arrest.
It is logical to conclude that my client lacked the opportunity
to dispose of the murder weapon outside the police search.
Then, where did the murder weapon go?
That one just struck the Madonna's weak spot.
So far it's anyone's game.
What you are looking at right now is the
study where the crime was committed.
The culprit broke in through the
window and searched for valuables...
But was discovered by the victim as he arrived home.
Huh?
Something wrong?
If you have any questions feel free to raise them.
Yes, if you permit...
Question!
Raising your hand?
Are you all right, Sensei?
Go ahead.
About the painting in the room, is it possible that it's upside-down?
The painting?
Yes.
The same painting was in our principal's office, so I think...
We sure can't tell which side of the painting should be up, but...
What does that have to do with the case?
During the process of our investigation, we
received no reports of the painting being moved.
My client also has no recollection of moving that painting.
Does something like that really matter?
He's right.
It's just a painting that's hard to understand.
Suppose that you are correct...
Does that pertain to our trial?
I'm sorry, let's forget about the painting.
Please continue the trial.
The painting is upside-down?
Despite all the mounting evidence against the defendant,
the Madonna still couldn't deliver the final blow.
She's having a rough time because
her opponent is that Attorney Kisaki.
Mom really did her best, didn't she?
For today, yeah.
But I doubt that Madonna would throw in the towel that easily.
Conan-kun, is your teacher's question bothering you?
If Sensei is right about that...
I wonder who turned the painting upside-down?
Perhaps Sensei simply just mistook things.
Maybe she was just nervous because
it's her first time serving as a juror.
You may be right.
If the painting really is upside-down, there must be a reason why.
Let's go check it out.
It seems this is the place.
Looks like someone's already ahead of us.
Shouldn't we wait until Mom gets here?
No way, who cares about her?
There's no mistake he collapsed here, right?
Well fancy seeing the great detective here.
Does Attorney Kisaki require anything?
No, I'm only here to check out the crime scene of this trial.
Am I in your way?
Be my guest.
I'm just confirming some matters for our next trial.
I wonder if you've obtained decisive evidence
that can turn the situation in your favor?
Say...
Did you investigate the painting?
Painting?
Oh, one of the jurors mentioned it, right?
Look, isn't it that one?
She said it was upside-down, but...
Ran-neechan, why don't you compare it
to the image you found on the website?
No doubt about it.
Just like Kobayashi-sensei said, this painting is indeed upside-down!
Like I said, what on earth does that have to do with the case?
No way the owner of the painting would
mistake its orientation, would he?
In that case, exactly who hung it upside-down?
Remove the painting!
Roger.
It was stuck on the metal wall with a magnet, huh?
Don't tell me this is...
A bloodstain?
That's impossible, isn't it?
It makes sense if it's on the outside, but why
should the blood get on the inner cover?
Perhaps someone touched it with their bloody hands.
An IOU?
It has the borrower's acknowledgment, and a fingerprint.
I see.
He used the painting as a secret safe.
This is...
An IOU with the amount of three million yen?
The borrower was Iwamatsu!?
Isn't that the defendant's name?
If the defendant's motive of theft was
actually regarding this IOU, then...
This will become quite the surprising new evidence.
I heard that the president...
Engaged in questionable monetary dealings
outside of his regular trade prior to his murder.
Did you know about this?
About what you mentioned, the president believed in
confidentiality and didn't tell anyone, which is why...
This is the first time I've heard that he had
something like that, hidden behind the painting.
Question him for further details outside.
This way.
I need to tell Mom about this!
Hara-san, how about you?
I don't know anything about the painting.
If it was the defendant who upended the painting...
Why didn't he take away the most important thing, the IOU?
Well...
Perhaps just as he was checking the inside
of the painting after he'd taken it down...
He heard the housekeeper coming down from the second floor.
That's why he carelessly hung it back and fled in a hurry.
If he had time to put the painting back,
why couldn't he just escape with it?
I'm telling you, he was in a frenzied
state when he stabbed the man!
He couldn't get his brain to think straight!
IS THAT CLEAR!?
Something's not right.
The owner should've kept the important
document inside the painting a secret...
So how did the culprit know about it?
Say, shouldn't there be a vase on top of this?
A vase?
Look, I don't see a vase despite there being a vase mat here.
You're right.
The area around the missing vase was bleached by the sun.
Miss, do you know anything about it?
That vase belonged to the Madam and
was placed there after her death...
But it looks like the Master got rid of it recently.
Is that so?
For a second I thought it was knocked off and
shattered as a result of the struggle with the culprit.
We didn't find any vase fragments
during the initial inspection of the scene.
And you're Conan-kun, right?
You have a keen sense of observation, I should note.
All he observed were useless things!
Well then, I'll be on my way.
Strange...
She looked pretty nervous when asked about the vase.
She's hiding something...
I heard you discovered Iwamatsu-san's IOU.
Looks like we've found the defendant's motive for murder.
So he didn't randomly choose this place
to break in and commit theft, right?
I shall submit this crucial evidence during our next trial.
Wouldn't it be better if you take back the not
guilty plea and enter a plea bargain instead?
I don't need you to worry about my choice of defense strategies.
Don't say I didn't warn you when you
embarrass yourself in front of the jurors!
Mom, you sure you'll be fine?
No problem, Ran.
Mom is the type of person who fires up when the going gets tough.
Right?
To get out of her pinch, she needs to
expose the truth behind this case.
And the key to it should be the upended painting...
As well as the whereabouts of the missing vase.
The unexpected discovery stirred the whole court.
The truth is inside the vase!
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION IV
JUROR KOBAYASHI SUMIKO
(PART TWO)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Vase
Next Conan's Hint
I accidentally dropped the vase!
What a waste!