Sensei!
You were talking with the others
after the trial, weren't you?
That's right.
We jurors need to deliberate on the case as a team.
And, what's the result?
Is the defendant guilty as charged?
What was it most of you decided?
I can't tell you something like that, can I?
C'mon, why not?
We'll keep it a secret!
When I said no...
I meant no!
Hey, wait up, Sensei!
Tell us!
Wait for us!
How did Kobayashi-sensei's question about
the painting or something like that turn out?
It was upside-down just like Sensei said.
I wonder who did such a thing?
I think if we find the answer to that,
the case will be as good as solved.
Suppose so.
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
The vase will show us the truth behind the case...
The surprising verdict to stir the entire court!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back then gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right?—I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? l can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears  I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Ouietly my tear drops
tear drops  Isn't that right?  You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right?  I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
Kobayashi-sensei was chosen to serve as a juror.
The lawyer who took on the defendant's
case and entered a plea of not guilty...
Was Ran's Mom, Attorney Kisaki.
The opposition is the Madonna of prosecutors...
Prosecutor Kujou.
Most of the evidence was against the defendant, but...
Attorney Kisaki skillfully pulled through.
The first trial ended in a precarious tie.
During the trial, Kobayashi-sensei was bothered
by the upended painting at the crime scene...
Which also intrigued me.
After visiting the crime scene...
We found an IOU by the defendant inside the
painting, indicating a loan from the victim.
Now this is shocking new evidence.
However...
Hara-san, the housekeeper of the victim's
residence, was behaving somewhat strangely.
What will the result of this trial be?
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION IV
JUROR KOBAYASHI SUMIKO
(PART TWO)
Tokyo Detention Center
What!?
Iwamatsu Toshio (35)
Defendant
My IOU was inside the painting?
Why did you hide the fact that you have
been borrowing from Ishigaki-san?
It's because once I borrowed from that bastard,
and he almost took my shop as collateral!
But if I told you about this...
You'd definitely think I did it, wouldn't you?
That's why...
The prosecution is considering using this fact
as proof of your motive to murder the victim.
Wrong!
I only went there to take back my lOU!
Can you swear you never touched the painting?
Yeah.
I didn't even know it was inside the painting until now.
You gotta believe me!
Thequestion is not whether I believe you...
But whether we can convince the jurors or not!
In any event, I will research just how to
overcome this situation before our next trial.
One more thing.
Did you see a vase in that room?
A vase?
Now that you mention it...
I did see a vase!
So it was there.
Oh?
Welcome back.
Welcome back, Mom.
Ran, you came!
Conan-kun said he wanted to ask you something...
So we came here right after school.
By "something"..
Do you mean the vase you wanted me to confirm with my client?
How was it?
Like Conan kun guessed, my client was
positive the vase was in the room.
There isn't a record about the vase in the police investigation files.
It could be that somebody took it away with them.
Does that vase have anything to do with the case?
It wasn't only the murder weapon that disappeared from the scene.
And, where was the vase when the defendant saw it?
Hold on a moment.
It fell from the shelf here...
And he said it rolled towards here.
Near the door...
Hello, Kisaki Law Office.
Yes.
Please hold.
Who is it?
It's Prosecutor Kujou.
Kisaki speaking.
Huh?
You found the murder weapon?
In a park pool located in Mizushima City 3rd District.
They discovered it after draining the pool for cleaning.
Kujou Reiko (33)
Prosecutor
According to the trace report...
It's been confirmed it was used during the murder.
How very kind of you to take the time to inform me of this.
But, don't you think Mizushima City is a Iittle
too far from the culprit's escape route?
It seems the time of the crime was actually fifteen
minutes earlier than what we originally thought.
We also obtained new testimony about someone resembling
Iwamatsu nearing the Ishigaki residence at that time.
You have been on a winning streak, Kisaki-sensei...
But perhaps this will be the first case in which you taste defeat.
Well thenf let's look forward to our next trial.
Have they found the murder weapon?
It seems the evidence against the defendant just keeps coming.
Not to mention that the IOU was a heavy blow to our case too.
Never say die.
It's our job as an attorney-at-law to thoroughly
defend our client once we take on their case.
Yes, ma'am!
The turn of affairs is growing more capricious...
Why don't I lend Ran's mother a hand for her sake?
Hara Yukie (66)
Housekeeper
Hey, hey!
Do you live in this house, ma'am?
You can say that.
The great detective Mouri Kogorou-san told us he planned to
catch the real culprit behind the case that happened here...
That's why we came!
Don't you know the culprit responsible for this
case was already caught and put on trial?
We were told that the culprit actually wasn't that person!
Who told you something like that?
Like I said, it was the great detective Mouri Kogorou!
He said the real culprit is still out there...
And that they killed the president because
they wanted to steal a valuable vase...
That's nonsense!
I mean that vase is...
Aw, forget it.
Great detective or not...
The culprit is already on trial—on trial I say.
So she really said "that vase"?
No doubt about it.
Why don't you explain already?
Did that old lady steal the vase?
Is it true that the real culprit is still on the loose?
You'll find out soon enough...
About the mystery of the missing vase from the scene.
I bet that lady will reveal the answer.
Is that our missing vase?
So it really was you that had it, ma'am.
Now then...
Why don't you tell me about everything?
Real Estate Company President Murder Case
Second Public Trial
Tsukano Tooru (46)
Victim's Brother-in-Law
The Court is now in session.
Before we proceed with witness examination, the
prosecution has requested to submit new evidence.
We have examined the painting mentioned in our last session.
An IOU with the amount of 3,000,000
yen was found inside the painting.
The name of the borrower was...
Iwamatsu Toshio.
And the missing murder weapon...
Has also been recovered.
The blood on the knife matched the victim's.
I don't know!
I don't know anything about that knife!
Damn it!
You want to make me into the culprit!?
Iwamatsu-san, stay calm!
Screw you!
Silence!
Let me go!
The defendant will refrain from uttering unruly remarks.
Completely with the Madonna's pace...
What about all that regarding the vase?
They're just getting started.
Before the Court accepts the new
evidence submitted by the prosecution...
Does the defense hold any objections?
No objections, Your Honor.
However, I would like to request, further cross-
examination against housekeeper, Hara-san.
I wonder what her purpose is in
bringing the witness out again now...
Does the witness have any recollection of seeing this vase?
Yes...
That's the vase from the master's study.
When was the last time it was in there?
I'm sure it was still there on the day of the incident...
Because I cleaned the study before I
worked my way to the second floor.
No doubt about it.
Hey what's this about?
We didn't find a vase at the scene, did we?
When and where was the last time you saw this vase?
At the garbage collection point the day after the incident.
I went to work like I always do, but the place was sealed off.
I had no choice but to head home, but then...
I saw the vase at the garbage collection point
I wonder why it was thrown away?
Is that why you brought it back with you?
I was only keeping it safe for a while.
Honest!
I bet she would've kept it for herself had she not been discovered.
Objection!
The purpose of this Court is to adjudicate upon the murder charges.
All the questioning regarding the witness's suspected theft...
Is cleary a tactic of the defense' meant to buy time!
The defense attorney will explain to
the Court the nature of the question.
In that case, I reguest the individual who
was present at the vase's discovery...
Mouri Kogorou, be summoned as a new witness.
Dad it's your turn!
She talked as if I were just an afterthought to the evidence!
Uncle, you have dust on you.
Well, l'll be going then.
I'm counting on you, Uncle.
Please explain how the vase is germane to the incident.
Why did the vase disappear?
It's because the culprit hid the knife inside it...
And took the vase away from the crime scene!
Objection!
Baseless speculation.
Can everyone see the smudges on the inside of the vase?
Some brown-colored stains...
Is that blood!?
When the housekeeper brought this back to the premises...
My Iittle grey cells suddenly had a flash of inspiration!
Don't tell me you were stealing the vase when the victim saw you...
And you stabbed him?
No way!
I didn't do such a thing!
The smudges on the inside the vase...
They look like blood.
What?
No doubt about it, they're bloodstains!
There's some on the bottom of the vase!
If you have any doubts regarding my famous deductions...
Be my guest as to compare the bloodstain
left on the vase and the victim's blood!
Even if that were true...
You cannot establish whether it was from the murder weapon.
After the culprit stabbed the victim...
They hid the knife inside the vase and
took it out of the study with them.
They then left the vase at the collection
point and fled only with the knife.
Why did they have to go through all the trouble?
They could have just escaped with the knife in the first place.
Well, it's that...
They'd smear their clothes if the knife's blood got on them.
At the time the defendant was arrested...
His coat sleeves and pants were stained with the victim's blood.
Would the culprit care about the blood
on the knife given the circumstances?
No, I mean...
Hey, didn't you already find out the truth?
Nah, it's just...
Uncle, let me take it from here.
What happened to him?
It's the Sleeping Kogorou!
The victim's murder occurred prior to the defendant's intrusion.
It was likely during the vacuuming of the
second floor by the housekeeper, Hara-san.
She testified that she heard noises coming from downstairs...
And, in the first floor study...
The victim was being killed by the culprit.
The culprit then took the painting off the wall...
And stole what they wanted from inside the painting.
But at just that moment, the culprit
heard some unexpected noises.
They must have panicked...
Given that they didn't even notice the painting was upside-down.
The person who invaded the premises was the
defendant with the intention to steal his IOU.
It was at that time he discovered the body of President Ishigaki.
And then someone came.
Have you returned?
Master?
At that instant, the culprit hid the knife in the vase on the floor...
And pretended they had just arrived.
Pretended they had just arrived?
Then, the real culprit is...
Correct.
The one who appeared at the study soon after Hara-san's arrival...
What's wrong, Hara-san?
Right...
The culprit is Tsukano-san.
It was you!
What are you talking about, Mouri-san?
Tsukano-san, l've already figured out everything.
The reason you touched the body upon "discovery"...
Was an attempt to hide the fact that his
blood got on you during the murder.
You soon had Hara-san call an ambulance and sent her away...
Allowing you to take the vase with the knife inside out of the study.
You then placed them at the collection point behind the house...
And also hid your gloves used in the murder inside as well.
Then, after you returned from the police questioning...
You removed the knife and gloves
from the vase and took them away.
You thought the vase would be collected
along with other trash the next day...
Effectively obliterating the evidence.
But...
Unfortunately, it was not a day for
nonflammable garbage collection.
The vase was left at the collection point, and Hara-san put it back.
Furthermore, because the Court raised the issue of
the missing murder weapon during the first trial...
You hurriedly disposed of the knife in the park pool.
All so it could be discovered during the pool's cleaning.
Cut the nonsense already!
What reason do I have to kill my brother-in-law?
About that, Attorney Kisaki has a report to make.
Director Tsukano was found embezzling the company's money.
We have testimony regarding his quarreling with the victim.
Those were just rumors!
Where is your evidence?
Did you find my fingerprints on the painting or what?
We probably won't find them.
It's likely you had your gloves on during the crime.
What did I tell you?
The jurors will do well to consider this important fact.
Mouri-san...
But, what about during the time you took
the knife and gloves out of the vase?
Since your gloves were inside the vase, you
likely used your bare hands to retrieve them.
I examined the inner side of the vase just in case.
The result...
Was just as I expected.
Inside were bloodstained fingerprints.
Your fingertip came into contact with blood
as you were removing the knife and gloves...
Leaving fingerprints.
But, you didn't notice them since you were
too focused on how to evacuate the scene.
You also mistakenly thought that the garbage
truck would collect the vase the next morning.
The person able to move the vase at
the crime scene to the collection point...
As well leave bloody fingerprints inside said vase...
Is the real culprit!
I would like to formally submit this vase as evidence.
Any objections from the prosecution?
We will forward the vase to forensics...
And investigate the bloodstain and
fingerprints on the vase immediately.
It's that guy's fault!
That greedy man!
With the excuse of punishing me for embezzling the money...
He snatched away the land title deed my deceased sister left me!
That's why, when he wasn 't home that day...
I remembered the painting my sister told me about...
What are you doing?
Acting like a goddamn despicable thief!
I was going easy on account of you being my wife's brother...
Yet not only did you embezzle money from my company...
You're also acting like a burglar now?
Please!
That's the land left by my sister!
Don't be stupid.
You don't deserve even a single cent.
To be frank, I could've just sent you to the police.
If you don't want that, then don't let me see you ever again!
My sister's land was the last thing l'd ever let him take away...
Not that land!
Regarding the suspected murder against Tsukano Tooru...
We will seek to press charges immediately.
The rain lasted almost forever
Although we have a moon so blue, I still await the shining sun
open my eyes...
「My wish」 l'm a bit tired of trying to live tough
「Deliver」 My cloudy path is still long
「Deeper」 I wish for it to keep radiating under the sky
「Stronger」 With your praying voice, it should all clear up
"I want to meet you" Nothing other than that is my true answer
Shout as many times as needed! If I paint my dream alone in the sky with a full moon
Perhaps you can see it too (full moon night crisis)
Perhaps you can see it too (I want to meet you)
Please stand next to the great detective Mouri.
How did you feel when your question proved
to be the crucial key to solving the case?
I was pretty surprised to be honest, but...
I'm so happy that I can help with ascertaining the truth!
Sensei is now a hero!
The word you're looking for is heroine.
As expected of our Detective Boys' advisor!
Though, she did orily merely point out the upended painting.
If the Court reguires my assistance with anything...
Feel free to summon me anytime!
That's not how the Court works!
NEXT EPISODE
Is love sweet or sour?
On the heart-pounding White Day...
A case has occurred amid the bitter flavor of death!
WHITE DAY OF BETRAYAL
(PART 0NE)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Sour
Next Conan's Hint
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE
What comes to mind
when I say "sweet
and sour"?
The taste of a kiss.
Huh?
A kiss!?
Just kidding.