What kind of chocolate is this?
My...
I would hope you'd know your own company's new product.
It's that thing being sold during March for White Day...
The "Spy Choco White".
Yes.
It's a very sour white chocolate that's even
more so than the popular Spy Choco Black.
Hey, hey...
Urai Taruto (53)
Urai Confections President
You aren't suggesting I taste-test this stuff, are you?
You know I can't eat sour things, right?
Haven't I always said this?
I'll handle the sweet stuff...
And you, the vice president, are in charge of the sour stuff.
Well, why don't you pretend that I tricked you into taking a bite?
Urai Hoshie (49)
Urai Taruto's Wife
Maybe you can already withstand it, who knows?
Give me a break.
Wasn't it just the other day when I ate the yuzu cake you
made for fun, and I ended up bedridden for a long time?
Sorry about that.
I was only trying to cure your aversion to sourness.
Regardless...
Have you thought of anything for the White Day speech?
The one on March 14th?
Do you have any ideas that would knock
all of those guests off their feet...
And instantly turn the party into a smash hit?
I have one idea, if you'd like to try it?
I bet everyone would be surprised!
Enough to make their eyes pop out?
eah...
I think even you might be surprised by this one.
Surprised to death, that is.
WHITE DAY OF BETRAYAL
(PART ONE)
Damn!
There was a 24-hour limit...
But there's less than a minute left!
If we fail to locate the spy among the crowd by then...
Everything will be blown to bits!
What are you doing?
Everything in a four-block radius has been cordoned off!
So hurry!
Hey, Youko!
Are you sure the intel is accurate!?
Yes!
The spy is black!
Don't make me repeat again!
he spy is black...
But...
Why are these chocolates all white!?
spyyy
SOURRR!
More sour this time —
Spy Choco White!
Popularly on sale now!
And thanks for the support so far of Spy Choco Black!
Ran, your Dad's pretty good, isn't he?
Not to mention...
He even got to co-star in a commercial with his beloved Youko-chan.
He must've been ecstatic, huh?
He was complaining that no one could see much
of his face because of the hat and sunglasses.
But it's thanks to that commercial that we were invited
to that sweets maker's White Day party, right?
That's tonight, huh?
Yeah.
It starts at 6:00 PM in Haido City Hotel.
I heard that March 14th happened to be
the day that company was established.
Speaking of White Day...
Ran, did you get one?
A return gift from Shinichi-kun!
Didn't you give him that, Ran?
Your handmade Valentine's chocolate!
Rather than giving him...
It's more like he helped himself to it...
I wonder if Makoto-san will give me anything?
As a White Day return gift!
But look, not too many boys pay attention to things like this.
I doubt they would even realize that March 14th is White Day.
That's true.
So if you give out chocolate on Valentine's Day...
You'll get return gifts on March 14th?
That's music to my ears!
Detective Satou!
So, Takagi-kun!
But I didn't get any Valentine's chocolates from you, Satou-san...
Although I waited and waited...
I did give you some, didn't I?
During the stakeout on February 14th.
Want one?
You mean that!?
And they're like leftovers!
Takagi-kun!
Chocolates are like cases...
They are never leftovers no matter how big or small they seem!
Come on...
Hey, you guys.
Done gathering information?
Shiratori-san...
What's with those boxes?
These are presents I'm giving Kobayashi-sensei for White Day.
See...
Biscuits, candies, white chocolates, marshmallows...
I couldn't decide which to go with!
That's why I got them all.
Then, if you'll excuse me!
That's Shiratori-kun for you...
He's good at love!
On the other hand, look what Takagi-kun did.
Excuse me for not being thoughtful!
Conan-kun!
What's wrong?
Sorry, I forgot something!
Please wait for me in the taxi!
By the way, you recovered from your cold?
You had a nasally voice didn't you?
I'm fine now.
Haido City Hotel
Okino Youko-chan couldn't make it!?
Are you sure!?
Yes...
We were just informed that the filming for her drama went over time.
To think I even brought a White Day present for her!
What's that?
You haven't even given anything to Mom or me yet!
Oh, great detective!
Welcome to Urai Confection's 8th anniversary party!
Uhm...
You are...?
I am president of Urai Cönfections, Urai Taruto.
I believe this is our first meeting, isn't it?
President!?
And...
This is my wife and vice president...
I'm Hoshie.
It's an honor to meet you...
Sleeping Kogorou-sama!
My!
I'm really flattered!
This is truly magnificent!
It's true.
Look at all the people here, Conan kun!
Here, here.
It's served in a buffet style.
Please help yourselves to whatever food or drinks you'd like!
Take a look here, Ran!
What a grand selection!
You guys better hurry and pick!
Fried prawns, fried prawns!
Hey, Dad...
Uncle, you're too greedy...
Delicious!
As expected of Haido City Hotel, their cuisine is first-class!
Say, what do you think he'll show us?
What do you mean?
President Urai!
According to Sonoko, he always does
something interesting at every party.
Doing things like magic tricks...
Dressing in a costume used in the commercials...
Or even doing a short skit under the spotlight, she said!
So I wonder if everyone's expecting,something this time as well?
A skit, huh?
Well, you delivered a fine performance in the commercial.
Absolutely!
You were the right man for the job.
Nah, nah...
Actually, it was Youko-chan who reguested you to us by saying,
Give Mouri-san the role of my investigative partner by all means."
That's because...
She's enamored with me!
That's not it...
Geez...
And now, for one of the leading actors of the commercial...
Please welcome the great detective Mouri Kogorou-sama!
Thank you!
Oh yes, Ran-chan.
Yes?
Would you like me to read your palm?
Read... my palm?
I didn't know you were well-versed in palm reading.
Well, I always read yours before waking you up each morning.
You have a short lifeline, so be careful.
You don't want to have a nearly death.
Hey, hey...
Now since our topic is Sour Spy Choco...
I, Mouri Kogorou, will share some of my investigation
stories where I made some...
Very sour!
No, very sorry mistakes, with all of you!
Wow, Ran-chan, your luck is strong.
Your intuition line is extending from your luna
mount towards the base of your little finger.
I do often win prize drawings!
Uhm...
How's my luck with love?
Let's see...
Your marriage line runs sideways and is Y-shaped.
This means you haven't been able to bond with the
person you like because of numerous obstacles...
And it appears that you're headed towards despair.
Hey, hey, hey...
chanto kiiteru
Are you still listening?
Yes!
I'm listening!
No, I meant you.
Perhaps.
But there's a good chance that you'll finally
be together at the end of a dramatic event.
So try not to quarrel with him too much.
Yes!
Hey...
What now, dear?
Are you doing a mystery skit this time?
Detective Mouri?
Please come here.
It appears to be your turn!
Sure...
Geez...
He should've told me about this beforehand!
Oh my, look at this man.
He really looks like he's dead!
Let's see...
The estimated time of death is 19:54 hours.
If my intuition as a long-time detective is correct...
The culprit is, without a doubt...
Right in this room!
And?
What do I do next?
President Urai!
Hello?
Hey!
He can't answer you no matter how much you try.
Because this person...
Isn't breathing.
He's dead!?
Really!?
Wait...
This is a joke, right?
Dear?
Dear!?
Dear!
The scent of almond is emanating from his mouth.
That of cyanide derivatives...
Death by poison.
The deceased is Urai Toruto-san, 53 years old.
He was the president of Urai Confections...
And the host of this party.
I heard from the coroner that it was death by poison.
Yes.
They said it was acute medicinal poisoning
via a hydrocyanic acid compound.
Then, the ones who were by the president's
side when he collapsed were...
Ran-kun, Conan-kun, and...
The president's wife, who is the vice president of Urai Confections...
Urai Hoshie-san —
only these three people?
Yes.
That's correct.
I believe it was right as Mouri-san was giving a speech on stage.
My husband let out a groan all of a sudden and collapsed...
And he hasn't moved since.
If I recall, the person right next to the president was you, wasn't it?
Yes.
I was reading Ranchan's palm.
Her palm?
Is that true?
Yes.
She was holding my left hand with both of her hands to read it.
If both of her hands were occupied...
She couldn't have manually administered the poison.
At that time, did the wife tell the president to do anything?
Like tell him to eat or drink something?
No, not really.
But you know...
She did say this while in the middle of reading
Ran-neechan's palm, didn't she?
Are you still listening?"
Listening?
At first I thought she was talking to me, but...
It turned out she was actually asking the president.
Because it's a rare opportunity to hear Mouri-san's
speech, yet his mind seemed absent.
But the president's reply at the time was kind of strange.
Strange?
He didn't reply with "l'm listening" or "I wasn't listening"...
But instead, he said, "Ah, perhaps".
That is indeed strange...
As an answer to whether he was still listening to my speech or not.
I suppose my husband gave such an ambiguous
answer because he was quite distracted.
Not to mention that, after Mouri-san's speech...
He was planning to make an important announcement.
Important announcement?
Yes.
That we were to be divorced and split the company into two.
That...
Is it true?
Yes.
Urai Confections had gotten large enough...
And we've often bumped heads due to differences
of opinion in management styles.
Although he did cry and beg me to reconsider.
Saying, "I don't mind splitting the company,
but please don't divorce me."
Without you, I can't go on."
In that case, could it be...
Broken up over this, he committed suicide.
It seems to be a viable possibility.
If that were the case, it would be a shame.
I'm a pro at sour products as he was with sweets.
I thought I had convinced him to do what we do
best and to take our expertises to the limit...
Come to think of it, my friend was saying...
That both the president and you were
confectionery contest champions.
No.
Only my husband was.
I took second, and didn't win the championship.
But...
Huh?
In any event...
If you're going to conduct a body search
on me, could you please hurry up?
If there were a culprit who administered poison to my husband...
It couldn't be anyone other than me who was next to him.
If that's the case, it's possible that I still have evidence
that I had the poison in my possession, right?
Yeah, well...
However, it'd be a big help if you used the staff
room past the door in the back to search me.
Since I'm sure the media is at the front door, trying
to rush in and get details about this incident.
If I were escorted out there by an officer...
They'd take it to mean that I was being
apprehended and taken to the station.
Good point...
Then, Satou-kun...
You're up.
Yes, sir.
This way.
Excuse us.
Let us through please.
Are you all right?
I shouldn't have worn such high heels to the party...
Do you need a shoulder to lean on?
I'm fine.
It's only a small sprain.
Let's get this over with quickly.
Inspector Megure...
We'll take these with us to examine them further, but...
It seems that none of the food or drink on
this table have had any poison applied.
I see.
Well...
Although the wife had some lemon
tea, I don't think he drank any of it.
After all, the president's aversion to sourness was well known.
Is that so?
Inspector...
Are you hungry?
I haven't eaten anything since breakfast...
And just when I was about to eat dinner, I was called here.
But doesn't your wife always make you a boxed lunch with love?
Well...
Midori and I had a Iittle fight before I left home to work...
I'm asking you, isn't there something you want to give me today!?
What on earth do you mean?
It really doesn't matter, so don't ask.
Those are souvenir gift bags for this White Day party.
If you'd like how about taking one home?
No...
"White Day"?
What's that?
It's the judgment day when the extent of your boyfriend's
love will be exposed in broad daylight!
First, you casually give him chocolate on Valentine's Day.
And if he returns the favor exactly one month later on March 14th...
The jolly bells of blinding romance will resound!
If he doesn't, the footsteps of catastrophe will close in.
Footsteps of catastrophe!?
Excuse me for not being thoughtful!
Say...
Are you done with that heel?
Yeah...
Now, the other one...
Not now, not now.
Focus on work, focus!
What?
A run-up murder?
Yeah.
That's correct, Inspector.
From what I've heard, each year the'president puts on
a performance at this party to surprise the guests.
Showing magic, dressing in costumes, or doing skits.
In short...
When the president first yelled out and collapsed,
it was an act as part of the skit.
Perhaps he was planning to rope me, the great detective Mouri
Kogorou and a special guest, into doing a mystery skit.
Not knowing that he'd actually be killed soon afterwards!
Then, the first person who ran up to the fallen president was...
His wife.
She knelt down next to the president's face and said this.
Hey, what now, dear?"
"Are you doing a mystery skit this time?"
Could she have administered the poison...
Directly into his mouth at that time!?
Yeah.
In other words, this crime was impossible
for anyone except his wife...
Who knew the content of the skit!
Oh, my.
To think that a great detective would utter such nonsense.
At the time you were on stage and may not have seen it, but...
After my husband collapsed, he didn't twitch even
once and we didn't hear him make a sound.
If I had really given him the poison at that time...
He would've struggled painfully and let out a groan, wouldn't he?
Hey, Ran!
How about it?
You were next to them, right?
It's just like she said...
He didn't move at all and really seemed like he was dead.
In other words...
Your deduction just now was the one you
often blurt out before you get serious...
Namely the absurd and fatuous " fail version", am I correct?
Fail version?
Although this is the one I remember best...
Hey, where'd the cigarette butt fly off to!?
And?
The results of the body search?
Yes, sir.
I found no traces of poison nor any traces
that she had handled posion.
And that's only natural.
In that case, this was indeed...
Inspector!
In the glove compartment of the president's car...
We found bottled poison and a case filled with medicinal wafers.
By wafers, you mean...
The thingamajig you enclose powdered medicine
in that soon dissolves in your mouth?
Yes.
When I mentioned that to the coroner...
They said that they'd found a half-dissolved
wafer between the president's rear teeth.
I see.
He hid the wafer containing the poison in his pocket...
And chose the right moment to take it.
This does appear to be a suicide after all, huh?
The culprit is definitely the wife.
But, just how did she do it?
NEXT EPISODE
The tragedy that befalls on White Day...
What's the miracle trick hidden in the sour
lemon that turns the impossible possible?
WHITE DAY OF BETRAYAL
(PART TWO)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Lemon
Next Conan's Hint
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE
Inspector, the more
you squeeze the
lemon, the more
sour it gets!
Idiot! Why don't
you squeeze your
brain instead!?