March 14th is White Day.
Speaking of White Day...
Ran, did you get one?
A return gift from Shinichi-kun!
Didn't you give him that, Ran?
Your handmade Valentine's chocolate!
Rather than giving him...
It's more like he helped himself to it...
I wonder if Makoto-san will give me anything?
As a White Day return gift!
So if you give out chocolate on Valentine's Day...
You'll get return gifts on March 14th?
First, you casually give him chocolate on Valentine's Day.
And if he returns the favor exactly one month later on March 14th...
The jolly bells of blinding romance will resound!
If he doesn't, the footsteps of catastrophe will close in.
Footsteps of catastrophe!?
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
A White Day with a sour taste...
I shall reveal the miraculous trick!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back the gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Quietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? l'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
We were invited to Urai Confection's 8th Anniversay party.
At the company's commemorative party each year,
President Urai Would showcase his magic tricks and skits.
All of the guests were looking forward
to his performancefor the year.
At that moment President Urai let out a groan and collapsed.
We thought at first he was doing a mystery skit this year, but...
The president actually had ceased breathing.
It was determined to be death by cyanide poisoning, but...
Standing closest to the president was his wife, Hoshie-san, who...
Was reading Ran's palm at the time, making it seem
impossible for her to have administered the poison.
The police found a bottle containing poison
and medicinal wafers in the president's car.
With the fact that Hoshie-san proposed
a divorce and corporate spin-off...
A suicide prompted by depression was considered.
But...
(PART TWO)
WHITE DAY OF BETRAYAL
Urai Confections 8th Anniversary Party
Say, ma'am...
I think you'd better call the restaurant soon.
Since you and the president only had things to
drink during the part and didn't eat anything.
You must have dinner reservations at
some expensive restaurant, right?
We didn't have any reservations like that.
Urai Hoshie (49)
Urai Taruto's Wife
To get my husband's metabolism going, he
was prohibited from eating out at night.
That's why I made healthy dishes for him every day instead.
I see.
Then, what dish did you make for tonight?
Let's see, what was it now?
This party would've been over around 9:00 PM.
And if you saw your guests off, it'd be even later.
So you should've already bought the ingredients, right?
After all, it couldn't be that you knew things
would turn out like this from the start.
What's this...
What's with... this child?
There's no doubt this person is the culprit.
But how did she administer the poison?
When the president collapsed, I remember her
having both her hands occupied reading Ran's palm.
If she had employed a trick...
It'd be with that phrase of "Are you still listening?".
But, what could she make him do with that lone phrase?
What's up, Chiba-kun?
Hay fever?
Yeah, I took some medicine but it doesn't seem to be effective...
But if I take too much, l'll get drowsy.
kiku
"Effective"?
I do wish there were some miraculous allergy
medicine that wouldn't make you drowsy...
"Miracle"?
Have them confirm the relevance between the poison
found in the victim's car and the medicinal wafers.
Yes, sir.
Oh, no!
Dad's cigarette is on the table!
Oh, damn!
It's burning the napkin!
But hey, it's a good thing it didn't catch fire.
Geez...
If I recall correctly, that napkin was under the wife's iced lemon tea.
I see.
That's why she purposely walked over there.
Hey, Detective Takagi!
Can you help me find something that Uncle Kogorou wants?
What's this he's looking for?
He said it's evidence of a miraculous
trick that the culprit tried to hide.
My husband's cause of death was acute
medicinal poisoning due to cyanide.
And it seemed only I was able to administer the poison.
But at that time, I was holding Ran-san's left hand
with my both hands and reading her palm...
It was impossible for me to have poisoned him manually.
Furthermore, a container of cyanide and medicinal wafers
were found in the glove compartment of my husband's car.
Combined with the fact that those same wafers were
found stuck between my husband's rear teeth...
We can only believe that my husband
packed poison inside the wafer...
And put it in his mouth during the part to commit suicide.
No other possibilities, right?
Yeah...
Then would you please hurry up
and release the guests of my party?
Since even my suspicion has been cleared.
Not to mention if I were the culprit...
I wouldn't have invited the great detective Mouri-san
to this party that would end up as a murder scene.
That's true...
But if that was part of a strategy you employed...
It'd be a different story!
No, no, no!
That wasn't me just now!
Hold on wait...
After my voice comes from somewhere else...
There's always a prickling sensation on my neck...
Oh yeah, sometimes it's the forehead...
Dad, could it be you've finally got it like usual?
Hey, Mouri-kun...
What did you mean by "strategy"?
That's of course...
A strategy devised in order for the murder trick to work.
So that Hoshie-san could poison her husband, President Urai!
By strategy, are you saying that I used you, Mouri-san?
Yeah.
Though the one you really used was my
daughter Ran, who I brought with me.
If my daughter had testified that both of your hands
had been occupied with reading her palm...
And that after the president collapsed he was unable to move...
I would believe her over anyone else, and
you would be removed from suspicion.
The reason why you committed the crime during my speech...
Was so that I vvouldn't be able to see through your
trick by having me at a distance such as on stage.
So what is this trick?
Just what are you saying that I could have done at that time?
You said something to your husband, didn't you?
chanto kiiteru
Are you still listening?"
Like I said, that's because...
The president loved being showy and would
do things such as magic tricks or skits...
And he couldn't stand sour things.
So you proposed this to the president beforehand, right?
Saying, "Everyone would be surprised if you ate the sour Spy
Choco White without making a face!" or something like that.
That's absurd.
Just a few days ago, my husband ate a sour-
flavored cake and was bedridden as a result.
There's no way he'd eat that chocolate.
There is a way.
By using a miraculous trick.
A miraculous trick?
You know what a "miracle fruit" is, don't you?
I know that!
It's a berry that makes sour things taste sweet when consumed.
It was pretty popular a few years ago.
It's a small, red berry native to Western Africa.
One that temporarily changes the
perception of sourness to sweetness...
It consists of miraculin, a suger protein
that acts on one's gustatory organ.
It is indeed a miraculous berry.
If thoroughly rolled on the tongue, the
effects will last for an hour or two.
That's why, having had the president eat the
berry in advance, the wife asked him this.
In regard to the miracle fruit, "Is it still effective?"
Then, could it be that the poison was...
Yeah.
At that time, of the things on the table...
The most suitable food for testing its effectiveness was
the lemon on the glass of iced tea his wife was drinking.
She had prepared a piece of lemon
by removing one of the wedges...
And inserted a medicinal wafer filled with poison in its place.
That way when the president put it in his
mouth, the poison would be released.
In short, the wife wrapped the lemon with poison in something...
And brought it to the party on her person.
She then swapped the poisoned lemon
with the one on her iced tea...
Hid the original one on her tea in the paper napkin...
And waited until my speech.
Later, from the mouth of the president who had collapsed
by ingesting the poison following her question...
She guickly removed the poisoned lemon and hid it.
And by the time everyone was focusing on the president...
She returned the original lemon that had been
wrapped in the napkin back to her glass.
Having done that, even when the police
came and investigated later...
They wouldn't find any poison on top of the table.
Incidentally, the reason you purposely took a glass from
the third row when you got your iced tea earlier...
Was because you wanted to get a glass that had
a lemon of similar size to the poisoned one.
Am I wrong?
As expected of a great detective.
You notice even the smallest details.
However, the reason I chose that glass was just out of habit.
Don't you sometimes do it?
Instead of taking the foremost item, you
reach for one in the back without realizing.
I do!
I definitely do the same when I buy milk from convenience stores.
Also, if my husband had taken the lemon
from my glass and put it in his mouth...
I think someone definitely would have noticed.
No, no one would've seen him.
The president himself would've taken precautions
to ensure that no one noticed him.
Since if he had been seen eating sour food with ease,
he would've been unable to surprise everyone.
However, regarding the evidence of you having
hidden the original lemon in a paper napkin...
Forensics has already secured it.
It's the same paper napkin that I burned on
purpose by flinging my cigarette on it.
Forensics!
Is that true?
Yes sir, this is it.
Please take a close look at that napkin.
The burn mark that stretches straight out turns
into a circular curve mid-way, doesn't it?
That's proof that the lemon was there.
It's how heat-fixed invisible ink works —
only that part of the paper is easy to burn.
Then, where's the lemon that had the poison prepared in it?
I gave the wife a body search, but didn't find any lemons on her.
Most likely...
She took the poisoned lemon from the fallen
president's mouth and temporarily hid it in her shoe.
And when she walked by the table with the glasses
lined up in order to undergo the body search...
She deliberately knocked over the glasses of iced tea on the floor.
By feigning an ankle sprain, she took the poisoned
lemon from her shoe and mixed it in with the others.
I see.
Then, go retrieve that lemon.
Roger!
No need.
Mouri-san reguested it earlier, and we already found it.
The lemon with a missing wedge and a
minute reaction to hydrocyanic acid.
If the traces of the president's saliva and both his and
the wife's fingerprints are found on this lemon...
It would be conclusive evidence.
Yeah.
It was because of a grudge regarding sourness that I used a lemon...
But it had indeed turned out to be a failure.
Since it's difficult to hide it.
A grudge regarding sourness?
Yeah.
I met my husband at a confectionery school.
He was a teacher and I was a student.
One day a few years into my studies...
Two people were chosen from the school
to compete in a confectionery contest.
I was one of the two chosen.
But, there was a clear winner before the contest was even held.
Since it was obvious that the other guy chosen
from the school — my boyfriend — would win.
The sour sweets that my boyfriend made were the absolute best.
So much so that even scouts from famous
overseas shops came to recruit him.
In spite of this...
No one could have thought that he'd
commit suicide the day before the contest.
At the time, I thought he was troubled by
various things having to do with his genius.
So I psyched myself up and won the
competition myself in memory of him.
Then, about the "I took second" you said earlier...
Yeah.
Since if he had competed, I never would have won.
And a few years later...
I married my husband, who had been overjoyed at my victory.
Precisely that man who drove my boyfriend to his death!
Drove him to his death?
My husband confessed to me when he became
bedridden from eating the sour cake the other day.
His becoming aversive to sourness was
because it reminded him of my ex.
He had eaten a pie my boyfriend had made before the contest...
And my husband said to him...
This is too sour.
Is your tongue stil working?
Like that.
My boyfriend, who had completely trusted my
husband, became neurotic and took his own life.
My husband told me this in tears.
That he had said that so I could win, and that he
never thought it would result with his death.
Not knowing just how much...
How much my boyfriend and I loved each other...
As expected of Mouri-san.
Who would've guessed you flung that cigarette on purpose!
Yeah, right?
On purpose?
Well, since today is White Day, I just felt I
was able to clearly discern black from white!
White Day...
I'd better contact Midori just in case.
Midori?
It's me.
My, if it isn't the demon inspector
who loves cases more than his wife!
So what a calling me for?
Hey, don't tell me you're drunk!
There ain't no reason I shouldn't be drunk!
You stupid octopus!
Oh, no...
All right, listen up.
In the cupboard next to the fridge, second shelf from the top.
I'd intended to give it to you after I got home,
but it seems l'll be home late tonight.
Well, just something to express my feelings.
Please accept it.
Oh, also...
I didn't have anything to eat for lunch or dinner.
So l'm counting on you for a feast!
Suuure!
Ran!
I guess l'll have to go and assist in the police questioning now, so...
Ask Takagi to take you guys home.
And on your way back...
Stop by Eri's and drop this off.
Really!?
A White Day present?
Don't get the wrong idea!
I just don't want the biscuits that I didn't
get to give Youko-chan to go to waste!
Sure, sure!
The wrapping's obviously different
from the one for Youko-chan...
Aunt Eri didn't seem happy, did she?
It seemed as if her face was twitching...
Don't worry.
That's the face she makes when she tries to hold back a smile.
It's proof that she's actually overjoyed!
And then there's Takagi-kun over here...
Ah-le?
I've somehow completely forgotten the streets in this area!
Why don't you just check the GPS?
Nah..
The GPS in this car has been acting up recently...
Guess there's no choice.
I'll look at the map and direct you.
What district was the Mouri Detective Agency in again?
It was the 5th District...
What a bother...
Awesome!
White Day secured!
Hey...
At least look in the glove compartment
of your own car once in a while!
I put that in there three days ago you know!
Detective Satou sure was happy, right?
Sure was...
Uhm, look, Ran-neechan...
Don't worry!
There's no way Shinichi would pay
attention to something like White Day.
I can just have a long phone call
with Sonoko and forget all about it.
An e-mail from Sonoko...
What can it be?
I got a White Day return gift from Makoto-san!
He said he got a white star mark of victory just for me!
Oh no...
What do I do?
Calling Sonoko...
Isn't such a good idea anymore...
The rain lasted almost forever
Although we have a moon so blue, I still await the shining sun
open my eyes...
「My wish」 l'm a bit tired of trying to live tough
「Deliver」 My cloudy path is still long
「Deeper」 I wish for it to keep radiating under the sky
「Stronger」 With your praying voice, it should all clear up
"I want to meet you" Nothing other than that is my true answer
Shout as many times as needed! If I paint my dream alone in the sky with a full moon
Perhaps you can see it too (full moon night crisis)
Perhaps you can see it too (I want to meet you)
Ah-le-le!?
There's something in the door's mail slot!
Was this here when we left?
Don't tell me...
Shinichi?
No reason it'd be from him...
What is it?
A notice of deficiency?
If I recall, the deadline to file a confirmed tax return is March 15th...
Wait...
That's tomorrow!
Cough drops?
Shinichi?
You had a nasally voice the last time I talked with you on the phone.
Try these and get well soon!
White Day.
I want to say that I didn't have any expectations...
But now that l've gotten a return gift...
It must mean that my feelings have been received.
I'm so happy!
Say, Makoto-san!
Sonoko-san...
I'm in the middle of a champion interview...
So you won't be giving me White Day
marshmallows or anything at all?
Well, I'II get to it soon...
Even though it's White Day, it can give you a black eye...