Don't come!
Hey!
Why is that dog glowing!?
It's a demon dog!
Demon dogs really do exist!
It's phosphorus.
Phosphorus has the property to emit a bluish
white glow upon exposure to oxygen; you know.
They just painted the dog with it to
make it glow and frighten people.
Geez don't just spoil the ending like that!
But, Holmes' The Hound of the Baskervilles is really popular...
So I thought you already knew.
Now look here...
Unlike Conan-kun and Shinichi, we aren't Holmes geeks!
Now that we know the demon dog's
a fake, there's no point in watching!
I'll watch another channel!
In that case, how about joinin' us on a real demon dog hunt?
Hattori-kun and Kazuha chan!
THE VICTIM IS KUDOU SHINICHI
We did ring the bell, but...
You didn't answer, and we heard screaming.
And since your front door is unlocked...
But even so, there's no reason for you to just barge in!
And?
What do you mean by "demon dog"?
It's just some random made-up story.
We don't know that just yet.
Did you know?
About five years ago, an extremely rich
elder named Inubushi Tsunechika died.
Yeah...
If I recall correctly, he was the president of the Inubushi Group.
Could it be the president was killed by the demon dog?
No, no.
He just died of an illness.
He apparently had terminal cancer.
Nevertheless, about that president...
It seems that he had lots of energy and
was a womanizer when he was young.
A little while after he died, a lot of people visited his place.
They were all saying, "l'm a child
connected to the president by blood!"
Illegitimate children?
Yeah.
Each one of them had a picture of their mother with the president.
Wouldn't something like that just be
a lie in order to get the inheritance?
You're absolutely right.
Even if they wanted to confirm it, the
old man himself is already gone.
And since they each said their own mother died as well...
They couldn't learn about the romance.
Normally they'd be turned away at this point.
But the president's wife by the name of Satomi-san...
She accepted them all as her adopted children.
All eight of them!
Eight of them!?
And now that the wife has been struck with illness, the case begins.
A case of inheritance...
Yeah.
The huge inheritance the wife received from the president...
Was to be divided amongst the eight
adopted children upon her death.
But two of the children have died in bizarre ways.
One of them fell from a cliff, and said this just before dying.
That what pushed him off was...
Something akin to a monster with a body engulfed
in crimson flames that grew bigger as it attacked.
An apparition that strongly resembled a dog!
It was probâbly someone who set a
plastic doll on fire and chased after him.
However...
That guy fled from the dog by bike for as far as one kilometer.
He would've noticed, no?
Then, was Heiji-niichan contacted by that Inubushi family?
No, one of the adopted children is an
acquaintance of Kazuha's mother.
\ I heard they were elementary schoolmates.
He said he used to live in Kansai.
And he's saying that the two people who died were killed by a curse.
A curse?
According to him, one of the eight children is an imposter
who holds a grudge against the Inubushi family...
And plans to use a cursed demon dog to
root out all those with Inubushi blood!
Root out!?
In fact, it was my dad, the chief detective with the
Osaka Police, who he really wanted to consult with.
But there's no way my dad can leave Osaka.
Having no choice, he asked if someone
could at least come and listen to his story.
That's where I step in.
But all in all, you still need to go to that Inubushi house, no?
Nah.
It seems he gave up all claim to the
inheritance and left the Inubushi family.
He has since changed his name back to his
mother's maiden name and lives here in Tokyo.
I'm going to go listen to his story tomorrow.
Well?
You guys wanna come?
Actually, that guy...
Has a reall hilarious name!
Kudou Shinichi"!?
No kidding?
See, isn't it hilarious?
Not funny!
Who is this may I ask?
A detective who was summoned by Shinichi-san!
That was a woman's voice just now, right?
Didn't that person live alone?
He has a bad back, so he has a lady come to
look after him two to three times a week.
It seems he can't even go to work at his company now.
Abukawa Funae (39)
Home Helper
Uhm...
Kudou-san is sleeping right now.
Kudou-san?
You have visitors.
Sound alseep, huh...
But isn't this room a bit too warm?
Yeah...
He seems to have a slight cold.
Kudou Shinichi (43)
Adopted Son of Inubushi
Also, he said he didn't sleep much at all last night
because he stayed up doing a lot of thinking.
But I think he should wake up soon.
Then, allow us to stay here until he does.
Please listen to what he has to say.
I don't think I can handle it anymore.
He'd rather die now and be at peace?
Did he really say that?
Yeah...
Saying that if he were going to be eaten by a cursed demon dog...
That man may have seen it as well, I mean the dog.
Guess so.
All right, l'm going to go buy groceries for dinner.
Could you two watch the-house for me?
Sure, no problem.
A cursed demon dog, huh...
Hey, did you hear anything else about the case?
Yeah, I heard about the names of those eight adopted children.
Well, the pronounciations are...
Shinichi, Takako, Saki, Tomoaki...
Miwako, Yoshiya, Keiji, and Miyuki.
It seems they were all named by...
President Inubushi Tsunechika who died five years ago.
And, who were the-two people that died?
Well, if I recall...
What's that sound?
I think he may have set a timer to play
music instead of an alarm clock.
This door...
It's been sealed with ducttape!
Suicide by charcoal?
Looks so.
I'll take care of the taped window.
And I'll get the grill out.
Damn, this is stuck on really tight!
Didn't he have back problems!?
Even made a footstool out of books...
Huh?
This charcoal grill...
What's going on here?
It's carbon monoxide poisoning!
Don't move from there!
You can't come inside!
We first came to this room about thirty minutes ago, right?
His jaw has started to stiffen.
His back is showing slight livor mortis.
And, this charcoal...
Not to mention that footstool made from stacked books.
There's no mistake.
Yeah.
Anyway I should...
Go call the police.
Before you do that...
We have just one question for you right now.
Why did you kill that man?
Why...?
That's our line.
If you're telling us it was the demon dog's curse...
You won't fool us!
Wait just a moment!
Why would I be the culprit?
I'm just an ordinary caretaker...
And I only returned from shopping just now!
Plus, it looks as if this door was sealed with duct tape.
And when I got here...
You were tearing the seals off of the window, right?
Yeah.
It was stuck on there real good.
Not to mention the fact that a charcoal grill was next to the body.
So, no matter howyou look at it...
Isn't this a charcoal-burning suicide?
That may be so.
Both the entry door and the window were sealed from the inside...
Making it a perfectly sealed-room.
And if the interior of the room were filled with carbon monoxide...
It'd be impossible for anyone else to be in the room.
In that case...
However, it is strange.
Despite Shinichi-san's having a bad back...
There's a footstool made from books in the lower part of the shelf.
Do you think some with a bad back
would've deliberately bent over...
And taken books from such a low shelf?
I wonder if the books on the shelves he could easily
reach were the ones he didn't want to step on?
That's why he forced himself...
Not to mention this charcoal...
Isn't hot even if I hold it in my hand.
You may not know this, little boy, but the charcoal...
If you burn charcoal in an airtight room...
The oxygen in the air will be exhausted, causing incomplete
combustion and carbon monoxide is generated.
If inhaled, carbon monoxide will
introduce itself to the bloodstream...
Combine with the hemoglobin and lead
to asphyxiation followed by death.
With that said...
Do you want to say that when the oxygen was finally
used up, the flame on the charcoal went out?
Yeah...
Well, it would've been extremely painful if
failed, followed by serious after-effects...
So I don't know what charcoal suiciders might be thinking.
But it was about thirty minutes ago that we
last saw this man sleeping in this room.
If he then sealed the door and window,
wouldn't it take more than ten minutes?
It would take even longer if he took it slow with his bad back.
Furthermore, filling this room with carbon
monoxide using just a single grill..
It would take quite a while and the
remaining time wouldn't be sufficient.
And even if the fire went o ut, it should still retain some heat.
In short, this charcoal...
Has already been burned and left cold for quite a while.
And that means what was placed in the grill
was just charcoal that wasn't on fire.
It also means that someone else could've been in this
room to seal the window and door with duct tape!
Ridiculous!
Are you saying I was in the room?
If so, you would've seen me, wouldn't you?
But I wasn't here!
You were holding your breath hiding, weren't you?
In the space between this bookshelf and the door!
You really thought up a good plan.
İf we saw the door and window all taped
up and a charcoal grill on the floor...
We'd think it was a charcoal-burning suicide.
And our attention would've been directed
to those instead of to the door...
Enabling you to safely hide behind the door!
And just as we were about to remove the tape
on the window and the grill from the room...
You took the chance to sneak out to the doorway.
You attempted to raise the room temperature in order
to slow the body temperature's drop rate, but...
Since his jaw has already begun to stiffen, more
than an hour would've passed since his death.
His back also showed slight livor mortis.
That's proof that you laid the deceased old man on
his bed to make it appear as if he were sleeping.
Well, talk about evidence...
Her fingerprints are still on the duct tape, aren't they?
That's right.
Since you had to apply the duct tape this sticky...
It would take more time if you had been wearing gloves.
I bet you planned on taking the tape down with us, and trying
to trick us by saying that's how your prints got on the tape.
But your plan is ruined, isn't it?
What is this?
Who on earth are you!?
Didn't we tell you when we rang the bell to this house?
That we're detectives.
This is wrong...
This isn't what I was told!
What's that?
From what I heard...
It was only a child detective who was coming today.
Huh?
"It was only a child so it's no big deal..."
Did this man tell you something like that?
It's the culprit!
It was the culprit who said that everything would be fine if I
followed the instructions, because l'd be dealing with a child!
What now?
Look lady, if you keep spewing nonsense, l'll teach you a lesson!
I'm not lying!
Because when I came here today, Kudou-san was already dead!
What do you mean?
I came in the afternoon as I usually do...
But when I rang the doorbell, no one answered.
I had no choice but to enter using the spare key I was given...
And the phone had been ringing.
When I answered, the caller told me in
an eerie, machine-modified voice...
"I have shut Kudou up inside his bedroom wardrobe."
"If you want to save him, you'd better hurry," they said...
Wardrobe?
This thing.
I came to this room half-unconvinced, and...
The wardrobe had indeed been sealed up with duct tape...
And a bar had been shoved through the handles,
so it couldn't be opened from the inside.
Soon after I removed it and opened the door...
Kudou-san was inside!
The edges of the door are sticky.
Yeah.
İt seems they drugged him to sleep...
And killed him by locking him up in
there with the burning charcoal grill.
You understand, right?
That what l'm saying is the truth?
Yeah.
This was indeed the true scene of the crime.
However...
If that was true, why didn't you call the police?
If you did something this unwise and were discovered, you
knew that the consequences would be irreversible, no?
Because...
It was stuck to the inside of the wardrobe door!
A picture of my son!
They said over the phone that if I didn't do what
I was told, my son would meet the same fate...
And you took them seriously?
Yeah.
It seems that person also knew that I often
got into arguments with Kudou-san...
And said that camouflaging it as a
suicide would be to my benefit as well.
Arguments?
Like over the meals I made.
Kudou-san was picky about his likes and dislikes...
And l've often complained about it to my coworkers.
Speaking of meals, what were you planning on doing?
You said you were going to buy groceries for
dinner earlier, but you didn't go, right?
I usually come here after buying groceries at the supermarket.
I was instructed to use those and make
it appear as if I had gone shopping.
Then what about dinner?
What did you plan on making?
Boiled mackerel in soy sauce.
You mean Abukawa-san the helper?
She came here today at noon.
Well, she was persistent today as well, a tough customer!
Persistent?
About the sliced mackerel.
A little of the red juice had collected inside
of the pack, so she demanded a discount.
Even though the price had already been lowered.
Well then, thank you very much!
Looks like what she said...
Might actually be the truth.
If she did something as noticeable as
haggling over the price of a fish...
It'd be revealed that her shopping time as an alibi was off.
And about the culprit...
Did they say anything in regards to who they were?
Well...
A vengeful spirit?
Did your caller really identify themselves as that?
Yeah...
After they muttered that, the line went dead.
Do you have any clues about it?
Such as someone who holds a grudge against the victim.
Yeah...
Actually...
Actually, the victim was an adopted son of the Inubushi
Group president, Tsunechika, who died five years ago.
And it seems he's been frightened about it.
He said that a bad person had infiltrated the Inubushi family...
And was intent on rooting out everyone with
Inubushi blood using a cursed demon dog!
Demon dog?
It sounds like a story from a mystery novel.
There was a Holmes story like that wasn't there?
Wasn't that The Inugami Clan?
The Inugami Clan is a mystery novel by
Yokomizo Seishi featuring Kindaichi Kousuke.
And, didn't you hear anything from the victim?
Like if he had a meeting planned with anyone...
I only heard that a young boy detective from Osaka was coming.
Since the culprit also knew of this...
It means that this was definitely a crime by an acguaintance.
Yeah...
Perhaps he was intending to go out somewhere with that culprit.
Why would you say that?
When I found him inside the wardrobe...
He was wearing a business suit and necktie.
Business suit?
And necktie?
So you removed those and put him in a jersey like that, right?
Yes...
The culprit ordered me to do so.
Then you laid the body on the bed...
And waited for the boy detective to come.
After you showed off the victim as if he was sleeping...
You said you were going shopping and entered the bedroom.
Then you moved the body to the floor and placed the charcoal grill...
And taped up the window and the door.
Finally, you pressed the CD's play button...
And hid yourself in a position that would become a blind spot.
After that, when Hattori-kun's group came in
after being surprised by the CD's music...
They'd focus on the window, body, and grill, enabling
you to leave the blind spot and move to the doorway.
Then you pretended that you had just returned from shopping...
Per the order from the culprit, is that correct?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
By the way, can you tell me if anything was stolen?
Not sure...
Only Kudou san himself would know the answer.
But...
The ornament attached to his necktie pin was removed.
Necktie pin?
Was there an expensive jewel attached?
No...
I only noticed that there were signs of
something having been removed from it.
As far as what that was, I almost never
see Kudou-san in a business suit, so...
Turn him face-up and put him on the stretcher!
Ready, and... go!
Something fell out of his mouth!
It was small and round...
A pearl!
Hey, investigate that necktie pin right now!
Because if this man's saliva is on it...
This pearl could be the victim's dying message that he
bit away from his necktie pin in his final moments!
What I recall is that blue moonlight
Your retreating figure waved to me, as the light of the moon took you away that day
From my heart, from my heart, I want to tell you
I love you, I love you — a feeling that cannot be reached
Were it a dream, were it a dream, I could have met with you
Although my wishes cannot come true
Mischievous magic on the moonlit night — you're imprisoned in the shade of the moon
Like the new moon obscured by darkness, your figure escapes my sight
Even though you're so close
NEXT EPISODE
A family accursed by a dog...
One more victim has fallen prey to the diabolical canine!
INUBUSHI CASTLE
THE ABLAZED DEMON DOG
(WILL-0'-THE-WISP CHAPTER)
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Spheres
Next Conan's Hint
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE