Hey!
Old man!
I think the Inubushi household is around here.
Do you know?
Inubushi?
What business do you have with them?
We're just thinking about solving a
little issue/involving a puppy's curse.
I'm going to be frank with you.
You had better give up.
If you stick your neck into that business
for no good reason, you'll get badly burnt.
And, where's the house?
You can see a roof that looks like a
castle half way up that mountain, right?
That's the Inubushi home.
A manor put under a curse by a dog!
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
What's the mystery behind the blazing dog that has pounced on the accursed Inubushi home?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back then gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops isn't that right? l'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Quietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
Hattori Heiji brought in a case.
The adopted children of Inubushi Tsunechika, the
Inubushi Group president who died five years ago...
One by one departed this world in bizarre ways.
What's more, they claimed it's the deed of
an aflamed apparition that resembled a dog.
Because one of the adopted children was
acquaintances with Kazuha's mother...
I went with Hattori to hear his story out, but...
To my surprise, his name was "Kudou Shinichi".
Although the kanji was different, it sounded just like my name.
But, before we got to ask him about the story...
Someone murdered Shinichi-san and
disguised it as a charcoal-burning suicide.
What on earth is the identity of the culprit
who called themselves "a vengeful spirit"?
And what's the meaning behind the pearl that
was held in the mouth of Shinichi-san's corpse?
What can it be...
(WILL-0'-THE-WISP CHAPTER)
INUBUSHI CASTLE
THE ABLAZED DEMON DOG
Well Heiji, is it true?
What you said about that Shinichi guy who was
the adopted son of the Inubushi family..
And a pearl that fell out of his corpse's mouth?
Yeah, it's true.
He likely bit the pearl off of his necktie's pin in his final moments...
Thinking that he'd leave a clue about the culprit.
Right?
Yeah.
Since that man's saliva was on the necktie
pın as well, it could be a dying message!
"It could be"?
It's not a sure thing?
Well...
His saliva was on it, but there was no trace of it having been bitten.
That's why the pearl may have been loosely attached
ın such a way that it was easy to remove...
Or...
It could be that the culprit wanted to deliver a message...
And forced the victim to hold the pearl in his mouth on purpose.
Isn't that right, Heiji-niichan?
Yeah!
You two are getting along well as usual.
True, it's like he's Heiji's assistant!'
Enough with the "assistant"...
Well either way, it's the work of someone with
quite a grudge against the Inubushi family.
Since despite Shinichi-san having already given up his portion
of the Inubushi inheritance and returning to Tokyo...
He still was murdered by someone.
That's right.
The wealthy old Inubushi Tsunechika passed his
inheritance to his wife Satomi-san, who has fallen ill.
If the culprit's intention was to increase their own share of the
ınheritance by decreasing the number of adopted children...
It should have nothing to do with Shinichi-san.
If I recall correctly, there were eight adopted children, right?
Yeah.
Although they are all from different mothers.
So I think, perhaps one of the eight children may really be a fake...
Who only wants to satisfy some sort of grudge?
But...
One of the real children could also hold a grudge.
Given they were neglected for so many years.
And?
Out of those eight people, which ones are dead?
Let's see..
The one who was murdered in a way to look like
a charcoal-burning suicide was Shinichi-san.
Inubushi Miwako
Adopted Child of Inubushi
And before that, a lady by the name of
Miwako was found dead near a marsh.
Despite having no apparent heat source,
the grass around the marsh was burning.
And the first victim was a man by the name
of Keiji who fell off a cliff to his death.
Inubushi Keiji
Adopted Child of Inubushi
He said he was chased by a dog on fire.
If you're scared, you could have stayed home.
But...
After hearing a scary story, you naturally
want to find out what's behind it, right?
That's what I think as well...
But it is still scary!
Hey, hey.
Even if you want me to go back, it's too late to do that.
Stop, go back!
There's a cliff up ahead!
Hurry and stop!
So close...
Geez...
Didn't you see the sign posted a while back?
Do be careful!
Someone also fell and died not long ago, you know.
Ah, no...
We're actually on our way to the Inubushi
home in order to investigate that accident.
Inubushi Miyuki (28)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
I'm actually a member of that Inubushi family.
Wow...
It really does look like a Japanese castle.
I hear that people in this area even call it "Inubushi Castle".
It doesn't look like a manor that's been
cursed by a demon dog at all, does it?
You're right.
What!?
So cute!
An Akita Inu!
Stop it Hachi.
These people are a police officer and his companions
who have come to investigate Keiji-niisan's accident.
No, l'm not a police officer...
You're the one who should stop, Miyuki-san!
When a dog barks for no reason, and you call its name or pat it...
Inubushi Takako (47)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
The dog will mistakenly think it's being praised.
How many times do I have to say this?
I'm sorry, Takako-san.
And what business do you have with us, Officer?
A few days ago another officer came and
said "That was definitely an accident!"
Then he simply left, you know.
No, l'm not a polic—
Actually, something happened that made us
think it may not have been an accident...
So we came all the way here to get the whole story.
Right, Officer?
Look, you...
Could it be that they're talking about
Shinichi-san who died in Tokyo?
Maybe it's what Shinichi-san said before leaving this house.
That nonsensical story about someone using a cursed dog
engulfed in flames to root out all those with Inubushi blood?
But there is no curse, so don't worry.
Also, if our mother hears a story like that, she will be sad.
Is Satomi-san right here?
I thought she had been hospitalized...
She is here.
But she's bedridden and can barely speak at all...
She suffered a stroke.
Inubushi Satomi (74)
Head of the Inubushi Family
She's been like this ever since she collapsed a month ago.
It would've been better for her to have been hospitalized...
But since she's getting on in years, we decided to care for her here.
Inubushi Tomoaki (42)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
My name is Inubushi Tomoaki...
A general practitioner at the nearby Inubushi Hospital.
Then, could it be that you're also one of the eight adopted children?
Yes.
When the hospital I was employed at
shut down, I was left out in the cold.
That's when Mother Satomi rescued me.
So then?
Did Satomi-san say anything?
About who reeks of being an impostor.
Well, not in particular...
Couldn't that Shinichi guy have been an impostor himself?
Inubushi Yoshiya (34)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
He was so scared of rumors about that imaginary demon dog...
And left this Inubushi household — a traitor, that's why!
What's wrong with you, Yoshiya-san?
Don't use such uncouth words in Mother's presence!
She couldn't have heard me.
She's sleeping anyway, right?
There's one person left.
The eight adopted children!
There were three who died, right?
So there should be five remaining, but we only have...
Miyuki-san, Takako-san...
Tomoaki-san, and the guy outside...
Yoshiya-san, these four people here.
That's right.
There should be one more person.
Could it be that they sustained injuries to their
face and are wearing some sort of weird mask?
This is not The Inugami Clan!
That other person is Saki-san.
She went to the cleaners a Iittle way from here
to pick up some clothes we had sent out.
Then, how about some tea while we wait?
Since it'd be hard to hear the whole story without everyone here.
In that case, why not tell them the demon dog's myth
that's been passed down through the Inubushi family?
Myth?
They burned it!?
One of the ancestors of this family burned a dog?
Yeah...
It was originated in the Meiji era.
When the only daughter of the Inubushi family suddenly
went missing, they had everyone in the village search for her.
But the Inubushi family dog showed up unexpectedly.
It was grasping the daughter in its
jaws, gravely injured and near death.
The enraged master whipped the dog endlessly...
And on top of all that, set its body on fire.
But later, the daughter regained consciousness...
She told her father that the dog had come to her rescue
when she had gotten lost and collapsed in the mountains.
He regretted his actions, and erected a proper grave for the dog.
However...
A fire broke out a few days later and the only one
to not make it out in time and die was the master.
Since then, it's been said that the Inubushi
family has been cursed by a fiery demon dog.
It sounds just like a fairy tale.
So, does that grave really exist?
Yeah, it's below the cliff that your car
almost fell from this afternoon.
If you want, shall we go see it?
It's true...
It says it's Fusatarou's grave, the heroic
and beloved dog of the Inubushi family.
This being the case, whenever a fiery dog appears...
People probably think it's this Fusatarou's curse.
I'm paying my proper respects so I don't get cursed!
Me too...
There's no such thing as curses, you know!
Hey, about the cliff Keiji-san fell off from, could this be the one?
Yeah...
It was right above this grave...
Saki-san!
Hang in there, Saki-san!
Saki-san...
Is she the remaining adopted child!?
Inubushi Saki (35)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
Dog...
On fire...
A dog on fire!?
Kazuha, call the police and an ambulance!
We'll go with Uncle Kogorou in the car to the top of the cliff!
You can't leave us girls waiting here alone in a place like this!
If you want to go to the top of the cliff, it'd be
faster than by car if you used the animal trail!
If that's the casef lead the way!
Ran-neechan, you two wait here with Uncle Kogorou!
All right, the top of the cliff!
It's burning.
There's no smell of oil.
It's almost as if a fiery dog just passed through.
Yeah.
Flaming footprints, you say!?
You're saying that kind of weird thing was atop the cliff?
Yeah, that's right.
There were sets of scattered flames starting about
twenty meters back from the edge of the cliff.
It looked as if a fiery demon dog had run through.
But you didn't see an actual demon dog, did you?
I say someone must've scattered oil and set it aflame
to make it look like there really was a demon dog!
No...
There wasn't any scent of oil.
And the space between each fire got wider
as it got closer to the edge of the cliff...
The flames became larger as well.
It's as if whatever the burning object was
grew bigger as it passed through.
Isn't that right, Miyuki-san?
Yeah.
So it's true...
The cursed demon dog...
It really exists, right!?
Even Saki-san who fell from the cliff was saying "a dog's on fire"!
Moron!
There's no way something like a demon dog exists in this world.
It was a trick!
The culprit just did something clever to make
it seem as if there were a demon dog.
This way, they could put the blame on the demon dog for their crime.
Exactly!
We're in an era where TV broadcasting goes digital, yet
you're still worked up over something like a demon dog...
Did you totally fall off the wagon?
Inspector Yamamura!
Ah, that was a pun with digital and
did you totally that I just thought up!
Who's this guy?
He's with the Gunma prefectural police...
Despite everything.
We're in Gunma after all...
Well, excuse me...
How's Saki-san who just fell from the cliff?
Well, I only heard she was being
transported to a hospital by ambulance.
That was my hospital.
And they just contacted me on my cell phone.
She passed away in the ambulance...
No way!
I don't know who's pulling the strings behind that demon dog...
But sure looks like someone's trying
to mess with our Inubushi family.
That's right.
Given that out of the eight adopted children...
Half, or rather four of us are no longer here.
Sof for the time being...
Of the four of you remaining, can I hear the alibis of you three?
When Saki-san fell from that cliff around 7 PM,
what were you doing and your whereabouts?
Miyuki-san was with us at the bottom
of the cliff to see that dog's grave...
So her alibi is solid.
7:00 is around when I was taking a bath.
I went out for a bit to check on Saki-san,
because she shouldn't have been that late.
But even now, she still got lost quite often.
I was at Mother's side, taking her temperature and
blood pressure and giving her a liquid diet.
Although, I don't think she'll be able to
verify that given that she's bedridden.
You two also don't seem to have anyone who can verify your alibis.
Yeah...
We usually have three caretakers around,
but they've all gone home for a break.
Mouri-san!
Asking this is my duty as a police officer!
Please don't take my job from me!
Huh?
This gentleman...
He's not with the police?
I completely forgot to mention...
This gentleman here is Mouri Kogorou-san.
Mo...
Mouri...
Kogorou?
So you're the great detective Mouri Kogorou-san!?
Well, yeah...
What's this?
The atmosphere sure has changed.
We were just a bit surprised is all...
Before the late Shinichi-san left this household, he told us...
That he already asked an acquaintance
that was affiliated with the police...
To resolve the mysterious events unfolding in the Inubushi home...
And to brace ourselves.
But to think he was referring to the famous Sleeping Kogorou!
Well, I was actually the one he asked for, though...
By the way, on the day Shinichi-san was
murdered in his home in Tokyo...
Had, any of you happened to have gone to Tokyo?
All four of us did go to Tokyo.
We all went to persuade him to return to the Inubushi home.
Since he seemed to be suspecting one of us, we
also wanted to ask him what his reason was.
Well, he looked so scared and didn't tell us anything.
As if he stayed quiet precisely because one of us was the culprit.
We heard about Shinichi-san's death once we returned here
from Saki-san, who had been watching the house for us.
So the four of you were together the entire time in Tokyo?
No...
We went together, but came back separately.
Anyway will you let us know already?
About what, you learned from Shinichi-san's case.
Because you said there was something related to Keiji-san
and Miwako-san who had passed away earlier.
We don't know whether it's related or not...
But the murdered Shinichi-san had it in his mouth.
A pearl that had been attached to his necktie pin!
What's the matter?
Well...
There was also something lying next to Keiji-san
who had fallen from the cliff like Saki-san.
A pachinko bali!
Pachinko ball?
Because that old guy loved pachinko...
We thought it had simply fallen out of his pocket.
And then...
After that, on the ground near the marsh where Miwako-san died...
There was a ping pong ball.
Sphere, sphere, sphere...
So the pearl wasn't a dying message...
But rather, a message deliberately left by the culprit.
Then, could it be...
That was also the same?
We found it after Saki-san had been taken away in the ambulance.
The thing that had rolled next to the dog's grave — a marble!
A marble?
Do you have it with you?
We thought it was someone's offering,
so we put it on the grave and left.
Well then...
We're going to go take a look at that marble.
Would you like to come with us, Inspector?
I also have something l'd like to ask.
Kazuha, wait here quietly and be good!
Ran-neechan too!
But we want to go too!
We're the ones who found it, you know!
Well, you can tag along...
If you want to go meet the demon dog!
I see...
We'll wait...
Sorry for the trouble.
Barging in on all of you like this, and
even having you treat us to dinner...
It's all right, don't worry about it.
I wonder if Heiji and the others will be back before dawn...
Dunno...
Regardless, it'II be tough from now on.
The meal preparation and cleaning was mostly done by Saki-san...
Saki-san did all those...!
Is there anything we can do to help?
Well, can I have you guys feed Hachi?
Yes!
I asked Takako-san and the others, but they refused to do it.
Why's that?
But Takako-san seems like she's used to dealing with dogs!
Yeah.
I heard thatTakako-san raised dogs before
she came here, so she's familiar with them.
But it seems she's been busy making
calls regarding funeral arrangements.
Tomoaki-san was bitten by a dog a
long time ago, and is aversive to them.
Since he'd always tremble in fear, Hachi would bark at him a lot.
Yoshiya-san is allergic to dogs.
He said if a dog's near him, he can't
stop sneezing or having a runny nose.
That's why it was always Takako-san,
Saki-san, or myself who fed him.
But can you guys do it?
Sure, no problem.
Where's the doghouse?
It's a little far...
Far?
Do you mean it's outside the house...?
It's fine!
It's at the edge of the yard, but it's surrounded by a fence.
Even a demon dog couldn't get in!
I see...
It's quite a large yard, isn't it?
Is that the doghouse?
It is!
Hachi's there too.
Hachi, we've brought your dinner!
Don't leave anything behind.
So cute!
If only the demon dog were like this too...
What's wrong?
What's that?
Did something light up over there?
What I recall is that blue moonlight
Your retreating figure waved to me, as the light of the moon took you away that day
From my heart, from my heart, I want to tell you
I love you, I love you - a feeling that cannot be reached
Were it a dream, were it a dream, I could have met with you
Although my wishes cannot come true
Mischievous magic on the moonlit night - you're imprisoned in the shade of the moon
Like the new moon obscured by darkness, your figure escapes my sight
Even though you're so close
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Onion
Next Conan's Hint