So there was an incoming call to Saki-san's
cell phone from the Inubushi home?
Yeah, about two hours before she fell from the cliff.
Then, those four adopted children seem
even more suspicious, don't they?
Suddenly asking her to buy something while she was out...
So that the time of her return would be delayed.
And we can assume it was possible for the culprit to
order the dog attack on her after dark, can't we?
Shouldn't it be three people?
Miyuki san has an alibi after all.
Miyuki-san is also suspicious.
If she had wanted to get the dog to attack, she could've blown a
dog whistle without being discovered even while she was with us.
Plus the fact that Miyuki-san was directly below the cliff.
The only person in that house who isn't
suspicious is the bedridden old lady, Satomi-san.
Inubushi Satomi (74)
Head of the Inubushi Family
You...
Why have you been taking charge this whole time?
Are you one of Mouri-san's assistants like Conan-kun?
Well...
Something like that.
I said stop with the "assistant" thing...
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
The burning demon dog's footsteps...
And the mystery of the spheres that were left behind.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The sky I saw back then gave me a flashback For an instant, I felt you
Despite my heart nearly being shuttered, your face kept popping up in the sunset
Why why why Though I already knew I couldn't say it
Lie lie I want you to stay with me I want your love
tear drops Isn't right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? I can never forget our love
tear drops tear drops Solve this mystery tear drops
Overflowing with tears I think I've become a little more honest with myself
To the starry night, I say: "I believe, forever my dream"
Ouietly my tear drops
tear drops Isn't that right? You noticed it, didn't you?
tear drops Isn't that right? I'm crying, am I not?
tear drops Isn't that right? This is my last love
tear drops tear drops It's only for you that my tear drops
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
The household under a dog's curse...
The Inubushi family
The previous head of the household,
Tsunechika, died five years ago...
And his surviving widow, Satomi-san,
had been confined to bed as well.
If she were to pass away, the enormous Inubushi inheritance
would be divided amongst the eight adopted children.
But those adopted children began
to die by bizarre means, one by one.
We proceeded to investigate the case, but the
fourth victim appeared right before our very eyes.
What's more, the crime scene was dotted with
burning footprints that were left behind.
Could it be that the ablazed demon dog really exists?
The serial killings of the Inubushi family...
Has it truly been the work of a devilish, cursed canine?
(FOOTSTEPS CHAPTER)
INUBUSHI CASTLE
THE ABLAZED DEMON DOG
So cute!
If only the demon dog were like this too...
What's wrong?
What's that?
Did something light up over there?
Kazuha-chan!
Get up!
The entrance is right there!
What's wrong?
All this racket...
The demon dog!
The demon dog showed up in the backyard!
Demon dog?
That's ridiculous!
Inubushi Yoshiya (34)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
There's no way it could appear on the grounds of the house!
Inubushi Miyuki (28)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
Don't tell me...
It jumped over the fence and got on our property?
Inubushi Takako (47)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
No way...
That's just absurd!
Inubushi Tomoaki (42)
Adopted Child of Inubushi
In any case...
Let's not go outside for the time being
with it sounding so dangerous.
Hachi is barking...
Isn't Hachi in danger?
We need to bring Hachi inside!
Hold on, you two!
It's just an ordinary marble no matter how you look at it.
A pachinko ball, a ping-pong ball, a pearl bead...
And a marble?
Just what is the culprit trying to say?
It must mean that, that!
What comes to mind if I say "dogs" and "beads"?
Hey!
Don't tell me...
You just thought up another stupid pun, didn't you?
Whatever it may be, just tell us.
We're all ears.
It might even end up being a hint.
Nah...
It's stupid, so never mind.
Hey, now!
Don't start getting all uppity!
Say it!
Never!
I'm not going to say it!
Indeed...
There seem to be traces of the grass having been burnt.
The rope that was stretched around the
edge of the cliff had been cut, too.
What's more...
The sign was taken down, too.
The guidepost at the fork in the road a ways back had also fallen.
I see.
In this darkness and without the guide
post, sign and the protective rope...
If she had been chased by a dog...
İt wouldn't be a surprise that she'd fly off the edge of the cliff.
The only problem is the identity of the fiery demon
dog that is said to have attacked her, right?
There was no such thing as a demon dog in the first place!
It was a psychological trick.
By using the myth of the cursed dog from
the past and the flaming footprints...
The culprit simply made it look as if a real demon dog existed.
They must've used fluorescent paint
on the dog's body to make it glow.
Fluorescent paint, you say?
Yeah.
If something that doesn't normally light up is
glowing fiercely, you would think it was on fire.
Then, what about the flaming footprints?
There's no smell of oil, right?
Something like that...
They must've simply used a gas burner to light them one by one, no?
What is it, Kazuha?
It looks like we'll be here for a little while...
So go ahead to bed if you're feeling sleepy—
WHAT!?
The demon dog showed up at the house!?
Are you sure?
Are you sure that the dog was really on fire?
Yeah...
Right, Ran-chan?
It wasn't anything like fluorescent paint.
Although it's gone out now...
There were even flaming footprints from each step that dog took.
It's true...
There are burn marks that match the ones above the cliff.
And, where did that dog come from?
From over that way.
These footprints are strange.
See, judging by the interval between the footsteps,
there should also be some prints around here.
But this is the only place that had a wide gap.
Not to mention only this part of the ground was disturbed.
Isn't that where you fell, Kazuha-chan?
About the time when I fell...
I smelled some sort of strange odor.
A strange odor?
What kind?
Something like a rotten onion...
An odor that was harsh on the nose.
Onion?
Also...
After we took refuge inside the house, we
immediately went back outside to take a look.
But they looked as if they were alive.
Of course that's the case.
The dog attacked you, after all.
Oh, no...
Not the demon dog, but the flaming footprints.
They hopped around as if they were dancing,
and made crackling and popping noises.
Kazuha-chan saw it too, right?
I did, I did.
It was almost as if the footprints were possessed by spirits as well!
But to think you dared going back outside...
Wasn't the demon dog supposed to be still around?
We knew that, but we were worried about Hachi.
We thought it might be eaten by the demon dog.
Regarding the demon dog's infiltration route, I've found it.
It was the back door.
It was unlatched and left wide open...
And there were dog prints as well.
In short...
The culprit who brought the demon dog onto
this property through the backdoor was...
Someone who was in this house.
It's highly probable that it was among these four people!
Since it'd be impossible for Satomi-san to
have done it because she's bedridden.
Say, Ran-neechan, you guys.
You said you came to the backyard in order to give Hachi its food...
But who asked you to do that?
It was Miyuki-san.
But...
It was because she said she was turned down by the other three.
Perhaps it could be easily predicted that we'd
be the ones taking the dog food out.
However, it is clear that someone has been raising
the demon dog somewhere near this house.
That's right.
If it wasn't nearby...
The culprit wouldn't have been able to set the dog on Ran-neechan's
party, who had suddenly been asked to do the feeding.
Do you happen to have any clues?
Such as hearing the barking of a dog in the forest or something.
Now that you mention it...
Miwako-san, who was the second to pass away,
told me about it and we went to inspect it once.
She said there was a strange cabin
where she could hear a dog barking.
Although we were too afraid to actually go inside.
What'd you say!?
Where was that!?
I think it was near the marsh where Miwako-san died...
Lead us to there immediately!
Immediately?
If we go immediately, we may be able to
find out the trick behind the demon dog!
That's right.
If the culprit is among you, you wouldn't
have had time to destroy the evidence yet.
But, I...
I am on duty tonight, so I need to get back to the hospital.
Soon as we finish investigating the cabin, I'll give you a ride there!
Not to mention you may be afraid of going through
that forest to get to the hospital by yourself!
However...
I merely followed Miwako-san at the time.
As far as where that marsh is...
If it's just to the marsh, I can show you the way.
Since I know my way around the forest...
And it's not that far from here!
So this is the marsh...
Hey...
Is it true that the area around this marsh was on fire?
Yeah
Although we merely found burn marks here and there.
And?
Where's the cabin you spoke of?
Let's see...
Over there!
It's that old cabin over there!
Then, let's advance into the demon dog's lair!
Please watch your step.
This marsh seems to be bottomless.
You're not coming?
There's no reason I should go, right?
I'll just wait inside the car!
That so?
Hey, hey...
What the hell is this?
There are black magic books all over the place!
Even a magic circle is drawn here on the floor.
There's no mistake that someone had been keeping a dog here.
But, who could it be?
Whoever it was placed a curse upon the dog here!
Moron!
If you could kill someone using a curse,
detectives would go out of business!
But Ran-san's art said the saw it...
Like—we—said...
That was some sort of trick...
What!?
Don't struggle!
Stay still!
Is he all right!?
Only suffered a slight burn.
However...
What we saw just now...
Was the demon dog, right...?
It showed up again!?
You're saying the demon dog showed up again!?
Yeah.
This makes for the third appearance tonight alone.
Was that dog really on fire?
Wasn't that just some sort of trick?
Well, it crossed our minds, but...
No matter how you look at it...
I think it's true that it was burning.
Its body was engulfed in flickering flames to begin with...
And where that dog ran, flaming footprints would be left behind.
Also, Tomoaki-san's arm was on fire
when the demon dog attacked him...
And he suffered a burn!
Are you all right?
I applied some first aid with the medical
supplies I had in my bag, but...
I had to call the hospital and get someone else to
take my place as the on-duty doctor for tonight.
However, why did you get out of the car?
Because I got scared while waiting all alone...
Anyway, the problem is what had fallen next to
Tomoaki-san after the demon dog attacked him...
This onion!
A round thing again?
What's the meaning of that?
Speaking of which, Kazuha-chan, you mentioned it right?
When you fell as we were running from the demon dog...
That you smelled something like a rotten onion.
Could it be that the demon dog and the onion are somehow related?
Well?
Do the police have any leads regarding the culprit
that's been pulling the strings behind the demon dog?
We did plan to call forensics in to investigate that
suspicious cabin first thing in the morning, but...
We probably won't be able to arrest the culprit.
Why not!?
BECAUSE!
Our opponent is a black magic sorcerer who
can place curses on dogs, remember!?
There's no way that normal mortals like we
police officers could have the upper hand!
To tell the truth, I'd like to get away
from this place as soon as possible!
"Black magic"!?
There were a lot of those in the cabin.
Plenty of books like that.
I'm asking just in case, but...
When we encountered that demon dog...
None of you had left this house, right?
I was on the phone making arrangements
for Saki-san's funeral the whole time.
I was chatting on the computer with my surv game buddies.
Surv game?
You mean survival games?
Yeah.
I'm an instructor at a nearby campground.
Once a month, me and my buddies
would do survival games together.
Then, you're familiar with the forests around here as well.
Sorta...
But, not as well as Miyuki who often
gathered wild plants with Mama Satomi.
And Satomi-san was still—?
Yeah.
I believe she'd been sleeping in that room.
By the way...
Where are Conan-kun and Hattori-kun?
We haven't seen them for a while.
They're probably stupefied from the shock
and loafing around somewhere, no?
Since they were convinced the demon dog was a trick...
But ended up witnessing it with their very own eyes.
There they are.
They're really at a loss.
Just forget all that bad stuff!
Right, right!
There are bizarre things in this world that you can never
comprehend, no matter how much you think about it!
Bizarre things that I can never comprehend?
What do you mean?
What else, the demon dog!
You guys saw it too, right, Heiji?
That monster was on fire!
Dad said you guys even looked closely
at where the flaming foorprints were!
As far as the flaming footprints trick goes...
Based on the smell resembling a rotten onion
Kazuha noticed when she tripped...
And what Ran-neechan saw immediately
after the demon dog disappeared...
The flames making crackling noises and hopping
around —
we've pretty much figured out!
Since the flaming footprints always
went on for about twenty meters...
And some kind of drag marks were left on the ground, too!
However, what we're really bothered by is...
That fiery body.
How did the culprit manage to set a fire on the dog that was
strong enough to burn Tomoaki-san when it pounced him?
If a cloth were put around a dog's body and set ablaze...
There should've been a charred dog corpse somewhere in the area.
And if the culprit had used water or a fire
extinguisher to put the flames out...
There should've been traces left behind, right?
If they waited in a truck for the dog to come back,
and put out the fire on the loading bed...
There wouldn't be any evidence left, but...
There were no tire tracks in the area, and
we didn't hear the sound of an engine.
What's more, where did the dog disappear to?
If it was on fire, when we rushed to Tomoaki-san's aid...
We should have been able to see where it went.
So, the dog wasn't there?
Right.
Almost as if it had been devoured by the darkness.
It was devoured?
You're saying it was eaten by the darkness?
So you want to eat?
Eat!?
I mean dinner...
If you want to eat, shall I reheat it?
I'll have some!
So hungry!
Then, I'll hurry.
There's something I want to ask.
Does anything come to mind when I say balls or beads?
Balls?
The culprit always leaves behind a
spherical object at the scene, right?
Is there some sort of link between this Inubushi home and spheres?
When you say "sphere", what comes to mind is that...
My former surname was "Tamaki", and that's about it.
Not to mention my nickname back when I was a kid was Tama-chan.
Tama-chan?
But don't make me out to be the culprit just because of that.
Especially considering I'm not referred to by that nickname here.
And do you know anything about the others' previous surnames?
No...
Since I was the last to come here and become an adopted child.
Come to think of it, you're quite a bit
younger than the others, right Miyuki-san?
Yeah.
It seems I was conceived when my father,
President Tsunechika, was in his mid fifties.
And my first name was supposed to be "Chikae",
with a kanji taken from my father's name.
But my mother disliked it, so I got the name I'm using instead.
Because my mother hated my father...
Saying she had been duped and dumped by a rich man.
In that case, why did you come here?
If you heard all those complaints from your
mother, shouldn't you be upset as well?
To tell the truth, I had no intention of coming here as well, but...
A little after my mother passed away due to illness...
I received a letter from Father.
Letter?
"My time is drawing near.
"If you would be so kind as to forgive me...
Come to the Inubushi Manor and protect
the princess for me," he wrote.
And I also heard all the other adopted
children received similar letters.
Regarding the "princess"...
Who is that?
Wouldn't it mean Miyuki-san?
She has "princess" in her name, you see.
Moron.
Would he write a letter to the princess
herself asking her to protect the princess?
I didn't know who it was at first, either...
But once I came here, I immediately
realized it meant Mother Satomi.
Because all the caretakers have been calling Mother a "princess".
Why is she the princess?
They said it was because Father had always called her that.
Although Mother would always jokingly tell them
to stop because she was embarrassed by that.
Could it be because this manor is like a castle?
Right, right!
I bet President Tsunechika felt like he was a feudal lord!
And, about my name...
It was supposed to be written as a single "kou"
kanji, and then to be read as Miyuki, but...
I followed Mother's recommendation...
And added the "princess" kanji.
So I wasn't originally a princess.
You changed your name?
Yeah.
Mother asked me to become a princess just like
her and live happily in this castle, that's why.
Speaking of names...
There are interesting stories regarding how we were named.
Your names, you say?
The culprit is likely to be among the remaining adopted children.
Someone who controlled a fiery demon dog and
assaulted the Inubushi family members one by one...
But who on earth is it?
What I recall is that blue moonlight
Your retreating figure waved to me, as the light of the moon took you away that day
From my heart, from my heart, I want to tell you
I love you, I love you - a feeling that cannot be reached
Were it a dream, were it a dream, I could have met with you
Although my wishes cannot come true
Mischievous magic on the moonlit night - you're improsoned in the shade of the moon
Like the new moon obscured by darkness, your figure escapes my sight
Even though you're so close
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Prayer Beads
Next Conan's Hint
When something
like a fiery dog
appears, you
should go bite it!
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT EPISODE
What? Scary!
Hot dog!
Hold on...