Speaking of names...
There are interesting stories
regarding how we were named.
Regarding your names?
Shinichi-san, who passed away in Tokyo...
KU  DOU  SHIN  ICHI
Said his real mother was forced to change his name
right before she submitted his registration of birth.
Right before?
Yeah.
At first, it was supposed to be written as the single
character for "benevolence" and pronounced Hitoshi.
HITOSHI
Why was it changed?
If I recall correctly, Shinichi-san said he heard it was changed
because our father thought Hitoshi would be too simple.
I guess it's true that Hitoshi would have
only a few strokes and would be simple.
And...
TAKA      KO
If Takako-san were a boy, the name would've had the characters
for "ponder" and "season" with the reading of Kouki.
KOU       KI
YOSHI      YA
If Yoshiya-san were a girl, it would've been the kanji
for "blessing" and "flower" pronounced Yuuka.
YUU
KA
TOMO    AKI
If Tomoki-san were a girl, it would've been
"know" and "spring" and read as Chiharu.
CHI     HARU
Are all of those really names that
President Tsunechika came up with?
Yeah.
The ones who have passed away — Keiji-san,
Miwako-san, and Saiki-san — all said so too.
KEI      JI
MI  WA  KO
SA      KI
Then it looks like there's some sort of secret in their names.
Yeah.
But, is it true?
The rumor that the culprit is one of us adopted children...
And is using the demon dog with the intention
of rooting out the Inubushi bloodline?
We don't know about that yet...
But we do know it's true that someone is
using a trick to commit serial murders.
And a clue to the mechanism behind the demon dog...
Has been picked up by us!
What's with that piece of cloth?
It was on the ground next to where Tomoaki-san
had been attacked by the demon dog.
There's no trace of it having been
burned, nor is there any smell of oil...
But there's no doubt it was used for something.
If you picked up that sort of evidence...
Why didn't you hand it over to the police officer immediately?
Takako-san...
We were just now thinking of handing it over.
Also, Miyuki-san...
You left the kettle unattended on the stove!
I'm sorry!
I meant to go back immediately...
Well, maybe we should go eat dinner right now.
That's right.
And before we eat, tell us what the people
who had stayed in the house were doing.
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
Every mystery shall be solved!
The final chapter of the Demon Dog series!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The former head of the Inubushi family,
Tsunechika, died five years ago...
And his surviving widow, the current head
Satomi-san, had been confined to bed as well.
If she were to pass away, the enormous inheritance
would be divided amongst the eight adopted children.
But those adopted children began
to die by bizarre means, one by one.
Were these caused by the fiery demon dog's curse
that's been tormenting the Inubushi family?
And finally, the demon dog appeared right in front of our very eyes.
What's the identity of the monster that was engulfed
in flames and had been attacking people?
Who on earth is controlling the demon dog?
Hey, Ran-chan...
Do you get this question?
So it says the hint is "Try thinking about
it after putting on glasses," right?
What are you two doing?
We're watching the midnight rerun of a quiz show.
It's really interesting!
Why not go to bed?
It's already past 1:00.
Aren't the futons already laid out in the guest room?
Because, when we think about the demon dog being around here...
We get scared and can't sleep!
Look, you...
Well then, can you solve this code?
Thirty seconds left!
If you solve it, we'll go to sleep!
Maybe Conan-kun can solve it.
He's wearing glasses, too!
Look here—the hint is glasses, or megane...
****************
Q18.
(Try thinking about it after putting on glasses!)
SOLVE THIS CODE
YA ME U RA NO ME KO
For this code, just turn all the "me" into "ne".
YA NE U RA NO NE KO
The cat in the attic!
I see!
ga
Since it's "me becomes ne"...
It makes sense if we change the "me" to "ne" and then read it!
I see...
This was the trick behind the demon dog!
Which means the culprit is...
None other than that person.
Mother...
Mother collapsed!?
Yeah.
It seems she snuck out of her futon.
So when Takako-san heard a strange sound
from the hallway and came to this room...
She had already collapsed in front of the bureau?
Yeah...
I only went to the restroom for a short while...
But how could this happen?
There are some things rolling around.
They're prayer beads.
Tears?
Hey, you...
She's grasping onto eight beads.
Only the fourth one from her thumb is a small heavenly bead.
Beads...
Eight...
Dog...
That's it!
It's that folklore!
In other words, Satomi-san already knew...
Which of these people is the serial murderer!
Hey...
Kazuha-chan.
Kazuha-chan, wake up.
What's wrong?
Can you come to the restroom with me?
Sure.
Geez!
You aren't a kid anymore.
Can't you at least go to the loo by yourself?
But...
We were just attacked by the demon dog in the backyard!
We shudder at the thought that it may
appear inside the house this time!
And why are you awake, my brave sir?
It's bothering you too, right, Dad?
You saw the demon dog after all.
Sorta...
It looks like the brat with glasses and the detective kid from Osaka...
Are sleeping without a care in the world, though.
But of course.
Because they said something like they knew who the culprit is.
They figured out the culprit!?
Are you saying they figured out the serial killer
who's mixed in with the adopted children?
Yeah.
Although they wouldn't tell us who.
It seemed they were able to discern some clues after
hearing about the names of the adopted children.
Hearing about their names?
TAMA    KI
Like how Miyuki-san's former surname was Tamaki...
KOU    KI
And that if Takako-san were a boy, the name would've had the
kanji for "ponder" and "season" with the reading of Kouki.
YUU    KA
And if Yoshiya-san were a girl, it would've been the kanji
for "blessing" and "flower", pronounced Yuuka.
CHI    HARU
If Tomoaki-san were a girl, it would've been
"know" and "spring" and read as Chiharu.
One more thing.
HITOSHI
Shinichi-san, who passed away in Tokyo...
Was supposed to have his name written as the single
character for "benevolence" and pronounced Hitoshi.
I bet it probably had something to do with the
prayer beads Satomi-san was grasping earlier.
She was grasping prayer beads?
They say she deliberately snuck out of her futon and grasped
onto the prayer beads that were inside the bureau.
Furthermore, she cut the string in order
to allow just eight beads to remain.
Beads...
Eight...
Was that some kind of fortune-telling?
But is there a type of fortune-telling that uses eight beads?
No, it's not fortune-telling.
It's a folklore.
A folklore?
We have eight beads and a demon dog.
Add in the names of everyone in the Inubushi family...
And it's got to be Nansou Satomi Hakkenden!
Hakkenden?
Wait, what's that?
hakken
Is it a story about discovering something?
You don't know about it?
Written by the literary master of the Edo period, Takizawa Bakin...
It's a well-known long epic novel!
Satomi Yoshizane, having his castle
besieged and assailed by the enemies...
Told his pet dog Yatsufusa:
"If you bring me back the head of their general,
I'll let you marry my daughter Fusehime."
Surprisingly, Yatsufusa snuck into the enemy camp, decapitated
their general, and actually returned with his head.
Fusehime thus said, "Even though it is a dog,
we cannot go back on a promise as a ruler..."
And ended up secluding herself in the mountains with Yatsufusa.
That's how the prologue goes.
What the heck is with that dog?
Was it cursed?
Exactly.
In fact, Yoshizane had become the castle lord by executing
a treacherous retainer who had killed the previous lord.
And the traitor's wife, Tamazusa, left this
final message as she was being beheaded.
"Even as my body is destroyed, my soul
shall turn into a vengeful spirit...
"And curse the Satomi clan through all eternity!"
So, the curse Tamazusa muttered was placed on the dog?
Yeah.
Though the curse put upon Yatsufusa was undone...
Thanks to Fusehime's unceasing
efforts of reading buddhist scriptures.
And?
What happened to the princess and the dog after that?
Yoshizane ordered his retainers to kill
the cursed dog and rescue the princess.
But Fusehime shielded Yatsufusa
from the attack and died as a result.
Just then...
Eight of the prayer beads the princess had
on her were scattered to the heavens.
And the odysseys of the eight swordsmen with names having the
kanji for "dog" and blessed by the beads in various regions...
EIGHT DOG CHRONICLES
Nansou Satomi Hakkenden
Was described in Nansou Satomi Eight Dog Chronicles.
But, what does that have to do with the names?
Engraved in each of the eight prayer beads
were one of these characters, you see.
Benevolence, justice, courtesy, wisdom,
loyalty, faith, filial piety, and respect.
The characters for the eight virtues!
But, the Inubushi family members don't
have those kanji in their names.
Although Shinichi-san was named Hitoshi
with the meaning of "benevolence"...
It was changed because they say it was too simple.
It wasn't because it was too simple.
Rather, it was avoided since it was too obvious!
SHIN        ICHI
If you take the man radical from Shin, and add
the two upper horizontal lines from Ichi...
JIN
BENEVOLENCE
You'll get the Jin character, see?
It's true!
I see!
Instead of directly using the kanji, they were
split into parts and placed into the names!
Takako-san would have the top part of the
"ponder" kanji put together with the Ko...
To form Kou meaning filial piety.
If she had been a boy, the name Kouki
would have the same parts too.
So then...
Yoshiya-san has the show radical and the
last swoosh of the Ya character to form...
Rei, or courtesy!
As for Tomoaki-san, by removing the
bottom part of the Aki character...
You get Chi like in Akechi Kogorou!
The murdered Keiji-san would be Chuu.
Miwako-san would be Gi.
Saki-san would be Shin.
And President Tsunechika would
become the Tei character, so to speak.
Then, the reason Satomi-san is called princess is...
Because the woman radical from the bottom
of Sa in addition to the second kanji...
Will form the kanji for princess?
You're right!
I bet President Tsunechika must have
really loved the Eight Dog Chronicles...
So he inserted the kanji on the
beads into the names of his children!
But, what about Miyuki-san?
What virtue kanji is she?
I recall that before she became an adopted child, her name was
Miyuki but written with just the one kanji from happiness.
If that's the case, the culprit is ascertained.
TAMA         KI          MIYUKI
Combining her former surname of Tamaki...
With the Miyuki character with one of the top lines removed...
TAMA       ZUSA
We get Tamazusa.
It's the name of the evil spirit that cursed the Satomi clan...
In the Eight Dog Chronicles!
No way!
Are you saying Miyuki-san is the serial murderer who's been
controlling the demon dog and killing the Inubushi people?
Yeah.
Roleplaying as Tamazusa, each time she killed the adopted
children representing the eight dog swordsmen...
She would leave a sphere behind as a symbol at the crime scene.
That's just nonsense!
Miyuki-san is a good person!
Just because she's a good person
doesn't mean she can't be the culprit.
No way!
Heiji!
Heiji, say it isn't true!
Miyuki-san isn't the culprit, right?
Huh?
Heiji isn't here.
Conan-kun isn't here either!
No way!
Hey...
Did Miyuki-san mention she was going to do something tonight?
She did say she was going to stay up all night
and watch over Satomi-san in her room.
So that she wouldn't sneak out of her futon again.
What!?
Miyuki-san has disappeared, you say!?
I reckoned that overnight care taking was tough...
So I entered this room to offer to take turns,
but instead I found this letter left here.
Letter?
I will atone for all the crimes I committed at
the cabin where I raised the demon dog.
Miyuki.
No way!
It can't be!
Miyuki-san is...
The culprit...
Why did she do it?
That scooter...
Isn't that Miyuki-san's?
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me the gasoline's leaking out!
So?
Who's going to check things out?
I don't want to!
I shall also decline.
Mr. Detective, why don't you go?
If Heiji were here, I bet he'd be the one charging in first...
Right...
I wonder where Conan-kun ran off to as well?
Demon dog!
It's here!
It's headed to the cabin!
Hey!
If it sets off the gasoline, the cabin will...
Conan-kun!?
Don't!
Run away!
Hey, it's all right.
Don't be afraid.
Huh?
It's not burning...
So it's just emitting a red light?
And what is that?
The ragged cloth around the dog's body...
It's imitation fire.
Heiji!
Imitation fire?
IMITATION FIRE
It was also on the set of that quiz
show you were watching too, right?
****************
Q18.
(Try thinking about it after putting on glasses!)
SOLVE THIS CODE
YA ME U RA NO ME KO
Blowing wind over shiny pieces of cloth with red LED
lights affixed to them creates the fake fire effect.
It's the same for that dog.
It was covered in cloth so that the cloth fluttered when it ran.
Red lights were set up under the cloth, and that's
why it really looked like it was a fiery demon dog.
If the lights were turned off via remote control, the dog
would be able to disappear instantly from our view.
Then, what about these flaming footprints?
Take a close look.
They're just disposable lighters that had the gas
outlet manipulated so that it would stay lit...
And strung on a piano wire, that's all.
Then...
The odor I smelled when I fell was the gas from the lighters?
Yeah.
Gas is originally odorless and therefore dangerous...
So they added a scent similar to that of rotten onions.
At the time you guys were chased by that
demon dog at the Inubushi house...
Because you fell, you forced the lighter into the ground.
That's why it was the only place where
the flaming footprints were absent.
But, no matter how much the gas comes out, if it's not on fire...
The spark for the flames was this charcoal enclosed
in wire mesh that was attached to the dog's tail.
When the dog passed over the lighters while
wearing this, they'd quickly catch on fire.
And I bet the dog had not been attacking people...
But rather, it was chasing the scent of the gas the
culprit laid on the ground, don't you think?
But, after we were attacked in the backyard at the house...
There weren't any lighters on the ground.
The dog was trained to return home while
biting the end of the piano line.
After the demon dog disappeared, the flames were hopping
around with a crackling and popping sound because of that.
Because the dog was dragging the piano wire with
all those lighters attached while it was running...
The lighters would have hit the rough surface
of the ground, causing said effects.
But when Tomoaki-san was attacked by the dog, there
were flames on his arm and he suffered burns, right?
Of course he'd suffer burns.
That's because you purposely set yourself on fire.
In order to make people think the demon dog was actually burning.
Then, Tomoaki-san is the culprit?
But, weren't you attacked by the demon dog?
The pet dog was simply trained to
jump on his master — you — in joy.
When we were investigating the cabin, he took out the piano wire
with the lighters attached from his bag and laid them out...
And he used a dog whistle to call the dog out
from the real doghouse somewhere near here.
Then, when he and the dog came together and
fell in the blind spot of the embankment...
He turned off the lights on the dog, had it
return home, and set fire to his own arm.
And the onion meant to misrepresent the odor that
Kazuha smelled was placed at that time as well!
Then, Miyuki-san's letter saying she'd
atone for the crimes here was...
That was written by Tomoaki-san.
In order to set Miyuki-san up as the culprit.
If that's the case, where is Miyuki-san?
She was put to sleep inside that cabin,
so we moved her to another location.
It's because Miyuki-san was looking for
something here along with Tomoaki-san.
I bet she was asked to help look for Satomi-san's medicine that
you supposedly dropped when you were attacked by the dog.
Were you watching us?
Yeah.
Because we've been trailing you from
the house, we immediately realized it.
The reason you drugged Miyuki-san
to sleep and took her to this cabin...
Was to make it look like she committed
suicide by fire along with the demon dog!
No...
No use trying to play dumb.
Dogs never forget their masters.
And the reason Hachi barks at you is
probably because you smell like this dog.
Plus, Satomi-san already knows everything.
Well, since you lied about your alibi of
watching over her the entire time...
Of course your lies would be exposed.
The reason why Satomi-san was grading the eight prayer beads,
with the fourth one from the top being a black heavenly bead...
Was because among Jin, Gi, Re, Chi,
Chuu, Shin, Kou, Tei, the fourth was...
Chi, meaning you were the culprit with this name.
And as for the reason Satomi-san
had tears rolling down her cheek...
Was because she hoped you'd be the first to
discover the beads and turn yourself in, wasn't it?
All in the order to not let your crimes accumulate any further.
With the Inubushi Manor resembling a castle so much...
I don't want to let go of it!
But since the inheritance tax was skyhigh...
I had to do it in order to increase my inheritance share.
Mama Satomi, whom I felt even closer to than my
own mother, had been keeping her memories...
In this very castle.
And this very castle is the last thing I want to let go...
Yeah, the credit is all mine again!
He coughed up everything as he was
crying in the interrogation room.
He said he killed those four who didn't
help out with maintaining the castle.
But, didn't Shinichi-san give up his share of the inheritance?
That wasn't because of the inheritance...
But in order to make it seem like a crime
caused by Tamazusa's curse, he said.
It seems he really thinks that Miyuki-san was Tamazusa's
reincarnation who had come to destroy this castle.
Since the time Satomi-san collapsed was in the middle
of her wild vegetable gathering with Miyuki-san.
No way...
I shall protect it!
This castle.
Miyuki-san...
Since I am, after all...
A princess of this castle, just like Mother!
Well, unlike Mother...
You're quite an unrefined princess!
Please don't say that!
Geez!
No, they're the same.
If you combine the fushi kanji from Inubushi...
And the hime kanji from her name...
Both of them would be Fusehime.
Next Conan's Hint
Map
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Next time, at a villa where piano sounds can be heard...
We'll take on a challenge regarding a diary's secret!