Hey, this is bad!
Does this mean the culprit's still here!?
Regardless, let's get out of here!
But, we have to save that boy!
Hey, you guys!
Don't you dare leave my side!
Right.
Split up and you're out.
You might even end up exactly like that boy.
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
Reverberating in a villa where there's not a soul to be seen...
Are the sounds of a piano and diary's secret!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
April 24th
Sir, this is no good.
The oil started leaking and caused your engine to fry.
It won't run unless you take it to a repair shop and get it fixed.
For now...
We'll tow it off with our wrecker.
Hey, are you going to just leave us here?
Good point...
I would've suggested you to take public
transportation to get back in the city.
But...
I guess you're unlikely to find any buses
or taxis in the mountains like this.
You mean we gotta walk all the way down the mountain?
That's a pretty considerable distance!
Couldn't you just give us a lift in your car?
Well, we could if it was just a single adult, but...
We can't take all of you along.
Then, why not just give the professor a ride?
You can just have them take you back to the
city, and come back for us in a rental car.
It'd only require about an hour round-trip!
You're right!
Then, if you guys can all just wait patiently.
Well, since the professor left...
It's been an hour and a half.
He's so late.
Maybe he got lost or something.
That's indeed a possibility.
I'm hungry...
Our bamboo shoot picking trip turned out to be a disaster.
Even though we picked a lot.
And we were supposed to have bamboo
shoot rice at the professor's place tonight!
It's raining.
Seriously!?
We didn't bring an umbrella!
Come to think of it, we passed by some villas in the car earlier...
Why don't we ask them to let us take shelter?
You're right.
Hey, Conan...
Doesn't look like anyone's here.
Because it's the off-season.
That's true.
It's gotten pretty dark.
Let's just get under an overhang for the time being.
So?
You still can't get hold of the professor?
I've been calling him for a while...
But it seems like he didn't turn it on.
It's from the professor's house.
Hey, what the hell are you doing, Professor?
Sorry, sorry...
I didn't want to lose things while we
were digging up bamboo shoots...
So I left my wallet and cell phone in Ai-kun's
backpack but had forgotten about it.
Then I came back home to get the
money, which is what's taken so long.
I'll be there with a rental car now, so
please hold on for about two hours!
What he said.
We have to wait two more hours!?
No way!
Geez!
And the rain's coming down harder now!
Be patient.
Getting upset won't get your stomach filled.
She's right!
The sound of a piano...
I can hear it.
It's coming from that house!
We've heard that song before, right?
That so?
I've heard it played with a violin before.
What song was that again?
Conan-kun, do you know?
Nah, I only know a little about music...
Composed by Johann Sebastian Bach...
It's in the orchestral suite number three in D major...
Second movement, "Air".
Better known as...
"Air on the G String".
Now that's the name I've heard of before!
This performer is as skilled as a pro.
Well then, let's go ask if we can take shelter there!
You think they'll make bamboo shoot rice for us?
That's really pushing it...
The sound of the piano stopped.
I hope it's a kind person!
No one's coming.
Nobody's answering the intercom, either.
How strange.
The door isn't locked!
Sorry for intruding!
We just want to take shelter from the rain!
It's pitch black...
I wonder why the lights aren't on?
I think I stepped on something!!
A potato chip?
There's a bunch scattered all over the hallway.
It seems they have an ill-mannered child around.
Hey!
Come over here, guys!
I found the piano!
But, if someone was playing the piano,
why didn't they come and greet us?
They may not have actually been playing it.
Since there's all sorts of audio equipment and CDs around...
It could be that they were just playing a CD here.
It was too skillful anyway.
Nah...
There's no doubt that the sound came from this piano.
Because the performance earlier...
Had this exact note that's slightly out of tune.
As usual, you have sharp ears despite
the fact that you can't hold a tune.
Lay off me.
How about Ayumi plays something for you guys?
The Flea Waltz
I can play "I Stepped On The Cat"!
Stop it, they'll get angry.
Regardless, we need to find the house owner...
Mitsuhiko-kun?
There was a tall person peering at us
through the window of that door!
Then, wouldn't that be the owner?
We should say hello!
It's stuck on something...
A push cart?
Hey, didn't we leave the hallway lights on?
Yeah...
Does that mean someone turned it off?
Could it be they're planning to trap us inside!?
It can't be...
Excuse us!
We're not strange people, you know!
Please come out!
The lights are on in that room!
You're right.
Maybe someone's in there!
Looks like the kitchen.
But, what's with all of this on the table?
Lots of crumbs from fried food, bread, and ham!
Looks as if a dog or something was eating it.
The owner appears to be quite wild.
They even left the wine glass toppled over.
A notebook?
Does this belong to the owner of this villa?
April 20th, sunny.
After I tried talking to him, he seemed like a good kid.
He smiles often and plays a lot.
Now, I don't know whether he understands
the situation he's in or not...
But I bet this kid has also spent countless
days living under great pressure.
Anyway, only two days left.
Just have to hold on until then.
April 22nd, cloudy.
Bach, Mozart, Chopin, Beethoven...
Your melodies make my heart quiver.
Born in the same era with such genius...
Your talents make me jealous.
Although they're not songs appropriate to play in this situation...
At least they can make me forget the time.
Just one more day.
Please let it pass without incident.
April 23rd, rainy.
This is bad.
It seems this young boy somehow knows who I am.
If this is revealed, it would be a hindrance in the future.
It's a pity, but looks like I have no choice but to kill him.
Kill!?
What does it mean by that!?
Probably a kidnapping.
Someone had kidnapped a young-aged boy...
And held him prisoner in this house.
No way!
What's written on the next page!?
The pages are stuck together and I can't peel them apart...
A blackout!?
Never mind that, the page just now
had something red on it, didn't it!?
Was that blood!?
What's more, it reads...
"Boy, I'm sorry.
"Forgive me."
The sound of the piano!
It's the song from earlier!
This is bad!
Does this mean the culprit's still here!?
Regardless, let's get out of here!
But, we have to save that boy!
Hey, wait!
You guys, don't you dare leave my side!
Right.
Split up and you're out.
You might even end up exactly like that boy.
A coffin!?
Hey...
If I recall, "Air on the G String" didn't enter the limelight until...
A hundred years after Bach's death.
Perhaps that's how long they intended to let him sleep here.
That is, to let that boy sleep inside this coffin.
Conan...
What do we do with this?
Well, for the time being...
I need to open it and take a look.
Please hold on for a moment!
From the contents of the diary we found earlier...
We know that someone had kidnapped
a small boy and confined him here.
And because it seemed the child knew who his captor
was, there was no choice but to kill him, right?
Yeah.
Furthermore, the last page of the diary had something red on it...
And written on it was: "Boy, I'm sorry. Forgive me:"
Then, inside that coffin...
Wouldn't it be that kid's corpse?
Yeah.
That's possible.
No way...
Hey, Haibara.
Keep those guys away for me.
This isn't something for kids to see.
Right.
Hey!
Aren't you a kid, too?
Don't ask, just go!
It's empty.
There's nothing inside.
Thank goodness!
In that case, there's a possibility that the little boy is still alive.
If he had been killed, they would've
wanted to put him in the coffin quickly.
No reason they'd take their time playing the piano.
In any case, let's call the police.
Do any of you have your cell phone?
I accidentally left mine with my backpack earlier.
I did as well...
Ayumi too...
Me too...
Hey, don't tell me you left them...
Where we first went after entering this villa...
Again!
That song from earlier...
Air on the G String.
Why did everyone leave their stuff in the piano room?
Because you left yours, Conan-kun!
So we followed suit too...
We had no choice!
Regardless, let's go to the piano room
together and take back our cell phones!
All right!
Don't be silly.
You don't even know what kind of
weapons your opponent might have.
If you carelessly approach them, who
knows what kind of trouble you'll get into!
But, if we don't do something soon, that boy will...
There's still about an hour left until
the professor gets here with the car.
We could choose to leave here and wait
until then, but it's pouring outside.
And it won't do us any good to just wait around.
So why don't we search for that kidnapped boy together?
Won't that be too risky?
The kidnapper is still here, you know.
It's all right.
As long as we can hear the piano playing,
we know the culprit is in that room.
But, there might be more than one culprit!
There's likely only one.
The entire diary used first person singulars...
And there was nothing to indicate there were any accomplices.
Not to mention there was only one wine glass.
But no matter what, you guys need to stick with me at all times!
Right!
But, how come the culprit hasn't come to catch us?
They probably don't want their face to be seen, no?
If they fail in their attack, they'd be in trouble when
we escape and tell the police what they looked like.
That's probably why they're playing the piano in the dark.
To make us feel frightened and chase us out of this place.
They probably haven't realized that we've already read
the diary and know about the kidnapping anyway.
But no matter what, if the owner of
this villa was investigated later...
Wouldn't they be revealed as the culprit?
The culprit probably doesn't even own this place.
With things as they are, it makes more sense that the
culprit picked some locks and broke into this house...
And we can naturally imagine that they pretended to be
the rich owner of this villa and invited the boy here.
Hey, is the piano music still there?
Yeah.
It's still playing.
It's so dark yet they're still playing so well.
Their fingers have memorized the placement of the keys.
There are pianists who are blind, you know.
But what kind of room is this?
It looks like a child's room.
It's a girl's room!
There are snacks scattered around here too.
A handheld game console?
And what's this?
Lots of them are drawn on the back of these newspaper flyers...
Figures that look like codes.
They're treasure maps from Monster Getter III!
They're maps you can get in-game.
If you don't draw them out on some piece
of paper, it'll be hard to find the treasure!
It sure seems like that child was confined in this
room the whole time, and had to play the games.
Thirty minutes left until the professor gets here...
Isn't this the kitchen we were in earlier?
Have we already circled through the entire house?
No.
The hallway splits into two ways, so
we still have other areas to search.
That's right.
Like the places down this hallway.
Huh?
Something's shining.
Water?
It's hot water!
Why is it here?
A photo...
This is odd.
The dishes are washed clean and the
garbage is also properly separated.
It indicates a methodical personality, but...
I wonder why the leftovers were left scattered on the table?
Hey, Ayumi isn't here!
Don't tell me she's been caught by the culprit!
That can't be.
The sound of the piano is still there, you know.
No.
This piano music is different!
The note that's slightly out of tune isn't there!
Perhaps they put that song from the CD
in the piano room on an endless loop...
Making us to think they were there, and in
fact secretly following our movements!
No way!
Anyway, let's look for her.
She may have simply gotten lost.
Hey, any signs?
No, nothing.
Then, was she really captured by the culprit?
In the worst case, the culprit may have already killed...
No way!
So the culprit really did kill him!?
No, I'm just saying that's a possibility—
My god!
Ayumi!
Where've you been!?
I was here the entire time...
If you were here, you could've answered us!
But, I thought you guys were looking for that boy!
Since everyone came out of the kitchen in a big panic...
That's right!
Ayumi found a photo!
A family photo...
Looks like a family of musicians.
The date printed on the photo is from a year ago.
Could it be that the kidnapped kid was
the one in the middle of the photo?
That can't be.
The child in the picture is a girl.
Yeah.
This photo is probably of the owners of this villa...
Or perhaps, the identity of our culprit.
Culprit!?
No way!
The key to solving this case should be hidden in this diary.
I'll reveal it at all cost!
Next Conan's Hint
Piano Chair
Look Forward to the Next Episode