Professor Agasa took us out on a
bamboo shoot-hunting trip, but...
The professor's car broke down, and
we weer left waiting in the mountains.
In order to take shelter from the rain,
we advanced to the villa vicinage...
And entered one of the villas,
beckoned by the sound of a piano.
Although there were traces of people having
lived there, there was no soul to be seen.
The diary left behind also had eerie entries in it.
It appeared as if the culprit had kidnapped a
boy and confined him to this very villa, but...
The boy had discovered their identity,
leading to the culprit plotting to kill him.
Finding the boy as quickly as possible became our objective.
However, an unexpected blackout caused the
entire villa to be enshrouded in darkness.
And the sound of the piano reverberated once more.
This is bad, the culprit is still in the villa!
In the deciding moment that determines your future
You cannot lie to yourself!
The mystery of the diary will be revealed!
What is the identity behind the genius pianist?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
That's right!
Ayumi found a photo!
A family photo...
Looks like a family of musicians.
The date printed on the photo if from a year ago.
Could it be that the kidnapped kid was
the one in the middle of the photo?
That can't be.
The child in the picture is a girl.
Yeah.
This photo is probably of the owners of this villa...
Or perhaps, the identity of our culprit.
Culprit!?
No way!
The key to solving this case should be hidden in this diary.
April 20th, sunny.
After I tried talking to him, he seemed like a good kid.
He smiles often and plays a lot.
Now, I don't know whether he understands
the situation he's in or not...
But I bet this kid has also spent countless
days living under great pressure.
Anyway, only 2 days left.
Just have to hold on until then.
April 22nd, cloudy.
Bach, Mozart, Chopin, Beethoven...
Your melodies make my heart quiver.
Born in the same era with such genius...
Your talents make me jealous.
Although they're not songs appropriate to play in this situation...
At least they can make me forget the time.
Just 1 more day.
Please let it pass without incident.
April 23rd, rainy.
This is bad.
It seems this young boy somehow knows who I am.
If this is revealed, it would be a hindrance in the future.
It's a pity, but looks like I have no choice but to kill him.
And the last entry is...
April 24th, rainy.
Boy, I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
First, what bothers me is...
The entry from April 21st was somehow omitted.
April 20th has an entry of "2 days left"...
And the entry from April 22nd reads "1 more day".
They appear to be connected as if the 21st never existed.
Also, the "April 24th, rainy" from the last entry is strange.
The red stain is probably from the spilled wine.
But since it's been soaked in and stuck the pages together...
It should've been written more than an hour before we found it.
So why does it say "rainy" then?
By the time we got here, an hour hadn't
even passed since it started raining.
What's more, this stain...
Definitely looks like some of the areas are sticking out.
As if someone soaked it again for some
reason after it had been wet once.
Why would they do this?
Both of the staples in the middle have their tips out of alignment...
And the holes have been made larger.
And two of the pages are sticking out from the edge.
There are traces of something having been written
on the page after the one that was sticking out.
Hey, Conan?
Rubbing that mechanical pencil lead on the diary...
What are you doing?
That's...
Monster Getter's...
Treasure map!
What does this mean?
I don't have absolute proof yet, so I can't say for sure, but...
I am sure that, if we go to the piano room
and check, the answer will reveal itself.
No one's here.
Like you said, the sound of the piano was from a CD.
Since it's a CD boombox, it can still
run by batteries during a blackout.
Huh?
Our bags are all gone!
No way!
Seriously?
So, how about it?
About your deduction.
You said you'd figure things out once we got here, right?
That...
Was supposed to be the case.
But I don't know anymore.
Perhaps this is...
Really frightening.
Hey, Conan?
Don't tell me that you want to play the
piano leisurely at a time like this!?
But the height of the chair isn't right for you.
Though it was right for Ayumi back then.
Maybe you can adjust the height if
you turn the dial under this cover?
Well, is it frightening?
That creepy piano player...
Yeah...
A frighteningly awesome prodigy indeed.
To the point that our prodigy's birth was resented.
A frighteningly awesome prodigy?
And we've been going up against that kind of person!?
Pretty much.
Good.
The height of the chair should be perfect like this now.
Well, with Ayumi-chan playing the piano...
Can I have everyone sing?
With all of your heart and in good cheer...
Sing a happy song!
Ready, go!
I stepped on the cat, I stepped on the cat
I stepped on the cat, so it scratched me
The cat scratched me, the cat scratched me
The cat was surprised, so it scratched me
You naughty — bad kitty —
Gotta trim your claws
Come on down — from the roof —
Shave your whiskers now
Can we stop playing...
Hide-and-seek now?
Whoever you are.
It's all right.
We're your friends, you know.
Amazing!
It's just what Conan-kun said!
So it really was a kid!
Looks like the electricity's back.
Then, let's have you answer a few questions.
Starting with your name...
And your age.
My name is Onoda Keita.
I'm seven.
Seven years old?
A first-grader?
Yeah.
Onada Keita (7)
Haido Elementary School Class 1-3
I'm Grade 1, Class 3 in Haido Elementary School.
So you're a first-grader just like all of us?
But, how did you know he was a kid, Conan-kun?
First, this was written in the diary:
"Bach, Mozart, Chopin, Beethoven...
"Your melodies make my heart quiver.
"Born in the same era with such genius...
"Your talents make me jealous," but...
Chopin was born sixty years after Bach passed away.
Can't really say they were geniuses born in the same era, right?
So it was a mystery for me as to who this was referring to...
Until I saw this photo that Ayumi-chan picked up, and then it hit me.
Turns out the person who was kidnapped
was the same age as the girl in this photo.
A piano genius, I should add.
That guy probably wanted his daughter to win at the Beckham
International Music Competition being held at the end of April...
So he kidnapped this boy and confined him in his own villa.
His own...?
So this villa belongs to the culprit?
Yeah.
The piano room in this photo is the same as this one.
Judging from the contents of that diary...
The one who kidnapped you was the
father of the girl in the photo, right?
Yeah.
He's Chiaki-chan's dad.
It was the first time we had met, but I've known his face.
Because Chiaki-chan showed me their photo.
But, I wasn't kidnapped or anything!
Chiaki-chan's dad came to save me!
Because the competition was coming up,
I was forced to practice piano all day.
And I never had any fun!
That's why you were doing things you normally
would get scolded for and couldn't do...
Like eating snacks while walking in the hallway...
Playing with the push cart, and playing
games to your heart's content, right?
Yeah.
It was fun to ride a push cart and speed down the hallway!
Then, the tall person I saw was...
I think it was this kid riding on the handle
of the push cart and peeking at you.
I see!
And the leftover food scattered on the kitchen table...
Was because you were hungry, yet the man who
brought you here left and couldn't be found, right?
Yeah.
I ate the ham, bread, and fried chicken that were in the fridge.
I can't cook, you know.
But this piano room sure is clean!
That's probably because your parents told you that you cannot
leave a mess in a room like this no matter what, right?
Yeah.
Mama told me that's because the music gods live in piano rooms.
And is that also why you always return the height
of the chair to its original position after playing?
Yeah.
Although when you guys first came here, I
got surprised and forgot to reset the chair.
I see.
That's why you looked defeated.
Because even though you were sure the performer was
a child, the chair wasn't set to a child's height.
Yeah.
I didn't realize the chair was adjustable.
But, did the culprit really run away?
In the diary, the day after "Because he knows
who I am, I have no choice but to kill him"...
Had this entry of "Boy, forgive me," you know.
Indeed, if those two entries were continuous...
It would seem as if the culprit had killed
him because there was no other choice.
But the two entries didn't follow each other.
Because this kid switched the pages.
He ran out of paper to draw on, and
drew in the diary without thinking.
So he did it to take out the page with this treasure map on it.
See, there are two pages sticking out from the edge, right?
Oh, you're right.
This is proof that pages were switched.
What do you mean?
This diary is the type of notebook that
was stapled together in the middle.
If all of the pages were the same size...
They will stick out according to the amount of thickness
they are stacked on when the book is closed.
So the protruding parts were cut in
order to make the edge flat and even.
The result is, the pages at the end are in fact
a bit larger than the pages in the middle.
That's why, if a page from the back is inserted
into the middle, it would stick out like this.
The reason why the staple tips in the middle page were
not aligned together was because of that as well.
Since he had pried the staples apart, switched pages...
And pressed them back down, causing the staples to misalign.
The treasure map in question was drawn on...
The right-hand side of the April 24th page that had the wine stain.
And on the back side of the date, the entry
for April 23rd should have been there.
But if he had merely removed that page, and the
owner had returned to write the next entry...
The owner would've noticed that
the entry for April 23rd was missing.
That's why, he brought the page from April
21st and placed it after April 23rd...
And added a stroke to change the 21 to 24,
and splashed wine on it like the original.
I see.
If the page was actually written on April 21st...
Then the back of it should contain the entry for April 20th.
So the entry of "I have no choice but to kill him"
we originally thought to be the 23rd...
Was in fact written on the 20th, right?
Yeah, in other words...
It started with "I have no choice but to kill him" on April 20th.
April 21st would be "After I tried talking
to him, he seemed like a good kid."
April 22nd would be the one with "Bach, Mozart..."
Followed by the entry from April 23rd that had been removed...
It finally ended with the entry from April
24th with "Boy, I'm sorry, forgive me."
If we assume the missing April 23rd entry was about
his feelings of regret for committing a crime...
Then the diary means he had planned to kill the boy
at first, but the murder intent gradually waned...
And he finally decided to leave the boy alone and run away.
Regardless, it's amazing that you'd come
up with the idea of removing pages!
You could've just ripped it apart, you know.
If I had ripped it out, it would've been discovered later.
And I learned this from my brother last year
who had just entered middle school.
When I had to write a lot of notes on
a musical score for homework...
He said I could cheat by substituting in pages from
a composition notebook I had used before.
And?
Do you have the page you removed?
"It's no use.
"I cannot do it after all.
"As someone who strives to be a musician in the same vein...
"The thought of sending his talent to the
grave deserves me nothing other than death.
"I shall ready myself."
Hey!
Did that man tell you where he was going?
No.
He only said that Mama was going to pick me up soon...
So he told me not to let anyone into
the house until then, and went away.
Come to think of it...
The photo was floating on hot water flowing in the hallway.
The bath!
There's hot water coming out from under the door!
He probably decided to commit suicide
by slitting his wrist in the warm bathtub.
With the hot water flowing, the blood wouldn't
clot and it'd be easy to die from exsanguination.
And the photo he was holding got washed away then.
Damn, it's locked!
It's no use.
It won't budge with a child's strength!
However, the hallway is too narrow for me
to use my Super Powered Sneakers...
And it's too wet for me to keep my footing!
In that case...
What are you doing, Conan?
Making marks on the wall?
Bring my shoes from the entranceway!
Hurry!
Listen.
You guys, stay back.
GO!
Awesome!
The floor's flooded!
He's unconscious, but still breathing.
The wound is shallow and he's lost less blood than I'd have thought.
If I perform first aid now, I can save him.
The reason the water overflowed into the hallway...
Is because the towel was carried by the flow, clogging the drain.
Hey!
Hand me that tall and thin can of shaving cream that's on the sink!
Right!
Here.
I can stop the bleeding by binding this to his upper arm.
All that's left is to take him to a hospital, but...
Transporting an adult with a child's strength isn't easy...
Don't worry.
I'll transport him to the hospital by car.
Professor!
It's amazing that you'd think to find us here!
Your backpacks were lined up in front of the entranceway, after all.
In front of the entranceway?
I put them there.
I wanted you guys to leave quickly.
Also, on the mountain road on my way here...
I picked up this lady who had run out of gas and was stranded there.
And I heard about everything from her.
Keita!
Mama!
I'm so glad!
So you're all right?
Yeah!
I'm totally fine.
Since Chiaki-chan's dad saved me, I got to play
and do all kinds of things I'd wanted to do!
It was super fun!
You're wrong, Keita-kun.
That man wasn't trying to save you...
No, it's quite possible that he saved you.
Because it's been such a long time since I last saw my child smile...
Perhaps the one who confined this child and
tied him up with "Practice, practice!"...
Was actually me, his own mother...
And?
What happened to the kidnapper afterwards?
I heard he gave himself up to the police
after being discharged from the hospital.
Well, he did prepare a coffin with the intent to bury Keita-kun...
So the judge could not take extenuating
circumstances into consideration.
But Keita-kun's mother made a request, so details
from the case weren't released to the public.
After all, the one who e-mailed the mother and asked
her to come to the villa was the culprit himself.
But, I'm worried about that Chiaki girl from the photo.
Yeah.
Her father's become a criminal, after all.
I hear they aren't going to tell Chiaki-chan until she's older.
Her parents divorced half a year ago anyway.
And?
Did that Chiaki kid win the competition?
Well...
I haven't heard anything about that.
Huh?
You didn't attend the competition, Chiaki-chan?
I talked to Mama about it and decided not to.
Because I was very, very worried about you going missing, Keita-kun.
I wasn't in the mood for the competition anyway!
I see...
But I was surprised that you were
actually playing at the villa with Papa!
My Mama also got nicer after that!
She isn't yelling "Practice, practice!" at me anymore.
However, you want to play it more now
that she doesn't bug you about it, right?
The piano!
Yeah!
Let's do the four-handed performance together again!
We'll play Mozart's sonata for two pianos!
Yeah, it's a promise!
They say that parents know not the heart of their children.
But, why did that kid only play that one song back there?
He said he watched the video of his brother's graduation ceremony.
When Air on the G String plays, it's a cue for
graduates to depart from the ceremony one by one.
That's why he thought he could get us to leave just like that.
Or...
Perhaps it was he himself who wanted to graduate...
From the pressure of being a genius.
Next Conan's Hint
Sherlock Holmes
Look Forward to the Next Episode