Damn!
Out of the money again?
I must be unlucky today...
Geez!
I got this fruit parfait in order to enjoy an authentic tropical mood!
So why won't you read your horse racing
paper at the detective agency?
Doesn't that strawberry look delicious!
If you're not eating it, I'll take it!
No way!
I was saving that for last, you know!
Lemme have it!
You can't!
Right...
This strawberry was the spark.
I didn't have a single clue at the time.
To think this was the start of a sweet and sour major case...
In the deciding moment that determines your future.
You cannot lie to yourself!
We're finally out of Japan...
And in deep-yearning London for a grand case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Geez!
I was looking forward to eating it!
What's with this cat?
Do cats eat strawberries?
It's just rolling it around and playing with it, no?
Geez, where'd this cat come from?
YOU LITTLE—!
Oh, Venus!
Venus!
Oh, I'm so glad you're unhurt!
Thank you so much for finding her!
I think she's thanking us.
My father is a detective!
Really?
How admirable!
I'm fond of crime novels myself!
And I love to hear stories.
But I have a flight to catch—such a shame...
I know!
May I invite you to my home?
In London.
What's she saying?
Not sure...
She spoke so quickly that I didn't get most of it.
Wow, that's great!
Oh, you accept?
Then, when can you visit?
We don't have school next weekend!
Oh, good!
Then, I will arrange your trip as soon as I return home!
That brat can speak English?
Looks that way...
OK?
Sure! All right!
Thank you, ma'am!
So you're going to the UK next weekend?
Hey, hey, what about school and everything?
Yeah...
Both Teitan Elementary and Teitan High will be on a four-day
break because the weekend overlaps with the holidays.
Ran and Uncle are excited about it too.
What's more, it seems Diana-san, the owner of the cat...
Diana Kingstone (58)
Happens to be really wealthy.
She said she's paying for our travel expenses and our hotel!
But isn't that something!
You'll be able to visit London, your heart's desire.
Yeah!
Dad's taken me to a lot of places overseas, but...
We've never been to London!
First, I'll have to go to Baker Street...
Hyde Park
Then, the place where Holmes and Watson strolled — Hyde Park...
And then the British Museum where Holmes
would go to investigate things.
The British Museum
And if we have time, maybe even the stage for
The Hound of the Baskervilles—Dartmoor...
And then where Holmes and his nemesis
Professor Moriarty fell—Reichenbach Falls!
There are so many places I want to go, I almost can't decide!
But...
Will you be all right?
Your passport.
I completely forgot!
Now look here...
Edogawa Conan is Kudou Shinichi's
shrunken form thanks to that poison.
You really shouldn't exist, you know?
There's no way someone like that could
fly overseas without a care in the world!
I guess you're right, but...
Hey, Professor...
Can't you do something?
Make me a fake passport or something!
Don't be ridiculous!
That's a crime!
Damn it!
I finally get the chance to pilgrimage to the
Holmes mecca and I have to stay home!?
Is that even fair?
Damn it...
As far as going, there is but one way.
Of course...
You have to promise to follow my instructions down to the letter.
Got it?
Amazing!
First class is so spacious!
Just how ridiculously rich is she?
That old lady?
But it's too bad...
That Conan-kun couldn't come with us.
Yeah...
He said something suddenly came up that he had to do, didn't he?
Oh, well...
He's coming on the next flight with Professor Agasa.
And to think she'd pay for the professor's travel as well...
Diana-san really is a wonderful person!
But she's not paying for souvenirs, so
don't spend your money mindlessly.
I bet you're going to buy a mountain of stuff, right?
For that Holmes geek detective brat.
I wasn't planning to buy a mountain load!
Though I bet he'd rather be there himself than get souvenirs.
So true.
Would've been great if Shinichi could've come with us.
Isn't the air conditioning on this plane a bit too strong?
Hey, don't act too conspicuous!
If Ran-kun and them find out we're on the same flight they are...
It's fine.
They're in first class.
They won't come back here.
But it was thanks to Ai-kun's brilliant suggestion...
To use the drug to only temporarily return you to Kudou
Shinichi in order to pass the departure inspection!
Yeah, I'm thankful...
Got it?
I'm giving you two pills—one for going and one for coming back.
The approximate duration of the drug's effect is 24 hours.
You need to calculate the correct time to take the drug...
So that you can return to your present form
right after getting through the UK customs!
But is it all right?
Since I'm taking the professor with me.
Yeah...
I'll be staying at Yoshida-san's place in the meantime.
Sorry about this...
I'm sure you know this already, but...
If you were to take it again before the time is
up, the effective window would be halved.
And don't forget that you would never be able to return home!
Yeah, yeah...
Heathrow Airport (UK)
Conan-kun and the professor...
They still haven't come out yet.
Their plane should've landed a while ago.
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun!
When did you get here?
Just now.
Didn't you notice.
The effect of the drug took longer to wear off than anticipated...
Forcing me to wait it out in the restroom for thirty minutes.
Anyway, now...
We still have some time before we meet
with that rich lady at the hotel tonight.
How about we do some sightseeing around London!
Where do you want to go, Conan-kun?
Of course, that'd be...
Sherlock Holmes Museum
As expected of the Sherlock Holmes Museum!
Awwwwsome!
Can I take this seat?
Of course!
Excellent!
I bet Shinichi would be just as cheerful if he were here.
That guy...
He may have said in his e-mail he didn't want any souvenirs, but...
I have a list of things to buy for him!
All right...
Why don't I give him a surprise?
It's from Shinichi's phone.
Who could it be?
It was Ran!?
Hello, Shinichi?
Ran?
Guess where I am right now?
I'm at 221B Baker Street!
Oh yeah...
You did e-mail me saying you were going to London, after all...
What's with that half-hearted reaction?
Try and be a little jealous!
My bad...
I'm just so busy now.
Oh, yeah!
Is there anywhere that you'd like me to take a photo of for you?
I'm not sure which places you'd like.
But I already said I didn't need anything like that, right?
I'm already here.
All right, I'm hanging up.
What's that!?
Stupid Shinichi!
Stupid, stupid, STUPID!
I'm sorry...
What were you doing?
Sorry...
Man, did I just make her mad?
You're leaving already?
Yeah...
I've enjoyed everything.
And the souvenir shop is next door too.
Well, if Holmes were really here...
I'd stay for days and weeks.
You're lying to me!
I know Holmes is here!
Let me see him!
I'm sorry, but Mr. Holmes is out on an investigation...
What kind of investigation?
Well, he is...
See, you're lying!
Save the trouble...
Someone will be killed if we don't do something right away!
And nobody can stop it but Holmes!
Oh, no!
Look at the time!
My sister's match is about to start!
I have to get back!
Can I be of some help?
Never mind!
Cheapskate!
Japanese?
Hey!
You speak Japanese?
Yeah...
I've lived in Japan before.
If you'd like, could you tell me about that
case you were talking about back there?
Why should I tell someone like you anything?
That's because...
I'm Holmes's apprentice, you know...
Glass-kun!
How'd you know my name?
Do you know me by any chance?
An elementary deduction.
There's white fluid and powder stuck around your mouth.
That's the cream and sugar put over strawberries, right?
And the container you're holding in your hand
has limes, cucumbers, and mint in it...
So the contents would be the drink called "Pimm's".
Since you're a child, they gave you regular
lemonade instead of liquor, didn't they?
Yeah...
I asked the vendor to do so.
And a sport where you can routinely get
strawberries and Pimm's while watching...
It has to be tennis at Wimbledon.
Today is the women's singles semi-finals.
The first match started at 1:00, and it's past 2:00 now.
So your sister must be participating in the second match.
One of the players is Wang Hai-li whose
parents are both Chinese, but...
You don't look Asian no matter how you look at it.
In that case, it must be her opponent.
The one dominating Wimbledon for four consecutive years...
Ranked No.1 in the world and nicknamed the Grass Court Queen...
Minerva Glass, that must be your big sister!
Also...
From your shirt pocket...
I could see the Wimbledon VIP lounge badge resting inside.
Amazing!
You really are Holmes's apprentice, aren't you?
So then, will you tell me about the whole story just now?
I was eating strawberries a little past noon while watching
the remaining winners practise at Court No. 15, but...
So, you like tennis, then?
Oh, yes!
It's quite thrilling!
Thrilling, you say?
Lucky you.
Well, you can expect a greater thrill soon.
What?
A person is about to be murdered...
Somewhere in London...
Right before your eyes...
Did you see that guy's face!?
His cap covered most of his face so I couldn't get a good look.
But...
He did give me this weird paper.
Tell Scotland Yard...
It's my Revelation.
If it doesn't make sense...
Go to Holmes.
He said that and ran off somewhere.
This is...
You can read English, right?
Yeah.
It looks like some sort of poem, but...
I have no idea what it's trying to hint at.
Oh, there you are!
Don't go running off by yourself!
I've been looking for you!
Who's he?
My sister's former coach, Ares.
Ares Ashley (30)
Minerva's Former Coach
I hear he used to be a really strong tennis player.
Because he was her coach, my mum is on good terms with him...
And now he helps us with all kinds of things.
My sister's busy with her tours, and our mum's eyes are bad.
Come on, Apollo...
Let's get back!
She's about to play!
But...
Just go ahead.
I'll take this to the police.
Plus, if he told you to take such a baffling letter to the police...
It means he's allowing some time to figure out the puzzle.
So it's not likely that something's going to happen right away.
You're right.
Then, I'll give you my mobile number.
Let me know if you figure anything out.
Apollo Glass (8)
Minvera's Younger Brother
My name is Apollo Glass.
And you?
It's Edogawa Conan.
Conan?
Sure is a name suitable for an apprentice of Holmes!
Bye then!
Promise you'll give me a call!
Yeah!
Conan-kun!
Who... were those people?
Was there some sort of trouble?
Don't tell me you're causing trouble even when we're overseas!
Actually, it's just like you said...
What!?
You're saying he got a mysterious code from some
guy giving an advance notice of a murder?
Is that true?
Yeah.
According to that kid named Apollo.
And?
What does it say?
Let's see...
The first line says...
"A rolling bell rises me," so...
I was awakened by the loud sound of a rolling bell.
The second line is...
I am a long-nosed wizard inhabiting a castle.
The third line is...
My morsel is a boiled egg that's gone as cold as a corpse.
The fourth line is...
I'll finish up my meal by gnawing on a whole pickle.
The fifth line is...
Now I remember, I should order a celebratory cake in advance.
The sixth line is...
The sound of the bell rings again and stirs up my hatred.
And finally, the seventh line is...
It tells me to finish everything by piercing
the white-colored back with two swords.
What's with that creepy note anyway?
Supposedly, the man who gave this advance
notice said, "This is my Revelation."
By "Revelation," did he mean something like a crime manifesto?
Forget it, forget it!
It's probably just some nutjob's idea of a prank!
But, I promised Apollo...
That I'd take this to Scotland Yard.
Wimbledon Centre Court
Minerva Glass (22)
Tennis Player
Yes!
Scotland Yard (London Police HQ)
You're saying that many other people also received that note?
What's more, all the ones who received those were children?
Right now in the station, there are tons
of kids and their parents with that note.
It seems like a man wearing a cap with dark skin and dreadlocks...
Had been giving out that note on the
street, in parks, and various other places!
And he'd whisper in their ears:
"A person is about to be murdered in London soon."
Hold on a minute...
If I recall correctly, that Apollo kid...
He was told "someone will be killed right before your eyes," right?
Hey, hey...
If that man had said the same thing to the other children...
It couldn't mean...
Right.
It would mean that someone is going
to die in front of each child's eyes.
In other words...
It means a large number of people might be killed at once, right?
Mass murder?
Here in London!?
Which means...
He plans to carry it out in some place where many people aggregate.
At this time of year, the tennis at Wimbledon would be suspicious.
I see!
Since everyone's watching the match oh TV...
No.
Of the kids that were handed the note, a fair number
of them were wearing racing-style bike helmets...
So I don't think that's the case.
Since they said they were glued to the TV
everyday, watching the Tour de France.
Tour de...?
What's that?
It's a bike race that's held in France.
The broadcasts of the race and
Wimbledon matches air concurrently...
So you can't watch both of them at the same time.
Then that means the British Museum...
Or Buckingham Palace...
At any rate, you guys go check out places where people might gather.
We may be able to figure something out!
I'm going to try and crack the code with the professor!
Hey!
Wait!
We'll be eating dinner at the hotel with Diana-san tonight!
We'll be back before then!
We could've gone and investigated with the
others while trying to solve the code, you know.
First of all, it's wiser for us to split up and gather information.
Since we have no idea when, where, or what's going to happen.
Also, if I tried to decipher the code like that...
I'd be exposed as Kudou Shinichi.
There's already a lot of exposure!
First, it started with, "I was awakened
by the loud sound of a rolling bell."
Could this possibly refer to an alarm clock?
And the next line, "I am a long-nosed wizard in a castle..."
Could refer to a castle somewhere.
The common keywords in lines three, four, and five are food names.
Boiled egg...
Pickle...
And cake.
And the sixth line...
"The sound of the bell rings again," could also mean a clock.
The "two swords" in the last line may
refer to blades or murder weapons.
Suppose we think in simple terms.
We can take it to mean that near a
castle-esque building are two clock shops...
Along with a grocery store, a cake shop, and
a shop that deals with cutlery or weapons...
And something will happen at a place like that.
Is there any place like that in London?
Let's buy a map and find out.
In the city of my dreams where Sherlock
Holmes took the stage — London...
A mystifying note of "Revelation" given to
me by chance by a boy named Apollo...
I shall solve this mystery...
And put a stop to this crime!
Hidden behind the "Revelation" are mysterious codes.
In order to obtain the deciphering key, we have
to scour the roads of London up and down.
No good!
My identity's on the verge of being exposed,
and Ran's chasing me up and down!
Next Conan's Hint
Big Ben
Look Forward to the Next Episode