So, you like tennis, then?
Oh, yes!
It's quite thrilling!
Thrilling, you say?
Lucky you.
Well, you can expect a greater thrill soon.
What?
A person is about to be murdered...
Somewhere in London...
Right before your eyes...
Tell Scotland Yard...
It's my Revelation.
If it doesn't make sense...
Go to Holmes.
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
Edogawa Conan is being cornered...
If Ran finds out, everything is doomed!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
After being invited by Diana-san, a British woman
we happened to make the acquaintance of...
We found ourselves preparing for a trip to London.
Of course, since I can't fly overseas as Edogawa Conan...
I temporarily returned to Kudou Shinichi's form
by taking medicine developed by Haibara...
And arrived at London separately from Ran.
It's the Sherlock Holmes mecca of my dreams!
So many places to go, I almost couldn't decide!
But, what awaited us there was a premonition of a major case.
Apollo, younger brother of the famous tennis player Minerva Glass...
Received a letter from a suspicious man.
Along with the words: "Someone will
be murdered right before your eyes."
Written on the letter were sentences resembling ciphers.
"I was awakened by the loud sound of a rolling bell."
"I am a long-nosed wizard in a castle."
"My morsel is a boiled egg that's gone as cold as a corpse."
"I'll finish up my meal by gnawing on a whole pickle."
"Now I remember, I should order a celebratory cake in advance."
"The sound of the bell stirs up my hatred."
"It tells me to finish everything by piercing
the white back with two swords."
What on earth did this man want to express?
Per Apollo's request, we delivered the
coded letter to Scotland Yard, but...
We learned there that many other children
had also received the same coded letter.
If people are to die in front of these many children...
Could this be a code indicative of a mass murder?
The British Museum!
Buckingham place.
Hyde Park...
Well...
We've gone and checked out places where
people would normally aggregate, but...
There was nothing strange.
And there wasn't anyone handing out strange flyers.
Well, since we got to sightsee London, it's not that bad.
Don't be stupid!
Being on the lookout for suspicious-looking
people almost made me paranoid...
I couldn't relax and sightsee at all!
Geez!
I'm gonna go buy some drinks—wait for me around here!
Sure.
A code, huh...
I took a photo of it on my phone just in case, but...
It's all Greek to me.
But, if it were Shinichi...
I want to call and ask him about this, but...
It feels awkward...
What's that?
Stupid Shinichi!
Since I yelled and hung up on him.
But...
I guess he had reason to be displeased about it.
He must've felt it as if I were bragging to him about
being at the place he'd wanted to go to for so long.
That was stupid of me...
I was the one getting excited over nothing.
I'd even gone so far as to look on the internet and take notes...
Really...
I'm a fool...
Love hurts, doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
Well, no...
Yes, something like that...
You can't ask him for advice, then.
He's not an expert in that field, I'm afraid.
Who is "he"?
Him!
Up there!
Sherlock Holmes!
I see...
I had returned to Baker Street without even realizing it...
Are you Japanese?
Yes...
Hai.
How nostalgic, the Japanese language.
I used to live in Japan, you know.
My mother underwent eye surgery in Japan...
And was hospitalized there for a while.
Uhm...
Might you be...
That Minerva Glass-san?
The tennis player?
If this turns into a big deal, I won't be able to come here anymore!
Do you come here often?
Yeah.
I always come here without fail before the Wimbledon finals...
In order to draw on Holmes's powers of
observation and discernment to win.
You really like Holmes, don't you?
Minerva Glass (22)
Tennis Player
Well, I suppose my mum's influence was strong.
My father was German, but my mother English.
She's a Sherlockian through and through.
But my mum has lost her vision, and can only
read Conan Doyle's works via Braille now.
And my father and little sister who
was six years younger than I was...
Both passed away eight years ago in a traffic accident.
Minerva!
Apollo Glass (8)
Minerva's Younger Brother
When my father died, Apollo there was still in my mother's tummy.
That's why I'm the central pillar of the Glass family today.
I thought he was still around here, because he hadn't called...
But he isn't...
Oh, that's too bad.
He's really an apprentice of Holmes!
Uhm...
How did you know?
That I was having love troubles...
Because that face you had...
I had seen myself with the same face in the mirror before.
Then, you've also had love troubles?
Still, I'm no longer troubled.
Holmes said it too.
"Love is an emotional thing.
"I will say nothing in praise of it...
"It is antagonistic to clear reasoning."
It's the same in tennis.
Love is 0.
No matter how much you add to zero, you'll just lose miserably.
Wrong...
This isn't it.
This isn't it either!
Damn!
There just isn't a place where two clock shops, a grocery store...
A cake shop, and a weapon shop are
concentrated near a castle-like building!
Hey, hey...
It's already 8:00 PM, you know.
What are you talking about?
It's still so bright out...
Oh, I forgot!
This time of year, it doesn't get dark in London until after 9:00.
Ran-neechan?
What's wrong?
What do you mean, "What's wrong?"
I told you that we promised to have dinner with
Diana-san at 8:00 in the hotel restaurant, didn't I?
Sorry...
I was so focused on solving the code with the professor.
We're about to begin eating already!
Then, the professor and I will pass.
We'll just get fish and chips or something around here.
Hey, hey...
Hold on, where are you?
Where are we?
Isn't there something like a landmark near you?
Well...
There's a big ferris wheel next to us!
The London Eye, then?
Well, we should get going!
Wai—
Geez...
What do you mean, the London Eye?
Aren't we right next to Big Ben?
I had no choice, did I?
If she comes to pick us up, we'll have to
stop investigating this wicked cipher.
But, Ran-kun will be worried...
It's all right.
We'll return to the hotel right about the time they finish their meal.
May I be excused?
I'll call my company.
Oh, you will.
Just hold on, I'm gonna bring those two back here.
Hey!
Now, can I ask about your successful adventures?
Mr. Sleeping Detective?
What do you want me to speakingu now?
As you can see, I've brought a party of friends tonight...
Since I learned you're a famous defective in Japan.
Now, start your story, OK?
O... OK...
The London Eye...
It's really far away!
I don't have a choice but to run there.
It's not quite far enough to need a taxi for.
Geez, that Conan-kun...
Immersing himself in deductions to the
point where he even forgets about hunger.
Just like...
Holmes said it too!
That the brain works best on an empty stomach!
Maybe I should call Shinichi and ask him about it.
It seems like such an urgent cipher.
But...
I just can't bring myself to.
It means that a large number of people
might be killed at once, right?
It seems to me like this code may not be
indicating stores that sell certain things.
Yeah...
The first line goes...
"I was awakened by the loud sound of a rolling bell."
Next is...
"I am a long-nosed wizard in a castle."
"My morsel is a boiled egg that's gone as cold as a corpse."
"I'll finish up my meal by gnawing on a whole pickle."
"Now I remember, I should order a celebratory cake in advance."
"The sound of the bell stirs up my hatred."
And then, the last...
"It tells me to finish everything by piercing
the white back with two swords."
I can't make heads nor tails of it...
If I could at least figure out what the "loud
sound of a rolling bell" in the first line meant...
We'd have a clue to latch onto, but...
Ran again...
Didn't I tell her to let me concentrate on the code?
Hello!?
Sorry, Shinichi?
It's me...
Oh, no!
This is Shinichi's phone!
You're asleep, right?
I know it's only 5:00 AM in Japan.
No, I've been awake!
I've been thinking about something.
Sorry about earlier.
I shouldn't have yelled at you and hung up.
I was so excited to be in the place
where you had always wanted to go...
But you must've thought I was just bragging.
It didn't really bother me!
And I really had things I was busy with at the time.
I see.
Sorry about that!
And Shinichi, there's a code I want you to solve.
About that code, that Conan kid already forwarded it to me.
Actually, I've been thinking about it without sleeping.
But the beginning part, "the loud sound of a rolling bell"...
Is where I'm stuck...
Loud sound...
Rolling bell...
I see!
It's Big Ben, Big Ben!
You hear it, don't you?
Big Ben's chime here...
That's what "loud sound of a rolling bell" was referring to!
Big Ben here?
Hold on, Shinichi!
What's the meaning of this!?
Oh, no...
Don't tell me you're here!?
In London!
It was the TV!
I just happened to tune into a live broadcast from London on TV...
You're here, aren't you!?
Wait...
I got another call coming in...
Later!
I see...
His weak reaction back then...
And his apparent annoyance when trying to hang up...
It was all because he's here in London!
Oh, man!
Ran's coming!
Hey...
Didn't you trick her into thinking we're next to the London Eye?
For the time being...
Let's flee!
I see...
And that's how I sent the culprit flying
with my one-armed shoulder throw.
Oh, baritsu!
Baritsu?
No, no!
Judo!
That's baritsu...
Which Holmes performed on Professor Moriarty when they fell!
Mastering baritsu means you're a brilliant detective!
No idea what she's saying, but...
Oh, yes!
I am...
Strongu detective!
I knew something was fishy!
To think Shinichi's not envious about this...
I won't let him have his way!
Excuse me...
Have you seen a Japanese boy?
Yes, I have!
I do believe he was rushing to the bridge over there.
No way...
The bridge I just crossed!?
He must've crossed from the opposite walkway...
SHINICHI!
This is bad...
If we don't manage to hide somewhere, she'll catch up to us!
Two Japanese people together will stand out!
Let's split up and flee after we get across the bridge!
You're right...
Hey, are you all right?
This damn drain cover was open...
There's something written on the side of this drain.
The Valley of Fear...
"Kyoufu no Tani."
It's the title of one of Holmes's stories.
Come on, hurry!
Why would that be there...?
Did you see a Japanese boy?
Yes, I did!
I saw him running over there!
Excuse me!
Excuse me...
I just passed him...
Excuse me!
Have you seen a Japanese boy?
Oh, the boy has...
Run into a phone booth just now.
Thanks...
Damn it!
If she finds me now, she'll know I'm Kudou Shinichi!
Damn...
In that case...
Shinichi...
You can't run away anymore.
Explain to me what this is all about!
SHINICHI!
Explain what?
I just happen to have come to London as well.
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me he took the antidote meant for the return trip?
Then, why were you running?
That's because...
I forgot to tell you that I was coming to London...
So I thought it'd be awkward...
Why didn't you tell me?
You had plenty of chances to, didn't you?
Well, that's...
Stupid...
Stupid of me...
I got excited over nothing...
I did so much research, and was worried to death about your stuff...
Wasn't that stupid of me!?
It's just like that person said.
Love is 0...
No matter how much you add to zero, you'll just lose miserably.
What are you talking about?
Minerva Glass-san said so!
Minerva Glass?
You met the Grass Court Queen?
I did!
At Baker Street!
So what!?
At Baker Street?
Then, was there a kid with her!?
There was.
She said he was her younger brother...
Did that kid say anything?
Like if he came back because he remembered anything...
Hey, calm down!
Calm down...?
Don't you get it...?
You're a detective, aren't you?
If you call yourself a detective, then why
don't you try to deduce what's in my heart!?
Idiot!
Hey, wait!
Ran!
I said wait!
The sender of the "Revelation" turned out
to be an extremely nefarious criminal.
If we don't solve the code soon, anything bad could happen!
I'm counting on you, Ran!
Find some clues at any cost!
Next Conan's Hint
Alphabet
Look Forward to the Next Episode