Hey, Ran!
Ran!
I said hey!
Your tea is overflowing.
It seems that brat with the glasses caught a cold.
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
An awkward atmosphere lingers around Ran
and Shinichi after the long-coming reunion!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What's waiting for us in London as soon as we arrived...
Was a coded message indicative of a massive murder manifesto.
In order to obtain some advice to solve the
code, Ran called Shinichi's phone, but...
During the call, I figured out that the first line of the cipher
was about London's famous clock tower Big Ben.
And I inadvertently used Shinichi's voice to inform Ran about it.
I was therefore chased by Ran who was
sure that Shinichi was in London.
Having no choice...
It was shortly after Ran-kun's phone call
last night that he began trembling.
It must've been because he was running all
around London sweating up a storm...
And that sweat got chilled by the night wind.
Geez!
And we're supposed to go back to Japan tomorrow night!
Now, now...
He took some medicine and his fever went down.
So he should be fine after a day's rest.
That's why...
You don't need to worry about me.
Ran-neechan and Uncle Kogorou, you guys go solve that code!
I think those seven lines of code probably...
Refer to various buildings or places, so there you go.
How do you know something like that?
Because Shinichi-niichan said so...
Shinichi did?
Come to think of it, Shinichi...
Said in front of Big Ben...
That the "loud sound of a rolling bell"
in the first line was Big Ben's chime!
In front of Big Ben!?
Don't tell me that detective brat came to London!?
Wait a sec!
You knew that, didn't you!?
If I had known, why would I have made a souvenir list!?
In any case...
Allow me to take care of Conan-kun.
And Ran-kun, much appreciated if I
could ask you two to decipher the code.
We somehow managed to fool them.
But to think you'd use up the antidote for the return trip...
I had no choice, did I?
If I hadn't taken it, it would've been revealed that Edogawa
Conan was the infantilized form of Kudou Shinichi!
What about your return trip?
There's no more medicine, you know.
And it's not like I can ask Haibara to bring more to me...
Well, I'll think of something while I'm cooped up in this room.
You're not going to go out?
Aren't you going to meet up with Ran-kun
and her father to solve that code?
Stupid!
I don't know when my body's going to revert
back to being Conan, so how could I go out?
Plus, right now...
I don't think I can face her...
Anyway, take a look at this morning's newspaper.
Based on the fingerprints that were on
the paper the code was written on...
They've narrowed it down to one suspect.
His name is Hades Sahara.
A serial murderer who's currently on the run.
First, we need to research this guy.
But if they've already confirmed the
culprit, they'll arrest him soon, right?
Stupid!
This guy left his fingerprints on purpose!
That means he's doing this knowing full well that he'll be arrested!
Having been told that the "loud sound of a rolling bell" is Big Ben...
You'd think that does make sense, but...
It's not like there are buildings shaped like
an egg or pickles scattering around here!
Excuse me!
Yes?
Is there an egg-shaped building here in London?
Ah yes, there's a City Hall near the Tower Bridge!
Is there!?
Who would've thought there'd really be a building shaped like this...
Then...
The third line...
"My morsel is a boiled egg that's gone
as cold as a corpse" refers to...
This City Hall, doesn't it?
What are these words... a code?
Do they mean a name?
The doll's name is Mazarin Stone!
Mazarin Stone...
"Mazarin no Houseki"...
Hi!
How did you get the doll?
The doll?
I found it there!
Beside the bench.
Under the shrubs.
Can I see that?
You can keep it!
I've got plenty already!
Goodbye!
What's that?
This might have something to do with that code.
Remember...
The culprit who was distributing the cipher said...
"If the code doesn't make sense, go to Holmes," didn't he?
If that's the case, he probably planted items...
Related to Holmes in the places indicated by the code, right?
Since this "Mazarin Stone" was the title of a
Holmes story, or so Shinichi told me before.
Hey!
I went through all the trouble to make you lunch!
But you haven't even touched it!
My bad.
I'm researching things for a case Inspector
Megure asked me to look into.
Geez!
Burying yourself in deductions to the point
where you even forget about hunger...
You'll starve to death sooner or later!
In "The Mazarin Stone," Holmes
said something similar, you know.
"The faculties become refined when you starve them," it was.
Holmes again?
"I am a brain, Watson."
"The rest of me is a mere appendix."
If everything besides the head is an appendix...
That means only the head is important!
Hey...
What are you doing?
Huh?
Something's written here...
T!
T?
I see!
Certain letters are hidden at the places in the code.
And if you put them together...
It'll make a word, right?
However...
What comes next after "egg" was "pickle," right?
No matter how you think about it, there's no way there
could be a thin disc-shaped building like sliced pickles.
But the code said that he gnawed on a whole pickle.
So it should be a pickle that hasn't been sliced yet...
That's stupid!
Pickles are just pickled young cucumbers!
There's no way such a long, narrow, and
round building could exist in this worl—
It must be that, right!?
No way!
Looks pretty bad...
This Hades Sahara guy.
It seems he used to be a hard-working company employee...
But his mother was struck with a serious disease.
In order to gather funds for her surgery,
he borrowed from acquaintances...
And heavily invested in stocks and with bookies where he lost it all.
Because of that, his mother was unable to receive
surgery and passed away last year in July.
The result is that Hades completely changed
and started his crime spree.
He slaughtered not only his acquaintances
who kept hounding him for collection...
But also his friend who had suggested he invest in stocks.
Furthermore, he blew up hospitals that had refused
to perform his mother's surgery one by one...
Resulting a large number of casualties.
Blew up?
He used explosives too?
Yeah...
While Hades was on the run, he came
across a woman named Hestia.
She's a military outcast and explosives expert.
And she helped Hades carry out his revenge.
As for that woman...
It says she blew herself up when the police
discovered her hideout not too long ago, but...
Since the body was blown to bits...
You mean the body could've been someone
else's, and she could still be alive?
Yeah.
But why hasn't such a dangerous criminal been arrested yet?
It seems he underwent many plastic surgeries while on the run.
Well, with this guy there's no telling what he'll do next.
Perhaps since this country allows bookies to prey
on those who bet everything they have...
It's Great Britain itself that he holds a grudge against.
It's Ran!
Apologies, but answer it for me...
If I answer that phone, it'll be too suspicious!
Don't dawdle, just answer it already!
She may have figured out something about the code!
You're right...
Hel—
PICK UP THE DAMN PHONE IF YOU'RE THERE, MORON!
Uhm, that's Ran's phone, right...?
Ran was shy and couldn't work up the courage to call you...
So the great yours truly had to do it himself!
Since this has something to do with Sherlock
Holmes, you're the number one expert!
Something to do with Holmes?
Yeah.
The "egg" in the third line was the egg-shaped City Hall.
The "pickle" in the fourth line turned out to be the building
in the shape of a young cucumber, called the "Gherkin".
But the problem is that there were Holmes-related
items scattered near those places.
What kind of items?
We found dolls near City Hall.
There were words about a Thingamajig Stone on their bod—
It was "Mazarin Stone".
You said in that story there was a scene where Holmes
said, "Everything besides the brain is an appendix."
That's why I...
I pulled off the doll's head, and the letter T appeared.
I see.
If you use what Holmes says in the story
with the hinted title as a guideline...
The keyword to solving the case will be revealed.
And next to the building called the "Gherkin," a bunch
of weird pens with cuts all over had been dropped.
"Dancing Men" is written on the barrel of the pen.
That's the title of a Holmes story, right?
Yeah.
We call it "Odoru Ningyou".
That's why I thought something might be in these too...
So I took off the caps at the tip and the bottom, but still got nothing.
Then, try taking the caps from the tip and bottom...
And putting them together.
The cuts will probably match up at some point.
Got it!
There's an N written there!
But how...?
Holmes said it in that story.
"If one knocks out all the central inferences and presents one's
audience with the starting point and the conclusion...
"One may produce a startling, though
possibly a meretricious, effect."
I see!
That's why we had to remove the pen's barrel from the middle...
And put the caps from the tip and bottom together!
Then, was there anything near Big Ben,
which is at the beginning of the code?
I also thought about that and searched for a bit...
But we couldn't find anything.
Dad did find a strange arrow drawn on the
road in front of the gate to Big Ben, though.
An arrow?
Yeah.
There's a bridge not far from Big Ben, right?
It seems to be pointing at the bridge.
I see...
In the middle of the bridge, near a drain with
its cover removed, there were words written.
The Valley of Fear.
"Kyoufu no Tani"!
Found it!
Found it, Shinichi!
Where's the keyword hidden around here, then?
The Valley of Fear...
That was a long novel...
Was there a bridge somewhere in the story?
No, it doesn't have to be a bridge.
Drain...
River...
Water...
Water!?
Is there something sunk in the river?
"When water is near and a weight is missing...
"It is not a very far-fetched supposition that
something has been sunk in the water."
Holmes said that.
So there should be something that's
been sunk into the River Thames.
On the street lamp attached to the bridge railing...
There's a thin rope tied, and the end of
the rope has been sunk in the river!
An A!
An A has been carved into it!
The letters that have been found are T, N, and A...
Hey, Shinichi...
The next place is probably a building that looks like a cake, but...
Where should we go?
We can't get anywhere over the phone!
Wait there!
I'll be on my way there soon!
It's fine if we just do it over the phone...
Since...
We've already managed to find three of the keywords ourselves...
If that detective brat is here in London...
Meeting up with him and solving the code
together would be faster, wouldn't it?
Or will something inconvenient happen if he comes here?
No, of course not!
Huh?
If it isn't it the girl from yesterday!
Minerva Glass-san!
Minerva Glass (22)
Tennis Player
Minerva Glass?
The tennis player?
Is it all right for you to be out and about?
The ladies' singles final is tomorrow, right?
Yeah.
I'm just taking a short break from training.
And are you all right now?
About your troubles last night.
Don't tell me, that person is your boyfriend?
He's my father.
And what's troubling me now is a code...
Apollo Glass (22)
Minerva's Younger Brother
A code?
Then you're just like my little brother Apollo.
It seems ho got a code from a bizarre man...
And gave it to a boy who called himself Holmes's apprentice.
Holmes's apprentice?
I think his name was Conan.
I see!
So what Conan-kun said about an Apollo-kun was actually you!
You know that kid?
Yeah.
But he caught a cold and is sleeping in the hotel today.
Did you hear that just now, Shinichi?
We just ran into the boy named Apollo-kun
who entrusted Conan-kun with the code...
Shinichi?
Sorry...
An urgent matter came up...
So I can't come and meet you...
Really?
Yeah...
I just got an email saying that a client from
another case is on their way to see me.
If it's an urgent matter, there's no helping it...
Well, I'll be at the hotel in the meantime, so give me a call anytime.
The one who made the code is a
heinous criminal named Hades Sahara.
If it's not solved soon, things might get really ugly.
If that Apollo kid is there, have him go with you.
Since he's probably more familiar with London than you.
Got it.
Say, Apollo-kun...
Can you come with us and take a stab at the code?
Yeah, sure!
I'm going back to the hotel.
I have a massage appointment.
Please take care of my brother then!
Sure!
But the next code is "cake," right?
Is there a building like that in London?
Cake?
I know a place like that!
Amazing!
It really looks like a wedding cake!
Of course it does.
Wedding cakes were originally designed
to look like the shape of this church.
And it's even named St. Bride's Church...
Sounds like a joke to me.
But Apollo-kun, you sure know a lot!
I used to come here with my sister all the time.
She used to say that she and Ares would
get married at this church one day.
Ares?
He's my sister's former coach!
Although my dad used to be Ares's coach.
Your dad...
If I recall, he passed away in a traffic accident?
Yeah.
It was while they were on their way to watch Ares's match.
That day, my sister caught a cold so she was home with my mum.
And I was still in my mom's tummy then.
After that, Ares suddenly said he'd retire from
playing and took over being my sister's coach.
Since it seemed that my dad's dream was
to train my sister to win at Wimbledon.
Then his dream was fulfilled!
Yeah!
But, Ares...
He still can't get over the idea that
my dad died because of his match.
So he broke things off with my sister
and even quit being her coach...
Even though he always liked her.
He'd say, "In tennis, love is 0...
"No matter how many zeroes you add together, you'll just lose."
And he'd try to act cool.
In tennis, love means zero, eh?
I see...
So that's why she said that.
Then, you've also had love troubles?
Still, I'm no longer troubled.
Love is 0.
No matter how many zeroes you add
together, you'll just lose miserably.
Come to think of it, I completely forgot that
I was supposed to tell her something!
Tell what to who!?
No...
Regardless, is it all right if we don't look for it?
There should be a keyword related to Holmes
hidden somewhere around this church, right?
That's right, we have to search!
What?
You say there are pieces of paper strewn about near
a church that's shaped like a wedding cake?
Then, what's written on the paper?
It's written by hand and says...
A Scandal in Bohemia.
"Bohemia no Shuubun"...
It's the story Irene Adler appeared in.
And?
Is there anything besides the title written on
that paper, or anything strange about it?
The paper is light pink, and the words look
like they were written with a black pen.
Other than that, there's nothing strange about it.
The paper is thick and can't be seen through.
You see, but you do not observe.
How rude!
I'm observing it just fine!
Oh, no...
That's a line that Holmes said to Watson in the story.
There's a scene where he shows
Watson a letter with that same color.
If I'm to look at the paper more thoroughly,
I'll have to take it out of its plastic bag.
It's inside a plastic bag?
Yeah.
Then, take it out of the bag and soak it in water!
The plastic bag is a hint telling us to soak it!
The water's washing away the letters...
S is the only letter that's still distinct!
It seems only the S was written with an oil-based pen.
Yeah.
The paper was thick in order to hide that fact.
If it were a thin sheet of paper, the letter written with an
oil-based pen would've bled through to the other side.
So this means...
The keyword from the cake-like St. Bride Church is...
S.
From the egg-shaped City Hall, we have...
T.
The pickle-like building, Gherkin, gave us...
N.
And from Big Ben, the loud sound of a rolling bell...
A.
In the code, Big Ben appears twice.
So if we treat it as if there are two As, we get...
SATAN.
The Devil.
But a massive murder probably will happen here in London!
While you were at the places shown in the
cipher, did you see anyone suspicious?
Come to think of it, I saw a woman wearing sunglasses.
That bastard Hades will probably attach
bombs to balloons and set them loose, no?
Could it be!?
Next Conan's Hint
Saturn.
Look Forward to the Next Episode