SATAN.
The Devil.
The Devil!?
But two letters still remain.
It's too early to determine it's Satan.
But, the two lines remaining are...
"I am a long-nosed wizard in a castle," and...
"Pierce the white back using two swords," right?
They're creeping me out before even
we've started looking for them!
As far as "I'm a long-nosed wizard in a castle," I know where that is.
The one with a long nose is the "elephant".
And then there's "castle".
In London, there's an area called "Elephant & Castle".
Check that out for me.
But, what part of that area should we go to?
Try the station for now.
Got it.
We'll go check out the Elephant & Castle Station.
In the deciding moment that determines your future.
You cannot lie to yourself!
I'll will can be seen hidden deep in the code...
What is the culprit's target?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What awaited us in London was a creepy, ciphered note.
It was a manifesto for the next crime of
Hades Sabara, a heinous criminal on the run.
Each line in the cipher represented
a distinctive building in London...
And each location held a hidden hint that
referred to the titles of Holmes stories.
Each hint was an alphabet letter.
We made progress in deciphering it, and
obtained five such letters from the alphabet.
Only two remain.
Just you wait, Hades.
I shall definitely solve this code and put a stop to your crime!
Well...
We've arrived at the station and searched for almost an hour, but...
We haven't found a thing at all!
Shinichi?
Is this really the right place?
Yeah, I think it's the right place.
But it could also mean a shopping mall in the same area.
Hey...
Hasn't that person...
Been walking back and forth the entire time we've been here?
That's true.
Hey, Shinichi!
I see a man carrying an attaché case...
And it has "Identity" written on it in big letters!
That's probably...
A Case of Identity.
It's the title of a Holmes story, known as "The
Case of the Disappearing Bridegroom" in Japan.
Ask that man about it.
It looks like he was paid by somebody to loiter around
this station in the same manner for the entire day.
He said that both the empty case and the clothes
he's wearing were given to him by that person.
The clothes too?
"My first glance is always at a woman's sleeve.
"In a man it is perhaps better first to take the knee of the trouser."
The knees of his trousers!
Try looking at that man's knees!
His knees?
But, there's nothing written there...
Then try rolling it up!
What're you doing!?
Hey, hey, what're you doing here!?
Found it!
On the inside of his pants near the knee is...
The letter U!
Putting it all together...
T, N, A, A, S, U.
The remaining cipher is...
The last line, "It tells me to finish everything by
piercing the white back with two swords," but...
I'm stuck at the "white back" and "two swords" parts.
There aren't any buildings or places with those shapes or names...
I see, this is it!
It's the mark for a porcelain maker!
By "pierce the white back with two swords" he means...
The two-sword trademark on the back of this
porcelain tableware famous for its white color!
Then, our next stop is a store for that porcelain maker in London?
If it's that store, I went there a lot with my mom!
Since my mom's favorite is that brand of porcelain.
And there's only one store in London.
Strange decorations?
Yeah.
I asked the store staff...
And they said they've been troubled by someone
hanging strange decorations on their sign each day.
What kind of decoration was it?
There are threads of various colors with a bell attached at the end...
And a letter is written on each bell.
Where the threads are tied together, there are some
words that look like a title written there, but...
It's stained and I can't quite make it out.
That title is probably...
A Study in Scarlet.
It's where Conan Doyle first conceived
Sherlock Holmes into this world...
His debut case, and we call it "Hiiro no Kenkyuu"!
Find a scarlet thread from that bundle.
That is, the thread that's a vivid red color.
The line Holmes says in that story goes...
"There's the scarlet thread of murder running
through the colorless skein of life...
"And our duty is to unravel it, and
isolate it, and expose every inch of it."
Got it!
The red thread!
One the bell attached to that thread, the letter R is written!
If R is the last letter, then...
The keywords are T, N, A, A, S, U, and R—those seven letters.
If five of those makes SATAN...
What do the remaining U and R mean?
Hey, Shinichi?
No, looks like we can leave it as just one A.
The letters are arranged...
SATURN...
The "Soil Planet"!
So the culprit probably...
Intends to commit something on Saturday, or "Soil Day"!
Soil Day...
Wait, that's tomorrow!
Wait, wait, wait!
Although we can associate "Soil Planet"
with "Soil Day" in Japanese...
English speakers don't call the sixth planet
in the solar system "Soil Planet", do they?
No.
The etymology for Saturday comes from the
agricultural god of Roman mythology, Saturnus.
Saturnus's Day became Saturday...
And Saturnus is pronounced Saturn in English!
Is that so...
But what's going to happen on Saturday, and where?
Apollo!
It sounds Apollo!
Mom!
How did you know I was here?
The solution of the code brought me here.
The last sentence might hint this boutique...
See? I told you so, Ares...
Yes...
You deserve to be a Sherlockian...
Now, we are going back to the hotel!
Tomorrow we are going to watch Minerva's game.
Not now...
Leave the code to us and go with your mama, kid!
But...
Say, your mother said they're going to go and cheer, but...
If I remember correctly, your mother's eyes...
Even though she can't see, she can tell by the sound.
Juno Glass (22)
Minerva's Mother
That's why Mom always goes to the finals at the very least.
Since Mom didn't go to cheer for her at the French
Open tennis finals last year, and my sister lost...
Ares Ashley (30)
Minerva's Former Coach
Apollo!
Be an angel and jump in the car!
Though I broke all of the codes...
I can't find out what and where it will happen!
Of course you can't...
Because you didn't break them.
Well, I gave you a chance...
It's your fault that you can't stop my final revenge...
Since you couldn't read my revelations.
Curse your incompetence...
Holmes's apprentice is on your side, right?
He'll make it clear...
Holmes's apprentice?
No kidding...
Geez, what a carefree person...
It's Saturday, and even though a mass murder
could happen somewhere in London today...
She's still out there walking her dog!
You've informed Scotland Yard about how the
cipher becomes "Saturday" when solved, right?
Yeah.
I told them how each of the seven lines in
the cipher indicated a building or place...
And there was one letter of the keyword hidden at each place.
And together they formed SATURN, meaning Saturday.
In other words, the culprit was probably
intending to do something on Saturday.
I explained everything, but...
They came back with, "Which Saturday is it?"
And hung up on me after saying, "If we don't know when,
where, or what's going to happen, we can't do anything."
And that detective brat?
Did he say anything?
Shinichi said he's got another investigation
to work on, so he'll leave the rest to us.
Leave the rest to us?
We've solved the cipher which was the only clue, and figured
out that something's going to happen on Saturday, right?
What else is there to do?
Maybe...
There's still something left unsolved in the cipher.
Since you only need one A to spell out the keyword SATURN...
Shouldn't there be another reason why Big Ben,
where that A was found, appears twice in the cipher?
Conan-kun...
Did you get over your cold?
Yeah...
But I'm still coughing a little.
What the hell is with this Hades Sabara guy anyway?
Why would he give out a ciphered manifesto of his crime?
He's probably a self-aggrandizing man.
Previously, he sent advance warning riddles
for the hospital bombings as well, but...
After he blew up the hospital, he deliberately sent the
police a videotape he took of the destruction...
Which was enclosed along with a letter explaining the riddle.
I see.
So he was saying, "Catch me if you can," huh?
If that's the case, we need to hurry and figure out
the cipher's true meaning to tell the police!
We have to proceed the matter with caution, though
In the case of the second hospital, they
had somehow solved the riddle...
But right after the bomb disposal team went in, he set the bomb off.
What the hell!?
Then, he'll commit it whether the cipher is solved or not!?
It also seems he sent a video of that incident.
It contained his laughing voice saying,
"You're too late!" recorded on the video.
So in order to stop his crime, it looks like we'd have to solve
the cipher completely and sneak over to that place...
And secretly creep up to that man and capture him.
If I recall, the City Hall and the Gherkin...
Were on the opposite sides of the River Thames.
While you were at places shown in the
cipher, did you see anyone suspicious?
Anyone suspicious?
Now that you mention it...
I saw a woman wearing sunglasses.
Did that person...
Look something like this?
She's an explosives expert who used to work with Hades.
I'm not sure if she looked like that or not...
I got it!
It's balloons!
That bastard Hades...
Will probably attach bombs to balloons and set them loose, no?
First, starting with Big Ben at the beginning of the code...
We connect it to the Elephant & Castle
Station from the second line...
And go to the City Hall from the third line.
Then, crossing the River Thames, we arrive
at the Gherkin from the fourth line.
Going through St. Bride's Church from the fifth line...
And returning to Big Ben for the sixth line.
Then, with the last line...
We head over to the porcelain store on Walton Street...
Here, take a look!
It looks just like a balloon, doesn't it!?
The reason Big Ben appeared twice is because we need to
connect the locations in the order shown in the code!
But that shape...
Rather than a balloon...
Could it be!?
Excuse me.
We're looking for this man, have you seen him?
I'm sorry?
He seemed to have entered the toilet you came out of...
Who is this man?
He's known to be the mass murderer terrifying the people in London...
And he seems to have changed his appearance to this.
Sorry, I haven't seen him!
I'm sorry to have disturbed you...
Oh, he won't be around here...
Yeah, I guess so...
Incompetent fools.
As I thought, there's no one who can even come close to my level.
It's a little lonely without any resistance from them...
But this is my final offering of revenge for my mother.
It's not too bad for everything to end peacefully.
Right...
For my mother's sake...
I shall silence this place.
Where the cheers echo...
In this Wimbledon Centre Court!
I, as Hades Sabara!
What!?
A tennis racquet?
Not a balloon?
It's true...
It's a little warped, but it does seem to me like a racquet.
Hey, hey!
If we're talking about tennis in London...
Wimbledon!
Minerva-san will begin her final match at 2:00 PM today!
But wasn't Wimbledon wrong?
I thought if he had told all the children he gave that cipher to, "A
person will die right before your eyes," it'd be wrong, but...
Since the police haven't issued a warning about a mass murder yet...
He probably only told those words to Apollo.
And the reason he also passed the cipher to other kids
was to confuse the investigation with false leads.
So, someone dying before Apollo's eyes...
Means that the culprit's target is likely in
the Wimbledon Ladies' Singles final!
But, why Wimbledon?
Maybe it has something to do with tennis.
Since the culprit passed the cipher to
Apollo-kun inside of Wimbledon too.
Perhaps that "something" was the bookie?
We know his mother died of heart disease...
Last July.
But it seems that, a month before, Hades placed
a losing bet with a bookie on some sort of game.
Speaking of which, Minerva-san lost at the French Open last year...
And that final match was in June, wasn't it?
If I recall, she had won all her matches up until the
final, which she had to drop out of due to injury.
So if Hades had to come up with the rest of the
cost needed for his mother's operation...
And had placed all his money on her sure
win at the French Open tennis...
He'd lost the bet and all of his money, causing
her mother to forgo her operation and died!
Then, could it be that the culprit's target is...
The Grass Court Queen...
Minerva Glass!?
I wonder if she's all right?
Yeah!
With Mom here, she'll win for sure!
But, is it all right?
We're always in the general admission seats.
Yes.
I dislike sitting in the family box.
The TV cameras will zoom in on me since
I don't appear to be watching the match.
And if Minerva sees my footage in the middle
of her match, she may get distracted.
But even so, that child...
She always seems to find me when the match is about to be over.
Still, it's such a shame...
To think this is the last time we'll be watching a match with you.
I'd even thought that you would do me
the honor of becoming my son-in-law.
I cannot take your daughter when I've
already taken your husband from you.
Hey, is it true that you're going to be someone else's coach?
Yeah.
That's why it'll be awkward for me to see you all again.
Well, it'll be fine.
Your sister is doing well enough even without me, after all.
Hey, hey!
It's already after 2:00, y'know!
The match is already starting!
But what are we going to do after we get to Wimbledon?
We don't even have tickets.
For that, where there's a will, there's a way!
A will...?
Well, Conan-kun?
Have you reached Apollo-kun?
No...
He probably turned his phone off while watching the game.
Hello?
Apollo!?
What were you doing?
You never called me!
Sorry...
Where are you now?
I couldn't take the call in the seats, so I came out to the passageway.
Anyway, since you called me...
Does it mean the culprit who gave me that code has been captured?
No, not yet, but...
Then don't call me now!
I'm watching my sister's game!
Well then...
Has anything strange happened at the court?
Like if anyone has spoken to you, or...
Yeah, some of my sister's fans said "good luck" to her.
And since they recognized me, Mom, and Ares...
They gave us a huge stuffed animal and said it's for my sister!
And how's your sister doing?
How she's doing?
I think it's just the usual.
Her match just started, after all.
But, why are you asking me this stuff?
Don't tell me, something's going to happen here!?
No!
It's nothing like that...
It's just that we wanted to watch your sister's game.
Do you have any extra tickets?
Extra?
He can't possibly have some...
Extra tickets, that is.
And we're here in front of the gates...
Even though we know there's a heinous
criminal somewhere inside that court...
Damn, I've no other choice...
Hey, hey!
Oh, Sleeping Detective!
Are you here for the game?
Diana-san!
I forgot our tickets!
Can you help me with this?
How about this idea?
I see.
As long as we have admission tickets,
even if we can't get into Centre Court...
We can still watch the final on this huge screen here!
So this is the famous Murray Mound...
But we sure were lucky!
That Diana-san has influence within the Steering Committee
here, and immediately arranged for admission tickets for us.
Of course, we weren't able to push our luck as
to obtain tickets for Centre Court though...
Who the hell is she?
That old lady...
Say, how's the match going?
It seems Minerva-san isn't in her top condition.
All of her serves are catching the net...
And she's losing with a score of 3-0.
Let!
First service!
Please... somebody...
Anybody, help...
Help me...
Holmes...!
My sister's being targeted by the culprit!?
Just a little longer...
Just a little longer, Mother...
There's no way they'd exist in this world...
Someone like Sherlock Holmes.
I'll help you!
I'm Holmes's apprentice!
Holmes's...
Apprentice?
Next Conan's Hint
Stuffed Bear
Look Forward to the Next Episode