Let.
First service.
She hit the net again...
Hey, hey...
Wasn't Minerva Glass famous for the precision of her serves?
She rarely double faults, but...
Why'd she hit the net?
Let.
First service.
She's catching the net every time...
I wonder if something's wrong with her serve?
No...
She hasn't broken form, so she should
be hitting where she intends to hit.
Then why?
What's wrong, Minerva?
What are you doing?
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
A message from the Grass Court Queen...
Can it reach Holmes's apprentice?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What awaited us in London was a creepy, ciphered note.
It was a manifesto precipitating the next crime of
Hades Sabara, a heinous criminal on the run.
After solving the code, we found out that Hades
was targeting Wimbledon's Centre Court.
Ran met the number one-ranked tennis player at Baker Street...
And she, Minerva Glass, was set to play
in the ladies' singles final on the court.
We rushed to Wimbledon immediately, but we
couldn't get into the Centre Court without tickets.
Damn...
Do we have no other choice but to watch and do nothing!?
Minerva-san lost the first set 0-6!
It's no wonder.
She kept grazing the net two or three times, followed by a soft serve.
Maybe something's wrong with her serve, and
that's why she can only do slice serves...
But that's strange...
Since it's still her first service, she could've switched
to a hard serve until she hits too far and gets a fault.
But not only has she not double faulted, she
hasn't even faulted a single time—why?
It's on the screen!
The spots where Minerva-san's serves have landed during this game.
They've also indicated the positions of
the serves where she had grazed the net.
They're neatly spaced as if she had
calculated where each serve would land...
This—could it be!?
Hey, is there anything odd about Minerva-san today?
You mean like...
How there's something wrong with her serve?
No, like if she's doing something she never does...
Or not doing something she always does.
Now that you mention it...
It looks like she isn't wearing her right wristband.
Even though she'd said in an interview that during a final,
she always wears the wristband her father gave her.
I wonder if she forgot to bring it?
Wristband?
Unbelievable!
We've entered the second set and Glass hasn't won a single game!
The unrivaled Grass Court Queen, Minerva Glass...
Just where has she gone?
Oh my...
It seems we'll be having a regret party tonight.
Even though we were given such a cute
stuffed animal from one of her fans...
It doesn't seem like we can give it to her.
An email from Holmes's apprentice...
"Let's meet at Murray Mound"?
My sister's being targeted by the culprit!?
Are you for real!?
Yeah.
Your sister probably knows this, so she's trying to
convey that with the placement of her serves.
But, how did she find out?
The culprit probably told her.
Through a letter or something placed inside her wristband.
It'd be impossible if it were her racquet
or something she always uses, but...
Since she only wears her wristband during
the final, there'd be a chance to sneak it in.
Now that you mention it...
We lost track of my sister's bag at the hotel a while ago, but...
We found it right away and checked the contents!
That must be when it was snuck in!
Since it's unlikely that you'd check the inside of the wristband.
Then I'll go tell everyone about that!
You can't!
We don't know how the culprit intends to kill your sister, but...
The opponent is a heinous criminal who blew
up a hospital after his riddle was solved!
If you create a fuss and get the match cancelled...
Your sister might be killed instantly, you know?
Then, what will you do!?
Are you saying you'd keep quiet and just watch!?
I don't plan to keep quiet.
So, will you give me your ticket?
I'll go into Centre Court in your place, find
the culprit, and protect your sister at all cost.
Conan-kun's going!?
Shouldn't I be the one to go!?
There's no way you can Uncle.
There's a chance the culprit knows that
you're a great detective from Japan.
Since I'm a kid, I can go near the culprit
without him being any the wiser.
Well, I'll give you my ticket, but...
If I don't get back there, Mum and Ares will worry.
Just send Ares an email saying, "I don't want to see Minerva
lose, so I'll wait for you guys outside," and it'll be okay.
But, still...
How do you plan to find the culprit in Centre Court?
They say that criminal Hades changes his appearance all the time!
About that, don't you always say this, Uncle?
"Where there's a will, there's a way."
A "will"?
Conan-kun!
It's all right if you end up not being able to catch the culprit, but...
You have to protect Minerva-san!
There's something I have to tell her!
Got it!
Scream, shout, shriek all you want.
Make as much noise as you can, so as to punctuate
the fearful silence that will soon follow!
Just a little longer...
Just a little longer, Mother...
Let.
First service.
As I thought.
What she's etching into the court is...
Braille.
To prevent the culprit from catching on, she's using the
placement of her serves to show letters in Braille.
The Braille that she memorized for the sake of her blind mother.
A Braille cell expresses a letter by etching dots in the
six positions arranged in a two-by-three rectangle.
She hit the net so often was because...
In order to etch on the bottom row, she needs to
let the ball graze the net or it won't be in position.
And depending on the letter, she may need a
lot of serves to hit as many as five positions.
That means, the first serve from her point of view is...
H.
Next was...
E.
After that...
L.
And the fourth was...
P.
Together, they form...
HELP.
She needs help!
She's asking for anyone who can read her code to help her.
Let.
First service.
Until her service game is up...
She's continuing to hit out HELP over and over.
So that means what she wants known is...
The message that Hades sent to her.
As I thought.
There's a piece of paper inserted into
the underside of her wristband, but...
As far as what's written there, it's mostly obscured and unreadable.
Damn!
I want to tell her somehow that I'm her ally, but...
How can I do that during the match without causing a commotion?
Come on, Minerva!
Come on!
Thank you...
If only you were a real person...
You'd gallantly appear and come to my aid.
But...
You are a fictional character after all.
There's no way you'd exist in this world...
Right...
Someone like Sherlock Holmes.
Minerva!
I'll help you!
I'm Holmes's apprentice!
Holmes's...
Apprentice?
Conan-kun!?
That idiot!
What's he doing?
So that brat is Holmes's apprentice?
That guy wore glasses and was a shrimp, but...
He is Holmes's apprentice and has great intelligence!
By "I'll help you," you mean...
You understood my message?
Oh, you can help me when you're so small?
Of course...
Thank you...
Then, I'm counting on you.
Mr. Holmes's Apprentice!
Thank you...
The first letter has four dots.
I've hit three of them, so what's left...
Is in the rear-right corner...
That position!
Out!
15-40.
Minerva-san scored a point!
But, I wonder what's wrong with...
Her opponent, Ms. Bauer.
She seems bewildered that she'd lost the point.
Even though it was a slice serve...
There's a good reason behind her losing that point.
Because the letter she just hit out wasn't...
The H E L or P she's hit many times before.
It was a G instead.
She's hitting out a letter she hadn't hit out before.
Meaning what she's hitting out now is likely
the message she got from the culprit.
Holmes's apprentice...
If I recall, Apollo said you're a young boy from Japan.
If you're going to call yourself an apprentice
of the great detective I love and respect...
Understand this message, then.
The next letter is the only one out of the 26 letters of the alphabet...
That can be represented...
Using just one dot!
Yes!
ace
Service A.
Since its position was in the upper left, it's literally an A in Braille.
Connecting it with the previous one...
We have G and A.
So what's next?
She's changed her serve patterns.
I see, so the time for fun and games is over...
Fault!
That serve was the first time she's faulted.
And it was really wide...
That means it's probably the end of the word.
After G, it was A, M, and E...
Meaning the first word is G A M E.
Let.
Second service.
But, what intense concentration...
To have accurately changed the
angle of her serves hitting the net...
And having placed each ball in the correct
six spots to represent letters in Braille.
As expected of the Grass Court Queen...
She can place her serves wherever she wants.
Deuce.
And Minerva-san had the advantage...
Another deuce?
That's the sixth time...
It's on purpose.
She's playing to deuces on purpose in order to
extend the game and produce more Braille letters.
Up until now, she's hit...
G A M E S E T D E A T H M.
If the GAME is SET, then DEATH, and m?
Advantage, Miss Glass.
The Braille just then was O.
That DEATH was followed by the letters M and O means...
Don't tell me...
This game goes to Miss Glass!
The score is now 3-1, with Bauer in the lead.
Since she's ended the game, the message ends here.
And the letter just now was M!
Putting it together gives us M O M.
Mother.
Then, the life Hades aims to take isn't that of Minerva herself...
But that of her mother?
Come to think of it, Ran said...
That Minerva lost at last year's French Open, which was
the only time her mother didn't come to support her.
If Hades had placed a large bet on Minerva's
win at that championship game...
And if he holds a grudge against her mother,
thinking her absence was the cause of the loss...
It'd make sense that he'd direct his
murderous intend toward her mother.
But...
How does he intend to murder her?
Is he near her?
They gave us a huge stuffed animal and said it was for my sister!
Don't tell me...
The stuffed animal her mother is holding...
That's right...
Hold it tightly and don't let go.
Because those are the fireworks that will
celebrate the conclusion of my revenge!
A bomb!?
What now!?
There's a bomb in that stuffed animal!?
Yeah!
Hades probably plans to set it off immediately
when the match concludes and kill your mother!
Then, I'll call and tell her to pretend she's
going to the toilet and leave her seat!
You can't!
If she does something unnatural like
that, he'll think that she's caught on...
And likely press the switch on the bomb via remote control!
Even if your mother is saved...
A large number of spectators around
her will be caught in the blast radius.
It'll be the biggest tragedy since the inception of Wimbledon!
No way...
That's why the only way to stop it is to find Hades
somewhere in the Centre Court stands and capture him!
But can you really find him?
Say...
Your mother and Ares aren't in the family box.
Do they always sit in the general admission seats?
Yeah.
My mum hates being filmed by the TV cameras, so she's
always in the general admission seats that are in the shade.
She said so during a magazine interview.
The shade?
Then...
That means Hades is probably in a
seat across from there, in the sun!
How come?
The video.
That guy always videotapes the moment
of his crime and sends it to the police.
If he read that magazine article...
It's likely he's in the seats across from her, a vantage point that
will allow him head-on footage of the moment of the blast!
Then, if you search for someone with a video
camera that's sitting in those seats...
No, there'd be a lot of people like that.
We have to narrow it down to one person.
Then, how?
Right...
How can I find him?
Out of these 15,000 spectators, how can I!?
Hey, what's that commotion!?
People are coming into the hallway in droves!
Don't tell me the match is over already!?
Not yet.
The match just entered the tie-break
since my sister tied it up 6-all.
I bet the spectators are yelling...
Because of the rain.
They're suspending the game by thirty minutes in order
to close the Centre Court roof, hence the commotion!
Then, will your mother also leave her
seat while the roof is being closed?
She won't.
She has an umbrella with her.
Mum really regrets not having gone to support Minerva due
to losing her eyesight, and costing her the French Open.
So she's always saying that she'll never
leave her seat until the match is over.
The echoing cheers are quite something
with the roof dosed, aren't they?
Yes.
But what happened to Apollo?
With Minerva playing such a great game...
You're right...
I'll give you the details later, but for now,
don't move from those seats!
Apollo...
What in the world?
This is bad!
The spectators who came into the
hallway are returning to their seats...
The match is about to start up again!
If Minerva loses this tie-break, the match will be over...
And Hades will press the switch on the bomb!
I have to somehow find that bastard before then...
But how am I supposed to find someone
whose face I don't even know!?
Apollo?
Did you send the email to Ares like I told you to?
Yeah.
By the way, I'm not sure if this will help, but...
My sister once told me about the method she
uses to find our mum's seat during the match.
Since I was surprised at the fact she always calls out to Mum
after she wins, even though she's never told where it is.
And?
What method is that?
She said she lobs the ball really high during the match.
Almost too high, I should add.
But as far as how that helps her find Mum, she never told me.
Almost too high, a high lob...
The Queen takes the stage once more.
Struggle all you can...
In order to prolong the time your mother
has left to live just by a little...
If I lose this tie-break...
Mother will...
Come on, Minerva!
Don't give up the fight...
Even though she has a championship point!
Hang in there, win the match!
Hang in...?
Grass Court Queen...
Can you do it?
OK!
Now, our game is on...
Hades!
If she loses the next point, Minerva-san will lose the match!
Now, there's no way out!
I'll show you...
This Grass Court Queen, Minerva Glass's...
True form!
Show yourself, Hades!
Reach it...
Please!
Next Conan's Hint
Woman with Sunglasses
Look Forward to the Next Episode