Rain's pouring down on Wimbledon.
The Centre Court roof is now closed.
Play will resume now.
Game count 6-all, second set, tie-break.
Miss Bauer, who won the first set, will serve.
The Queen takes the stage once more.
Struggle all you can...
In order to prolong the time your
mother has left to live just by a little...
If I lose this tie-break...
Mother will...
Come on, Minerva!
Don't give up the fight...
Even though she has a championship point!
Hang in there, win the match!
Hang in...?
Grass Court Queen...
Can you do it?
OK!
In the deciding moment that determines your future.
You cannot lie to yourself!
Long and life-shortening rally exchanges...
Two unexpected guests and two rising hearts!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What awaited us in London was a creepy, ciphered note.
It was a manifesto precipitating the next crime of
Hades Sabara, a heinous criminal on the run.
After solving the code, we determined that Hades's
target was in Wimbledon's Centre Court...
The tennis player participating in the Ladies'
Singles final match—Minerva Glass.
However, according to the Braille message sent by Minerva
using her serves and the positions where the ball landed...
Hades's true target was not Minerva herself, but her mother,
Juno, who was sitting in the stands rooting for her.
In sync with the end of the match,
Hades will press the detonator switch.
If we can't locate him before then...
Play!
As expected of Holmes's Apprentice...
A great idea.
However, it's a fairly risky request.
Since my opponent is ranked number
two in the world, a powerful server...
Who possesses a serve exceeding 120 mph...
Demeter Bauer!
Yes!
1-0, Miss Bauer.
But if this method allows us to capture the culprit...
If I can save my mother this way...
I'll show you...
This Grass Court Queen, Minerva Glass's...
True form!
1-all!
Amazing!
A service ace right back!
But how do they determine the winner from a tie-break?
Whoever reaches seven points would normally win this set...
But when the score is 6-all, the game continues until
a player holds a 2-point lead over the other.
Then, if the Grass Court Queen falls behind by two points...
My sister who lost the first set will lose, and the match will be over.
And when that happens, the bomb that my mum's holding...
Will be detonated by that Hades guy, right?
Out!
7-6, Miss Bauer.
Hey, if she's trailing 7-6, that means...
Her opponent has the championship point!
If she loses the next point, Minerva-san will lose the match!
Sis...
Now, there's no way out, Grass Court Queen!
In synch with the end of the match, I'll push
the switch and blow your mother up!
Then, as I mentioned in the message inserted in your
wristband, I'll give you the footage as a present.
The footage of your mother being blown to bits!
To you, who shamefully lost at the French Open
last year, and thus allowed my mother to die...
To you, who triumphed at Wimbledon on the day
of my mother's funeral just a month later...
And arrogantly hoisted your trophy!
I shall give you a taste of my rage and sorrow!
Well, Mr. Holmes's Apprentice?
As you wished, I've given the championship point to my opponent.
And with the high lob just now, I've even found my mother.
So, you'll also have to concentrate hard and find him.
The culprit.
With your name as Holmes's Apprentice on the line!
First, an easy one to the center.
She'll hit it back with a forehand and send it to my ad court.
Then I'll apply a severe cross-slice!
You should be able to return it on a day like this, right?
What an amazing rally.
They've passed it back and forth over ten times!
Come on, Minerva-san!
A frame shot...
A big one!
It's out!
In that case, I'll return it with a volley before it goes out...
Oh no, too shallow!
She's coming up to the net!
It's a chance ball for her opponent!
Finish!
Backcourt, left side...
Just on the line!
It's in!
Good, we'll start over with this!
But, what a long rally!
Hasn't it been over thirty times so far?
Could Minerva-san possibly be dragging this rally on?
Not to mention she used a volley to
return a ball that was going out...
But...
What reason does she have for dragging this out?
Now, Hades...
Where?
Where are you?
Show yourself, Hades!
A cord ball!?
Reach it...
Please!
No way!
She didn't reach it!
Then, could it be!?
My sister...
Lost!?
Same, set, and...
Match won by...
Challenge!
What's that?
A challenge?
It's called the challenge system.
If a player disagrees with the umpire's call...
They can get the position of the ball
confirmed up to three times per set.
Using ten pieces of equipment collectively called the
Hawk-Eye, the recorded data is replayed using CG.
So, Minerva-san must be insisting that
the cord ball just now was out.
Don't know when to give up, Queen?
Begging for your life in front of the guillotine?
But the decision won't be overturned.
And after the cheers of joy, a silent interval in between
the blast and the screams will be born...
Let that be a requiem for my mother!
It's out!
The challenge was a success!
Then, they're tied 7-all!
I somehow pulled through...
But for rallying, that was my limit.
But...
It seems like that face means he found him!
All right!
She's caught up!
However, the next one is the final set.
No matter who wins, Hades will set
the bomb off once the match is over!
It'll be OK.
Holmes's Apprentice sent me an email saying he found the culprit.
He's probably on his way to catch him now.
Please! Let me in!
Like I've been telling you...
This is the wrong place for your ticket!
I must see someone before the game is over!
I will come back right away, please!
You might need this?
When this boy ran into me...
We happened to exchange our tickets.
Well, you can enter here then!
There you go, boy.
Now, youse!
Whatcha still lingering round here for?
Tosa dialect?
Youse finally found the culprit, so youse had better hurry...
Gotta capture him, zeyo!
Shin-chan!
Mom!?
Roger that!
But I wonder how Shin-chan found the culprit?
The movement of the spectators' heads.
When a guest comes to watch tennis, their head
will follow the ball and swivel left and right.
When the ball goes left, they do this...
When it's hit back to the right, they do this.
If they're sitting in a place that faces the
players' sides, they'll definitely do it.
But if there was someone who didn't move at
all, he'd stand out and catch your eye, right?
If it was the championship point, all the more so.
Which means he's the culprit who aims to blow up the
Grass Court Queen's mother at the end of the match...
And capture that moment with his video camera!
If he doesn't capture her mother in his
camera frame before the match is over...
The fans will probably stand up in excitement
and block his view once the match concludes.
I see!
That's why Shin-chan said that to her...
"Even though she has a championship point, hang in there!"
If he can get her to stretch out the rally,
he can get more time to find the culprit.
But how befitting of the Grass Court Queen!
To go along with his request without even asking why...
No, since it's a method she also uses frequently...
I'm sure she immediately understood the intent behind it.
The extremely high lob that she often hits during a game...
Is done for the purpose of finding her mother.
If she knows the ball will go out anyway,
it's fine for her to take her eyes off it.
And from the spectators who follow the
ball up and down with their heads...
She finds her blind mother who stays still.
The question now is whether Shin-chan will
be able to capture the culprit he found.
There won't be any problem.
He'll stealthily creep up behind the culprit...
And just shoot him with that tranquilizer watch of his.
All right, perfect!
Oh!
You're Holmes's Apprentice!
You made Minerva rise!
What!?
But you know, that was against the manner...
Never do it!
Could he have sniffed me out?
That's Holmes's Apprentice...
Then, the man getting flustered really is...
In that case, I have no choice.
I'll detonate the bomb now...
And escape from here amidst the confusion!
No way!
From that distance!?
As expected of the Grass Court Queen...
Setting up a nice shot in front of the goal!
Security!?
Ah, the ball just happened to come...
Thank you...
I see...
So Dad had already called the police and had them standing by...
Yeah...
I asked a good friend in Scotland Yard to do so.
Since I solved the cipher and realized this was going to be the target.
It was quite an ordeal!
In order to make it easier for Shin-chan to solve
the code as well, I had to follow you around.
So, the woman with sunglasses that was hanging
around Ran and the others was you, Mom?
I almost thought it was Hades's accomplice, that explosives expert!
As for her, I hear that they've confirmed
her death in that suicide bombing.
They've analyzed the DNA from the scene.
Which means that stuffed animal bomb was actually her parting gift.
If you'd already figured all that out...
Why didn't you go and catch him yourself, Dad!?
Actually, I was the one who solved the riddle
from the second hospital bombing incident.
The culprit would've been on the lookout
for me, so I couldn't have gotten close.
Anyway, don't be so angry.
After all, the method you used to locate the culprit was superb.
And to enable you to move freely no
matter where the culprit was located...
We even got a hold of tickets for
each section of the stadium for you.
But come on...
If you came to pursue this case, you could've at least contacted me!
No...
We actually came to London because that child asked us to.
That child?
Game, set, and...
Match won by...
Miss Glass!
Splendid!
How does it feel?
Has this feeling made you feel nostalgic?
The reason Minerva asked you to stop being her coach...
Wasn't because she wanted to make you into
an ordinary husband who would quit tennis.
It's because she wanted you to regain this feeling.
You, who had retired for her sake.
Be yourself, Ares.
You do feel the passion, right?
She won!
Minerva-san won!
Then, since the explosion didn't occur...
He must have apprehended the culprit!
Yeah!
Holmes's Apprentice just emailed me saying he did!
Say, Apollo-kun...
Can I meet with your sister after this?
I have something I need to tell her.
But she'll probably be busy with all
kinds of press conferences and stuff.
How about emailing her?
I'll give you her address.
Thanks!
Hey...
Hold on a sec.
Isn't that...
That Diana lady!?
No way...
That's the royal box!
Could she be from the royal family?
Or possibly a noble, or a family friend...
Then, that man I threw in the restaurant...
Might be a prince from somewhere!?
Should I call and ask?
No, don't...
I don't want to know...
What was the key to your victory?
What led to my victory?
Well, I suppose I owe it to Holmes's Apprentice?
But the reason I'm smiling so much is...
Because of a Japanese girl whose email I just received.
What a surprise!
To think you'd come all this way to see us off...
Is it all right?
You must be really busy today...
Yeah.
I have a lot of things to do, but I played hooky and came here.
Because no matter what, I had to thank you for the email.
What's this about your email?
Those words really resounded in my heart.
"It's true that in tennis, love is zero...
"But zero is also..."
Please don't say that here!
Actually, I merely passed those words on from him...
"Him"?
Could it be the boyfriend who was causing
you distress in front of the Holmes statue?
Yes...
Well...
Stupid...
Stupid of me...
I got excited over nothing...
It's just like that person said.
Love is 0...
No matter how many zeroes you add
together, you'll just lose miserably.
What are you talking about?
Don't you get it?
You're a detective, aren't you?
If you call yourself a detective, why don't
you try to deduce what's in my heart!?
Idiot!
Hey, wait!
Ran!
I said wait!
Hey!
No!
Let me go!
You're really troublesome!
You're a troublesome and tough case, you know!
With all these distracting emotions...
Even if I were Holmes, it'd still be impossible to figure out!
The heart of the girl whom one likes...
How can one accurately deduce that!
As for love is zero?
Don't make me laugh!
Tell the Grass Court Queen this!
Zero is where everything starts!
Nothing would ever be born if we didn't depart from there...
And nothing would ever be achieved!
Tell her that!
I see...
Your boyfriend has a way with words!
That's why, if you can tell those words to Ares-san too...
About that, I've already sent Ares an email and received his reply.
He said he's got training to do, so he can't meet with me for a while.
So he's training some other player?
He did say he was going to be someone else's coach.
No, it's his own.
It seems he's going to make a comeback as a tennis player.
In order to take a Queen as my bride, it
looks like I'll have to become a King.
Well, since I've gotten quite rusty...
zero
I'm pretty much starting at 0 like you said.
love
No, maybe it's 0 that I'm starting from?
But, it's too bad Holmes's Apprentice couldn't be here.
I had wanted to express my thanks to that child as well...
It seems there was some matter in Japan he had to attend to.
He said they'd already gotten their tickets and
left with the Professor on an earlier flight.
Then, please give him my regards!
Sure!
You'd better thank Ai-kun for this.
Yeah...
But come on...
That Haibara Ai child asked us over the phone.
She said you'd probably use both
antidotes for Ran-chan's sake anyway...
So we should bring you an extra pill just in case.
If she read my mind, she could've given me a hundred of them!
He'll never learn...
All right, let's hide!
Geez, and I ended up being "it"...
There's someone here in this building!
252...
Someone in need of rescue!
They disguised as demolition workers
and confined someone here...
Which means they're a couple of bad guys!
Next Conan's Hint
Convenience Store Lunchbox
Look Forward to the Next Episode