In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
Sounds reverberating in an abandoned building...
A predetermined rhythm becomes the signal of case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
EMERGENCY SITUATION 252
(PART ONE)
Really, Conan-kun?
You found a culprit at Wimbledon and caught him?
Yeah.
What kind of case was that?
It involved a heinous criminal terrifying London.
He'd already blown up two hospitals in the past.
As expected of the Grass Court Queen...
Setting up a nice shot in front of the goal!
Geez...
You're awesome!
Then, it must've made the news, right?
It seems it hasn't yet.
But there was news about a boy from Japan who yelled out and disrupted the match.
Was that you too?
Yeah, I had to do it to apprehend the culprit...
Well, you couldn't have gone public with that, right?
Since Edogawa Conan is a boy who never entered the UK.
Yeah...
Dad covered for me pretty well.
Kamen Yaiba!
You're right!
This is the newest figurine that's on sale today!
As expected, Yaiba is awesome!
Really!
And it's well-made too!
I want it, I want it!
Look, they have Laser Police right here as well!
I wonder if Mom will buy it for me?
Not heeding my instructions, you consumed the antidote...
Returned to Kudou Shinichi's body, and met with that girl from the detective agency in London, right?
Yeah...
Thanks for that extra pill...
I'm sure you didn't get caught up in the moment...
And confess to her or anything, did you!?
Hey!
No!
Let me go!
You're really troublesome!
Huh?
You're a troublesome and tough case, you know!
With all these distracting emotions...
Even if I were Holmes, it'd still be impossible to figure out!
The heart of the girl whom one likes...
How can one accurately deduce that!
I'll spell it out again.
Right now you can only temporarily return to that body by taking a pill.
Under such conditions, what would happen if you confessed to the one who's been waiting in vain?
You even told me once before yourself.
She'll want to meet you even more than before...
And you'll end up hurting her instead!
Did I have a choice?
She wouldn't stop...
Don't forget...
Your existence is one where taking center stage is forbidden.
So until the time comes, you must forever continue to hide.
What's that?
You want to play hide-and-go-seek?
Then, let's play kick-the-can!
We happen to have a can since Genta-kun just finished his juice!
In that case, I know a good place!
We should go, we should go!
Let's go!
Look, look, it's this building here, this building.
I went inside through the gap under these shutters a while ago and took a look...
And there was no one there.
Genta-kun, it's amazing that you'd discover a place like this!
It should be fun if we play kick-the-can inside!
If I recall correctly, this is a building that's scheduled to be demolished next week.
But to think they'd leave the shutters open, how careless...
Wow, it's true!
The inside is practically empty!
I told you!
This place is perfect!
Hey, you guys!
"If you want a game of hide-and-seek, let's play ♪", huh...
All right, hide!
Yeah!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten!
Gezz, and I ended up being "it"...
Well, did tell them to let me know right away if they found any suspicious people or objects.
And after we play one round, they'll probably get tired of it.
That said, allow me to finish 'em!
I found Haibara.
Ai-chan, he found you too?
Sorry about that.
But it can't be helped.
Since our "it" is someone who'd stubbornly chase after people that are like their lives depend on it...
And smoke them out with his demonic abilities.
What's with you, saying things like that?
Nothing.
Genta-kun's the only one left...
I'm sure it's only a matter of time.
Only the third and fourth floors are left for searching.
Genta should be on one of them.
Hey, Conan!
It's Genta's voice...
Can you hear me, Conan?
What's wrong, Genta?
There's someone here on this building!
What do you mean?
I heard a sound just now...
Like someone's pounding on a wall.
Again!
Hey, Genta!
The sound just came out again.
Someone's definitely around here!
Hey, are you sure?
Yeah!
The're sounds of someone pounding on a wall...
From far away.
Is that sound still coming out?
Not now, but...
It sounded twice, then five times...
And it sounded twice again and stopped.
252...
Someone in need of rescue!
Isn't that the radio code used by the Tokyo Fire Department?
Mys sister taught me about it a while ago.
She said it might come in handy if I memorize it.
252 is the code used when there are people unable to flee and in need of rescue.
254 is the code for those on standby to wait in place.
Then, if the sound Genta-kun heard was 252...
Doesn't that mean someone is trying to call for help?
Unbelievable...
Anyway, let's go where Genta is.
We'll talk about that afterward.
It was quiet?
You mean, there weren't any sounds in the time it took us to get here?
Right.
It seems we'll have to search each room one by one.
Where did you hear that sound from?
From that direction.
Was it this sound?
Yeah...
But, it isn't 252.
Guess we'll have to take a look.
The sound's coming from the floor above.
From this room.
You guys, stay back.
Since we don't know what could be inside.
What's the matter, kids?
You can't.
You can't just waltz in this building like that.
What are you guys doing?
We're going to demolish this building, so we're striking the walls to inspect their strength.
Striking up a rhythm in this manner!
This guy got caught up in the moment and began to strike to the beat of a song.
Take your job seriously.
There are still a lot of rooms we have to inspect.
Yeah, yeah.
Then, the 252 Genta-kun heard was...
Just a coincidence due to the song being in the rhythm 252.
What the...
Say...
Only the two of you are here?
Yeah.
That's right.
But, isn't this the trash from the lunch boxes you bought from the convenience store this afternoon?
There are three lunch boxes, you know?
This guy here ate two of them himself.
I can gobble up two lunches in one bite!
Regardless, kids, you're not allowed here.
That's right, you should leave right away.
Understood!
Hurry home and do your homework.
You can play after that.
Yes!
Well then, lets' go home.
Good luck with your work!
That's right...
Can I ask one last question?
About the amount of explosives you'll be using to implode this building.
Hard to say...
We haven't finished surveying, so we don't really know.
This building is pretty big, so I think it'll take a good amount.
I see!
Then, it'll be a pretty big explosion, right?
Yeah!
You can come see it then!
Bye then!
In the end, nothing was wrong.
Yeah, and I thought it might've been a case...
Well. let's all come to watch when they do the building implosion!
We should!
It sounds like it'll be amazing!
No...
I'm sure there won't be any building implosion.
When demolishing buildings...
It's usually done by either setting heavy machinery on top of the building and above...
Or demolishing it from the side.
All the more so if it's a building in the city center.
But, I've seen it done on TV!
They were huge buildings in the middle of town...
With a boom, they'd collapse nicely down, right?
That was probably footage from foreign countries.
In Japan, there have only been a few building implosions so far.
But the Haido Art Museum was demolished using the Professor's bomb, right?
That's right, the Tropical Rainbow!
It was very pretty!
Yeah!
It was awesome!
That's because it was combined with an event...
And since the buildings near that art museum were all abandoned, special permission was given.
And the "Professor's Bomb"...
Was only his gimmick to emit seven colors after the actual explosives were set off.
Also, that art museum was much larger than this place.
I heard that if it wasn't imploded, it would've been too costly.
Well, the handling of explosives and the legal regulations concerned with it are strict in Japan.
Since there are still buildings in use right next to this one, it would be impossible for such a place to bee imploded.
And one needs to cross-check and thoroughly examine the building's construction blueprints...
In order to fine-tune the amount of explosive powder and its placement.
That's why it can't be done by using just a hammer without any machinery.
Then, who were those people just now?
They disguised as demolition workers and confined someone here...
Which means they're a couple of bad guys!
Confined?
Yeah.
There were boxed lunches for three people.
There's no doubt they're hiding the fact there's another person.
But, they said it was because that fat guy ate two of them...
There were three sets of used disposable chopsticks.
If one person had gobbled up two of them...
Why would he have changed his chopsticks?
Then, that 252 sound Genta-kun heard was...
Probably...
Someone hitting the wall as an SOS when they heard us playing kick-the-can...
Someone who's been confined here.
In short, inside this building, there's a 252...
A person in need of rescue.
There's someone who must be saved!
Detective Conan Episode 622
Fansub Release by DCTP
OCR: Nixx Car
OCR Editing: DJ VK
In short, inside this building, there's a 252...
A person in need of rescue.
There's someone who must be saved!
But, this is so unbelievable...
That those two just now could have confined someone here...
They both had the same uniform on, too.
They couldn't have prepared those so quickly, right?
They were already wearing the same overalls to begin with.
So even if they were spotted entering this building, they wouldn't have looked suspicious.
They'd appear to be some sort of contractors.
But, if the person in confinement is calling for help by using the sound for 252...
Why didn't they just say that using their voice?
I suppose it's because that person has their hands and feet bound, and their mouth sealed with something.
In that state, they probably wouldn't be able to call for help except by kicking something with their feet to make noise.
Then, since we can't hear that sound anymore, could it mean!?
Don't worry, the hostage is still alive.
If those two guys had killed the hostage, they would've fled long before they'd have shown us their faces.
and I'd guess this is a kidnapping...
Meaning killing the hostage before the transaction takes place would be too risky.
They probably knocked the person unconscious and shut them in somewhere.
Kidnapping!?
Well, don't be to concerned.
We'll just report it to the police and it'll be case closed.
It'd probably be better if I called Detective Takagi, who'll be easier to talk to.
Huh?
Conan-kun, your cell phone's wallpaper...
It's that uncle from the detective agency!
Yeah...
Uncle came home drunk and messed with it a while ago, so now it's my wallpaper.
Ayumi's is a picture of me playing with some sparklers.
It's in my backpack right now, but I'll show it to you later!
Mine is Kamen Yaiba!
What about Haibara-san?
The professor's sleeping face.
Mine is of a stray cat from my neighborhood...
But I think I lost my phone somewhere during kick-the-can.
No way...
Yes way.
Keep it down.
I'm about to call the police right now...
Who did you say you were calling?
These aren't your average brats...
Seeing through the fact that we weren't demolition workers just by meeting with us and having a short chat!
Yeah...
We were almost owned by them!
Indeed!
I only met and chatted with you to gain solid proof.
We actually already called the police!
Told them someone had been confined here, too!
Right, Detective Takagi?
What!?
What the hell...
There's no one aroun---
Damn!
They freaking got away!
We'll have to round them up one by one!
Yeah, before we're reported to the police!
Hey, brats, where are you!?
Get the hell over here!
That's not going to make them come out!
If they're not there, they must be in another room.
We can't fool around like this!
Yeah.
As usual, behind the door is the best place in a pinch...
Now's our chance.
All right, now's the time to call the police...
Oh no!
You guys go down the stairs and get out of here!
I'll be right behind you!
You brat, gotcha!
Before that...
I'll take one of them down!
Where are those brats!?
What just happened?
The door's bashed in...
Hey, take a look...
The brat's out cold!
Dunno what happened, but I guess we're lucky!
For the time being, let's bind him with duct tape and shut him around here!
Yeah...
Since this brat seems like the smartest and toughest one!
Hey, the shutters have been closed!
They won't open!
No way!
Looks like before those two set out to get us...
They made sure to cut off our escape route in case we evaded capture.
Where's Conan-kun?
He said he'd be right behind us!
Edogawa-kun...
Probably fell into hands.
And it's inevitable that we'd have come down to the first floor in order to flee outside.
So they'll probably be here any minute now.
Then, we should call the police now!
We could call, but...
Before we could explain the situation, they'd probably snatch our phone away...
And say things like we children are just playing detective games to fool the police, and then have them hang up on us.
In order to calmly report this to the police, it looks like we'll have to let them go by us once again.
But how?
Let's break the window and climb out!
It's no use.
The window is fixed.
And there are metal wires attached to the glass panel, so it's unlikely we can break it.
Then, what do we do?
How about we do this?
Hey, do you think they've already called the police?
It's all right!
We can just explain the brats' call away!
The bad guys are here!
You guys, don't come out, all right!?
They think they can hide from us like that?
I'll get the brat with the auburn hair.
You get the brats hiding by the pillar!
No, don't come!
Shut up and come here!
Hey...
It's only their backpacks!
Don't tell me, this brat used herself and those backpacks as decoys...
And allowed the other brats who'd been hiding somewhere else to get away?
Damn!
It'll be hell finding them if they've fled upstairs!
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Call the police!
Hurry, hurry!
It's ringing right now...
Hey, you brats!
Can you hear me!?
If you dare call the police or anything...
The brat with the auburn hair and brat with the glasses will lose their live, so you better think twice!
Hello, this is 110.
Is this about a crime, or an accident?
Hello?
What on earth should I do?
Damn, we've got no choice!
Let's set this place on fire and scram!
But the situation is pretty bad...
In order to make a breakthrough...
I'll be waiting in ambush at the stairs.
You call out and threaten them so we can corner them from both flanks!
Hey, you brats!
Come the hell out!
EMERGENCY SITUATION 252
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Cell Phone Wallpaper
Look Forward to the Next Episode