This is bad!
The Detective Boys are in a perilous pinch!
The whole thing started from a game of kick-the-can.
Since it was a building soon to be demolished, we thought it'd be no problem if we played there...
But I heard thumping sounds coming out.
It was in the rhythm 2-5-2.
It was the code meaning "someone in need of rescue" used by the Tokyo Fire Department.
We assumed someone was calling for help, so we started our search...
And it turned out that sound was from the demolition workers.
Just as we'd decided it was no big deal...
Conan-kun figured out.
They were actually bad guys who'd confining someone here.
We thought to call the police, but were discovered by the men...
And Conan was caught by them!
The building's exit was cut off, rendering us unable to escape.
There was no other way but to seek an opportunity to call the police, but...
If we were to do something like that, they would've caught us...
So, heeding Ai-chan's idea, we went ahead and tricked those bad men.
Our strategy seemed to have worked, but...
Even Haibara-san was captured in the end!
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
Decipher the radio code...
And get through the pinch, Detective Boys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
EMERGENCY SITUATION 252
(PART TWO)
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Call the police!
Hurry, hurry!
It's ringing right now...
Hey, you brats!
Can you hear me!?
If you dare call the police or anything...
The brat with the auburn hair and the brat with the glasses will lose their lives, so you better think twice!
Hello, this is 110.
Is this about a crime, or an accident?
Hello?
What's the matter?
Hel—
Hey...
You're not telling the police?
I had no choice...
Conan-kun and Ai-chan will be in danger.
But what are we gonna do now?
What to do...
For now, let's hide somewhere!
The fact that we haven't heard any sirens...
Means those brats really did take our orders to heart.
Well, what do we do with these two brats?
Take them to the room on the fourth floor where we're holding that old man.
I'll find the rest of the brats and be back.
But, you really sure that old man's got money?
Yeah, he's rumored to have earned a boatload!
But...
When we called his house, no one answered, right?
She'll come home soon.
His only daughter who sometimes answers the phone and sounds like a middle-schooler, that is.
We'll threaten that girl and get her to bring the money here...
Then shut her up in this building as well, and set it on fire so we can get the hell out of Dodge.
You're right.
But those brats sure were unlucky.
If they hadn't come to play in this abandoned building, they wouldn't have ended up in ashes!
Well, I'm going to go look for the other rascals.
You'd better keep close watch on those two brats.
You never know what they'll do!
Yeah, yeah.
Damn!
Why aren't they anywhere!?
Hey...
It's already past 6:00!
If we don't hurry, these brats' parents will start to worry and make a big fuss...
What about that old man?
I mean the one we kidnapped and shut in that locker!
Ah, I peeked in earlier and found him snoring.
And?
Did you call that old man's house?
Yeah, I've been calling since a little while ago, but no one's picking up still.
Regardless, where could those brats have disappeared to?
Did you really search thoroughly?
Yeah!
I'm very methodical, unlike you, sloppy one.
I carefully searched every nook and cranny!
He still can't find them despite having done so...
Which means it should be safe to assume they're hiding in one of the lockers in this room.
They came to this room and hid themselves before we were brought here...
And can't come out now even if they wanted to.
We've got no choice.
If we search once more and still don't find them...
Let's set this place on fire and scram.
Yeah...
Looks like we'll have to give up on the money.
Start spreading the gasoline.
Aye, leave it to me!
What do we do?
We'll all be turned to ashes!
We've no choice but to take them down, do we?
You're right...
Perhaps this is our chance now that there's only one of them...
The sound just now was from the detective badge...
No doubt.
Could it be...
As I thought, it's Conan-kun!
Conan-kun's hitting the detective badge against the floor.
The sound just now came out twice, then five times, and finally four more times.
Isn't this the whachacallit code Mitsuhiko-kun said earlier?
It's the radio code used by the Tokyo Fire Department.
Let's see, 254 means...
"Wait in place"!
Yeah, that's right.
You guys, do not move from there under any circumstances until further instructed!
But the situation is pretty bad.
Our opponents are those two, who have kidnapped and confined some old man...
And are scheming to make off with the ransom money.
We came here to play by chance, but those two found us...
And Haibara and I have been captured and restrained.
And one of the kidnappers, with the intent to burn us all to death along with the hostage...
Is spreading the gasoline around the room.
And other is looking for Genta and the others.
But Genta and the others are likely hiding in one of the lockers in this confinement room...
And are unable to come out.
In order to make a breakthrough...
We have to make this guy who's been left on watch leave this 4th floor room, but...
This stinks!
Guess I'll finish spreading this thing right before we're ready to light it.
The only thing I can do with my mouth sealed and my four limbs tied...
Is to strike the detective badge against the floor and give coded directions to Genta and the others.
But how can I get the guy to leave like this?
Now, I'll try calling the house of that kidnapped old man again...
Phone?
That reminds me...
Huh?
Conan-kun, your cell phone's wallpaper...
It's that uncle from the detective agency!
Yeah...
Uncle came home drunk and messed with it a while ago, so now it's my wallpaper.
Ayumi's is a picture me playing with some sparklers.
It's in my backpack right now, but I'll show it to you later!
Mine is Kamen Yaiba!
What about Haibara-san?
The professor's sleeping face.
Mine is of a stray cat from my neighborhood...
But I think I lost my phone somewhere during kick-the-can.
Hold on...
My cell phone is on the second floor hallway where I passed out.
Ayumi-chan's is probably on the first floor, inside her backpack.
Genta's is likely somewhere on the third floor where he was hiding.
Haibara had her body searched by those guys before getting tied up, and she wasn't carrying her cell phone...
So her phone is possibly in her backpack that was kicked over there by one of the culprits earlier.
And there's Mitsuhiko's.
The way they're scattered around is perfect!
Damn, when the hell is she gonna come home?
That old geezer's daughter!
Hello?
What?
You say a young man answered the phone?
Did you really call that old geezer's house?
I couldn't have gotten the phone number wrong, man...
I hung up immediately and called again after confirming the number...
And the same guy answered!
And?
Did you say anything to that man?
How could I say anything?
I thought he was a cop so I hung up right away!
You idiot!
No way he could've been a cop!
Because no one should know yet whether he's been kidnapped or not!
But man...
This is different from what we'd planned!
The old geezer was supposed to live with his middle school-aged daughter who sometimes answered the phone...
And we were going to threaten her to bring the ransom money here, right?
This whole shit is getting real bad!
Yeah...
Guess we can't help it that this whole thing started stinking to high heaven.
Let's light the fire and scram!
We'll burn those brats to death along with the hostage!
"Light the fire and scram"?
But every one of those brats saw our faces!
Not good...
If we don't make a move soon...
What are we gonna do with the brats we haven't found yet?
Don't ask me!
There's sound coming from the detective badge again.
This time it was 5-5-5, huh.
555 is the code for "call to report".
So wouldn't that mean to "call the police"?
No, if it was that, it should be 554, "request for police".
Then where are we supposed to call?
The sound again.
The number of sounds is 9-5-3.
953 is the code signifying that the cause of fire is "playing with fire".
Doesn't that mean to call the police and tell them that those guys are planning to light the fire?
But "arson" should be 951.
So, does it mean to call someone who's playing with fire?
But, who's playing with fire?
I see, it's Ayumi-chan's cell phone.
He must mean to call Ayumi-chan's cell phone, which has the picture of the sparklers as its wallpaper!
Why are you freaking out?
Light the fire and get down here already!
We don't know where those other brats are hiding, but...
By the time they notice the building's on fire, they'll already be overcome by the smoke and won't be able to make it out!
Hold on.
A cell phone ringtone.
The brats are on the first floor!
Hey, where are you!?
Give up and come out!
Good.
The next one is...
This time it's 6-5-5.
655 means an "inebriated person".
It means someone who's really drunk.
In that case...
It's Conan-kun's cell phone!
Because its wallpaper is a picture of him and the drunk Uncle from the detective agency!
Hey, how goes it?
Did you find the brats?
About that, the ringtone suddenly stopped...
So maybe they turned off the phone.
Wait, upstairs!
A different ringtone is sounding on the floor above me!
Then, I'll go take a look...
No, I'll go!
You stay there and watch those brats!
Did they split up and hide in different places!?
Good, let's move on before he finishes climbing the stairs.
"Itinerant"?
Yeah, 658 is the code indicating an "itinerant".
What does that mean?
It's someone wo doesn't have a set place to live and loiters around.
So that would be...
The stray cat that's on my cell phone?
Another ringtone?
Hey, another ringtone's coming from the floor above again!
I can hear that sound faintly from where I am on the fourth floor too.
Can it be those brats are coming up here?
Good, and for the finale...
652 means a "bedridden senior".
That's gotta be...
Ai-chan's cell phone...
THE PROFESSOR'S SLEEPING FACE!
It sounded like those brats just now...
Hey...
Don't tell me they're in one of these lockers?
Hey!
It's the vibration sound from a cell phone!
I can hear it coming from real close!
Hey, what now?
It stopped.
It seems those brats are getting in touch via cell phone and trying to find each other.
All right...
Block the door to that room with something, and you join the search too!
Got it!
I'll be waiting in ambush at the stairs.
You call out and threaten them so we can corner them from both flanks!
Well, this should do the trick.
Hey, you brats, come the hell out!
I know you're around here!
Strange...
I can't hear the sounds anymore.
Same here.
It's that brat's cell phone...
Dropped on the hallway floor!
What the hell?
The brats are calling each other's phone one by one in an attempt to confuse us!
Then where the hell are those brats?
That's it, I got it!
The confinement room!
This was all a strategy in order to get you out from that room!
So those brats are in that room?
Yeah.
Since those lockers haven't been searched even once!
Damn, so the brats' voices earlier really was...
Punks!
Stop dawdling, hurry back there and tie those brats up good!
Shit, those brats...
Little bastards tricked us!
Gotcha!
Hey!
Hey, what's wrong?
Did you find the brats?
Respond!
No, the brats are all gone!
They may have already called the police!
Things are bad so I'm outta here!
You'd better scram too!
Hey!
Hold on...
But, why are we letting the other guy get away?
It was just one more guy, so we could've just combined our strength and...
It's all right.
This guy here will tell the police all about the other culprit.
And since we've run out of weapons, there's no need to take a risky gamble.
No way...
I can hear footsteps!
They're coming closer and closer...
So he didn't flee?
You guys, stay back.
This feeling...
Could it be!?
Subaru-san...
Why are you here?
Well, see...
It's getting dark, but the lights at the professor's house never came on.
So I got curious and checked it out, but found the front door left unlocked...
With neither the professor nor that child in sight.
Just as I was pondering what might have happened, two silent calls came in back-to-back.
I thought perhaps the two of them had gotten caught up in some sort of case...
So, using these spare pursuit glasses in the professor's room...
I ascertained the location of your detective badges, and finally made my way here.
Then, could it be the kidnapped old man is...
Yeah.
You all know him very well...
It's Professor Agasa!
Professor!
The fact that the front door was unlocked...
Means the kidnappers likely disguised as home delivery staff and got into the house...
Abducted the professor and confined him here.
Since the professor invents all sorts of things...
They mistook that to mean he's considerably rich.
So true...
Most of the professor's inventions are junk, and he's actually getting poorer...
Then, the middle-school-aged daughter who sometimes answers the phone...
Was in fact Haibara, right?
Since Ai-chan's voice and her way of speech are like an adult's!
Anyway, Subaru-san...
Did you happen to see the other culprit?
Yeah.
He was out cold near the stairs.
He must have been frantically trying to flee, and lost his footing on the steps.
But Subaru-san's just like Superman!
To have caught on to the abnormalities and come to rescue us!
Yeah, right.
Coming to check on the situation just because the house lights weren't on...
It's as if he had been keeping watch the entire time.
Yeah.
It's true that I had been keeping watch for your return the entire time.
I made too much curry for lunch today, so I was thinking of sharing some.
Curry!
Then, we should all go to the professor's house tomorrow at noon for curry!
Next-day curry is the best, you know!
The Next Day
You kicked the wall without knowing what 252 was!?
Yeah, since I heard everyone's voices...
I kicked the wall while clinging to that bit of hope.
Conveying my thoughts of, "Hurry, call the police here, right now!"
Hur-ry...
Call the po-lice here...
Right now...
So the rhythm 2-5-2 was just a fluke...
It's wonderful that you guys understood my intention.
Goes to show you can transmit your thoughts if you try!
Who would've thought that my voice was that old...
You were looking for a reply to a love letter from 13 years ago?
See, it's this girl.
How cute!
Since that special effects drama is a memory of her...
And it's etched deeply into my mind.
Video?
Perhaps it was left somewhere in here as a video letter?
VIDEO LETTER OF FIRST LOVE
Next Conan's Hint
Prone To Sweat A Lot
The next episode is about Detective Chiba's first love!
First love - it's a thing in the past.
In the past?