"Child Crime Prevention Project," you say?
Yes.
Since there have been repeated instances of child kidnappings in the metropolitan area lately.
But...
Why did you come all the way from the police headquarters, Inspector Shiratori?
Well...
I just happened to be in the vicinity to gather information about a case, so I dropped by...
You dropped by for the purpose of seeing Kobayashi-sensei's face, right?
Chiba-kun...
And I just saw him this morning when I gave him his bento...
Why did you follow me here in the first place?
It's all right, isn't it?
I'm an alumnus of this school, after all.
I'm an alumnus here too - which graduating class were you?
Let's see...
I think the 20th graduating class.
In that case, you were two classes below me!
Then do you remember him?
The science teacher, "Skeleton" Kunigami?
Yeah!
He's still doing well...
And the students are calling him Shinigami-sensei out of fear!
Well, we need to get going!
But...
Since it's been a while since I've visited my alma mater...
Is it all right if I walk around the building for a bit?
In the deciding moment that determines your future...
You cannot lie to yourself!
His classmate from elementary school...
How will Detective Chiba's love turn out?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
VIDEO LETTER OF FIRST LOVE
Look for a crime prevention video for you?
Yeah...
Since the police gave me this flyer during lunch break...
I was thinking of showing a crime prevention video in the AV room tomorrow during ethics period.
Why do we have to be the ones to look for that video?
If it's in the storage area of the AV room, couldn't you just look for it yourself?
Well...
I have to go a staff meeting, and...
That reminds me...
You haven't shown that old video of your choir contest to us yet, have you?
Basically...
You're terrible at finding things.
Yes...
Because, there's a ridiculous number of videotapes in the storage area!
The words on the labels are fading, and there also are a lot of videos with labels stacked on top of each other...
I don't know which is which!
So, she plans to use you to find it since you seem to be skilled in such searches.
Figures...
So many tapes...
Just like Sensei said, the words are fading...
And some of them have labels stacked on top of each other.
They're not sorted according to school year either...
It's going to be tough to search.
Let's just give it up!
We detective Boys are very cautious anyway...
So we don't need to watch anything like a crime prevention video!
You can never be too careful.
Since no matter how cautious you are...
There could be a case that a man of unknown character who is after your life...
May be stealthily lurking next door!
Are you talking about Subaru-san?
If he bothers you so much, why not just stay over at the detective agency?
No way.
Anyway, how are we going to find the video?
If we play all of them and check their contents, we might find it eventually, but...
All of them!?
There's no need for that.
Since we were asked to help...
That means Sensei already came and checked the shelves but still couldn't find it.
Even if the words on the labels are fading, you can still read some of them.
And it's hard to imagine that such an important educational video would be taped over with a new label stuck on it.
Then, why couldn't she find it?
In short, that videotape wasn't one the VHS tapes on the shelf.
Instead it was put away somewhere...
Meaning there's high probability that it was a Beta videotape!
See, here it is.
The crime prevention video.
The video for the choir competition is here too!
I see.
So Kobayashi-sensei's homeroom teacher was a fan of Beta videos.
What on earth is "Beta"?
A long time ago, there were both Beta and VHS tapes.
But Beta ended up losing out and faded away, or so I heard.
But why did Beta lose out?
Dunno...
Maybe its performance wasn't good.
That's not the case!
At the time, Beta was better than VHS in both picture quality and sound...
And the size of the cassette was smaller, so it was very popular among enthusiasts!
Detective Chiba...
Well, it was inferior in regards to recording length...
So its sales strategy failed.
What are you doing in a place like this?
I came to pass out the crime prevention flyers, and took the chance to wander around the building...
Since I was a graduate of this school, I felt nostalgic.
But that doesn't explain why you were hiding in the AV room, does it?
Well...
Actually...
You were looking for a reply to a love letter from 13 years ago?
Really?
Yeah...
I was on the broadcasting team.
One time our team recorded and broadcast a mini-drama during lunch break, and became an instant hit.
Having nothing to lose, I suggested our team record a live action special effects drama and show it in the school arts festival.
What happened next was a girl teammate in the same grade as myself became enthusiastic about it...
Other team members got on board because of her, and we completed the SFX drama.
Thinking that girl was truly a fan of SFX like me, I dropped all sorts of hardcore fan jargon...
But it completely bored her.
When I asked her, "Do you really like special effects?"
It's not special effects that I like...
Don't make me spell it out for you, dummy!
She said that with her face all red.
I couldn't help but to send her a love letter the next day.
I... guess I misunderstood after all, huh?
No, that was a nice read!
You were right on mark!
That girl liked you too, Detective Chiba!
Really?
And?
Why would the reply to that love letter be in this AV room's storage area?
Did you get the reply but lose it here?
No...
I got her reply in a letter soon after that, and I still have it.
She didn't give it to you directly?
That girl had to transfer schools suddenly, and I hastily gave her my letter at her farewell party.
So she mailed it from her new address?
But wasn't her reply written in that letter?
I thought it would be too, so I read it with my heart pounding, but..
Dear Chiba-kun,
It's easy to write my feelings in a letter, but since I don't
know whether you'll understand them, I'll put them in the
storage area of the AV room for safekeeping, I hope my
thoughts can be etched directly onto you, Chiba-kun
She wrote...
"It's easy to write my feelings in a letter...
...but since I don't know whether you'll understand them...
...I'll put them in the storage area of the AV room for safekeeping...
...I hope my thoughts can be etched directly onto you, Chiba-kun." in the letter.
I see.
She hid that reply somewhere in this storage area where no one other than Detective Chiba would look.
Yeah.
I immediately searched here from top bottom after reading it, but didn't find anything like a letter.
Then, have you seen each other since?
Not once in the last 13 years.
She never went to the class reunions either.
Then, why are you looking for that kind of thing now?
I got a call from her earlier.
She said, "I'm going to the class reunion next week, are you?"
After I told her I was planning to...
She asked me, "You probably forgot since it was so long ago, but did you see reply video?"
Video?
So?
How did you respond?
I simply told her that I hadn't.
After hearing that she muttered "I see..." and hung up.
Detective Chiba, you're horrible!
Did I have a choice?
Since I really hadn't seen it.
But hold on a minute.
By "video", could that mean...
It was recorded on one of these tapes and left somewhere in here as a video letter?
Yeah, my thoughts exactly and I came here to look for it.
Since I didn't check the contents of the videos back then.
And?
Have you found that video letter?
No, I picked up the videos I was likely to choose, and watched them with fast-forward...
But there are so many.
And you guys came in during the middle of it.
Then, let's all look for it!
But it'll be tough to check all of those.
There's no need to watch them from beginning to end.
If she added it that sort of video letter...
She'd insert it at the end after what was originally recorded, so it would be harder to find.
I see!
So we only need to check the final footage of the videotapes!
This task is exhausting...
Guess this wasn't it either...
How many are left?
This was the last one.
But we haven't seen the special effects drama you filmed, Detective Chiba!
Well, that video was confiscated by Kunigami-sensei.
No way...
Come to think of it, Kunigami-sensei was the advisor for the school broadcasting team.
But it's all right.
Since that special effects drama is a memory of her...
And it's etched deeply into my mind.
Or something like that!
Uhm...
We've been wondering, but...
Why are you opening the lid of the video?
This is a habit of mine.
My big brother used to work part-time at a video rental store...
And he was told to check whether the returned videos had been rewound to the beginning by opening the lid.
It became a habit for my brother, and he'd even do it at home after we finished watching a tape.
I thought it was cool so I copied it, and got the habit from him this way.
How long have you had that habit?
Probably since third or fourth grade.
And when did you film that SFX drama?
Summer of sixth grade.
And she immediately transferred schools afterwards.
Haibara, get a writing brush and a cup of water.
You guys, go to the shelves and get the old videos with labels stacked on top of each other.
Kunigami-sensei has always been known as a sinister cheapskate...
And whenever he confiscated videotapes, he was likely to immediately erase the contents by recording over it.
"Has always been"?
Why would you know that?
You're just a first year...
W...
Well, details schmetails...
There sure are lot.
Are we going to check the contents of these too?
No.
By wtting a writing brush with water and going over the label like this...
The words from the label underneath will show up.
Got it on my first try!
This is Detective Chiba's SFX video, isn't it?
Wait, it says Kamen Baiya...
That's a cheap parody of Yaiba...
But there's a video letter inside this, right?
No, if that girl knew about Detective Chiba's habit of opening this part of a videotape...
Then it's very likely that the message will be revealed by opening the tape lid.
Huh?
There's nothing in there!
Seriously...?
Detective Conan Episode 624
Fansub Release by DCTP
OCR by Nixx Car
OCR editing by DJ VK
What's this, Conan?
Nothing's written there!
This is odd...
I was almost certain that the message would be written here, but...
In that case, her video letter was indeed recorded onto this tape!
She's right.
For the time being, let's play it and find out.
There's nothing on it, huh...
Perhaps it was erased when it was taped over...
That's not it.
Although it was taped over, the last scene of my SFX drama was still left on the tape for a bit.
And nothing is taped after that.
That reminds me, a bit of her footage was in the last scene of the SFX drama.
See, it's this girl.
Thank you, Kamen Baiya!
How cute!
Right?
Her name was Miike Naeko, and the boys in class were all enamored with her.
But...
It's impossible.
Yeah...
That such an idol-like girl would be interested in Detective Chiba...
Hey now...
Did this girl really like you?
Do you remember having done anything to raise her flag?
I actually don't remember anything like that...
Except the fact that I made her cry once.
Did you bully her?
How mean!
Oh, no...
I never bullied her...
She just started crying.
If I recall, it was on a day when we left school late since we were busy with our broadcasting work...
And she suddenly started crying at the crosswalk.
Chiba-kun is a dummy!
I hate you!
She said so and ran home.
I guess she'd wanted to go home early that day for some reason.
Did you force her to stay...
So that you could kiss her or something!?
There's no way I'd do something like that!
Which means you must've said something to her.
Do you remember what you said to her?
Well, I do remember that time...
I fell when I was chasing after her...
And got a pretty deep gash on my palm from that.
I see!
So the girl patched you up, right Detective Chiba?
Oh, no...
She was already long gone without realizing I had fallen...
Is that so?
But...
The scar from then is still etched on my palm like this.
Etched?
Come to think of it, he said that was written in the letter from that girl as well.
"I hope my thoughts can be etched directly onto Chiba-kun."
"To be etched directly," would be on the body...
I see, that's how it was!
Could it be that Conan-kun...
Figured it out?
Yeah, I figured it out.
Ever since Detective Chiba was a child...
He's been prone to sweat a lot!
It's true I was prone to sweating.
Since I was chubby, although not as much as Genta-kun.
Does that have anything to do with this?
When you open the videotape lid, you have to put both hands on the sides for support, right?
That girl wrote her message here, using a water-based pen...
So that the message would be etched onto the sweat-prone Detective Chiba's palm.
Of course, it's written backwards so that you can read it.
See, I opened the lid and I got a red stain on my hand---that's the proof!
I see.
If it was written with a red water-based pen on the black side, it'd be invisible.
And since nobody would normally touch there, there's no worry that the others would read it.
But it's been 3 years, will it still be readable?
It's all right.
Using this torn piece of paper...
Wetting it with water...
Placing it on the side of the tape...
And then removing it...
The girl's message from 13 years ago is thus resurrected!
It says, "I like you too!"
She also felt the same way!
Awesome!
When is the class reunion that she's also attending?
It's tonight...
Then, don't you think you'd better go?
But...
Even if I tell her that I finally got her message...
No, you have to go!
Her feelings from 13 years ago have finally reached you, right?
There's no reason she wouldn't be happy, you see?
Kobayashi-sensei...
Sorry...
I overheard your conversation.
It's not special effects that I like...
Don't make me spell it out for you, dummy!
Miike-san hasn't come?
Right, she said something came up.
Although she was looking forward to this by saying that she finally got her wish to be with someone she likes.
"Be with someone she likes"?
Well...
Maybe she got married of something?
What am I going to tell those kids...
Shoot...
Illegal parking...
I was going to come and repark my car as soon as I saw her face, but I guess I trudged along due to the shock...
Uhm...
It's all right.
I haven't submitted the data yet after all.
And since you left the engine running, you were planning to come back soon, right?
Yeah...
Not to mention there are times when you have to stop your car for police detective work.
That's wrong!
Even for a police detective, illegal parking is still illegal!
You have to enforce the rules!
Well, I didn't stop for an investigation after all...
Alright, I'll pay the fine, so could I get the ticket for illegal parking?
Yes, sir!
I put on a big show back there...
And that 15,000 yen fine sure is painful.
But, how did she know?
That I was a police detective...
What's wrong?
Did that illegal parking guy bother you or something?
No...
Regardless, is it really all right to miss your reunion?
Yeah.
Since I've never gone to it before, I figured it would've been awkward if I did go.
Plus...
I already met the person who I wanted to see the most.
Although, it seems he's completely forgotten about me...
Could you mean...
Your childhood friend who's now a police detective at the HQ?
Yes!
Now that I'm being transferred to the HQ, I finally get to be in the same workplace as him.
So I was going to meet him and confess to him if he still remembered me...
But life isn't that rosy after all, huh.
Geez, to have forgotten such a fine girl...
Just forget that good-for-nothing bum!
He's not good-for-nothing.
He's as cute and baby-faced as ever...
Plus, being the youngest child and well-loved by my parents, I was never scolded by anyone even once...
But the time, he...
All right, I'm heading home first!
I want to watch some TV!
No, you can't cross!
The light is red!
What's the big deal?
There aren't any cars coming...
And no one's watching!
I'm watching!
And you're a witness too!
If you try to cut some slack by breaking the rules even once, it'll become habit!
You might think you can break a bad habit, but you can't!
Why can't you understand something like that?
Really...
Chiba-kun hasn't changed at all!
You were rejected?
Yeah, well...
I guess that's how it went...
Are you serious?
So she was out of your league after all...
Hey!
What are you doing?
We're going to continue collecting information.
Roger!
Keep this between us!
Yeah...
I overheard something juicy!
I gotta tell Miwako.
Uhm...
If he was been rejected by someone, that means he's free, right?
Yeah, I guess.
Uhm, what's your name?
I got transferred from Haido Police Station...
I'm Miike Naeko!
Nice to meet you!
Next Episode
You want me to go into this haunted house and confirm the accuracy of the corpses?
Ran...
You'll never be able to tell Shinichi-kun that you like him if you keep this up!
I'll take Anna to the hospital...
Don't touch her!
She may have suffered from cyanide poisoning!
Poison?
THE SCREAMING OPERATION ROOM
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Scratch Marks
Look Forward to the Next Episode
How did you get the wounds?
The neighbor's cat scatched me.
Wierd.
No, it's true...