Every single person retains possessions they're unwilling to part with
In order to protect them to the end, fighting for them is our instinct
As for me, I've continued deceiving you for who knows how many years?
(PART ONE)
Light Music Club concert starts at 3:
BBS J3S<U uSfc'blSf
15115 /33<UTU®*'6I3 d-
^">#Nb0JbJPlN*-*xUt:
!5g£ £3<UTU®*'bl3 d-
Mountain hut style fried noodles, try some'
^">^b03blPl
Entry number five
Third year English major
Arisugawa Arisa-san!
I told you not to break our set!
Now what do we do with our show this evening'?
How about some ice-chilled drinks?
Two more submarine-shaped UFOs'
Get movin'!
Cosplay Photo Museum is now open!
Now, allow me to introduce'
An alumnus of Beika Umveristy as well as a prominent detective
Please welcome Mouri Kogorou-san!
Thank you!
How does it feel to visit your alma mater after such a long time?
It must feel nostalgic, right?
Well, yes
The buildings are still run-down as usual.
But!
Beautiful ladies sure are plentiful!
Geez!
He said he was giving a speech at his alma
mater's festival, so I came to take a look
But sure enough, he was after the female students'
Well, why not let him?
Let him stretch his wings for once at an event like this
The only thing he's stretchingis his horn
And'
Did you stretch your wings in London, Ran?
You told me in an email that you
happened to run into Shmichi-kun there.
Sorta
u
Don't tell me, you two did something you couldn't tell me, did you7
What's that supposed to mean1
Speaking,of London!
Shut up!
Can you not butt in for once?
nothing to do with a brat like you!
This is an adult conversation that has
xcep i as eve ing o owi me
Well' since it's that Holmes geek we're talking about
I suppose he simply droned on about Holmes stuff and nothing else.
Well
Actually
SHINICHIKUN
CONFESSED TO YOU17
You're too loud, Sonoko!
So that son of a gun finally took the plunge, huh?
But under those circumstances, I wouldn't say he confessed to you
on'tyou get it
You're a detective, aren't you?
If you call yourself a detective, then why
Idiot)
Hey, wait!
I said wait!
Let me go!
You're really troublesome!
You're a troublesome, tough case, you know!
With all these distracting emotions
Even if I were Holmes, it'd still be impossible to figure out!
The heart of the girl whom one likes
How can one accurately deduce that'
But rather, it was you who forced him to confess1
You're right
And?
Did you properly reply to him, Ran?
Reply... about what?
Oh—Oh my god, I can't believe it1
I've always been in love with you too'
Like that!^
Why would I have to say anything like that1?
Don't tell me
I was wrong to have not said anything bac *
Of course!
If you don't spell it out for him
Shimchi-kun might think you rejected him!
Idiot
I definitely gotthe message back then
If you're going to tell him, call him right here and now'
I'll be your audience!
Hey, are«you going to do it now'?
And now, I shall enumerate the 108 attributes
a detective should never be without!
The first being
Wisdom1
Now there's no telling when he'll be done blabbering.
It's not often that we get a great detective to come
So we had wanted to show him, but
I'm Mouri Kogorou's daughter.
Did you have some business with my father?
Could you have a case you Want him to take on?
No, it's not that
But if you're his daughter, does that mean
you've been to crime scenes with your father?
Yeah, sometimes
More than that, it's all the time!
In that case
You've seen some before, right?
and confirm the accuracy of the zombies?
You want me to go into this haunted house
We thought that someone who's seen numerous
eir own eyes
(22)
th Ye
Would be able to give a more realistic assessment!
Uhm
Actually, we're in the art track of the literature
department, majoring in film studies.
We're filming a horror movie for our final project.
But apparently the scene where one of
the characters dies isn't realistic
sify - 4th Year
Tf? (22)
feA/ttl'
iichi (22)
Or so says this annoying woman who thinks she's a genius director.
sity - 4th Year
taA-tti'
As such, when I asked her to use this
haunted house and walk the walk
Could that woman
lUimuw
iv \
What's the deal with these folks?
When is Sleeping Kogorou coming?^
i lieu :> vvny we uiuugiii meu ucicuivc :>
daughter and her friends here! ^
After all, they've said that they've seen murdered bodies before.
Then, give your impressions to your dad after you see them
Anna...
It's almost time for our shift change!
/
U
Hold on, what's this Mutsumi?
4i ^
You haven't even got your make-up on yet'
So I thought it'd be better if I just
had you do it for me from the start.
(21)
mi (21)
Geez, guess I have no choice, huh7
All right, we'll let these folks enter in thirty minutes'
I'm sure you'll want to show them your zombie act, right?
Be prepared to feast your eyes upon the manner of my death!
No, I'm not going in<
It's going to be all right!
It's all fake, you know7
But
Sonoko, even you were shocked just now!
That was only because it was unexpected
That's the whole point of haunted houses
that you like him if you keep this up!
You'll never be able to tell Shinichi-kun
What I'm saying is, come!
Use this to strengthen your courage'
If you can clear this game, there's no doubt
you'll step up to becoming a strong woman!
Hey, hey
Really?
How's that even possible?
I was so Scared
See
Looks like it's super fun
Super fun my foot!
If you're that scared, how about we escort you through it?
We do know where each gimmick is.
Then we gladly accept your offer!
Because that way, even this girl will go in'
Hey now, Sonoko>
I said it'll be all right!
You'll only be scared at the beginning.
Geez
Yeah, you're right.
Hey now
This is just the beginning, you know?
Boy'
How could I get lost?
She's been hugging me tight the entire time
Well, it's done pretty well for a
Bad taste, though
But I wish Hashiguchi could have seen this too.
Since this haunted house and the horror movie final project
Were both planned by Hashiguchi.
Did that person drop out of school?
No.
He committed suicide.
By poison
Just one month ago.
We heard that his doctor told him he had an
took his own life because of the torture.
And the suicide note found on him said he
Plus, the ones who discovered his body were
Us two and the ones you met earlier
We had nightmares from that for a while.
I think it was after that
That all of a sudden Anna became enthusiastic about the making
Right, Tsujiei7
Tsujiei?
he have
Huh?
He was with us just a moment ago, right?
I'm going to check around here, so you guys go ahead.
The exit is straight ahead!
He said it was straight ahead, but
s so dark, I can barely see
CALU5C U5...
Wow
Sure looks like they're doing an operation
The patient is Anna-san from earlier.
The doctors operating on her are mannequins, though
The exit sign
head of the bed*in order to get out
Looks like we'll have to pass beside the
Hey, hey
There's nothing to be surprised at, is there?
Ladies?
hat's right
This sort of thing
Is just fake, after all
I told you, don't be such crybabies!
But, something's wrong with Anna.
Yeah
up in bed and open her eyes with a snicker
After the blood gushes out, she'd normally sit
Hey Anna, don't give us a raw deal!
Weren't you going to show us your grotesque manner of death?
Hey, say something, Anna!
Hey
Is she not breathing?
Hey, Anna!
Hang in there, Anna!
Anna!
What7
What happened7
An almond scent from her mouth
Hey, Anna!
/Answer me, Anna!
Move it!
I'll take Anna to the hospital
Don't touch her'
There's an almond scent coming from her mouth!
She may have suffered from cyanide poisoning!
tUOSIOd
An almond scent7
Really?
Don't sniff, amateur'
The almond scent is the smell of gas that results from the
ingested poison reacting with the acid from her gastric fluids!
If you breathe in too much of it, you'll die'
That's... what they said in the detective drama.
The so-called<'almond scent" is not like the smell
of those sweet, fragrant nuts we usually eat
But they said it's the bittersweet smell of
the almond plant before it's harvested!
Is that so
But, with things as they seem now
Anna-san most likely
Commited suicide
Suicide?
Are youlre saying that she took the
Yes, most likely
LCl 5 5CC...
What's her name?
i era ure epar men # a ami nna-san
A 4th year in the art track of Beika University's
1$ that correct7
With the zombie make-up*on, she looks completely different from
the picture on the student ID that-was in her belongings
the picture on the student ID'that was in her belongings
And?
What's the basis for saying that
She suddenly appeared to be in great pain!
We-were just following this exit sign
And when we were passing by thelhead of the bed like this
Her body suddenly convulsed.
And she struggled, thumping her feet repeatedly
So much that the entire bed shook and rattled'
After that, blood shot out from her abdomen
Blood7
Hey, wasn't the cause of death poison?
i es...
we can't say so definitively, but
The coroner hasn't arrived yet so
An almond scent was coming from her mouth, and something
resembling a capsule was caught between her teeth
So it was probably death by poison.
The gushing blood was a gimmick.
A gimmick?
Inside the bed, there's a switch like this.
If you press it
Hey, now
Did it get on you7
It does often fly over that way
Well, It's water-based so it should;come right off. ]l
So the bed shaking was also a gimmick?
And the lower left bedpost diagonal from it are slightly shortened
As the actor lying,on the bed playing the patient rocks their body
The bed also shakes and rattles in response to this.
If that's the case, her feet repeatedly
striking the bed was also a trick7
No.
That can only be done
By the person lying in the bed themselves'
Hey, wait'
I VSI \J\A I
blood spray, there isn't anything else.
Aside from the mechanism for the
Please do not touch the crime scene without permission'
That's right
ere pe icure.
We saw it from here whemshe was thumping her feet, right7
Yeah
The sheet on top had come off, and
Her right foot came out
I 3CC.
It certainly seems as though she took the poison while
Ran-kun's group'was passing by the head of the bed
At that time, there wasn't anyone else in her vicinity, was there?
Especially near her face?
Right.
It was dark, but I think it was just us
poison, I think we should've seen them.
If someone had'forced her to take the
By the way, where were you all when she showed signs of pain?
I was about to sneak up on those girls.
Putting this on my chest, too.
We were with those folks the whole time in the
role of their guides through this haunted house.
But I pretended to have gotten lost
midway and put on a simple trick item
To startle them in the operation room
just like Hachiya and I arranged
Well, after we parted ways, Tsujiei and I each did our own thing.
And you were?
I was in the X ray room next door
And I'd been waiting for the guests to come the entire time
Is that so
But no one came even after I heard
their screams, so I got anxious
Why the anxiety?
Because
From this operation room, you have to go through
that X-ray room in order to get to the exit.
So I came to check and see what happened
And Anna was
Anna was
Hey, Mutsumi!
What's with your face?
Your tears are messing up your make-up.
Because!
Anna just died, you know!?
You guys sure are taking it well'
How could we be taking it well?
We feel the same way as when Hashiguchi commi ted suicide
Suicide?
You know about it since ou're a detective ri ht?
The case where a 4th year Beika University student
commi e suici e y poison in isapa men a mon a o
Yeah, if I recall
His body was found by some colleagues who
And those "colleagues" were myself, Tsujiei, Mutsumi
And Anna here
That Hashiguchi
He was putting so much work into the final movie project, but
He didn't show up at the university for a whole week.
We got worried, so we decided to go together
and check up on him after classes.
But when we rang the doorbell, there was no answer.
Thinking that he was probably asleep or had gone
But then Anna said
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Let's ask the manager to unlock the door
After her suggestion, we went in and
That's how you found Hashiguchi-san who
had committed suicide via poison, right?
Yeah
In his room, there was a suicide note in his own handwriting.
RecentlyJI started not feeling well, so I went to the doctor
tumor with only six months to live.
We asked the police after that
And learned that he had died on that
day when we were all in a lecture
It was after that, right?
That Anna started to change.
Yeah.
Saying that it was for Hashiguchi, she suddenly started to work
on the final movie project and this haunted house feverishly.
However, it just wasn't normal!
and had to be taken to the hospital.
She even took too many sleeping pills once
Her reason was that she wanted to experience a life-or-death
situation in order to study the realistic manner of death
Something like that7
Right.
she had actually kept a nail in her mouth the entire day
And one time when we wondered why she was silent
A nailk
Could it be that Anna
Put the capsule containing poison into her mouth?
Just like the nail!
And if she accidently bit it by chance
So you're saying she attempted to experience a
near-death situation, but she actually died from it?
As we surmised, this appears to be a case of suicide, right?
I wonder if that's really the case?
Conan-kun!?
Because, look at this
At this lady's cheek
The marks aren't make-up but look like they were really-scratched
And there's even blood oozing from them.
Wouldn't this mean that someone was forcing her mouth shut
And she was trying to pry the arm away
leaving her fingernail marks?
What now!?
Inspector!
There's skin and blood underneath her fingernails!
This is a murder case disguised as a suicide
The culprit who poisoned Anna-san in the dark
Who on earth is it?
Mutsumi-san, you're the culprit!
Then, Haichiya Knchi-san, you're the culprit!
You've been fidgeting this whole time, Tsujiei-san!
Your guilt is causing you to act suspiciously, isn't it?
There are red lines on it
Anna-san had already been poisoned to death.