Uncle Kogoro was invited to the campus
festival of his alma mater, Beika University.
Ran, Sonoko, and I came along...
Where Tsujiei Sonsaku-san, a student majoring
in film arts, began speaking with us.
He took us to the haunted house his team was
running—The "Screaming Hospital Ward".
They wanted Ran and Sonoko, who have encountered a number
of cases, to check out the appearances of their zombies.
Especially since Tadami Anna-san was
pretty confident about her zombie acting.
But what Anna-san really showed us in
the end was her own manner of death.
She suddenly convulsed in front of us and passed away.
The cause of death was cyanide poisoning.
It was considered to be a case of suicide by
ingesting poison, but I was not to be fooled.
This is a murder case disguised as a suicide.
What's more, their mutual friend Hashiguichi-san
who had killed himself a month earlier...
Had something to do with this case.
Who on earth is the culprit who poisoned Anna-san in the dark?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
His name is: Detective Conan!
(PART TWO)
It was after that, right?
Hachiya Kiichi (22)
Beika University - 4th Year
That Anna started to change
Tsujiei Sonsaku (22)
Beika University - 4th Year
Saying that it was for Hashiguchi, she suddenly started to work
on the final movie project and this haunted house feverishly.
But, isn't it normal to put in extra effort
for a friend who has passed away?
However, it just wasn't normal!
She even took too many sleeping pills once
and had to be taken to the hospital.
Her reason was that she wanted to experience a life-or-death
situation in order to study the realistic manner of death...
Something like that?
Right.
And one time when we wondered why she was silent, she
had actually kept a nail in her mouth the entire day.
A nail!?
Could it be that Anna...
Suguri Mutsumi (21)
Beika University - 4th Year
Put the capsule containing poison into her mouth?
I see!
Just like the nail!
And if she accidently bit it by chance...
So you're saying she attempted to experience a near-death
situation, but she actually died from it?
As we surmised, this appears to be a case of suicide, right?
I wonder if that's really the case?
Conan-kun!?
Because, look at this...
At this lady's cheek.
The marks aren't make-up but look like they were really scratched...
And there's even blood oozing from them.
Wouldn't this mean that someone was forcing her mouth shut...
And she was trying to pry the arm
away, leaving her fingernail marks?
What now!?
Inspector!
There's skin and blood underneath her fingernails!
In other words, someone forced the poison capsule into her mouth...
And plugged up both her mouth and nose until she swallowed it.
But if that's the case, it means she had already died
by the time Ran-kun and the others arrived here.
Was she really struggling by striking her feet against the bed?
Yes.
I see, so that's how it was!
Sonoko?
The culprit poisoned and murdered Anna-san
before we came, and then snuck into the bed!
Then the culprit rocked the bed, thumped their feet...
And lifted the sheet on top so that Anna-san's foot would show.
Then snuck out from the bed, making it
seem as if Anna-san had still been alive!
In short, the one it was possible for was...
Mutsumi-san, it could only have been you!
Me?
Because with your small build, you could easily
slip from the bed without being noticed.
Plus, out of everyone here...
Only you are wearing sandals!
You could've put your sandals back on
right after you got out from the bed!
Look here...
Since the culprit's feet wouldn't have been seen anyway,
would there have been any reason to take off their shoes?
Then you, being the next smallish build, are the culprit!
Idiot!
My ankle is sprained!
I can manage to walk normally, but...
It'd be too painful for me to do something
like thump my feet vigorously.
Here, take a look!
There's a patch on my foot, and it's all
wrapped up with bandages for support!
Then it's you, who's beenffidgeting this whole time!
Your guilt is causing you to act suspiciously, isn't it?
This is because of my chronic athlete's foot being itchy...
Hey...
Your shoes are all red, you know?
I've been stepping on my feet to suppress the itching...
This is fake blood.
You stepped on it somewhere.
Then it was probably when you were rocking the bed earlier?
There's a lot of fake blood that's pooled
up near the upper right bedpost.
Anyway, for the three of you who were in this area...
After poisoning her, any of you would've been able to sneak
under the bed and make it seem as if she were still alive...
And then sneak out of the bed and show
up as if nothing had happened.
No way...
That's impossible.
As you can see, there are doctor
mannequins on either side of the bed.
If someone had wanted to sneak out from the side, they'd
bump into the mannequins and quickly be exposed.
And if they left via the foot of the bed without obstruction...
The folks at the head of the bed would've seem them.
Furthermore...
This bed is handmade.
It wouldn't support the weight of two adults.
Handmade?
Yeah.
This way, there'd be a creaking sound when
someone wriggles, making it scarier.
That's what Anna said.
But it really was too uncomfortable to sleep on,
so the other guys who played the role hated it.
Could it be that the scratch wounds on
her cheek were made by Anna herself?
In order to make it scarier, she drew her own blood...
That does sound like Anna.
Yeah.
So it does seem like a suicide...
No.
The placement of those wounds shows her struggle with the culprit.
But I don't understand.
Just how did the culprit make it seem as if she were still alive?
On the top sheet, there are some red
lines on the underside near her feet.
This is red water-based paint.
Fake blood?
If I recall correctly, under the bed...
A cardboard box...
And sticky tape attached toithese sheet scraps.
There's no doubt.
The culprit made use of this space...
In order to make Anna-san's manner of death play out believably.
Anna!
And then?
What did you find, Coroner?
The livor mortis was pink in color.
The cause of death is indeed poisoning by cyanide derivatives.
I see.
As a precaution, I examined what the victim was said
to have been wearing at the time of death...
The mask, and the tube attached to it.
But those were not the cause of her poisoning.
It was the capsule in her mouth?
Yeah.
Tested positive for high hydrocyanic acid concentration.
I have doubts about the fingernail marks, but...
If there were witnesses at the time
the vie suddenly struggled in pain...
It would seem clear to me that she herself bit
down on the poisoned capsule in her mouth.
Since the victim had the mask on, no one
else could have put the capsule inside.
Geez.
If she really did put that sort of thing in her mouth in order to
experience what it's like to be under the Grim Reaper's scythe...
Then she was hopeless.
Can we be released then?
Since it was a suicide...
No, I mean you've learned it was an accidental death.
You may leave after you accompany Takagi-kun
to the station for detailed questioning.
Huh?
Where's Takagi-kun?
If you're talking about the other detective
he got held up by that boy with glasses.
Huh, why?
Dunno...
Uhm...
Sonoko suddenly said she's starting her deduction show.
She wants everyone to gather in the operating room.
Good.
Already shot her with the tranquilizer dart.
And I've placed the mini-speaker inside her collar.
What's left is to use this to mimic Sonoko's voice.
What's the meaning of this?
Sonoko-kun?
Anna-san's death could only be considered an accidental
one due to her biting down on the poisoned capsule.
So tell me, what is there to deduce?
No.
It's obvious from the fingernail marks on Anna-san's cheek...
That this was a murder done by someone...
Who forced the poisoned capsule into
Anna-san's mouth against her will.
In short, before Ran and I came into this operating room...
Anna-san had already been poisoned to death.
Either by Mutsumi-san, who was in the X-ray room next door...
Or by Tsujiei-san or Hachiya-san, who both claim to
have entered this operating room after we had.
It was one of you three!
Hey now...
You all saw it, right?
The moment when Anna-san struggled in pain.
Yes.
Her body convulsed...
And she thumped her feet repeatedly.
In that case...
It only seemed like she was convulsing because the bed was shaking.
Then, how do you explain her thumping feet?
The sheet was turned up, and you even saw her foot, right?
Yeah...
Don't you realize?
That the bed is handmade, and the framework
was a lattice and had gaps all over?
If someone got under the bed, don't you
think they could've done something?
Under the bed?
I see!
They grasped the dead Anna-san's feet from under
the bed along with the sheets and struck them...
To make it seem as if she were struggling?
Like so?
Hey!
Is someone under the bed?
It's me!
Conan-kun?
Sonoko-neechan told me to push my
fists up from underneath the bed.
How was it?
How?
The striking feet that we saw were faster, and...
It was a bit different because the
bottom sheet was also coming up.
Plus, if the sheet on top had come off too much...
And it was seen that the sheet wasigrasped along
with the feet, the trick would be exposed.
Then, how about...
If we do this?
It's Takagi-kun, right?
Like Conan-kun, Takagi-kun's using both his hands from below...
But the striking is faster than before...
And the bottom sheet isn't coming up!
No way!
There's no one in the bed, so how can there just be feet?
That's just ridiculous!
The feet are coming from below the bed...
Through a gap in the sheets?
Just what the heck is going on here?
Takagi-kun!
The trick was simple.
First, lift up the sheet where the knees would go.
Then fold the sheet up to about the knee.
Affix the sheet scrap that was under the bed with sticky tape
so that it would cover up the exposed bed framework.
Pass the switch to spray the blood through the
gap in the sheets, and everything is set
All you need to do afterwards is to put your
legs through the gap in the sheets...
And like Detective Takagi did earlier, strike the
bed and stick your feet out the top sheet.
That's how you could make it seem like Anna-san,
who was lying on the bad, was still alive!
Then, immediately press the switch to spray the blood.
While we were surprised by that, swiftly remove
your own feet from the gap in the sheets...
Put on your shoes, and pull the attached sheet inside the bed...
Remove the sticky tape, and sneak out via the foot
of the bed which was hidden from our view.
In short, the culprit came here before
we entered this operating room...
Forced Anna-san to take the poison and murdered her...
Set up the trick with the sheets, and used both hands to shake
the bed when we came to the head of Anna-san's bed.
And after simulating Anna-san's struggling...
They snuck out from the bed and showed
up before us as if nothing had happened.
In short, the ones who could've done it...
Were you guys who appeared in front of us soon after that.
Hey, hey...
There's nothing to be surprised at, is there?
Ladies?
That's right...
This sort of thing...
Is just fake, after all...
What?
What happened?
I see.
Only one of you three could have carried out the crime.
Hey, it wasn't me!
Plus if that were the case, if the top sheet had come
off too much when the feet were striking...
Wouldn't Anna's feet have been shown too?
That's right!
If Anna's feet were seen, that sort of trick would've been exposed!
In order to ensure that wouldn't happen, the culprit had already...
Positioned Anna-san's legs so that they were bent to the outside.
Don't be ridiculous.
That kind of trick would've been exposed as
soon as the sheet above her was lifted!
That's why the culprit made the first move.
Isn't that right?
Saying you were taking Anna-san to the hospital...
You reached into the bed and lifted her.
I'll take Anna to the hospital...
Tsujiei Sonsaku-san?
I see!
If he lifted her up, no one would have known
that her legs had been bent while in the bed.
You're wrong!
I really thought Anna had some sort of illness!
By the way...
Has your athlete's foot gone away?
After tossing the capsule of poison into
Anna-san's mouth while she was lying in bed...
In order to seal her mouth and nose until she ingested it...
It wouldn't work if the bed were to wobble.
So to prevent it from wobbling, you wedged your own
shoe underneath the upper right bedpost, right?
Forgetting there was a pool of fake blood.
Because of that, the bedpost left a red, squarish mark on your shoe.
Unfortunately, you only realized that after the police had come.
So, pretending that you had athlete's foot...
You rubbed the shoe with fake blood
on the sole against the other shoe.
In order to conceal the square mark
by making it completely blood-red!
But, if we hadn't been your escorts through this haunted house...
This trick wouldn't have worked, right?
That's right!
We brought you here only because Mouri-san
just so happened to be unavailable...
It didn't "just happen"!
From the start, you've targeted the person whom
Mouri Kogoro was sure to bring along...
His daughter Ran!
The first being...
Wisdom!
Geez...
Now there's no telling when he'll be done blabbering.
It's not often that we get a great detective to come...
So we had wanted to show him, but...
I'm Mouri Kogoro's daughter.
Did you have some business with my father?
No, it's not that...
Could you have a case you want him to take on?
But if you're his daughter, does that mean
you've been to crime scenes with your father?
Yeah, sometimes...
In that case...
You've seen some before, right?
You purposely mentioned Detective Mouri's name
while you were beside her and brought her here...
And set her up to be the witness, right?
Since she's a girl, she'd likely be scared and
you could bring up the idea of escorting her.
It'd also be easy to suggest pranking
her by pretending to get lost inside.
If you had already hidden a scary item under the bed
you could quickly put it on and show yourself.
Nonsense!
What proof do you have?
Then why don't you show us?
This athlete's foot of yours!
That's...
Multiple red lines were on the underside of the top sheet.
Those were marks from your toenails
when you slipped your legs into the bed.
You only realized it after you had murdered Anna-san
and were bending her legs to the outside, right?
That her toenails had a red pedicure.
That's why it should still be on your feet.
In a quandary, you quickly applied it to your toenails...
The red fake blood, that is!
Allow me.
I see.
Since you slipped your feet into the bed
while the fake blood had not yet dried...
The fake blood from your toenails got onto the top sheet.
Well, Mutsumi-san was wearing sandals...
And Hachiya-san had already shown us his toes.
That's why you were the only suspect remaining.
Hey, it's a joke right?
Why did you kill Anna?
You know that Anna and I often bumped heads
over the acting in death scenes, right?
She was really annoying, so I blurted out...
"Well, have you ever seen someone die?"
To which Anna replied...
Of course I have!
I've replayed it hundreds of times; it even shows up in my dreams!
What do you mean by that?
I asked Hashiguchi-kun...
For a favor.
"Since you're going to kill yourself anyway...
"Why don't you record that manner of death on video for me?"
No way...
She said that?
When we found Hashiguchi's body in his room
didn't you think Anna was acting weird?
She seeemed strangely excited and yelled, "Call the police!"
And "He might've left a suicide note somewhere, so look for it!
Then, could she have been...
Yeah.
She said she pocketed the tape from the video camera that
had been secretly set up to record from the bookshelf.
That's why I made Anna go the same way Hashiguchi had gone!
I told her the tooth blackening on her teeth
had come off and I'd fix it for her...
Then I cracked the capsule open into her
mouth, and threw the capsule in as well!
She didn't try to stop him, but instead encouraged him!
Even if he only had half a year due to his illness...
Just half a year more...
We would've completed our graduation movie project...
And we may have been able to show it to him...
But now...
All because of her...
Regardless, Uncle Kogoro never got there after all...
Now, the 104th a tribute is something that everyone has—patience!
If you run out of it, you'll never be able to do detective work...
No way...
He's still giving his speech...
That's too long...
My target this time is the Angel's Crown.
Treasure, GET!
Man, this is bad!
Inspector Nakamori saw my face!
What's more
The day of my planned appearance coincides with my date with Aoko?
Don't tell me —
she also discovered my identity!?
I look forward to our rendezvous under the moonlight.
Next Conan's Hint
Ice Cream