"I pledge to clean up Japan once and for all."
Now then, whose line was that?
Huh?
I knew I've heard it somewhere before...
But who was it?
Sakamoto Ryouma.
They say on June 29th in Year 3 of Bunkyuu, or 1863...
Ryouma wrote that in a letter he addressed to his elder sister, Otome.
You sure know a lot, Conan-kun!
That's what I heard on TV!
But Sonoko, why are you quoting Ryouma?
There's a Ryouma exhibition that's been held at Uncle Jirokichi's Suzuki Grand Museum since last week.
And the guy who sent out an advance notice of attendance is...
None other than my dear...
Kaitou Kid-sama!
'Twas him, zeyo!
"Zeyo"?
Sonoko...
You spoke in a Tosa dialect...
That's exactly it!
I was studying up on Ryouma, and I totally got into his dialect!
But...
I don't think there's anything at the Ryouma exhibition that Kid would want to steal.
Of course there is!
It's the gunbelt Ryouma is said to have received from Takasugi Shinsaku along with a pistol!
Gunbelt!
That's right.
It's a magnificent belt with a huge ruby embedded in the buckle.
Is it the real thing?
Ryouma even wrote about that belt in a letter...
And we have a certificate of authenticity from a famous appraiser.
Well, why wouldn't it be real?
Jirokichi-san bought it, after all.
Actually, I heard he wasn't able to acquire it.
The person planning to put on the exhibition with the belt as a centerpiece...
Doesn't seem to want to sell it.
Having no choice, Uncle said, "If you're going to have a Ryouma exhibition, have it at my museum!"
And lent him the space.
But further proof is that Kid is targeting it!
No.
Actually he isn't...
Hey, hey...
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
An advance notice different than usual...
A fierce battle for treasures against Kid!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
CONAN & KID'S BATTLE FOR
RYOUMA'S TREASURE (PART ONE)
What?
He's coming to return some stolen items?
Did Kid really write that in his advance notice?
Yeah.
"In the Ryouma exhibition, which is being held now...
"I shall make a visit with the purpose of returning three items in a few days."
"Kaitou Kid."
What three items?
It seems the organizer of the Ryouma exhibition, Tarumi Shishihiko-san...
Had also held another Ryouma exhibition 20 years ago.
Some items were stolen at that time.
A letter written by Sakamoto Ryouma the night before he was assassinated...
Addressed to his wife, Oryou, although unfinished...
A sake cup from Oumiya Inn stained with Ryouma's blood upon his death...
And finally, a pistol Ryouma had hidden under his clothes, a Smith & Wesson Model 1, these three items.
But, those items weren't stolen by Kid.
I think it was...
Yeah.
Nicknamed the Shouwa Era's Woman of Twenty Faces...
It was the damsel thief...
"Phantom Lady"!
We don't know what kind of relationship Kid and Lady have.
But after stealing the three items, the Lady ceased her crimes...
And two years later Kid made his appearance.
From this we can assume they may be master and apprentice.
And?
When is that guy coming?
Who knows.
It doesn't say anything other than "in a few days" in the notice.
Then, we should stop the Ryouma exhibition now and turn away the visitors!
If the time and date are uncertain, our security will be at a disadvantage and that's what his aim is!
If he's just returning things, it'll be easy for him to slip into the crowd!
But here's the thing, Nakamori-kun.
Isn't he saying he's coming all the way to return things?
Why should we refuse?
No, but Superintendent...
Besides, if we want to apprehend Kid, don't we have to invite him first?
Suzuki Jirokichi who received the notice also said this:
"Make the entrance large and the exit narrow.
That's the basics for catching a rat!"
The Suzuki Grand Museum
Uncle!
It's been a while.
Oh, since that time with the Iron Tanuki!
Hello.
There's quite a crowd of visitors lined up.
Yeah.
In addition to the popularity of Ryouma, they also heard about Kid's notice.
Of course, if I were in charge of the exhibition...
I would have flooded the newspapers and TV stations with ads...
And gathered a crowd several times this size!
But isn't this rare?
For Uncle to lend out space in the museum for someone else's exhibition.
I didn't intend to at first.
But since I learned Kid would be after it, I knew I couldn't leave it up to amateurs.
Amateurs?
Yeah.
The man behind this exhibition named Tarumi...
Had also held the ones for Yoshitsune and Nobunaga...
Whenever there's a boom for historical figures.
But because of lax security, something always gets stolen by unidentified thieves each time.
Then you should've bought it!
That Ryouma's gunbelt!
Was the price too unreasonable?
No, on the contrary, I haggled down the price.
After all, he wouldn't allow me to show it to my appraiser before buying it...
So I couldn't ascertain its authenticity.
But didn't you get a certification from a well-known appraiser?
Yes, but...
I felt uneasy about whether or not it'd be able to hook Kid.
But Kid did take the bait, didn't he?
Even though his target doesn't seem to be the gunbelt...
Tarumi Shishihiko (58)
Ryouma Exhibition Organizer
That gunbelt is without a doubt...
The genuine thing received by Ryouma from Takasugi Shinsaku!
Isn't that right, Hanamura-sensei?
Hanamura Masanosuke (63)
Appraiser
Indeed.
Based on the condition of the leather, it is undoubtedly an antique.
The ruby in the buckle is also superb.
Moreover, Ryouma even drew an illustration of the belt in his missive.
I am thus compelled to declare it genuine.
Hanamura Masanosuke...
His judgment is tried and true, but his appraisal fees are exorbitant.
He's an appraiser who rarely takes on any jobs.
Well then, why don't you ladies also come and see the genuine articles with your own eyes?
The exhibition hasn't started yet, but it's my special treat.
So this is Ryouma's gunbelt!
It gives off a certain je ne sais quoi.
And there really is a picture of the belt in this letter.
But you can't read the words...
You're right.
"This here is a gunbelt from ages gone, worn around the waist by American men...
"'Twas used to carry their pistols and bullets, akin to a sash holding a scabbard...
"As to why none of the present New Yorkers don such an engrossing and convenient article...
"'Tis to me an utterly mystifying observation."
That's what it says.
It does sound like Ryouma!
Zeyo, zeyo!
Hey, hey.
What's that gigantic vase?
That's...
The vase that Ryouma was said to have hidden in as a child when playing hide-and-seek but got stuck in.
We also have the Buddha statue Ryouma praised after observing...
And a ball-and-cup toy Ryouma yearned for on display.
So everything goes, huh.
Could this hanging scroll be...
It's the scroll he wrote without thinking as he lamented the depravity of the shogunate system.
As I thought!
Well, I still have doubts about its authenticity.
He's right.
If you lack confidence in my eyes to that extent...
Then after the Ryouma exhibition is concluded, you are welcome to show these to your own appraiser.
Yeah, that is my intent.
Of course, that's provided you are able to keep these items away from that...
Magician of the Moonlight's devilish grasp!
Well then, I appreciate your assistance with the museum's security, Advisor Suzuki.
Yeah.
What a pair of shady folks.
Say...
Is it possible that the items on display are insured for a lot of money?
I also suspected that and looked into it, but the amount is only a drop in the bucket.
With even the admission fee being low, should anything get stolen he is bound to suffer substantial losses, but...
Well, Uncle!
How will you play your hand?
I mean your must have preparations, right?
To counter Kid!
About that...
No way!
You did practically nothing?
Right.
"Right," huh?
If he were coming to steal something, I would've thought of ideas to stop him.
But since he's coming to return things, there's no way to stop him.
Not to mention all three items are small and can easily slip under his clothes.
And the best I could do was create that space.
"Spaced Reserved for Kaitou Kid's Returned Treasures," huh?
If we at least knew what time and day he was coming, we could take some sort of measures, but...
Huh?
So he didn't write when he was coming in his notice?
Yeah, that's right.
Even though Kid's never before sent out a notice that didn't specify a time or date, or at least a hint about it...
Inspector Nakamori...
Then, could it be that it's a copycat pretending to be Kid?
No, that manifesto definitely came from that guy.
I bet he intends to send another notice with the time and date after he sees an opportunity, right?
Like, maybe his schedule is full and he's waiting until it's convenient for him.
If we assume that to be true...
What in the world is he waiting for?
As expected, a huge turnout!
But the most popular spot is...
"Spaced Reserved for Kaitou Kid's Returned Treasures"?
Ryouma must be crying.
Hey, don't push me!
Hold on a minute!
I see.
They put sensors only on that space...
And they let police officers mix in with the crowd.
I'm sorry...
I was only playing a prank...
Please, I'm terribly sorry and I regret my actions, so please forgive!
So that anyone who takes suspicious actions gets intervened immediately, huh.
Advisor!
This is bad, Advisor!
What's this boisterousness?
This was just delivered ro your house in the mail!
This is...
Kid's manifesto?
What?
Tomorrow at 20:00 when the museum closes...
I shall bring the pistol and the other items...
And in the name of the Bakumatsu patriot, Sakamoto Ryouma...
I pledge to clean up once and for all.
Kaitou Kid.
KID!
What does that mean?
Clean up...
Water...
Don't tell me!
Rain...
Was Kid waiting for this?
I pledge to clean up once and for all.
Right now!
Detective Conan Episode 627
Fansub Release bt DCTP
OCR: Nixx Car
OCR Editing: DJ VK
Please take notice of this long line of spectators!
Having heard that Kaitou Kid has announced his arrival time as 20:00 tomorrow...
One after another, Kid fans are descending on the Suzuki Grand Museum despite it having just closed!
Will Kid really be able to return per his announcement...
The Sakamoto Ryouma's letter, sake cup, and pistol that were stolen 20 years ago?
And will he feel inclined to appropriate Ryouma's gunbelt as a reward?
Furthermore, what is the motive behind his sudden reveal of the time?
Will everything be made clear tomorrow?
What?
Rain, you say?
You mean Kid waited until it was going to rain before choosing his arrival time?
Yeah.
It's going to rain any moment now outside.
And the weather report for tomorrow also said so.
But how does that guy intend to utilize the rain?
Does he plan to break in through the ceiling of this exhibition room?
No.
I have my staff check every day before we open, but nothing resembling explosives had been set up.
Could his plan pertain to the visitors' clothing?
Because, see...
If it's raining, many people will be wearing ponchos or raincoats.
I see!
If he wears rain gear, it would be easy to blend into the crowd!
Zeyo, zeyo!
I really doubt Kid would have such a trifling reason to wait for rain...
But nonetheless, we should halt the Ryouma exhibition and turn away the visitors tomorrow.
That way, Kid will have no choice but to waltz into the exhibition room where we're guarding...
For the purpose of returning the three items all by himself.
It'll be the perfect situation in which to capture him!
But, that guy always disguises himself as you or your subordinates...
Or uses sleeping gas to knock you out in that situation.
No.
If we equip everyone with gas masks and constantly have them confirm each other with passwords, we'll be fine.
With the bothersome visitors out of the way, we'll be sure to nab him!
I fear that we cannot endorse such a strategy.
I did go through the trouble of gathering items related to Sakamoto Ryouma...
And organizing this Ryouma exhibition for visitors to see, after all.
How would it look if you blockaded the exhibition for an entire day simply because of a single thief?
No, but...
Furthermore, during the case of his teleportation...
I heard he almost stopped his criminal performance because the crowd was locked out.
Isn't he coming to return those three items that were stolen from me 20 years ago?
I'd be quite upset if it were suspended.
Anyway, please allow the guests to enter as usual tomorrow!
Whether Kid is caught or not depends solely upon your competence.
In addition, there is something we'd like you to carefully guard.
After Kid returns those three items, he intends to steal the highlight of this Ryouma exhibition.
Namely...
That Ryouma's gunbelt as his reward, or so did the rumors say.
Well, we do have faith...
In you police officers.
Damn.
If you have faith in us, you should cooperate, I say!
But this is a problem.
With so many visitors, it'll be easy for him to return the three items.
I know a way that can deter him!
See, it's written on the advance notice you received, right?
"Tomorrow at 20:00 when the museum closes, I shall bring the pistol and the other items.
"And in the name of the Bakimatsu patriot, Sakamoto Ryouma...
"I pledge to clean up once and for all."
What about it?
It's because instead of stealing things like usual, Kid is returning things this time, right?
And one of those is a pistol.
So if we install a metal detecting gate like they have at airports and check everyone, we'd expose him right away!
Since the one carrying the pistol will be Kid!
It's true like you said.
Conan-kun, you're so smart!
We police already thought about installing that, but the higher ups stopped us.
Why?
If we were to protect things from being stolen, we'd put one at the museum entrance.
But they fear if he sees that kind of thing before entering the museum, he might end up not returning the items.
Instead of at the museum entrance, why don't we put the gate in front of the Ryouma exhibition room?
We can install a lot so the visitors can move more smoothly!
Listen, boy...
That's a genius idea!
And while we're at it, we can perfect the plan by setting up X-ray machines to scan the contents of handbags!
Hey, hey...
You know Kid's coming tomorrow.
There's no way you could prepare those in time!
Nonsense.
With the power of my Suzuki Financial Group, it's a guaranteed cakewalk.
If we can capture that guy with the gates, great.
And if anyone turns tail and retreats due to the gates, we will know that's Kid!
All right!
Begin setting up the gates immediately!
You have an entire night to turn this museum into a gargantuan Anti-Kid mousetrap!
Roger!
As expected, rich men enjoy doing flashy things...
All right, you guys!
There's also the possibility that Kid brought the pistol into the building ahead of time!
Use metal detectors to check every nook and cranny of this museum!
Roger!
The Next Day
To the officer guarding the museum entrance, how's the situation?
Sir.
I have not yet observed any guests quickly turning tail after seeing the gate.
Any problems at the metal detectors?
No.
There have been no guests with a pistol.
And in the exhibition room?
At this time, there is no one resembling Kid in the premises.
But is Kid really coming?
You idiot!
Kid's never failed to show up any time he's made an announcement!
Pardon me.
How, come forth, Kid.
This time, I swear I'll apprehend you once and for all!
Amazing!
They really made it look like the airport terminals.
Not to mention there are even three gates.
That's Uncle for you!
Way to go!
Something still bothers me.
If he deliberately wrote in his notice that he's "bring the pistol and the other items"...
Of course he should've been able to predict that things would turn out this way.
What's more, I still haven't figured out how he intends to use the rain.
And I don't get the meaning behind the last sentence of the notice, "I pledge to clean up once and for all."
Was he merely trying to be clever by using Ryouma's words?
Or is there something he truly intends to clean up?
Damn...
What on earth is Kid's aim?
Next Episode
Seventeen centimeters would be about...
Roughly this size?
Kid!
This time I only came to return the stolen items.
Hey, let's go in too.
I think it'd be better if you didn't!
Since it seems Kid really is going to clean up in here!
Kaitou Kid!
CONAN & KID'S BATTLE FOR RYOUMA'S TREASURE
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Watercolor Paint
Look Forward to the Next Episode
I'm planning to return the treasures this time, so don't get in my way!
Don't bet on it!