Kid once again delivered his advance notice.
But this time, he claimed he would return the items stolen by another thief in the past to the original owner.
The items, three in total, were all related to Sakamoto Ryouma.
Meanwhile, the original owner Mr. Tarumi and the appraiser Mr. Hanamura...
Tarumi Shishihiko (58)
Ryouma Exhibition Organizer
Hanamura Masanosuke (63)
Appraiser
Held a Ryouma exhibition in the Suzuki Grand Museum.
A ruby-adorned gunbelt was put on display, said to be received by Ryouma from Takasugi Shinsaku along with a pistol.
And rumor has it that he was aiming to steal that gunbelt.
Since the pistol was among the items Kid promised to return...
Metal detecting gates were installed at the exhibition.
But, it still bothers me...
Can we really catch Kid with this move?
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A never-before-heard return of treasures...
What is Kid's real intention?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
To the officer guarding the museum entrance, how's the situation?
Sir.
I have yet to observe any guests quickly turning tail after seeing the gate.
Any problems at the metal detectors?
No.
There have been no guests with a pistol.
And in the exhibition room?
At this time, there is no one resembling Kid on the premises.
But is Kid really coming?
You idiot!
Kid's never failed to show up each time he's made an announcement!
Pardon me...
How, come forth, Kid...
This time, I swear I'll apprehend you once and for all!
Wow, amazing!
They really made it look like the airport terminals.
Not to mention there are even three gates.
That's Uncle for you!
Way to go!
Something still bothers me.
If he deliberately wrote in his notice that he'd "bring the pistol and the other items"...
Of course he should've been able to predict that things would turn out this way.
What's more, I still haven't figured out how he intends to use the rain.
And I don't get the meaning behind the last sentence of the notice, "I pledge to clean up once and for all."
Was he merely trying to be clever by using Ryouma's words?
Or is there something he truly intends to clean up?
Well then, we should go in too!
The hallway behind the Ryouma exhibition entrance is blocked by a wall...
So that one has to pass through the gates to get in.
The only thing between them are the restrooms...
But inside each restroom...
There is only one window.
Metal bars are installed to prevent any entrance from the outside.
Bringing a pistol inside thus seems impossible, but...
Conan-kun.
We're going in.
Yes!
Whoa!
Look at all of the people!
Attention, our valued quests.
The traffic in this room has become extremely high.
Our sincere apologies, but we are imposing a viewing limit of ten minutes to the Ryouma exhibition.
But no matter what he says, it doesn't seem like anyone plans on leaving.
That's right.
It's still two hours before the announced time, but Kid-sama might already be here!
But with the gates, he wouldn't be able to sneak the pistol in...
Besides, see...
I heard he was coming here today to return things that another thief stole.
He might just give up, you know?
Say...
What other thief?
The three items Kid's returning this time...
Ryouma's last letter, his blood-stained sake cup, and the pistol he had on him when he was assassinated...
They were all stolen twenty years ago by the damsel thief, Phantom Lady.
Phantom Lady?
She was a great thief known as the Shouwa's Woman of Twenty Faces!
She used to deploy horror-inducing tricks and target only the rich and large corporations with unscrupulous earnings...
So she was really popular!
Well, she loses to my Kid-sama of course!
But them...
Why Would Kid come to return things that lady thief stole?
How should I know!
Maybe they know each other?
They're both thieves after all.
I have to use the restroom again...
Go ahead without me!
Geez.
But it sure is crowded here.
Almost like a bargain sale...
Sonoko, you all right?
Geez, who pushed me?
Phantom Lady.
Phantom Lady...
Got it.
It seems Phantom Lady really was the one who stole those three items 20 years ago.
But for some reason she suddenly stopped all criminal activity afterwards...
Wait, she still did send out advanced notices and leave evidence of forced entries after that, but nothing was found stolen.
Ryouma's Pistol
Smith & Wesson Model 1 1/2
First issue
Caliber: .32
Ammunition: Rimfire
Shots: 5
Length: Approximately 17cm
Let's see, the Ryouma's pistol taken in her last heist was a .32 caliber, five shots...
About 17 centimeters in Length.
Seventeen centimeters would be about...
Roughly this size?
June 24th, 1867.
This pistol also appeared in Ryouma's letter addressed to his elder sister Otome on that date.
"Measuring six sun [7 inches] and chambering five shots, and while it way appear smaller than a dagger...
" 'Tis a firearm capable of killing a man from a distance of fifty ken [100 yards] proximately."
So it said.
Kid!
The door won't open...
Damn, he shut it with a stopper!
Hey, how'd you get the gun in?
Did you pass the gates?
Yeah.
If I remove the lead from the inside grip, I can pass right through!
It also becomes super light.
Well, due to the sheer number, transporting them was tough!
The lead from the grip?
Sheer number of them?
What's he talking about?
I'll say it again.
This time I only came to return the stolen items.
Don't get in the way, Great Detective!
See ya!
Wait...
Hold it!
Damn!
Hey, will it really be all right?
What if Kid gets caught by the police?
It'll be fine.
Let us have faith in our elusive gentleman.
After he makes his magnificent escape, we will once again make huge profits.
But...
He's coming to return those items!
There's no need to fret.
I've worked our plan all out.
Say, mister.
What happened to your finger?
I was appraising a Japanese sword this morning and accidentally cut my finger...
Damn...
Is he already in the exhibition?
Where?
Where'd he go?
What're you---
Ran-neechan!
Sorry about that.
I was afraid you were going to get crushed in a crowd like this, Conan-kun.
And by the looks of things...
It'll get even worse at the announced time.
Huh, Sonoko...
There's something on your right sleeve.
It seems to be some writing.
"Tetsu no hitotsu"?
"One piece of iron"?
Is it some kind of code?
Say, Sonoko-neechan.
Did you bump into anything inside the exhibition?
That's it!
Someone knocked me into the gunbelt display case.
The gunbelt display case...
Could it be he...
Really intends to produce rain?
In order to clean up...
This soiled exhibition!
Damn, that bastard Kid...
Where does he plan to get in?
Inspector Nakamori.
Even a slippery guy like him cannot pass through the metal detecting gates while carrying a pistol.
Yeah, I'd like to think so too.
But he's just...
If he managed to get through the gates, maybe the pistol he has is a counterfeit.
I supposed that would have to be the case.
Of course, I'll have Sensei here examine the three items immediately upon their return.
Yes.
I pray that they are indeed the genuine articles.
Aside from that, is Ryouma's gunbelt all right?
Although we did a final check on the display case before the museum opened.
How about we head to the exhibition now?
Yeah.
Since if the three items he's returning turned out to be fake, and if the gunbelt were stolen on top of that...
It would be just too terrible.
It's now completely crowded.
Kid-sama's announced time is in four more minutes.
Think it's about time that we go in?
But there are so many people that we wouldn't even see Kid if he showed up.
It's Inspector Nakamori.
And Uncle Jirokichi too!
I'm with the police.
Please let us through.
Hey, let's go in too.
I think it'd be better if you didn't!
Conan-kun?
Why shouldn't we go in?
Well, you don't want to get wet, right?
Since it seems Kid really is going to clean up in here!
Damn, there are too many visitors!
We can't guard properly like this!
What?
That's...
Kaitou Kid!
He's standing on the gun belt case!
Kid-sama, you're awesome!
He got through the metal detecting gates so he's unarmed!
Seize him!
Roger!
You bastard, Kid!
What "clean up"?
The only thing that's getting cleaned up down to the bone is you, after your arrest!
Correct, I'm cleaning up.
But in order to clean things up, I need water.
So, right now, in this very room...
I shall create some rain for your viewing pleasure.
Rain?
What the heck is that guy up to?
That bastard, he used the flame to set off the fire sprinklers!
Well then, I shall take my leave.
Hey, wait!
Aren't you going return those three items?
About that, this shower shall make everything clear.
Just like how rain washes away the mud.
Blasted guy!
He tampered with the sprinkler's water pressure!
The water mist is obscuring him...
Damn...
He disappeared!
Freaking Kid...
Think he can escape by blending in with the quests?
Hey!
Did any guests leave through the gate just now?
Yes...
Two or three people did.
It's them!
Go and detain the one who's wet among them!
That's Kid!
If he changed into his disguise during the shower, he should be soaking wet!
But, however...
Since it's pouring outside as well, nearly all of the guests are soaked.
Then the footprints!
Follow the damp footprints that lead away from the gate!
However...
Naturally, the floor's covered in damp frootprints too.
What now!?
I see.
So that's why he was waiting for a rainy day.
Then what about the three items he said he'd return?
They're here.
They are placed here on top of the gunbelt's display case.
Oh dear, my bad.
I accidentally got my blood on the sake cup.
Oh well...
Since all three items appear to be replicas...
It won't be a problem.
The problem is whether this gunbelt is safe or not.
The anti-theft device was destroyed!?
So, does it mean Kid switched the gunbelt inside with a fake!?
Damn!
He completely got you, didn't he?
Huh?
What seems to be the matter?
There's something dripping down from the case's description plate.
Is it paint?
Why, it's double-layered...
I see!
He stuck another plate with the same descriptions written in watercolors over the original...
So that the writing underneath would appear when it got drenched.
I see!
So this was because my sleeve was damp from the rain.
The letters from the gunbelt description plate was thus reversed on your sleeve.
So, what's written on it?
Let's see.
"This gunbelt was a complete counterfeit from the start, because..."
Because...
They assumed it would be stolen and manufactured a large number of them.
Isn't that right?
What was essential was that the stolen items appear on the news and be made known to the world.
Then, those who're responsible for the large number of forgeries sold them to wealthy Ryouma fans via a third party.
They'd say that those items were stolen just a few days before!
The advantage to this kind of operation is that nothing will be reported even if the buyers discover that the items are fake.
Since they attempted to secretly purchase stolen goods, they're in a bind and can't take the matter to court.
That's why Phantom Lady's crimes went unnoticed after she stole those three items.
Since she only targeted those who bought the three items' forgeries.
She then entrusted the mass of forgeries that she had gathered to you.
The Lady then asked you to expose the dirty deeds of those two, right?
Because, without the cooperation the exhibition organizer who knowingly displayed fakes...
And the appraiser who certifies the forgeries as real, these crimes cannot be committed.
Am I right?
Mister Thief, or Would-be Ryouma?
Hey, is what it says on this plate true?
Wrong!
That's just nonsense!
First of all, where are they?
The so-called "mass numbers of forgeries"?
Here we only have a plastic pistol...
A fake sake cup and a letter, these three items.
Inspector!
This gun belt and pistol were put around my waist without me knowing!
My waist too...
What!?
"borrowed from Mr. Tarumi's warehouse," huh?
Damn that Kid!
He took advantage of the crowd to put the belts on our waists!
I see.
You folks broke that anti-theft device in advance to make it look like a robbery...
And this time you planned to sell of the gunbelts, is that right?
Inspector!
What is it this time!?
There's also text where the paint came off of this other description plate!
What?
It meticulously goes into detail about why this item is a forgery.
And the last bit of text is in English.
In English?
PULL...
Pull... pull down?
Is it telling me to pull down this hanging scroll?
What the!?
This is...
Ryouma's letter!
And there are many more copies of it?
It appears that they are all the same letter as the one that was placed on the gunbelt case.
It's a trap!
It's a setup by Kid!
I concur!
There is no evidence that we made or sold any of th---
Wait, Sonoko!?
Well, it's written on Kid-sama's plate!
It says "crash it"!
Hey, hey what are these?
There are a pethora of sake cups inside the vase!
What's more appears that each of them has blood on it.
If we conduct a DNA test on the blood, it'll be clear who was making the phony sake cups.
Unless you plan to explain it away by rubbing your cut finger on them like earlier?
What you did was to get your blood on all of the cups.
Well, I'm sure we'll find it when we search your warehouse.
A mountain load of forged items that you haven't sold yet!
I'm surprised that you figured out I was Kid!
Don't I look like an ordinary middle-aged guy?
It was easy.
Even though they were forged plastic pistols, they would get quite bulky if you must carry a lot of them, right?
All the more so when combined with the letters and sake cups.
That's why I searched through the crowd for someone with a disproportionately skinny lower body.
And that would be you who were pretending to be fat in order to hide so many items on your person.
Of course, you won't show signs of sweating because you're in disguise.
So I stuck one of these button transmitters on that skinny ankle of yours...
And when my pursuit glasses caught your position, I called out to you.
Well?
Are you turning me over to the police?
Nah.
I'll let you got this time for Ryouma's sake.
Are you a Ryouma fan?
My motheris.
She once played the role of Ryouma's elder sister Otome, so she's gone gaga over him.
I see!
Well, she got rave reviews for being to cute to play Otome...
And her popularity soared because of that.
Well, we're the same.
Consider us both to be unable to stand up to our mothers.
Later!
"We're the same"?
Hey, don't tell me that Phantom Lady is...
*Hey, hey, isn't that Miyasaka Yuuya over there?
*You know, he's the one who was on the news last year after being charged with injury to others due to inebriation.
Ready...
Action!
You idiot!
He beat me up again...
Miyasaka-san is...
DEAD!
Something...
Something wasn't right.
THE PROMO VIDEO SHOOTING CASE
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Liquid Foundation
Maybe we can see Kid-sama again next week!
Since our hint is "li-kid"!
Sonoko...