The wind is so soothing!
You're right!
Near the outlying island we're headed to...
Awesomely beautiful fish will be swimming around in schools!
I'm so thrilled right now!
It would've been great if Ai-chan could've come with us.
She said she hates getting sunburned.
Conan-kun!
The seagulls!
The seagulls are over there.
Never mind that...
Don't you think the clouds look threatening?
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A tragedy on an outlying island...
An altercation among the video crew!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Kurahashi-san, thank you again for everything.
Sonoko-san, for your constant patronage...
We thank you from the bottom of our hearts.
Alright, let's put our baggage in our rooms and go diving at once!
Kurohashi Osamu (43)
Pension Owner
To tell you the truth, a storm is coming up.
I apologize for you guys coming all the way here, but...
With it being so dangerous, it'd be better if you didn't go near the sea.
Is that so?
Gurgle gurgle...
How disappointing.
I wanted to see those pretty fish...
I did expect things would turn out somewhat like this...
Kurahashi Keiko (38)
Kurahashi's Wife
Well, everyone, allow me to show you your rooms.
What a bummer.
And I was looking forward to this!
Now that I think about it, we're in the typhoon season after all.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Looks like there's a filming session of some sort.
Filming?
Hey, Okita.
Make sure the lighting is perfect.
Roger.
Miyasaka Yuuya (30)
Actor
Good, good, just like that.
Hey, hey, isn't that Miyasaka Yuuya over there?
Who's he?
A celebrity?
He's an actor!
You know, he's the one who was on the news last year after being charged with injury to others due to inebriation.
I remember that.
Because of that, the drama he was starring in got canceled if I recall correctly.
Ayumi also remembers that because I loved that drama.
And after that, he's hardly been seen on TV and other media, but...
I wonder what he's filming at a place like this?
Looks fun to me.
Let's go check it out!
Yes!
Hey, hey.
Akimoto Saeko (25)
Actress
Wow, I didn't know the actress Akimoto Saeko was here too!
An actress!?
Where?
Cut!
Good, OK.
Oops, I'm sorry.
It's fine.
Sorry about that.
We're guests lodging at the nearby pension, but...
We came across to your filming, so we took a peek...
Kitagawa Miki (22)
Make-up Artist
Then, I bet we're staying at the same pension.
What is this filming about?
Actually, we're filming shots for Miyasaka Yuuya-san's promotional video.
What's the story about?
Miyasaka-san, after having drifted to a deserted island with Saeko-san...
Utilizes his outstanding survival skills to protect her from danger at all cost.
That's the story.
A deserted island, huh...
All right, I'm counting on you.
Aye-aye.
Hey, Miki.
He's calling me.
Later.
Who are those folks?
They're guests staying at the same pension as us.
Huh?
That famous actress is putting on make-up all by herself.
Say, wasn't that lady earlier a make-up artist?
Stop it.
Saeko-san is watching.
I don't give a damn.
We should continue filming.
So that's how it goes.
What do you mean?
Miyasaka Yuuya and Akimoto Saeko had hit the gossip news at one point!
They said another woman appeared and got in their way!
Everyone can hear you...
Coming up, Scene 14.
It's the scene where I slide down the cliff in order to save Saeko who's underneath.
Hey, Yamamoto.
Are you prepared for this?
Yamamoto Eiji (21)
Assistant Director
Yes...
The preparations are ready.
Hold on a sec!
Okita Mitsuo (23)
Camera Assistant
Miyasaka-san, what's the meaning of this!?
I've never heard about me having to do a stunt job!
But, you were in the Gymnastics Club...
And being athletic is your only strength, no?
Without that, nobody would want to hire you as a camera assistant.
Of course you can call it quits.
Takayama Shingo (28)
Cameraman
But in return, don't expect me to pay you even a penny!
How dare he take advantage of me!?
It'd be wise for you to get ready.
Miyasaka-san won't hear of it after he's made a decision.
I know that all right!
Doesn't mean you can say it casually just because it doesn't concern you!
Hey, is he really going to slide down from that high?
No matter the reason, it's too reckless!
Scary!
Even if he really has quick reflexes...
This is too much...
Ready...
Action!
Cut!
Hey, Okita, you all right!?
Oww...
That fall just now packed no punch at all.
Okita, one more time!
What's with you, throwing that look?
I think it's best if you called it quits!
Right, right!
What'd you say?
Miyasaka-san, didn't you see that?
He was too close to suffering a serious injury!
She's right!
That's right!
You have no right to butt into my decision!
Who the heck threw away a cola can right here?
My bad...
You again, Genta-kun?
The cola made a smudge on this...
This is bad...
You idiot!
How dare you soil my important prop!
Now, now, calm down.
Are you all right, Yamamoto-san?
Shit, bunch of good-for-nothings!
It's freaking raining...
Miyasaka-kun, it seems even the skies have abandoned you.
With the way things are going, it's almost like a farce.
Shut up!
Everyone, let's get back to the pension!
Now, please use these to dry yourselves.
The bathtubs are all ready to go, so please feel free to use them.
How about it, everyone?
While we're waiting for our meals to be ready...
How about we play some recreational games to enhance our friendships?
Seconded!
Sounds like fun to me!
You must be joking.
It's not like we're on a school trip.
Give me a break.
Typical pension papa, always thinking about befriending guests whenever there's a chance!
We have some equipment maintenance to do.
Excuse us.
Well, I'll go first!
Eight of spades!
Well...
I'll put down eight of diamonds!
Ayumi has...
Uhm...
Got it!
Six of hearts!
Is Miyasaka-san always acting like that?
I also heard he was involved in some sort of incident a while ago.
Miyasaka-san is trying really hard to rebuild his plummeting popularity due to that incident.
The promotional video this time was also an out-of-pocket production of his.
He's betting everything on this project.
That's why he became quite nervous.
My apologizes for letting you undergo some unpleasant experiences.
Not at all!
Who is it?
It's me.
Huh, what's this?
You haven't changed yet?
It's none of your business.
What do you want?
How about a drink before our meals?
With the weather like this, your filming for today is over, right?
He beat me up again...
Damn!
That bastard Miyasaka, messing with me like that!
Hey, Okita.
Here.
What's the matter, Takayama-san?
Miyasaka said...
He wants to film some behind-the-scenes, so he's asking you to turn the camera on and come to his room.
So I'm doing the filming?
Not you, Takayama-san?
Right, Miyasaka requested you.
Maybe it's his way of apologizing about earlier?
Here you go.
This will be my second pass!
Argh, pass-3!
I can't pass anymore!
I'll also call...
Pass-3!
Geez, Conan-kun is so cunning, stopping all of us from making a move!
Cunning?
Isn't that how you should play a game of "Sevens"?
This is terrible!
Miyasaka-san is...
DEAD!
What do you mean, Miyasaka-san is dead?
I was told to keep the camera on and go to Miyasaka-san's room to film some behind-the-scenes...
And then...
What's wrong?
Takayama-san, Miyasaka-san is...!
Miya-san...
It can't be!
Okita!
Go call everyone here now!
Yes!
Is that for real?
Yeah.
No way...
At any rate, let's go check!
You guys, wait outside for a bit.
Takayama-san, is Miyasaka-san really...?
There's no pulse.
It's too late.
Miyasaka-san...
No way...
NO!
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Miyasaka-kun...
Someone drove a knife into his heart.
Something's wrong...
Conan-kun!
You can't go in.
I'm sorry.
This...
Huh?
Isn't that my liquid foundation?
Why is it here?
You'd better not touch it!
We need to preserve the scene.
We should keep this room as-is and lock this place.
When the police arrive, I'll use the master key to unlock this room.
The police?
Someone's dead.
We have no reason not to call the police.
That's right, but...
Miki-san, you should go rest in your room...
I agree.
Yes...
Excuse me...
Although I contacted the police...
They said they cannot send out a ship before the storm peters out.
That means the culprit is among us, right?
I mean, isn't that the case?
The storm is so strong outside, even the cops can't come.
We can definitely rule out the possibility of an outsider.
As much as I don't want to admit, that's what I think as well.
No way...
Uhm, what should we do about their meals?
I regret to say this, but it'll have to wait until the police arrive.
It doesn't matter to me.
I don't want to dine with a murderer anyway.
Saying that as if you were not the culprit!
What now?
Are you suspecting me!?
Now, now.
We should all calm down and reflect upon the events up until now.
Miki-san, are you feeling all right now?
Yes, better.
I'm sorry for letting you worry.
Now everyone's here.
Miki-san, have a seat.
Thank you.
Now then, regarding the time of crime...
It's between Miyasaka-san's departure from the lobby...
And the time when Okita-san discovered his body.
In the meantime, most of us were in the lobby.
In other words, me, Ran, Miki-san, Kurahashi-san...
And the four kids have alibis, is that correct?
Having that said, the ones without alibis...
Will be the actress Saeko-san, the cameraman Takayama-san...
The AD Yamamoto-san, and the assistant Okita-san...
And my wife, totaling five people.
I was preparing for everyone's meal the entire time!
Yeah, there's absolutely no way that you'd be the culprit.
You've never met Miyasaka-san prior to today.
You lack motive.
In other words, I suppose the culprit must be among the four of us?
For the time being, I will videotape us for the testimony records.
Now, who wants to start defending themselves?
Uhm, can I ask just one thing?
Hey, Conan-kun!
I'm only asking a question.
This is directed to Okita-san, but...
Miyasaka-san's room is auto-locked, right?
So how did you get in his room?
Was the door open?
In other words, when Okita arrived at the door, Miyasaka was still alive.
And from there, he pretended to be the primary discoverer after taking care of Miyasaka!
You were mad at Miyasaka because of that stunt thing.
It seems very likely!
Just wait a minute!
When I got there, a cosmetic bottle was used as a stopper, and the door was ajar!
That belongs to Saeko-san, right?
Doesn't that mean you'd been to Miyasaka-san's room?
Hold on, are you suspecting me as well?
And to begin with, what reason would I have to do that?
You have a motive, don't you!?
Saeko-san, you suspect that there's a thing between me and Miyasaka-san, and you're jealous!
So there's a love entanglement?
If you're going that far, I will tell the truth.
I did go to Miyasaka-kun's room all right.
In order to question the relationship between him and Miki.
But...
My, bad, but I don't feel like talking about that now.
He didn't let me in his room, but shooed me away instead.
But I wasn't carrying the foundation on me.
So as to why it was at Miyasaka-kun's room, I have no idea at all.
In fact, I have something I'd like to ask Takayama-san.
What?
At the time I discovered Miyasaka-san's body, you appeared too fast, don't you think?
Almost as if you were waiting for me to run out of the room!
Perhaps you were lying about Miyasaka-san calling me, and in actuality you are the culprit, Takayama-san...
With the intend to make a scapegoat out of me, no?
What the!?
I already knew it.
You were betting on mahjong and borrowed a truckload of money from Miyasaka-san!
You idiot!
I only went to check on you out of concern whether you could get the filming job done or not!
It had nothing to do with my debt!
I wonder?
What about you, Yamamoto-kun?
The murder weapon was that of a prop knife, the one you brought with you, no?
Did you do it out of rage because Miyasaka-kun beat you senseless?
Since he's always been treating you like a dog so far, right?
So your grudge and pain built up and...
You're wrong, it wasn't me!
When Miyasaka-san hit me, I lost that knife somewhere!
I went to search for it immediately...
But the rain kept getting heavier.
And I just couldn't find it anywhere.
That so?
What was it?
That feeling of discrepancy I got when I saw Miyasaka-san's body.
Something...
Something wasn't right.
Say, Okita-san.
Back then when we went to Miyasaka-san's room...
I recall you were videotaping, right?
Yeah.
Since the time I entered Miyasaka-san's room, I've been taping without pausing.
Which means the surroundings at the time of our discovering Miyasaka-san's body were being filmed nonstop, right?
If we watch it, I think maybe we can pick up some sort of clue.
I'm sorry, but I can't stand watching it!
Something like a video of Miyasaka-san's body!
Conan-kun, Miki-san is still shocked at the fact that Miyasaka-san is no longer with us.
OK?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Who on earth is the culprit responsible for Miyasaka-san's murder?
Takayama-san is indebted to Miyasaka-san for a large sum of money.
Perhaps after killing Miyasaka-san, he made okita-san go to his room...
With the plan to shift the blame, which is a valid assumption.
Okita-san was pissed because he was forced to perform dangerous stunts.
Did he murder Miyasaka-san and pretend to be the primary discoverer?
Saeko-san has been jealous about the relationship between Miki-san and Miyasaka-san.
Her make-up item was also at the crime scene.
Yamamoto-san bore a grudge having getting beaten.
It may be possible that he's lying about losing his knife.
At any rate, the culprit is among the people in this pension.
No doubt about it.
How much longer do we have to stay in this damned room?
Stranded on this island by the storm, where else could anyone flee to?
I'm not the culprit for sure.
Takayama-san, you've been pretty anxious about the cops coming!
The feeling of discrepancy I got when I first saw him is gone.
The culprit just escaped!
I finally figured out why I had that feeling of discrepancy!
THE PROMO VIDEO SHOOTING CASE
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Window
Ran, I know who the culprit is!
As expected of the Deduction Queen!
Again, I haven't done my usual thing!