After setting foot on an island in the south for some R&R at a pension...
We came across actor Miyasaka Yuuya-san and
his staff who were filming a promotional video.
Miyasaka-san's popularity plummeted thanks to a drunken
incident that resulted in the injury of a bystander.
The promo video production was an
attempt to salvage his reputation.
But his ordering his staff member to do reckless
stunts and lashing out with violence...
Resulted in a buildup of hatred amongst his crew.
As for Miyasaka-san's former love interest
and co-star Akimoto Saeko-san...
She was miffed with the makeup artist Kitagawa
Miki-san for getting intimate with Miyasaka-san.
Then, the case happened admist the rampaging storm.
Miyasaka-san was found murdered inside the pension's guest room.
A murder case inside the pension, sealed off by the storm.
The culprit is definitely among these people!
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
The inexplicable sense of discrepancy at the crime scene...
The video camera had documented the truth!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE PROMO VIDEO SHOOTING CASE
(PART TWO)
Okita Mitsuo (23)
Camera Assistant
Takayama Shingo (28)
Cameraman
Hey!
How much longer do we have to stay in this damned room?
Kurahashi Keiko (28)
Kurahashi's Wife
Kurohashi Osamu (43)
Pension Owner
Until the police arrive.
If everyone remains in the same room,
the culprit will be unable to escape.
Akimoto Saeko (25)
Actress
Escape, you say?
Stranded on this island by the storm,
where else could anyone flee to?
Yamamoto Eiji (21)
Assistant Director
I'm not the culprit for sure.
There's no need for me to flee.
Kitagawa Miki (22)
Make-up Artist
I'm going back to my room.
If you want to suspect that I'm the culprit, suit yourself.
First of all, are the cops really coming?
Takayama-san, you've been pretty anxious about the cops coming.
Could you be...
The culprit!?
What the hell?
I only asked because I felt that the cops are
taking too much of their sweet time!
Cut the crap!
The testimony recording is over!
I'm returning to my room too!
His flying off the handle all of a sudden
only makes him more suspicious.
May I return to my room as well?
Me too, then.
Now that all those four people without an alibi are gone...
I think there's no point for us to remain here any longer.
Please excuse me.
Everyone just left.
Sounds like my belly's growling...
It's natural that your stomach is
empty, given that it's getting so late.
I'll go get something you can eat right now.
Awesome!
Is it true that Takayama-san is indeed our culprit?
Well, who knows?
He did look like he was afraid of the police coming. though.
The sense of discrepancy I got when I saw Miyasaka-san's body...
It's been bothering me all this time.
I've got no choice.
If I can't watch the recorded video, I'll have to
give the crime scene another thorough look.
Ah-le?
My wallet is missing!
I guess I accidentally dropped it inside Miyasaka-san's room earlier.
Huh?
Why would you know you dropped it inside
Miyasaka-san's room and not anywhere else?
Just a gut feeling...
Don't poke your nose into details!
Understood.
I'll go get it for you, then.
I'll go with you too!
I want you to wait right here.
Poor soul.
To have a knife driven inside so deep...
Oh no!
He's turned completely cold...
Can't believe I dropped my wallet in a place like this!
Oh, so you found it?
Weird.
The feeling of discrepancy I got when I first saw him is gone.
What was that?
Was it just my mind playing tricks?
Thanks for the meal!
Yummy!
This is delicious!
Glad to hear.
I wonder if Conan-kun got his wallet back?
Miki-oneesan!
I feel insecure when I'm alone.
So can I join everyone here?
Of course, and please help yourself with some food.
Have a seat here.
Thank you.
Miki-san, what's the matter?
Just now...
Takayama-san ran past outside the window!
In a storm like this!?
Could it be...!?
As we though, Takayama-san's indeed our culprit.
I see, he was afraid of the police coming, so he made his escape!
Hey, you guys!
Kurahashi-san!
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
The culprit just escaped!
The culprit?
It's Takayama-san!
Miki-san witnessed Takayama-san's escape
through the living room window just now!
Are you sure he ran towards this direction?
Yes.
I saw him running east.
But there's a cliff ahead of us and it's a dead end.
Hey, Takayama-san!
Hey!
Takayama-san!
This...
Takayama-san...
Those kids got so tired, they're sleeping soundly.
First it was Miyasaka-san, and now Takayama-san...
I guess he wasn't paying attention in the dark during his getaway...
And slipped and fell to his death off the cliff.
Idiot of a man.
But, it's a good thing that we found out who the culprit was.
This case is as good as solved.
However, was Takayama-san really the culprit?
No doubt about it, now is there?
Are you saying there's a legitimate reason for
him to run outside in such a stormy night?
But he should've been well aware of the fact that he
couldn't leave this island even if he ran outside.
That's...
Even if we assume Takayama-san was the culprit...
It'd be too much of a coincidence for him
to lose his life in a freak accident.
Perhaps Takayama-san was also...
In other words, you mean the suspicion cast
upon us has not been completely lifted.
Now that Takayama-san's gone...
Someone among the three of us---myself, Okita-kun, and
Yamamoto-kun---is the killer, is that what you're saying?
I'm not the culprit!
I'll prove it to you right now!
This is the video I took when to Miyasaka-san's room.
After watching this, you will know that it
wasn't me who murdered Miyasaka-san!
Is he going to play the video?
I'm sorry, I've said this before, but that video is just...
Yeah, Miyasaka-san's body is on tape.
But it's for the sake of clearing my name!
Pardon me, but close your eyes if you don't want to see it!
Detective Conan Episode 630
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Now, I'll start playing.
I'm... Okita in charge of the behind-the-scenes.
I'm about to pay a surprise visit to Miyasaka-san's room.
In front of me is Miyasaka-san's room.
Well, I wonder what Miyasaka-san's doing right now?
Huh?
The door is slightly open...
Something's stuck in the door.
Hmm, it looks like some kind of cosmetics.
All right, I'm going in.
What's wrong?
Takayama-san, Miyasaka-san is...
Miya-san...
It can't be!
Okita!
Go call everyone here now!
Yes!
How about it?
When I arrived, Miyasaka-san was already dead!
Are we now all clear that I didn't do this!?
In that case...
It'd be either Saeko-san ot Yamamoto-san who could've done it...
Hold it, don't blurt out weird things!
That's right, I didn't do it!
I finally figured out why I had that feeling of discrepancy!
Conan-kun.
Restroom...
Sonoko?
Don't tell me...
What's this all of a sudden?
Whenever Sonoko starts doing this little dance, it's
the cue for her becoming the Deduction Queen!
"Deduction Queen"?
I'm afraid that we have made an
egregious assumption error all this time.
Okita-san, sorry to bother you, but can
you know show us the video just now again?
Please show us the part where the
footage of Miyasaka-san's body is.
It's around this part.
Yamamoto-san...
Can I have your confirmation that the knife was
indeed one of the props used during filming?
Yes...
I would assume that's the case.
Take a closer look.
Don't you feel something's off?
Something's off?
The cola smudge is missing!
You're right!
I see no smudges on the knife handle!
But wait a second...
When I went back there to search for Conan-kun's wallet earlier...
I took another look at the body.
But I was pretty sure that the knife had a cola smudge on it!
Yeah.
In that case, it means there were two knives as a matter of fact.
What did you say!?
Two knives!?
Wait a minute.
What do you mean?
Are you saying that after stabbing him, someone
stabbed him again with another knife?
What reason would anyone have to do something like that?
And to begin with, when on earth did
the culprit knife him a second time?
The room is secured with an auto-lock, and no one should
be able to gain entrance without my master key.
But, you could easily open the door from inside the room.
From inside the room?
But nothing was inside the room except Miyasaka-san's body!
What if we assume Miyasaka-san was not dead at that time?
What proof do you have for saying that?
The proof is the...
Liquid foundation.
It's the liquid foundation bottle that got stuck
in the door of Miyasaka-san's room.
To think it was stuck in the door in an upended position...
Quite unnatural, don't you think?
Does anyone sense the meaning?
Meaning?
A reversed liquid foundation...
If you reserve the word "liquid"...
"Dokkiri"!
That's right.
It was a dokkiri video, or candid camera
made to surprise everyone by playing dead.
I surmise that the knife without a cola
smudge stuck in him in the beginning...
Was a fake one that had a trick blade.
And the blood was make-up used for filming.
Using those to stage a dead body...
And having our shocking reactions upon
discovering the "body" caught on tape...
Was the plan for the prank video all along.
Sounds just like something Miyasaka-kun would think of.
No.
This plan was brought to Miyasaka-san by the culprit...
With the intent to kill him off by carrying it out.
However, Miyasaka-san took a certain action
that was out of the culprit's anticipation.
Miyasaka-san, who hadn't the slightest idea
he would actually be murdered later...
Placed the liquid foundation as a playful hint.
Unbeknownst to him, that became his dying message.
By the way, an accomplice is needed
in order to pull off this kind of prank.
An accomplice?
That reminds me, at that time...
There's no pulse.
It's too late.
The one who confirmed Miyasaka-san's death was Takayama-san.
Does that mean, Takayama-san acted as
the accomplice for the prank video?
So the incredible timing when he
showed up was not a fluke after all.
What's wrong?
Okita!
Go call everyone here now!
It was done in order to prevent me
from getting close to Miyasaka-san.
So, is Takayama-san the culprit after all?
No.
There's no way Takayama-san could've
murdered Miyasaka-san whatsoever.
Because the time of the crime wasn't
between our return to the pension...
And our rushing to Miyasaka-san's
room after hearing about his death...
But instead it was between our exiting Miyasaka-san's
room and Kurahashi-san's reentering the room.
And during that interval, each one of us was in this lobby...
Barring one person.
Right.
The one available for committing the crime in that time frame...
Miki-san, you should go rest in your room...
Yes...
Excuse me...
Miki-san.
It was none other than you!
You proposed the candid camera project to Miyasaka-san and
Takayama-san, and those two found it amusing and OK'ed it.
Then, with things going as you planned...
We promptly sealed off Miyasaka-san's room,
having been convinced that he was murdered.
After everyone left, you took a return trip to Miyasaka-san's room.
And Miyasaka-san, still alive at the time, opened the door...
To let Miki-san in.
Perhaps they were supposed to show up in front of
everyone else and reveal the prank according to plan.
To his surprise, he found himself stabbed
in the heart with a real knife this time.
After repositioning the body to where he was during the prank...
Miki-san exited the room.
The door automatically locked up.
As such, you have obtained a solid alibi of which the others lacked.
Then, what about Takayama-san...?
I believe Takayama-san must've sensed something went wrong,
for Miyasaka-san never showed up to reveal the prank.
His fidgeting about in an anxious manner
was pretty apparent to everyone, right?
And if Takayama-san learned that
Miyasaka-san's death turned out to be real...
Her alibi trick based on the prank would shatter.
Thus Miki-san called Takayama-san out near the cliff.
And when returning to the lobby with an innocent look...
She lied about having seen Takayama-san running
away, in an attempt to set him up as the murderer.
It wasn't a lie!
I really did see it!
No way you could have.
Since even if you did look outside the dark
exterior from a bright lobby like this...
The windows would only reflect the interior surroundings.
You still wouldn't be able to see what's outside!
Don't just stay quiet, say something!
I...
Did it.
Miki-san!
No way...
I was a no-name actress in the past.
For a moment, I happened to land myself a huge gig.
It was a guest role in a popular drama starring Miyasaka.
I immediately informed my grandmother, my only relative, about it.
Grandma was really happy for me, even in a hospital
bed, and was looking forward to the air date.
But...
Takayama and Miyasaka got so hammered
that they injured someone...
And the drama was cancelled.
The episode with my appearance never got aired,
and Grandma passed away waiting in vain.
If only those two hadn't caused such an incident...
I could've shown her my fifteen minutes of fame!
In the and, I wasn't able to get another big role like that...
And I gave up on being an actress.
Everything was ruined by Miyasaka's gang, and I
couldn't forgive them whenever I thought about it.
But they said...
Who's gonna be that dumb to give up acting
because of that stupid incident?
I'm definitely gonna make a comeback as a star!
Without contemplating his mistake for even a bit...
He and is sorry ass got to stay as an actor...
And I had to give up on my acting career?
It wasn't fair at all!
That's why...
Stop being a pathetic drama queen!
Things never turn out as you wish in the realm of acting.
But even so, all of us gritted our teeth and kept doing our best.
Not getting a good role simply means
you weren't putting in enough effort.
It's your choice whether to give up or not.
And yet you shifted responsibility onto others
and even robbed them of their lives...
How pathetic can you get!?
During the following police investigation...
They uncovered the fake knife with
a halved blade in Miki-san's room.
This is bad!
I overslept!
Hey!
I'm still right here!
They just ditched me...
"The Prank Is A Success!"
My legs went limp!
Next Episode
So that guy is the stalker?
Yeah.
He came yesterday and the day before too.
He must've used the time during Ayumi-can's practice.
To think he used Ayumi-chan for
something like that---it's unforgivable!
That's right!
We'll definitely seek out the culprit ourselves!
WHAT THE FLOWER CLOCK KNEW
Next Conan's Hint
Paint
Look Forward to the Next Episode
A flower clock
is fabulous!
Whatever, let's get
something to eat!
That's your
stomach clock...