Damn, I'm late...
You're late!
My bad...
Where are Genta and Mitsuhiko?
Geez, look at them...
What the... that hurt!
Sorry!
My hand slipped!
That's because you twirled it with too much force!
There's only two days remaining.
That's why I'm all worked up.
After the lengthy flower clock renovation had been finished...
A ceremony to commemorate the occasion was in order.
They needed some elementary schoolgirl
baton twirlers for the event...
And Ayumi-chan was selected.
That's why she's been practicing every morning.
It's that person!
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A baffling case occurred in the park.
Only the flower clock saw the truth!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
So that guy is the stalker?
Yeah.
He was here yesterday and the day before too.
Good thing we came here as bodyguards!
Leave it to me!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Knock it off already!
Ayumi's scared of you, y'know!
Watch it!
We don't know who we're dealing with!
He reeks of booze!
What happened?
Are you all right?
If he climbs that high while in a drunken state...
is he drunk?
Yeah, he had extremely foul alcohol breath!
If he should fall from that height, he
won't walk away with a light injury!
I'm sorry, everyone...
For making you wake up early.
It's all right.
Everyone already volunteered.
Plus, we can't possibly let you go alone to a place where
such a disgusting guy is hanging around, Yoshida-san.
Thank you, Ai-chan!
I swear I've seen them somewhere else...
That hat and coat.
Is he someone you know?
I can't be sure of that...
I bet I'd recognize him if I see his face, but...
You couldn't see his face when he breathed on you?
It was deeply concealed by his hat.
The Next Day
Is he going to come today too?
If he does, I'm totally gonna reveal his true identity!
Yeah.
That's our guy, isn't it?
Is he dead?
Yeah.
The wound on his cheek...
Did the tip of that hand cut him?
Looks like he was a pretty thin man...
Paint?
That guy was a stalker!
He was targeting Ayumi, who was practicing early in the morning!
He came yesterday too.
He looked really drunk.
And then he climbed up this arch.
He was drunk and climbed the arch?
Very close to falling down, I should add.
His body indeed reeked of alcohol.
Inspector.
This is the security guard who patrolled the park last night.
Thank you for your hard work.
About what time did you patrol around this flower clock?
I started my patrol shift at 3:00 in the morning.
And I checked around the flower clock at approximately 3:50.
Was the body there?
It wasn't.
I didn't find any trace of the flowers being disturbed.
This has got to be an accident!
Mouri-kun!
So you came!
Conan was late coming home, so Ran told me to come get him.
The position of the stone number 6 on
the clock is right beneath the arch.
In other words, he climbed up the arch and fell while inebriated...
And hit his head on this stone.
That's what happened.
Looks that way.
And the man's time of death was between 3:50 and 4:30 AM.
The reason being he suffered from a slash
wound by the clock's long hand.
That means the clock was pointing at the thirty -minute
position after he fell to his death.
What time did you guys arrive?
Let's see...
It was about 5:20.
That goes to show the man's cheek was slashed at 4:30.
In that case, Mouri-kun.
Can you take these children back home?
I have to?
Aren't you here to pick them up?
The death was an accident, and all that's
left is to confirm the man's identity.
And I have a good idea about it.
What's that?
He was a painter, wasn't he?
Since that person had traces of paint on his hands.
Well, something like that...
Couldn't he merely have gotten paint on him somewhere else?
But he even had old, dried paint in the creases of his palms.
I bet he worked with paint a lot when he was alive.
What Conan-kun just said.
Weill, that's the way it is.
There's no need for Sleeping Kogorou
to make an appearance time.
Indeed...
All right you guys, let's go home!
Yes!
What's this all of a sudden?
I just remembered!
About where I met that man before.
He came to my place once before to buy alcohol!
Thanks to the testimony from Genta's father...
We found out that the man had worked
at a nearby signboard factory.
There's no doubt.
He's Yoda Shousaku, a member of our staff.
So he died after getting hammered?
Sounds just like him...
Does that mean he was a bad drunk by nature?
Yeah.
He becomes arrogant when he's drunk and really stirs things up.
This is so cool!
Oh, that one is Yoda's last work.
Huh?
This part is broken.
Last month, Yoda tried to mount that
sign while under the influence...
And he fell down with it.
That guy Yoda has been afraid of heights ever since.
Taking days off from work and binging on booze.
He had acrophobia?
But that man...
Can you give me more information in detail?
The real culprit had us in their trap all this time.
What do you mean by that, Conan?
Yoda-san was afraid of heights.
Could that kind of guy possibly climb up an arch?
Then, who was that man that we saw?
It was likely the culprit.
Not knowing that Yoda-san had acrophobia...
They pretended to be Yoda-san and repeatedly acted strangely...
In order to make the murder look like an accidental death.
No way...
They must've used the time during Ayumi-chan's practice.
To make you into a witness.
How cruel!
To think they used Ayumi-chan for something
like that—it's unforgivable!
That's right!
We're definitely going to find the culprit ourselves!
Yes!
"Revisit a hundred times"!
Basic investigation dogma!
Right, dawg.
Hide now!
Kawaguchi Kyouichirou (30)
Physical Education Instructor
You're Kawaguchi Kyouichirou-san, aren't you?
A P.E. instructor at a high school in Niigata?
Yes, that's correct.
DO you know Yoda Shousaku-san?
Of course, I know him very well.
My hatred for him knows no bounds.
Three years ago, while Yoda-san was still
teaching art at the same high school...
He had an illicit infatuation towards your girlfriend,
who was an English teacher at that same school.
One day, when Yoda-san took her for a ride against her will...
He got into an accident, and your girlfriend was the one who died.
That was not an accident.
Yoda disguised it as an accident while
in fact murdering my girlfriend!
And since a week ago, you've been staying at a
business hotel in front of Haido Station, right?
I heard rumors that Yoda lived around
here, so I came to find him.
Regardless, can you tell us your whereabouts
between 3:50 and 4:30 this morning?
Is it about my alibi?
I'm in luck then.
What do you mean?
You can confirm it with 119...
About when I called an ambulance.
An ambulance?
I was being careless.
I thought I accidentally ingested a button
battery when taking medicine tablets.
That's why I called an ambulance.
Well, turned out to be a normal button when
the doctors checked on me, so I was safe.
Pretty sure it was about 3:30 when they
transported me to the hospital.
And it was after 4:30 when they discharged me.
From that hospital to this park...
It'll take a good twenty minutes no matter how you rush.
Ask the hospital too.
If you do that, you'll definitely understand
that I couldn't have done it.
Please investigate carefully.
The person just now has an alibi of being in
the hospital between 3:30 and 4:30, right?
The method of drugging the victim to sleep...
Injuring his cheek with the clock hand in advance...
And finally killing him by hitting his head against the clock's number
stone after leaving the hospital sounds possible, though.
No.
While it may be possible given the time frame since his death
was estimated to be between 4:00 and past 5:00 AM...
The fact that they assured us the victim's cheek wound
was inflicted post-mortem nullifies your theory.
Is that so?
Plus, they said that traces of stone shards from
the clock were found in the laceration...
There's no doubt the scene of crime was here.
You know a lot!
Ah, no...
Uncle said so after he heard it from the police.
So you used Detective Mouri's voice again
to make the police officers talk, huh?
How about the paint on the victim's hands?
Anything characteristic about them?
Well, they said it was normal paint
that can be found anywhere.
Since he was a signboard maker...
There's no surprise that he had paint on his hand, now is there?
But they said he had been taking days off work.
So the fact that there were new paint marks raises a flag.
I see.
What's this door for?
Must be the clock's machine room.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
The chain lock securing the door was broken.
What does that tell us?
Hey,hey!
What are you kids doing there?
Someone broke the chain lock.
What now?
You're right.
Who could've done this?
This door leads to the clock's machine room, doesn't it?
That's right.
But during the flower clock's repair, we've installed
what we call "moveless drive units"...
It's a new type of drive system inserted directly in the hands.
So we emptied the clockwork in the
room and converted it into storage.
There's paint spilled on the floor.
It's the same color as the paint on the victim's hand.
It's dry.
So he didn't get the paint from here?
Hey, hey, how does it look inside?
Hey!
What's this?
Owww...
Are you all right, kids?
Conan-kun?
Young boy, let's go now.
Detective Conan Episode 631
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Did you figure out something?
Yeah.
Looks like there's no doubt that Kawaguchi guy is our man.
But he has an alibi, right?
The number stones are firmly affixed to the ground
so the crime scene was no doubt at the flower clock.
And the only time to cut his cheek with the long hand
without disturbing the flowers on the clock...
Had to be half past the hour.
But...
At 4:30, the only possible candidate, he just got out of the hospital.
Let's play on the seesaw now!
Genta-kun!
Are you all right?
Ouch, ouch...
I hit my head...
And you skinned your cheek!
I see!
It can be done this way!
Conan-kun!
Whatever, let's follow him!
Just as I expected.
Conan-kun, what's going on?
Did you find out something?
Yeah...
Hey, you guys!
What the hell are you doing there?
Uncle, you showed up at a good time!
Hurry on home and do your homework!
Well, Mouri-kun?
What's this you have to tell us about?
One of my drinking pals is friends with Yoda-san...
And he let me in on a surprising fact.
Surprising fact?
Actually, ever since Yoda-san fell from
mounting a signboard last month...
He's developed a serious case of acrophobia.
We already knew that ages ago...
Huh?
Then, the fact that he caused a traffic accident in his hometown...
And let a woman die in the process?
We've obtained information on that as well.
That woman was actually my girlfriend.
And you are?
My name is Kawaguchi.
Currently your prime suspect.
Am I right?
So the gang's all here.
Kawaguchi-san, why have you come?
Before I return to Niigata, I figure I should
pay Yoda's scene of death a last visit.
Ah, no, we can't let you go yet...
But, didn't you already confirm with the hospital?
So you know that I'm not the culprit, right?
I shall be excused, then.
Hold on a moment!
No, I didn't say anything...
Round 'n round I go...
Twirl twirl!
My line of questioning isn't quite finished yet, Kawaguchi-san.
So you're that famous Mouri Kogorou-san?
What more is there you need to ask?
Inspector.
Regarding Kawaguchi-san's alibi, can you recount it for me?
He was at the hospital the entire time
during 3:30 and 4:30 this morning.
And it takes twenty minutes from that hospital to here.
Simply put, I couldn't possibly commit the crime.
Then you could've come here at 5:00, right?
Even if I did come at 5:00, there'd be nothing to do.
Wrong.
You confined Yoda-san inside the flower
clock's machine room beforehand...
And arrived here at 5:00 to finish him off.
What's this?
Balderdash.
In that case, the cheek wound on the body can't be explained.
It so happens to be 5:00 now.
Twelve hours ago, Kawaguchi-san killed Yoda-san by smashing
his head against the number 6 stone on the flower clock.
And after cutting his cheek with the long
hand which was pointing at 12...
You put down his body near the number 6.
Without disturbing the flowers, how the heck
did I manage to walk near the number 12?
From where the number 5 is...
You could've stepped across the hedge and onto
the stone without deranging the flowers.
And while carrying Yoda-san's body in your arms...
You walked atop the hands of the flower clock towards
the tip of the long hand with it pointing at 12...
And wounded Yoda-san's cheek with the tip.
Then you retraced your steps by walking on the hands again.
Do you have evidence?
Prove it!
No use acting so tough.
What the flower clock saw was the entirety of your crime.
And it silently told me the truth.
What?
There are minute traces of blood on the stone near the number 12.
The stone and the clock hands weren't making contact to begin with.
But since you were stepping on it while carrying Yoda-san...
The hand warped down and touched the stone.
And the blood coming from Yoda-san's cheek
when you cut him traveled down the hand...
And got on that stone.
We should be able to match it with Yoda-san's blood after lab tests.
Even if that's the case, you still can't pin it on me for that.
If we investigate the surface of the hands, we should
be able to find traces that match your shoes.
Ignoring the short hand, for the long hand
to stay supported by that stone...
So that you.can step on top of it without crushing
the flowers, you only have one minute.
It'd be impossible for you to walk back
and forth and cut Yoda-san's cheek...
And wipe away your shoe prints in such a short time frame.
That's...
Kawaguchi-san.
You may not be aware of this, but Yoda-san
left a message indicating you're the culprit.
That's nonsense!
Conan!
Show the inspector the way.
Yes!
Come with me.
Ah, you too, Kawaguchi-san.
Are you sure Yoda-san's message is in here?
I can't seem to find it anywhere.
That's right!
What the!?
This is...
What was spilled on the floor was in fact fluorescent paint.
Since it's become dark in here, the light started to show.
What do you mean?
Uncle Kogorou said this.
Fluorescent paint will not glow in the dark
unless it was exposed to light beforehand.
Since it was dark in here the entire time...
It didn't glow during the time Kawaguchi-san
locked Yoda-san in; that's what he said.
I see!
He chose to enter and exit this place during
the night to avoid surveillance...
That's why it wasn't exposed to light even with the door open.
But where exactly is the message?
Right there.
This...
The culprit is...
Kawaguchi!
Yoda-san, who was being held hostage here...
Noticed the spilled paint and left his final message with it.
But unfortunately for him, it was the same color
as the spilled fluorescent paint on the floor.
That's why Yoda-san's message couldn't
be seen under bright daylight.
We shall investigate this room thoroughly!
We will definitely pick up evidence of Yoda-san's confinement
and traces of your breaking and entering!
Damn it!
And I thought it was a perfect plan!
This is...
This is just...
One week later than originally planned...
The opening ceremony for the flower clock finally took place.
"I shall put an end to your allotted time by way of a formless sword."
"From: The Guardian of Time."
Wait, say...
Isn't this letter threatening a murder!?
One of the clocks is slow by 0.5 seconds!
THE GUARDIANS OF TIME'S SWORD
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Six o'Clock
Speaking of 6:00 PM, it's the time when Detective Conan starts!
Excluding some locations.
Stay tuned!