"I am the Guardian of Time".
"And to the foolish woman who commits
blasphemy against time's flow...
"As punishment, in the instant you were born into this world...
"I shall put an end to your allotted time by way of a formless sword.
"From: The Guardian of Time."
Wait, say...
Isn't this letter threatening a murder!?
Yes...
Starting two years ago, we've been receiving this
letter every year as the mistress's birthday nears.
Oume Gakumichi (42)
Hoshina Family Butler
Always from an unidentified sender.
But since it started two years ago...
Does that mean nothing happened to the
mistress last year or the year before?
Yes.
We were able to complete both of her
birthday parties without incident.
However, because the mistress already
spoke about the letter to her guests...
The number of guests coming to the birthday
party has been decreasing each year.
And that's why you'd like me, Mouri Kogorou,
to uncover the sender of these letters?
Yes!
If possible, we'd like for you to come to
the mistress's 50th birthday party...
And perhaps even serve as a sort of bodyguard.
A quinquagenarian woman?
Nah, as far as bodyguarding goes...
We've prepared this amount to cover your retainer fee.
Case accepted!
Thank you very much...
Say...
What does the "blasphemy against
time's flow" part in the letter mean?
Who knows?
Wouldn't that mean to disobey or disgrace time?
Then, does that mean the mistress is really loose about time?
Oh, no.
It's...
Exactly the opposite.
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A threat that stops time...
Terror rampages during a birthday party!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
You're late by 2 minutes and 17 seconds.
Did we not agree to meet at precisely 1430 hours, Detective Mouri?
Well...
It's quite a long way here from the garage...
And it was raining.
Hoshina Rukako (50)
Head the Hoshina Family
Human life has a limit.
I make it a point to not waste even one second!
Also, Oume-san.
The clock in the study is slow by nearly one second.
Yes, ma'am!
I shall see that it is fixed at once!
I see.
She rules overtime as if she were the "Goddess of Time" herself.
Come now, Mistress.
Just as people need their days off...
Karube Teigo (45)
Architect
Wouldn't it be better to relax and allow your
clocks some time to catch their breath?
Well, clocks have no blood coursing through them...
Suou Chiaki (39)
Interior Designer
So they have no need for rest as we humans do, do they?
Wrong—they're the same as humans.
Just as humans need checkups, if we neglect
to occasionally inspect and oil our clocks...
They'll soon rust and find it hard to move.
Clocks continue working even as we humans sleep.
Furagaki Rinsaku (64)
Clock Technician
They wear down their gears as they indicate the time
and even their springs gradually weaken, you know.
Uhm, these people must be...
Karube-san, who planned this mansion...
Suou-san, who took care of the interior design...
And the one who constructed the great
clock attached to this house, Furugaki-san.
They are all guests for tonight's birthday party.
I only came to check on the condition of that great clock.
Your birthday part is merely an aside.
If you'll excuse me, I'll let myself in.
After all, I promised an old friend of mine that
I'd look after that great clock as long as I lived.
"An old friend"?
He's referring to a clock technician that I used to employ.
An impeccable gentleman who, until
his accidental death four years ago...
Took care of just about every clock in this mansion.
He was your elder brother, if I'm not mistaken?
Yes.
It was also my brother's recommendation that
permitted me to do the interior design here.
Oh, that's right, Mistress!
I happened to come across a rather fabulous carpet!
Would you care to see a sample?
Yes, later.
All right!
Well, everyone...
Let's not just stand here and talk—please come in.
I would be glad to take your umbrellas.
Thank you.
It is my pleasure.
Thanks.
Sure.
I'm good.
Mine's a foldable type.
Understood.
Here.
I shall take good care of it.
Still...
What an impressive number of clocks!
Indeed.
Did you purchase all of these yourself, Mistress?
Yeah.
My husband, who passed away from illness
last year, often complained about them.
He'd say it's as if he married a bunch of clocks.
Well, it is true that I am enchanted by clocks.
By these charming tick-tock sounds...
And the sounds that play when the long hands point straight up.
You're right...
It's quite magnificent when they all chime together.
Amazing!
It's so lively that I feel like I'm in an amusement park!
Oume-san...
Yes, ma'am?
One of the clocks is slow by 0.5 seconds!
What's the meaning of this!?
My sincere apologies!
I will see that it is fixed immediately!
If this is the case, make sure that the technicians are aware!
If all of these clocks don't chime at my exact birth
time of 6:00 PM, I will fire every last one of them!
Duly noted!
It's no surprise that only your brother
could be trusted to calibrate the clocks.
I hired as many as three people to fill his position after his death...
Yet each week I find that one or two clocks slow down.
But not the great clock that's attached to this mansion.
It's only been off a handful of times in the past ten years.
Well, it's only natural given that the maker of the
clock himself comes to maintain it each year.
Amazing!
This is quite an impressive sight.
I wonder what this door's for?
So this great clock also has a dial facing the backyard!
It's the man from before...
Why's he praying toward the well?
Because that's where the deadly fall took place.
My elder brother, who was the former clock technician here...
Was blown away by the wind while
repairing the dial on this great clock.
That well was here from before we rebuilt this house.
Since it's dangerous, I've arranged to have
workers come and fill it in next week.
Then, I suppose I'll go offer my prayers later.
Since he was a childhood friend of mine.
Then, please pass along,my prayers as well.
You're not going yourself?
You are his sister, after all.
I've already prayed at his grave this morning.
Since today is the anniversary of his death.
This is the date he died on?
He had an accident on the mistress's birthday?
Yes.
Well, we'll discuss the details in my room.
Since I would also like Detective Mouri to find
the sender of those threatening letters for me.
Yeah...
It was nothing.
So she never got to tell you anything about that accident, did she?
Right.
She did share a lot of detail about those who
held grudges against her at work, though.
Say...
The sender referred to themselves
as the "Guardian of Time," right?
What about it?
If that's the case...
Wouldn't a clock technician also be a guardian of time?
Then, are you saying one of the three currently
employed clock technicians could be the sender?
I'm just stating an example.
Bu if you put it that way...
A woman so strict about time is more befitting
of the title "Guardian of Time," isn't she?
Oume-san, it's about time.
As you wish.
It's caught my interest for quite some time...
Would you mind me taking a look at your gold watch?
Here, be my guest.
Very nice.
My!
The silver pocket watch you had before was
lovely, but this one suits you as well, Mistress!
It's a one-of-a-kind timepiece specially
ordered from a Swiss craftsman.
Having been replaced on a whim and then relegated to
rusting in a drawer, I feel sorry for the previous watch!
You need not worry about that.
Since that watch...
Is no longer in my possession.
It broke, so I got rid of it.
No way...
A blackout?
Damn!
What, so it's just for blowing out
the candles on the birthday cake?
Hold on, what's the meaning of this!?
What?
What's the matter?
Did someone flee out the window!?
What was that just now?
The lights!
Someone turn on the lights!
Detective Conan Episode 632
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
I see.
As she was blowing out the candles on her birthday cake...
And soon after the room became dark...
Someone stabbed the owner of this mansion,
Hoshina Rukako-san, in the chest with a weapon.
Then, within a matter of seconds, with the weapon
in tow, and before the lights came back on...
They fled though a window looking
out over the backyard, you say?
Yes.
Please take a look.
At the blood splatter on the ground
from when the mistress was stabbed.
See the area here where the blood was obstructed?
This is proof that someone was standing here when
they removed the weapon used for stabbing...
And became drenched with a large amount of blood splatter.
But then, disregarding the fact that some guests in this
room do have some amount of blood on them...
Not a single person was splattered with blood to that extent.
Moreover, there are traces of blood that appear to have rubbed
against the window frame and the balcony handrail.
The culprit, drenched in blood, fled through that
window, and there's no doubt about it, Inspector!
But, Mouri-kun...
If that were the case, something that should be present is missing.
This is the second floor.
It had been raining until the evening
and the ground had been muddy.
They should've been distinctly left behind.
The culprit's footprints, I mean, from when
they leapt from this balkony and fled.
That's impossible!
It's coming down again...
Uhm...
Is it true that the culprit didn't leave behind any footprints?
Yeah...
Then, could it be that the sender of that threatening letter was...
The clock technician who passed away four years ago!?
Moron!
How would a dead person go around sending letters?
But...
Wasn't the sender's name the "Guardian of Time"?
And isn't a clock technician also a guardian of time?
What's this about a threatening letter?
It seems they've been delivered
to the victim for the past two years.
In the instant you were born into this world...
"I shall put an end to your allotted time by
way of a formless sword," said the letter.
In the instant she was born into the world?
It seems 6:00 PM earlier in the night was
the same as the victim's time of birth.
And every year she also blows out the candles at precisely 6:00.
And so?
Did the clock technician who died four years
ago hold a grudge against the victim?
I don't know the details, but...
It seems he died in an accident on this
exact day, the mistress's birthday.
He didn't just die.
He was killed!
By that cold-blooded woman who ruled over
time as if she were some kind of goddess!
There was a terrible storm that day.
That clock technician was doing repairs on the dial
of the great clock while attached to a lifeline.
But the gust buffeted him so much that he fell
into the well at the foot of the great clock.
But that was an accident, wasn't it?
Yeah...
It would've been just an ordinary, careless accident.
If only she had delayed the start of her birthday party...
And gone to search for the clock technician!
Then, she went ahead with the party
even though someone was missing?
Yeah.
Thanks to that, it wasn't until the next
morning that his body was found.
According to the police, it appeared he
drowned to death during the party.
Due to the well having water inside.
Well, if someone else had gone to look for
my brother, he might have been saved.
Once the party started, things got extremely busy...
There wasn't any time left to find someone...
l-lnspector...
A-Apparantly the one who held the deepest grudge against
the victim was indeed that dead clock technician...
Hey, you...
I knew it!
The culprit was that person's ghost!
T-That's why there weren't any footprints!
If that's the case, that ghost sure had bad eyesight!
Because, take a look!
At the mistress's necklace.
It glows in the dark.
Fluorescent paint must be on it.
It was done so that they would know exactly
where the mistress was, even in the dark.
Hey!
Who touched the necklace?
During the party, she allowed many people to touch it.
Because this birthday party was also the unveiling
of the new accessories the mistress had bought.
Come to think of it, she also showed off and
had people touch her golden pocket watch.
Then...
The guest with fluorescent paint on
their fingers is the culprit, right?
Well, if I were the culprit, I'd have
already washed it off in the restroom.
Would've been nice if we could narrow it down to a
few people with the fingerprints on the necklace...
But I believe many people touched it.
That's so dumb, Uncle!
Ghosts wouldn't leave fingerprints if they touched something!
Because, they can float through the air like wind
and flee without anyone having seen them!
You're the dumb one!
There's no reason a ghost would have to deliberately use
fluorescent paint in order to stab someone in the dark!
But then...
There weren't any footprints from anyone having fled, right?
If it wasn't a ghost, then the culprit...
Must have made it seem as if they had
escaped but is still here among us, right?
I-I see!
Someone planted blood on the balcony
railing and the window frame in advance...
And made it seem as if they had
opened the window and fled outside!
Moreover, the fact the culprit hasn't gone outside means...
The long, sharp weapon akin to an ice
pick used to stab the victim's heart...
Might still be hidden somewhere on their person!
Then, if you would please allow us to take your statements
one by one in a separate room while we search your persons.
Now hold on!
How do you explain the blood splatter?
According to what you said, shouldn't a large
amount of it have been sprayed onto the culprit?
He's right.
Without that problem being cleared up, I wouldn't
care to undergo questioning or a body search.
I agree.
Why are they searching us when we're not suspicious?
Isn't that rude?
Come now, it's just for the sake of being thorough.
Excuse me, but I've got matters to attend to, so I'll be leaving.
Then, me too.
Me too.
H-Hold on!
Everyone, please wait.
You understand, right?
A person has just died, you know?
Everyone had come today in order to
celebrate the mistress's birthday.
And if the culprit who killed her might be among us...
Wouldn't it be right to cooperate with the police?
Otherwise, the ghost of the clock technician
as well as my childhood friend...
Might end up being made out to be the culprit.
So you're the architect...
The name's Karube.
I designed this mansion.
You have blood on your hands and your shirt cuffs.
It must have gotten there when I rushed to
the mistress's side when she collapsed.
But there's no blood on me other than that, is there?
Yes.
And, did you notice anything at the time of the crime?
Come to think of it, I think I heard a sound
like cloth rubbing together approaching us.
Maybe the culprit was a woman in a dress?
By the way, the tip of that pipe of yours...
It looks long and sharp to me, so would you allow us to examine it?
Of course.
Hold on, you're way out of line!
While it's true the clock technician who
died four years ago was my brother...
And that I'm likely to have the strongest motive...
But that was just an unfortunate accident.
I held no grudge against the mistress!
But...
You were in charge of the mansion's interior design, Suou-san.
As such, you could have set up any number of tricks.
The same could be said of Karube-san the architect,
and Furugaki-san who constructed that great clock!
But probably not Furugaki-san, who's getting on in years.
How come?
After the culprit stabbed the mistress, they moved
quite nimbly and brushed up against my left side!
So here, you can see traces of blood
having rubbed off on my left arm, don't you?
By the way, what's that you have stuck in your hair?
An ornate hairpin my brother bought me a while ago.
Would you mind if we examined it?
Check it to your heart's content!
But you have return it to me later!
Yes, ma'am...
It's not like those in historical dramas.
There's no blade inside!
It seems that way.
It was you, wasn't it?
The clock craftsman who constructed that great clock.
Yeah, I'm Furugaki.
It seems that you have a little blood
that flew onto your right shoulder.
I guess it was because that woman was stabbed to the right of me.
It looks like an extensively well-used cane.
Have you been using it for a long time?
Yeah.
It's a cane that the clock technician we
spoke of earlier gave to me ten years ago.
And for your information, I think the
culprit was a pretty plump fellow.
I was pushed right before that women let out a scream.
By a soft, springy body.
The culprit should be among the people in the grand hall back then.
Who in the world is this culprit that considers
themselves the "Guardian of Time"?
Next Episode
I see, I've got it!
That "Guardian of Time" really passed through here...
At the time of the crime!
Dad?
Round and round I go...
I was indeed on the verge of falling...
Into the cunning scheme...
Set up by the culprit snickering in this very room!
THE GUARDIAN OF TIME'S SWORD
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Clock Hand
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Ran, I've got it!
The culprit is the Time Stopper!
Stop that hack deduction!