A threatening letter from the Guardian of Time.
The letter warned that the mistress of a
clock mansion, Hoshina Rukako-san...
Was to be murdered during her birthday party.
We were invited to the party, along with Uncle,
who had taken up the job of her bodyguard.
Still, as the chime indicating 6:00 PM sounded,
she was murdered by a person unknown.
The culprit used a sharp weapon akin to an
ice pick to stab Rukako-san in the heart...
And then apparently fled from the balcony.
But the baffling part was, on the ground wet from the rain...
There wasn't even a single footprint left by the culprit.
Four years ago, during the birthday party at Hoshina Manor...
Someone also lost their life.
A clock technician fell as he was repairing the great clock...
The search was delayed because of the party, and he died.
Ran trembled at the thought of the Guardian of Time
being the ghost of the clock technician, but...
No, that's not it.
I shall definitely unravel their true identity!
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
The real culprit that reigns over time...
Let's solve the mystery of the invisible murder weapon!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a chi d and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
So you're the architect...
The name's Karube.
I designed this mansion.
You have blood on your hands and your shirt cuffs.
It must have gotten there when I rushed to
the mistress's side when she collapsed.
But there's no blood on me other than that, is there?
Yes.
And, did you notice anything at the time of the crime?
Karube Teigo (45)
Architect
Come to think of it, I think I heard a sound
like cloth rubbing together approaching us.
Maybe the culprit was a woman in a dress?
By the way, the tip of that pipe of yours...
It looks long and sharp to me, so would you allow us to examine it?
Hold on, you're way out of line!
While it's true the clock technician who
died four years ago was my brother...
And that I'm likely to have the strongest motive...
But that was just an unfortunate accident.
I held no grudge against the mistress!
But...
You were in charge of the mansion's interior design, Suou-san.
As such, you could have set up any number of tricks.
The same could be said of Karube-san the architect
and Furugaki-san who constructed that great clock!
Suou Chiaki (39)
Interior Designer
But probably not Furugaki-san, who's getting on in years.
How come?
After the culprit stabbed the mistress, they moved
quite nimbly and brushed up against my left side!
So here, you can see traces of blood having
rubbed off on my left arm, don't you?
By the way, what's that you have stuck in your hair?
An ornate hairpin my brother bought me a while ago.
Would you mind if we examined it?
Check it to your heart's content!
It's not like those in historical dramas.
There's no blade inside!
It seems that way.
It was you, wasn't it?
The clock craftsman who constructed that great clock.
Yeah, I'm Furugaki.
It seems that you have a little blood
that flew onto your right shoulder.
Furugaki Rinsaku (64)
Clock Technician
I guess it was because that woman was stabbed to the right of me.
And for your information, I think the
culprit was a pretty plump fellow.
I was pushed right before that woman let out a scream.
By a soft, springy body.
It's true that I weigh 78 kilograms and am slightly overweight, but...
Does that have any bearing on the case?
No, it's just for our records.
By the way, Oume-san...
Regarding this knife found next to the cake...
We found your fingerprints on it.
Oume Gakumichi (42)
Hoshina Family Butler
Of course you did!
It was my duty as butler to cut the cake after all.
Say...
After the flames from the candles were out
you didn't turn the lights back on immediately.
How come?
That's because the mistress didn't give me the signal.
Usually, right after they're blown out,
the clocks would chime for 6:00 PM.
And after they finished chiming, the mistress would
snap her fingers as a cue to turn back on the lights.
But at that time, the clocks didn't chime immediately, did they?
Right...
But the three clock technicians monitoring the clocks that
were supposedly behind said they all chimed on time.
Apart from that...
Even though you were right by the mistress's side, you
don't have even one drop of blood splatter on you!?
Isn't that because the culprit had a large build?
That's why the blood splatter didn't reach me.
Someone in a dress who moved nimbly,
yet is plump and of a large build...
Was there such a person among the guests?
No.
We checked all of the 65 guests who came to the party,
but there wasn't anyone matching that description.
And, there were no guests possessing anything
resembling a weapon, is that right?
Yes.
And I was told there was no luminol
reaction on the belongings of those four.
In short, like that threatening letter said...
The murder might as well have been carried
out using a "formless sword," then?
It sure seems that way...
Say...
About the blood on the handrail and window
frame, was it all from the mistress?
Yeah.
I don't know how they were able to obtain the
mistress's blood before the crime, but...
If they wanted to make it look like they fled through the window...
They would've had to plant the blood beforehand.
But, isn't that strange?
If they're making it look like they fled from here...
Rather than making these rubbed-of blood marks, it would've
been more convincing if they had left clear, bloody footprints.
Who knows?
Maybe they thought if the marks were too clear, the jig
would have been up before the crime even started?
Hey, hey!
Midnight already?
I see, so this room was directly below that great clock.
No, that's not it!
These blood marks weren't made beforehand!
That "Guardian of Time" really passed through here...
At the time of the crime...
And all according to plan!
The results from everyone's body search...
Showed that no one had hidden a weapon on their person.
In addition, it seems no one had been covered
in a large amount of blood splatter, so...
We'll wrap things up for today, and conduct
more thorough interviews at a later date.
Well?
No objections, right, Mouri-kun?
Yeah.
It seems instead of the mystery of the missing weapon...
If we consider the fleeing from this balcony without
leaving any footprints behind as some sort of trick...
It would be for the best.
Dad!?
Round and round I go again...
Twirl, twirl!
Watch out!
Oh no!
What do you think you're doing, geez!
You were about to fall!
True.
I was indeed on the verge of falling...
Into the cunning scheme...
Set up by the culprit snickering in this very room!
Then, the culprit really is someone here?
Now look here, Mouri-kun.
Although it's intriguing that the culprit's
footprints were absent below the balcony...
It's unthinkable that the culprit could be someone here!
Then...
Allow me to reconstruct the crime at once.
Reconstruct?
Yeah.
It'll take a short while to prepare, so if the inspector and
guests would please leave the room for a few moments.
Just how long do they expect to keep us waiting?
It seems the young detective and the butler
have been in and out quite a few times now.
I wonder if they'll really be able to prove it?
How to stab someone without getting blood splatter
on them, and how to dispose of the weapon...
Geez, going so far as to shut even me out of the room...
He'll really get it if this turns out to be another worthless deduction!
Thank you for waiting!
We have finished our preparations, so if
everyone would please enter the room!
Oh, Inspector.
Inspector, please hang this around your neck.
Isn't this the flashlight watch that Conan-kun's always wearing?
Yeah.
We're having you play the part of the murdered victim...
Meaning this will take the place of the
necklace covered in fluorescent paint.
It doesn't seem like much has been changed.
Yeah.
The only thing that's different is that boy with
glasses standing in front of the closed window.
I don't know what you're up to, but out with it already.
What's going on?
We're recreating the scene as it was at the time of the crime.
First, the lights in the room were turned off
and the cake was brought here, right?
Yes.
All right, Inspector.
On my cue, please blow out the candles as the victim did.
Three...
Two...
One...
Go!
Who was that!?
Who just hit me in the head with a stick!?
Hey, hey, what's with this experiment?
It's useless even if you open the window and pretend to have fled!
Since I saw the stick used by whoever hit me!
That means the one who still has the
stick is definitely the one who hit me!
Sorry...
The one who hit you, Inspector...
Was me.
Don't talk nonsense, Conan-kun.
For,starters, you're not even carrying a stick!
There's no reason I would be.
Since the stick I hit you with
flew away and disappeared out the window.
What?
Is that true?
That the stick flew over here?
Yes.
But, what flew over here wasn't a stick.
It was an umbrella pulled by a string.
An umbrella?
Hey, is it true?
Yes.
This umbrella.
Well now, it took quite a while to prepare this.
I had to ask the butler for a long string...
Then ask the clockwork technicians to set the great
clock ahead so that it read 6:00—the time of the crime.
The clock?
What's all this about?
This is how the trick worked.
First, prepare a long string and tie a weight in the middle of it...
And on one end of the string, install a slippery, ring-like object.
Then attach that ring through the gap in the
decorative tip of the great clock's hour hand...
As you dangle the end with the weight so that
it goes over the handrail of the balcony.
Next, you pass the other end of the string through
the gap in the window and into the room.
Wait until the room's darkened for
blowing out the candles on the cake...
And then tie the string in the room onto the
umbrella handle to complete the preparations.
Afterwards, as when Conan hit your head
with the umbrella seconds before 6:00...
A few seconds later, the great clock's
hour hand would face straight down.
The ring on the string would fall
out from the gap in the ornament.
Meanwhile, the dangling weight would fall as the umbrella
was pulled to force its way out the window...
And it fell from the balcony.
And thus, its disappearance from the room is complete.
Now look, Mouri-kun...
The weapon and the weight weren't on the ground below.
And first of all, wouldn't someone have
noticed the presence of the string?
In that case, let's say the string is a fishing
line that's thin and hard to see...
If we inserted the weight in the middle of that line
into the lattice of the well below the great clock...
Wouldn't that work?
I see!
The murder weapon pulled by the
weight would be sucked into the well!
Yeah.
Since the well is scheduled to be filled two weeks later,
the weapon would never again seen the light of day.
Then, why wasn't the culprit drenched in the blood splatter?
That reminds me...
Wasn't there a lot of testimony about the culprit's description?
That the culprit was of large build,
plump, nimble, and a woman in a dress.
In fact...
Those were all descriptions of the weapon.
The weapon?
It seemed to be nimble because the blood-soaked weapon
flew out the window as a result of the trick just now.
It was thought to be of large build because the
weapon covers quite a large area when expanded.
And it was said to be plump since you'd feel a springy
resistance if you were pushed by the weapon...
Given that the weapon was covered in cloth, you could
hear a rubbing sound resembling the fabric of a dress.
What on earth is this weapon you're talking about?
The same thing I hit you with, Inspector.
It's this!
An umbrella?
See, if the culprit attached a sharp weapon
with something like a screw to this tip...
They could have stabbed the mistress and pulled it out...
Without getting blood splatter on them, no?
Right, Uncle?
But, but...
This happened during the party!
If someone carried an umbrella in, wouldn't it stand out?
No, it could be smuggled in on the culprit's person.
Karube-san...
It was your foldable umbrella, to be exact!
But, Mouri-kun...
While using an umbrella as the weapon
could prevent the blood splatter...
It would've been a hassle to fold the umbrella later, wouldn't it?
That's right...
There wasn't enough time to do that between the
mistress's scream and the start of the great clock's chime!
Folding it could have been done instantly.
Just close the umbrella without
worrying about blood on your hands...
And cinch it up with a rubber band or
something along those lines on your wrist.
I see...
That's why both of Karube-san's
hands have so much blood on them.
Correct.
As the last person to close the small
window on the great clock dial...
You were able to set up the line trick on the hour hand...
And by saying you were going to pray at the well afterwards...
You could've pulled the line lowered to the ground toward
the well, as you tied the weight while pretending to pray.
Next, as the architect who designed this mansion...
You would've found it easy to estimate how much line you needed.
And by holding the mistress's pocket
watch before your crime, you could...
Set the time a few seconds ahead, and between the mistress's
blowing of the candles and the chime of the great clock...
You were able to use the short interval to commit the crime!
But wasn't Karube-san the who said
he heard the rubbing sound of fabric?
If he were the culprit, would he say something
so closely linked with an umbrella?
He purposely said it.
He purposely threw in a true fact in order to mislead us...
Into thinking the culprit might be a woman in a dress.
Had he told a complete lie, he'd be the only one
to testify differently than the other guests...
And would've appeared suspicious.
But...
But didn't Karube-san stop the guests when they wanted to
leave without cooperating with the police investigation?
Saying we should assist the police for the late mistress's sake!
I think he would've just left if he were the culprit!
That's right.
Even if he had wanted to leave, he couldn't have.
Because the rain suddenly started up again.
The umbrella he carried when he first came here had
been used as the weapon, and was then in the well.
If he had just left, the fact that he no longer had
the umbrella he should have would be revealed.
How careless of you.
If only you had anticipated such a
thing and brought an extra umbrella...
No, I did place an extra umbrella into my bag, but...
It seems my wife unfortunately took
the extra umbrella out of my bag.
Since a note saying, "Isn't one umbrella enough?" was inside.
Well, since it was raining like I'd been waiting for...
I wasn't able to curb my impatience and neglected
to double-check, and that was my mistake.
You say you'd been waiting...
So ever since two years ago when
the first threatening letter was received...
You'd been planning this murder?
Yeah...
If it's raining, the lack of footprints from the
fleeing culprit can be explained away...
And since no one will go out to that roofless balcony,
I wouldn't have to worry about having my trick exposed.
Although, when the rain stopped right
before my crime, I did get a bit nervous.
So, you admit to the crime?
Yes.
Since the umbrella that fell into the wall will be covered
with the mistress's blood and with my fingerprints.
But, why?
Why did you kill that woman?
Because I wanted to avenge my childhood friend,
the clock technician, who died because of her.
Is that reason enough?
But, didn't you say it at my brother's funeral?
That it was an unfortunate accident?
Yes.
I did let myself believe that.
Until I heard that woman's conversation on the day of the funeral.
Hold on, what's the meaning of this?
How come you still haven't found a replacement clock technician?
I sincerely apologize...
Whenever I think of the late clock technician,
I can't bring myself to look for a replacement...
Haven't I already told you!?
Broken clocks must be thrown away and replaced with new ones!
Isn't it the same with clock technicians!?
How cruel...
He was a man who loved clocks more than anyone...
So you're working here as a clock technician?
Yeah!
But are you doing all right?
Isn't the mistress here really strict about time?
It's fine, it's fine!
That makes it even more worthwhile!
And since I arrived, not a single clock has had to be thrown out!
After all, these clocks here have my spirit
inside, and are just like my family!
We're all doing our best!
Big brother...
Maybe...
Instead of avenging him...
It was more like I wanted to rescue them.
From the Tyrant of Time...
His so-called family...
Clocks.
They're necessary partners in our daily
lives—it's an inseverable relationship.
But, once in a while, they lose time.
Genta-kun, you're late!
My bad!
My alarm clock was acting up!
Don't tell me you're still using that old clock?
Yeah!
Since I got it from my late grandma...
I might get cursed if I throw it away!
But if it's your precious clock, then cut it some slack.
Since clocks don't rest even when we sleep, and
work nonstop with that tick-tock sound...
Regardless, Edogawa-kun sure is late.
If we don't leave soon, it'll be night
by the time we get to the campsite!
I bet he's still asleep!
Tick, tock, tick, tock, tick, tock...
Hostess!
Please bring each of us some drinks!
My, my.
Sir, aren't you a generous one!
I think Dad recently frequents this area to get his drink fix.
To think he's able to drink sake in such a smoky place!
So this means someone among the customers killed the hostess.
THE SUPER NARROW SHOP CRIME SCENE
Next Conan's Hint is...
Glass
Our next story has a Shouwa vibe?
There's no screen time for you!
This Great Detective will be on a roll!