Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A bistro with a Showa Era atmosphere...
A cunning trick a place without elbow room!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Come in!
We have special discounts!
Nakamura Susumu (64)
Company Employee and Horse-Racing Fan
Geez...
The main race was an outrageous upset!
Aww, out-of-the-money!
Ougi Chihiro(35)
Japanese Dance Instructor
I can't possibly win thanks to that giant-killin' underdog!
Any chance you guys bet on the Touto Derby?
Loyal customers who love horse
betting often come here on Saturdays.
We always come here soon after a race ends.
And talk about who wins or loses.
I see.
So that's how it is.
To tell the truth, I'm also a bettor!
Huh?
Please let me take a look.
Here you go.
Shinohara Masao (25)
Freeter
Trifecta on numbers 1,2, and 3?
Aren't these today's winning tickets at 100-1 odds!?
What was that!?
That's exactly it!
Wow, you're really lucky, mister!
Since the cat's out of the bag, the lucky yours
truly shall treat everyone here tonight!
But, these tickets...
Hostess!
Please bring each of us some drinks for starters!
My, my.
Mishima Satsuki (50)
Hostess
Sir, aren't you a generous one!
Nah, you're flattering me.
Uhm, what was that just now?
Oh, you mean this?
Just a little help.
Since my shop's so narrow...
I find it easier to move about on this.
See?
I see...
I wonder whether or not Lady Luck will knock on my door as well?
Aren't you getting your retirement allowance soon?
Retirement allowance?
Oh, no...
It's not all that much.
Say, say...
Why not splurge that money and take me to Awaii-hay!
Hey, hey.
Oh my, quite a luxurious player, aren't you?
Mr. Moneybags.
If that's the case, instead of some cheap sake...
Why don't I get you something more high-class?
No, I'm good.
Why don't you go to Shounan Hawaiian
Center or something like that instead!
I guess.
Each year I'd visit the hotel over there...
And hold a presentation on the spot.
So that may be a good idea.
Yo, let the show begin!
What presentation?
I'm a Japanese traditional dance instructor!
Geez.
Whenever you're drunk, you always go overboard like that.
Since you're going as far as to hold presentations...
Certainly your academy business must be blooming, I assume?
That can't be the case.
Once during her presentation, she accidentally
slipped and did a split while falling down.
An academy with such a lousy instructor can never bloom!
Dont'cha go ahead and recite that sort of nonsense!
Presentations, huh?
It's a wonder some people never know their place.
Say what!?
I dare you say that again!
You sure that's wise?
Talking back to me like that.
Now, now, calm down.
Looks delicious!
Yeah.
After I left my hometown and came here,
this is the bistro I happened to run into.
Now it feels completely like Mom's cooking.
This guy wanted to be a top restaurant chef so
bad, he left home for Tokyo if memory serves.
There's a saying that goes, "Dreams may'shatter, but whatever."
Are you still working at the fish market I introduced you to?
Yes... thanks to you...
Hostess, you're good at taking care of people.
If you want to be a chef, you need to train
your/eyes to discern quality fish.
Right?
Shinohara-kun?
It's been great training for me.
I see, so that's why you took on the fish market job.
That reminds me, why are your pants all wet like that?
This happened when I was walking on the street earlier...
And the hostess "happened" to splash water on you with a bucket.
How'd you know that?
So you did that again?
You can't tell right from wrong at all.
It's a trick you always use to reel in the lucky horse
bettors who'd won a little cash to spend.
If you keep this up, divine punishment will ensue.
Stop badmouthing the hostess already!
I couldn't get any job offers after I came to Tokyo...
But she helped me out when I was about to lose hope.
She's my savior!
Now, don't get all worked up like that.
I've been feeling a strong chill for a while now.
My apologies.
The walls are plywood patched with iron plates...
So wind will come in through this gap.
This chill's getting me too, so I'm going to the restroom.
Now, stand up and make way already.
Lady's coming through.
No room to swing a cat here—can't help it.
Now that we've gotten our asses up, I
might as well go buy some cigarettes.
I need to withdraw some money before the ATM closes.
I'll take a puff too.
Tobacco,tobacco...
Huh?
Did I put it in here?
I think Dad recently frequents this area to get his drink fix.
To think he's able to drink sake in such a smoky place!
Isn't that Uncle?
You're right!
You're taking a puff at a place like this?
Huh?
What're you guys doing here?
So everyone's returned, huh?
What?
Hostess!
Hostess, please hang in there!
What!?
And that was a summary of this case.
The single stab in the chest from this knife was her cause of death.
On the handle of the murder weapon...
There's the bistro's trademark "Satsuki".
All the knives in the hostess's shop...
Apparently have that particular symbol on them.
We did not find any signs of rummaging in the bistro.
We can assume this was unlikely a crime for gain.
By the way...
Why are you here, Mouri-kun?
Oh, yes...
Since I won the long shot, I bought dinner
for all the regular customers here.
Looks like someone's having lots of fun.
Oh, no, it's nothing like that...
And, at the time of incident, everyone including
me had stepped outside the shop.
I see.
So the hostess was all by herself in the shop.
And due to those frosted glass stripes, nobody
can see what's going on from the outside?
Right.
Which means the only ones who knew the
hostess was alone were these customers.
So within five minutes after everyone's departure...
Someone amongst the customers killed the hostess?
All right, let's hear what the customers have to say.
What do you mean, you want to question us?
Judging from the circumstances of the scene, it's highly probable
that someone among you three committed the crime.
Stop spewing nonsense!
As such, during the five minutes around the incident...
What were your whereabouts and actions?
Please tell us in detail.
That reminds me, at that time...
Even after everyone else left the shop, only
Ougi-san failed to do for quite a while.
Perhaps Ougi-san...
Purposely waited for a chance to be alone with the hostess?
Why'd I have to do something like that...
Don't tell me, you've been borrowing from the hostess
since your academy was on the verge of closing?
What the...
That hostess always puts on a smile when lending..
But rumor has it she would turn into a demon upon collections.
I see.
So did you really borrow money from the hostess?
Yes.
Recently she's been demanding me
to pay my debt, almost every day.
When I was about to leave the shop earlier,
she again pressed me to pay up today.
So you flew into a rage and picked up the knife at the counter...
Wrong!
The argument became pointless, so I stormed off like a shot!
But then the hostess ended up dead...
So I merely found it hard to mention all that.
Ah-le?
This person's sleeve looks kind of wet.
I see!
If I recall, you're a southpaw, aren't you?
When you were drinking wine...
Using the fan...
And pinning the tack, you used your left hand.
The reason why your left sleeve is wet...
Was because you washed off the blood in the restroom
which you got from stabbing the hostess, no?
The water faucet in the restroom was broken
and the water sprayed up, that's all!
As a precaution, let the medical examiner
test her for a luminol reaction.
Roger.
Excuse me, this way please.
By the way, Nakamura-san.
What is it?
After you said you were buying cigarettes and left the shop...
You turned right on the street ahead.
However, I was certain that you came from
the opposite direction upon return.
Even though the cigarette vending machine's down here...
Why did you return via the opposite direction?
That's...
Because the vending machine's out of cigarettes...
I went all the way to the convenience store on Big Street.
Oh, Inspector.
We've discovered the hostess's notebook...
And it shows that Nakamura-san has been
making monthly payments of 100,000 yen.
This is too much of a payment for a drinking tab.
What kind of money is this?
No, that's...
Actually, the hostess got hold of my secret.
Secret?
I've been embezzling money from my company
to lash out on horse-betting...
And she blackmailed me saying she'd break
the news to my company if I didn't pay.
But I didn't kill her!
I really walked to the convenience store on Big Street!
By the way, Shinohara-san.
Yes?
In this notebook, we've found records
of your name, Shinohara-san...
And fish names like "horse mackerel" or "squid".
What are these?
Since I'm working part-time at a fish market...
Sometimes I receive orders from her.
I guess that's the record of those?
What were you doing within the five minutes after you left the shop?
Since I didn't have cash on me, I went
to withdraw some at a nearby ATM.
Here's my receipt.
Here.
The time confirms it.
After Shinohara-san stepped out of the
bistro, he walked towards Front Street.
Since the ATM's right here, it's impossible
for him to secretly return to the shop.
Given that there are no inconsistencies on his ATM receipt...
It seems impossible for him to have killed her.
If I recall, Uncle said he bought dinner for everyone.
What's in the knife stand are all Japanese kitchen knives.
This is...
Juice?
He mentioned the hostess was a non-drinker.
A brandy glass?
This hasn't been used.
The brandy bottle has been...
I see.
I've figured it out.
The trick to this case!
Hey, hey, dozing off during an investigation?
Well then, might as well attach my mini speaker now.
Conan-kun!
You can't just wander around like that!
Got it...
Inspector Megure.
According to the test results, no luminol reaction
could be detected from Ougi-san's clothes.
Moreover, we also confirmed with
the convenient store on Big Street...
That Nakamura-san was indeed there to make a purchase.
Guess I don't need this today.
In that case, everyone...
Please come to the station for further questioning.
Inspector, there's no need for that.
I shall solve the case right here on the spot.
Mouri-kun, have you figured out who the culprit is?
Yeah.
The brandy glass left on the cutting board...
Clued me in to the culprit's identity.
Brandy?
Please pour me a glassful, Inspector!
Damn it, he freaking woke up!
Are you all right?
I'm all right.
Never mind me, go check out the bistro counter.
Ougi-san had wine.
Nakamura-san.had Japanese sake.
I had beer.
Shinohara-san.had some sour mix.
What's more, on the cutting board you can see a
glass of juice the hostess had been drinking...
And a brandy glass that hadn't been used at all.
What's wrong about them?
About that brandy glass...
I wonder who that was for?
None of us customers ordered brandy
before we stepped out of the shop.
That's indeed out of place.
Look at the highest place of the shelf.
You can see the brandy bottle on the shelf has been moved a little.
It's likely the culprit, after going out the shop,
made a phone call from the outside...
And placed an order for the fancy brandy on the shelf.
Perhaps telling lies about that expensive
beverage being a treat from me.
In order for the short hostess to reach the brandy...
She had to stand on her tiptoes by
leaning against the shelf and wall.
The culprit used the chance and pushed
the knife through the gap in the wall...
Are you saying they stabbed her from outside the shop?
At the back of the shop, there's a dark alley
that allows passage of one person.
And the wall made of plywood patched with iron plates...
Has a thin gap on it.
The culprit made a phone call in the back alley...
Lured the hostess near the wall...
And inserted the knife in the gap and killed her.
The knife was presumably stolen from the shop beforehand.
However, when we discovered the hostess...
She was lying flat on the counter facing us!
That's right.
If she was stabbed near the wall, she
wouldn't have collapsed like that!
The hostess's chair is the type that can
turn around in a narrow counter...
A swivel chair.
Ironically, the force from the hostess's collapse
exerted on the chair caused it to turn...
And she fell on the counter facing the front as a result.
But since the knife has a handle...
Shouldn't it be unable to go through the wall gap?
Takagi-kun, how goes it?
Well...
The handle is blocked out.
What if the handle wasn't on the knife?
What was that!?
The chef's knives we use in preparing Western
cuisine have rivets attached on the handle...
But Japanese knives simply have blades inserted in their handles.
Very easy to pull apart.
Inspector, it's just Hike what Mouri-san said!
So that means...
The culprit allowed us to discover the body...
While walking behind the counter, pretending to be worried.
And then slipped the handle back on the blade...
At the same time holding the hostess up.
Don't tell me...
Really!?
Right.
The person who had the need to deploy
the trick using the plug-fit knife...
Had to rush to her first.
Shinohara-san.
It was none other than you!
But I was at the ATM...
That's right.
He has an alibi.
No.
If the crime was committed at the back of the shop...
The ATM would've been surprisingly close.
His alibi means nothing.
If we're talking about Shinohara-kun who's
aiming to become a top restaurant chef...
It's possible that he knows well about the fact
that Japanese knife handles are removable.
Do you have solid evidence confirming that I did it?
The envelope of the receipt you showed us earlier.
I saw smudges on it.
That's iron rust, isn't it?
During the crime, it's likely you were holding the knife blade
without its handle in your hand with a handkerchief.
As such, the rust on the wall's iron plate got on your handkerchief.
Without noticing that, you put the handkerchief back
into the same pocket where the envelope was.
So the rust got on it.
If we compare the iron plate and the envelope rust...
I guarantee that we will confirm a .
But, why?
Wasn't the hostess your savior?
Hell no!
The reason why that woman introduced
me to the job with a kind facade...
Was because she could use me to steal produce from the market!
What was that?
At first she merely asked for leftovers or damaged fish meat.
But then her greed escalated...
Recently she even pesteringly demanded me to bring her
free high-end produce like sea urchins and salmon roe!
I couldn't take it anymore!
When I told her I was going to quit my job...
if you quit, I will expose everything you did so far at the market.
When that happens, you'll go to jail for theft.
But that was per your instructions, Hostess...
Well...
Where on earth can you find solid proof
hat I instructed you to do so?
You're the only one who'll get caught.
Well, since you can't possibly become a top chef after all...
That's probably better for you.
I could never bring myself to abandon
my dream of becoming a top chef!
That's why!
However, you used a knife, equivalent to the lifeline of a top chef...
As a weapon for murder.
As such, you are...
No longer qualified to become a top chef, am I wrong?
Huh?
That reminds me, Dad...
Didn't you say you won the long shot?
Huh?
Aren't those all 100 yen tickets?
Even though I won the long shot, the payoff wasn't
much since I only wagered 100 yen each...
But since vanity got the best of me,
I shot the works and am all broke!
Forgive me!
I won't forgive you!
Pretty please!
Wait up!
Will he be able to gallop away from this?
Let your body soak in its energy to the fullest.
Why do I have to go on a yoga diet too?
The lawsuit was against me...
Atsuko-san lost her lawsuit...
And must've been deep in shock.
What is?
Since lack of sleep is bad for your body's beauty...
I'm going to solve it right here and right now.
BEWARE OF DIETING
Next Conan's Hint
Microwave
Merry Christmas!
Whay the haste? Still too early for that!
Viewers, let's meet again around then.