The sun is almighty.
Let your body soak in its energy to the fullest.
Don't be so stiff...
Free your mind and body more instead.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah...
Why do I have to go on a yoga diet too?
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
I too participated in some diet training...
Featuring scary battles between women!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
Hiss name is: Detective Conan!
Yoga Diet Training Studio
As expected of Ran!
To think you were able to win free invitations to the yoga studio favored by celebrities!
Even so, you still had no reason at all to bring me along...
All right!
In two days and one night, I shall reclaim my nice body!
Don't strain yourself too hard all of a sudden.
Satoyama Tsukiko (34)
Training Studio and Instructor
If you hurt your body, you'll get absolutely nothing out of it.
OK!
Cookie
Training Studio Idol Dog
Nevertheless, what an impressive yoga studio this is!
Uhm, what exactly does "Chandni" mean?
In the Hindi language, it actually means "moonlight".
Just like "tsuki" in your name, Tsukiko-san.
Yeah.
Taking in the energy of nature...
And staying healthy both physically and mentally.
My parents that also operated a yoga
training studio named me after that concept.
That concept has since been acclaimed
by everyone, enabling me to go this far.
I'm truly grateful for that.
Well, our dishes are also quite popular.
Despite all being low in calories, our menu range is wide.
Limori Kaoru (29)
Chef
All of our vegetables are home-grown and organic.
Not to mention they taste really good!
My, is that really the case?
Degawa Atsuko (26)
Diet Training Participant
Like the pretentious chef, the dishes looked decent but tasted awful!
What the?!
Hot!
What the hell is this!?
My tongue is all burnt!
Do you plan on bringing this trash out and
getting fired like at the previous restaurant?
Fired?
Herdal tea, unlike Japanese tea, requires hot water to serve.
In that case, warn me first!
Or I'm gonna post lots of stuff on the internet
about how I was treated poorly here!
If do that, I bet your reputation will plummet!
That's...
Atsuko-san...
Inomata Yasuko (26)
Atsuko Friend
You didn't have to go that far...
As the daughter of some pathetic employee,
you've got the nerve to talk back?
That's right.
Why don't you bow down to me?
I can consider forgiving you if you do.
What the!?
I'm truly sorry for the inconvenience.
Tsukiko-san...
I'll have you know...
This is not coercion but a reasonable suggestion!
No matter what happens, always consider how to
offer our customers the most pleasant experience.
Could she be the daughter of Degawa Corporation's president?
I've heard rumors about her being an incorrigible complainer.
Hello?
Well?
Everything end well?
What the hell!?
You lost the lawsuit!?
The hell are you doing!?
The lawsuit was against me, so what do I do if you lose!?
Huh?
You want to cease representing me?
Fine.
But don't ever think you'll be able to
continue as an attorney like before.
Keep that in mind!
Don't ever let this idiot of a dog near me!
Say, say, did someone sue Atsuko-san over her complaints?
Yes...
To tell the truth, there are many more...
I bet she's suffering deep in her heart.
Let's leave her alone for now.
Yes...
Looks delicious!
So true!
Here, welcome to our Chandni's famous buffet.
Pick whatever you like.
Yes!
But, be mindful about not exceeding
your personal calorie allowance.
Also, please enjoy your meals in your own rooms.
If you compare your meals with each
other and feel stressed over that...
It'll have a bad influence on your mind and body.
This food wrap is all empty!
Bring me a new one this very instant!
My sincerest apologies.
Pretty nasty woman as usual.
Maybe she's just forcing herself to put up a front.
Well, I don't care either way.
Now then, since I have an allowance of 600 kilocalories...
"Lightly pickled Queen-of-the Night," huh?
Root Vegetable and Herd Stew
This smells so good!
I'll get this one!
I'll try this out too!
Wait...
This one has a larger serving, so I'll take this!
All serving sizes are the same.
If so, it shouldn't be a problem even if I exchange in, no?
Sorry for the wait.
My calorie allowance is only enough for me to eat one dish!
But you're here with the purpose of going on a diet.
Wow...
The clouds have broken and the moon's out.
The moon is imbued with strong cleansing power.
It's also good for our beauty, so why don't we do yoga right now?
I despise the idea.
I don't want to eat my meal cold!
Now, please don't say that.
You can heat your food in your room even when it gets cold.
And if you work hard...
As a reward, you are welcome to have
a helping of these strawberries.
I'll make an exception and join, then.
All right, everyone, please place your meals in
your rooms and gather in the yard soon after.
You're going out?
Yeah.
I'm going to our patch to pick up some vegetables for tomorrow's breakfast.
Now, bathing under the moonlight...
Everyone, please allow your minds to be purified.
Atsuko-san...
How the hell am I supposed to do this!?
I quit, I quit!
Atsuko-san?
What is it, you guys are so noisy...
I'm gonna have dinner right now, so don't bother me.
That's right, this is covered in my sweat...
So go wash it!
Yasuko-san, are you all right?
I'm fine, don't worry about me.
Hey, everyone.
Did something happen?
No, nothing much.
Now, let's call Yasuko-san and resume our yoga session.
What is that?
Yasuko-s...
Thank you very much!
Atsuko-san and Yasuko-san both didn't show up after all.
Yasuko-san?
What's the matter?
I just went to Atsuko-san's room to check on her, but...
Her door was licked, and she didn't reply.
Well, I'm concerned.
I'll go check on things, so feel free to
drink some tea in the dining room.
OK.
There, there.
What's wrong?
Detective Conan Episode 635
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
The victim is Degawa Atsuko-san, age 26.
Cause of death is cyanide poison found in this vegetable stew.
It seems the contents of the small bottle
on the table matches the same poison.
The estimated time of death?
Between 6:30 PM and 7:30 PM.
That's between when Degawa-san quit yoga to the
discovery of her body, found thirty minutes ago.
Atsuko-san...
Upon discovery of her body...
The door and window were locked from the inside, is that correct?
Yes.
No doubt about it.
The key to this room was found in the body's pocket.
The spare key was inside the combination safe.
Satoyama-san took it out and brought
it here in order to unlock this room.
A suicide...
Atsuko-san lost her lawsuit...
And must've been deep in shock.
That's why she...
What do you mean by lawsuit?
She was a notorious complainer, you know.
Complainer?
But she got sued over that, and it seems
several lawsuits had been filed against her.
This afternoon, her attorney called her...
And it seems her case had been lost.
She stayed in her room the entire afternoon.
I bet she was pretty down at that time.
So does that mean the pain of losing her lawsuit
got the best of her, prompting her suicide?
Ah-le-le?
The strawberries are topped with condensed milk.
You're right, she must've snuck it in without permission.
To think she'd forgotten to take a bite out
of her dessert, isn't that kind of weird?
Conan-kun...
A person with suicidal thoughts isn't mentally stable.
Thing like this do happen.
Atsuko-san was sued by many others...
People hated her...
She must've taken it really hard...
That reminds me, Kaoru-san...
Didn't you also get fired from the restaurant you
worked at due to one of Atsuko-san's complaint?
Limori-san, was that true?
It was, but...
That doesn't mean I was the one who poisoned her.
Not to mention dinner was self-service.
There's no way I could've known which dish
she would choose from the variety of dishes!
That's true.
Moreover, that person snatched away the bowl Ran was having.
Then, what did you do after Degawa-san
put down her meal inside her room?
I went to the patch which is a ten minute walk...
And picked up some vegetables for tomorrow morning.
After that, I stayed in the kitchen the entire time making preparations.
No doubt about it.
I saw her working in the kitchen the whole time I was in the yard.
Now do you see?
It wasn't me.
Suppose she pretended to go to the patch...
But in fact secretly returned and administered the poison - something like that is...
Isn't it true you were also able to gain access to the key in the safe?
What the?
Kaoru-san, don't tell me you---!?
You're the one who's pretending to be friends with her...
But in fact you loathed her to the bone, didn't you?
We saw you earlier.
You were trampling on her clothes in the laundry room!
Did that really happen?
Yeah...
But I was doing yoga with you guys, wasn't I?
And during our break, I was in the laundry room the entire time.
But after everyone resumed their yoga session...
You had the chance to go to her room without being noticed, right?
And then you poisoned...
I didn't do such a thing!
By the way, Satoyama-san, how about you?
I was practicing yoga with everyone.
She was with the entire time.
My apologies!
I'll grab it now.
Hey, Cookie, wait up!
Gotcha.
Now, now, calm down.
Poor thing's probably really scared.
I'll clean this up for you.
Clean up?
Not here.
The thing that's supposed to be here.
There, there stay put for a while.
I see, I've got it!
The truth behind this case!
Well then, please come to the station for further questioning.
OK.
Sonoko, don't tell me...
All this humdrum is making me fall asleep.
What is?
Since lack of sleep is bad for your body's beauty...
I'm going to solve it right here and right now.
What now?
First, Kaoru-san...
Looks like you still haven't noticed, but
there's a yellow smudge on your shoulder.
That's pollen from Queen of the Night, right?
Epiphyllum oxypetalum
Queen fo the Night usually blooms after dark...
And its flower life will end shortly within a single night.
Its pedals are also edible food materials.
We had "lightly pickled Queen of the
Night" on our dinner menu, right?
Which means you actually did go to the patch
to pick some Queen of the Night flowers.
Since the yellow pollen wasn't there before you went out...
Yet you had some on your clothes when you returned.
Conan-kun apparently witnessed that.
Yeah, I remember it clearly!
And Yasuko-san...
You're not the culprit either.
Even if Yasuko-san had gone to Atsuko-san's
room and administered the poison...
She wouldn't have been able to lock it from the outside.
Since the room keys were in Atsuko-san's pocket and Inside the safe.
If that's the case, it was a suicide after all?
Can't we just leave the deceased alone to rest in peace?
See, the moon is beautiful.
As if it were mourning over the dead.
No.
The moon does not mourn over the dead.
What it does is shine light on the truth.
Tsukiko-san...
The truth is you were the one who murdered Atsuko-san!
Sonoko-san, what do you...
Tsukiko-san...
The reason you had to lure Atsuko-san with strawberries
to make her do yoga under the moonlight was...
Because it was necessary for her
to place her dinner in her room.
Even if I did make her put her dinner in her room,
I still had no time to pour poison in her food!
That was irrelevant.
Because the poison ended up mixed in with the food
spontaneously, thanks to a certain action by Atsuko-san.
What exactly do you mean?
Ran, try to recall the events.
When we went to her room out of concern...
What was she doing at that time?
Let's see...
Since I heard a microwave chime going off...
I think she was heating her food.
Right.
At that time, she likely covered her bowl with food wrap.
But this is strange.
I couldn't find the supposedly thrown-away used food wrap.
Come to think of it, there wasn't any.
But what about it?
You all have experience with this, right?
If you microwave food with plastic wrap...
The steam will condense into many droplets on the wrap...
And drip down onto the food.
What if we assume the poison was laced on the plastic wrap?
I-I see!
Tsukiko-san...
You applied posion to a segment of the food wrap beforehand...
Allowed it to dry, and rolled it back to the original position.
Then, no matter which dish Atsuko-san took...
You could posion her by creating a situation
in which microwaving were required.
Interesting deduction, but...
Didn't I hand her a new roll of food wrap in front of everyone?
How was I able to poison the wrap?
That was also part of your scheme.
You wanted to show us that you had indeed
exchanged a new roll of wrap for her.
But I tore apart the strip and gave it to her!
I couldn't have done anything fishy!
If you take a food wrap box and open its side tab...
You can remove the roll without removing the strip.
I see.
Well?
The moonlight yoga and the exchange of food wrap...
Were all part of the calculated plan you had come up with.
Do you have proof that I did it?
For starters, the poisoned food wrap you're
talking about is nowhere to be found!
But of course.
Because you already hid it in a certain place.
Where was it?
Tsukiko-san...
Why did you bring Cookie, who was told not to
ever go near the victim, with you to this room?
That's...
That's because you needed to retrieve
the used wrap laced with poison...
And hid it in Cookie's pocket.
Inspector Chiba, check inside Cookie's pocket now!
There it is!
When you came into Atsuko-san's room
with the excuse of checking on her...
You quickly planted the poison bottle in the room...
Placed the used wrap in a plastic bag...
And hid it inside Cookie's pocket.
But to a dog with a keen sense of smell, the odor of the
poison was hard to endure even while inside a bag.
An upset Cookie started to run around...
Causing you to lose the chance to dispose of the wrap.
Yes.
I am the culprit.
Tsukiko-san...
Why?
Three years ago, the training studio my parents operated...
Was forced to shut down because of that woman's complaint.
They were deeply in debt thanks to her,
and committed suicide afterwards.
No way...
These three years since my parents died...
I sweated blood and exerted all available
effort to establish this Chandni.
But a week ago, that woman called in for a reservation.
That bitch didn't even recognize who I was.
And then she said...
I heard rumors that celebrities started frequenting your place...
But if you can't manage to please me, I'll tear your studio down!
I couldn't forgive her!
I wasn't about to let that kind of bitch
mess around with my Chandni!
That's why I silenced her...
Her mouth which spewed out nothing but complaints...
For eternity...
Days Later
Yummy!
As expected of Ran.
To think you've won a prize of all-you can eat desserts this time!
Exercise a lot and enjoy the pleasure of eating.
Both are important, right?
Well said!
Don't complain when a huge weight rebound hits...
Next Episode
I shall gladly accept your invitation to appear on your show.
...They're asking Dad to appear on "The Most
Useful School in the World" show as an instructor.
It's Principal Sakai!
And Vice Principal Ueda!
Class President Arita is also here!
About How much do you think vase is worth?
I'll give it an estimate of around 160 million yen!
It's an amazing treasure that would cause
even Kaitou Kid's face to turn blue.
THE MOST USEFUL SCHOOL IN THE WORLD CASE
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Puffed Rice Maker
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Our next story sets the stage in that popular show!
A TV show? I want to be on it!
Please don't.