Yeah.
Yes.
Of course I do.
Yeah.
Yes.
I see.
Understood!
I shall gladly accept your invitation to appear on your show.
Yeah, that's right.
Say, Ran-neechan...
What show?
About that, they're asking Dad to appear on "The Most
Useful School in the World" show as an instructor.
Wow, that's amazing!
For real?
Isn't "The Most Useful School, in the World" one
of the most iconic shows on Nichiuri TV?
And may I inquire how much my appearance fee would be?
Well, that sort of amount is a little bit...
He's planning to refuse?
Okino Yoko-chan will appear as one of the guest panelists?
I'm in!
I'll do it!
Please allow me to participate!
Appearance fee?
Ha, I won't be needing that sort of thing!
Dad...
Looks like they're one step ahead.
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
Uncle Kogorou will appear as a lecturer on that popular show?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Is this too gaudy after all?
Perhaps Yoko-chan would like the necktie I usually wear better..
Nothing will change no matter which you wear.
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop dilly-dallying, hurry up and come!
Yes!
My apologies, Sensei.
Isn't that the leading figure in the enka realm, Kimijima Noburou?
Enka is a genre of music that resembles traditional Japanese ballads.
It's true!
Kimijima Noburou (67)
Leading Figure in Erika
But he looks kind of frightening and strict.
Kimijima Noburou is not only strict to others,
but is also famous for his self-discipline.
That's why he's still dominating the top seat in the realm of enka.
Pretty supportive of him, aren't you, Uncle?
Kamisuwa Mikihiko (52)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Well, Mouri-san!
It's been a longtime
Kamisuwa-san!
it's been a while since Hiroshima.
Is your injury all healed?
Yeah, completely.
I'm counting on you for today, Mouri-san.
Yes!
I assume our staff member has already informed you about it, but...
We would like Mouri-san to deliver a lecture on ways
to protect yourself against all the crimes around you.
Yeah.
Just leave it all to yours truly, Mouri Kogorou!
Mouri Kogorou-san, right?
It's a pleasure working with you today.
Likewise.
Hashimoto Yoshinari(22)
Assistant Director
I'm the assistant director in charge, Hashimoto.
This is your green room.
Feel free.
Allow me to introduce...
This is our instructor for the first period, Mouri Kogorou-san.
And that is our instructor for the second
period, Yamazaki Tetsushi-san.
Nice o meet you, I'm Mouri Kogorou.
I'm Yamazaki.
Glad to meet you.
Puffed rice maker?
Is puffed rice still available out there?
Yeah.
Yamazaki Tetsushi (32)
Puffed Rice Maker Company President
I have taken over the company my father left me.
And it's still quite popular among children these days.
I'll show it to you later as well, kid.
And here we have,our third period instructor, Honma Kentarou-san.
Nice to meet you, I'm Mouri Kogorou.
I conduct appraisals for antiques, and the name is Honma.
Honma Kentarou (70)
Antique Appraiser
Unfortunately, I am not the type who carries name cards.
My apologies.
Uhm...
I can't seem to see Okino Yoko-chan anywhere.
It's because the green room for our guest
panelist is on the floor below us.
Is that so?
There's no way she'll be placed in the same room as you, is there?
Well then, I shall call you guys again
when it's time for our rehearsal.
Please enjoy your boxed lunches until then.
I see, so Yoko-chan's green room is on the floor below...
I shall go and greet her now.
You're taking your lunch?
Yoko-chan's green room is...
Hold it, Dad.
Why are you taking your lunch with you if you're going to greet her?
What do you think?
Of course it's because I plan to have lunch with Yoko-chan!
It wouldn't taste as good if I had to eat with those fellas.
I knew you were up to something like that.
Then again, we seem to have followed
suit and brought our lunches as well...
Yes.
Understood.
Uhm...
I'd like to ask you something.
Where is Okino Yoko-chan's green room?
Aren't you Conan-kun?
Takikawa-sensei!
Who is he?
Someone you know?
Yeah.
He's a friend of Professor Agasa and also a college professor.
Takikawa Youji
College Professor
I'll be attending a meeting for a program now.
Conan-kun, what brings you here?
Since Uncle Mouri is going to appear in "The Most
Useful School in the World" filming today...
I'm tagging along.
Is that so?
Uhm...
Okino Yoko-san still hasn't arrived yet.
Is that so?
Well then, please do your best.
So Yoko-chan hasn't come yet?
Regardless...
Shouldn't you go and greet Principal Sakai before that?
You're right.
In that case, I'll get to it now.
Taking your lunch with you again?
Have a look at this.
Sakai Masaaki
"Principal"
This is quite a work of art.
Splendid, don't you think?
Regarding this vase, it was made in China back in the Qing Dynasty.
Qing Dynasty?
That's right.
This vase was made in the time when Qianlong, the sixth emperor
of the Qing Dynasty and an art enthusiast, reigned.
Come on in.
Hi there.
I'm Mouri Kogorou.
I dropped by to say hi, Principal Sakai...
My apologies, but can that wait?
We're having an important discussion right now.
So Kimijima Noburou is also a guest panelist for today's filming?
Pardon the intrusion then.
But actually, we saw you as well earlier, Kimijima-san...
And we were just talking about you.
I bet they weren't pleasant things, right?
On the contrary!
To tell the truth, the first record I bought when I was still in
elementary school was that famous song of yours, Kimijima-san...
"A man must have guts, so bring it on!"
Oh, that song?
I see you have quite a pair of trained eyes.
So Uncle's a fan of Kimijima Noburou, I see...
Kimijima-san...
It's almost time for my meeting now.
Is that right?
Hey, do you like vases?
Well everyone, I shall see you later.
Yeah.
That guy's going to talk all day and night, so be warned.
OK...
See you all later.
Now, come with me.
You know, that song is a wonder!
I can feel the true spirit of a man!
Isn't that right?
Despite the warning, these two sure hit it off well with each other.
Please let me help.
Shinobu!
Do not make the guests worry about you!
Hurry up and make the tea!
Oki Shinobu (25)
Kimijima's Disciple
I am terribly sorry, Sensei...
Sorry about that...
By the way, regarding that vase...
About how much do you think that is worth?
I'm going to have Honma-sensei do an
appraisal on that in today's lecture.
Who was Honma-sensei again...
Ah.
That appraiser who seems unapproachable.
It's true that Honma-sensei may be a difficult person.
However, on the subject of appraising relic
antiques, his keen eyes are tried and true.
See, wasn't there a hack appraiser with the name Hanamura or
something who was behind that case involving Kaitou Kid?
They're like the difference between heaven and hell.
In fact, the ceramics and porcelain in this era
are especially popular among connoisseurs.
The estimated value for this ranges from
100 million to 160 million yen, or so I think?
100 million!?
That high!?
A vase like that...
No, I mean that vase is worth 100 million!?
Come to think of it, recently at auction in the United Kingdom...
Another vase also from the Qing Dynasty like this one got auctioned
off for an equivalent of 5.7 billion yen, according to the news.
So it's an amazing treasure that would cause
even Kaitou Kid's face to turn pale.
But then again, that guy should have
no interest in something like a vase.
So this is where they film "The Most Useful School in the World"!
It's just like on TV.
That's a given.
However, this place is surprisingly tight.
They say things appear to be more spacious on TV.
That's right, Dad.
They've given us the script for today.
I don't need something like that.
You don't need it?
So that's a puffed rice maker?
Let's see, the second period of lecture is...
"Experience the fine traditional puffed rice maker!"
"Rice, wheat, and corn kernels will turn into snacks with a pop!"
So it says.
How exactly do you make snacks using this machine?
You need to stay tuned for that.
I bet you'll be surprised!
So this is a puffed rice maker...
If I recall, its formal nomenclature is "grain expander".
Pour grains such as raw rice in the rotating pressure chamber...
And the machine will puff them via rapid decompression
and turn them into a snack.
This is the first time I've seen the actual machine.
Well, if it isn't Honma-sensei?
I trust to do your best today.
The third period of class is...
"Ascertain real or fake—a history of counterfeiting
and modern technology of replica".
We've gone the extra mile and prepared real and fake antiques...
And asked Honma-sensei to give a lecture on their differences.
The items lined up over there are all counterfeits
prepared by Honma-sensei.
And the artifact is one Kimijima-senseq brought.
It's this one.
What do you think?
Quite a work of art, right?
This is...
If you'll allow me.
Remarkable...
Where did you get this?
Well, well, Honma-sensei.
I can see it caught your eye.
Apologies, Honma-sensei, please appraise it when we're rolling.
Well then, we would like to use these
three as examples of counterfeits.
Understood.
So that's how it was...
That's why Kimijima-san bothered to go as far
as to bring his proud vase to the TV station.
Principal Sakai and Vice Principal Ueda...
And Class President Arita have arrived!
How do you do; the name is a Sakai.
I look forward to working with you for today.
Ueda Shinya
"Vice Principal"
I'm Vice Principal Ueda.
Nice working with you.
Arita Teppei
"Class President"
I'm Class President Arita.
It's a pleasure to meet you!
Oh, no, the pleasure is all mine.
Nice to meet you guys.
Tsuchiya Daisuke (45)
Director
Now, if everyone is ready to begin...
I would like to start the rehearsal right now.
Let's start with the first period...
The lecture from Mouri Kogorou-san.
Good morning!
Yoko-chan!
It's really the Okino Yoko!
Huh?
Yoko-chan, you don't have to come until
the rehearsal for second period.
I know.
But when I read the script in the green room...
I learned that Mouri-san is the instructor for or first period .
Does that mean -!?
You took the trouble just to see yours truly!?
No...
I'm just here to say hello...
Let's get to the rehearsal!
For starters, what should I begin with?
In that case...
To kick off...
Shall we start with your performance
corner on the art of self-defense?
A big ten-four!
Dad's really giving it his all!
I hope he doesn't give out too soon during rehearsal
Conan-kun, you guys also came?
Yeah.
We're observing.
Since I rushed here in a hurry, I'm all sweaty.
Hey, excuse us!
Don't you think it's rude to take sneak pictures without permission?
No, I'm just...
Hey, bastard!
You took sneak shots of Yoko-chan!?
Dad...
I'm sorry...
I'm a fan of Yoko-chan, so I couldn't help...
If you're a fan, watch your manners all the more!
He did it...
As a grown man, how insolent of you
to take peeping photos of an idol!
Be ashamed!
But still...
You didn't have to go and break it!
Screw it all!
I'm going home!
Wait...
Please hold on!
Now, now...
Yamazaki-san, calm down.
Yoko-chan, we'll handle this, so please wait outside.
All right.
Mouri-san, please continue with your rehearsal.
Got it.
Kimijima-sensei, please do us a favor.
I'll buy you a replacement cell phone.
Learn from this lesson and stop taking pictures
of other people without permission.
I'm truly sorry for this...
Idiot!
No need to apologize!
Damn...
Kimijima-san's vase and three counterfeit items...
And what we still need is...
Hey, they say there's an awesome relic vase on display?
Lemme take a look!
You can't!
This 'un?
Wow, this is epic!
Lem me touch it...
Hey, you can't just go ahead and take it out!
It'll be fine. it'll be fine!
Just lemme feel it little!
You'll be in trouble if you touch it with bare hands!
Just a little, just a little!
We shall proceed to the rehearsal for second period.
Now, Yamazaki-san, would you please begin.
Yes.
Geez. that Kimijima-sensei is a handful.
Although we managed to restore Yamazaki-sensei's mood...
It was a close shave since we almost couldn't film.
Well, I guess that guy who took photos
in secret was in the wrong too.
Then, I'll go ahead.
Huh?
Honma-sensei, where are you going?
I'm not interested.
Saying things like that...
But the truth is he's actually scared, no?
Scared?
Well, Okino-kun, go ahead with the hammer.
Got it!
Please strike on this with full force.
What's this?
Well, just keep watching.
Ran-neechan, I think it'd be best if you covered your ears.
I'm asking what this is about!
All right, here comes!
That was scary...
Well, that's how it goes.
But wait, you knew about it, Conan-kun?
Yeah...
Since I've watched it on TV before.
That was some shocking noise.
It sure surprised me.
Me too.
Uhm...
I want to apologize for saying unnecessary things in the green room.
Because of me, you were scolded by Kimijima-san, weren't you?
It's all right.
Please don't give it another thought.
Don't make me repeat myself!
Yeah!
I said there's nothing to worry about, didn't I?
Although Sensei is a strict person...
I still have complete respect for Kimijima-sensei.
Something is troubling her, right?
You see, since my "Okino" and her "Oki" are similar names...
Somehow we feel a sort of close bond between us.
We even talk to each other sometimes when we're at the same set.
Say, is Oki Shinobu-san a disciple of Kimijima-sensei?
Yeah, that's right.
She said that the name Oki Shinobu was given to her by Sensei.
I see.
That's why I thought her name sounded like an enka singer.
However...
Although she's working harder than everyone
else in order to make her debut...
Her effort is not paying off.
She also mumbled last time about how she should give up
and go back to her hometown if she really has no talent.
Is that so...
Kamisuwa-san!
Something's gone wrong.
What is it this time?
What!?
Kimijima-san's vase is missing, you say!?
The vase from the Qing Dynasty is missing?
We're in deep trouble...
It seems nobody saw anything...
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
During the rehearsal of the first period, I swear it was still right here.
Isn't that right, Arita-san?
Yeah...
Why would you know something like that?
Oh, no, just a bit...
What the heck is the meaning of this?
Somebody must have stolen my vase.
No, we can't determine that just yet...
Who was it!?
Who stole my vase!?
Principal Sakai!
Don't tell me you did it!?
W-W-Why me?
When I showed my vase to you...
Didn't you express a great deal of interest!?
Sensei, please calm yourself down!
If we assume someone did steal it...
There shouldn't be anyone who could have carried some a container
with a vase hidden in it-out of the studio during rehearsal.
Which means the culprit is still in this studio.
And the missing Qing Dynasty vase should
also be somewhere in this studio!
I have a request, Mouri-san!
I'm sure Mouri-san can find the vase without fail!
Of course I will!
That man is definitely hiding something from us.
Please do excuse me.
He know something else?
As for today's filming, we'll call it a day here.
Hold on a moment!
Before we call it a day, let's wrap up the case.
THE MOST USEFUL SCHOOL IN THE WORLD CASE
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Loud Sound
We'll try our hands at an experiment on how to make things disappear on "The Most Useful School in the World" show later tonight!
Watch it or lose out!