On the iconic show "The Most Useful
School in the World" from Nichiuri TV .
Uncle was scheduled to make an appearance.
While visiting the TV station where
the filming would take place...
The prominent enka singer, Kimijima Noburou-san,
who was also appearing on the same show...
Showed off his proud vase to us.
While the appraisal of his vase was
to be conducted during the show...
According to Kimijima-san, it was valued at over 100 million yen.
However, that vase suddenly disappeared during the rehearsal.
Could it be that someone stole it?
If that was the case, the culprit would have to be in this studio...
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
Surfacing from that popular show is the
mystery of the sudden missing vase.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Will you hear me out, Kimijima-san?
Since the beginning of the rehearsal, I
haven't stepped out of the studio at all.
Well, not just Principal Sakai.
During the rehearsal, no one carried any personal belongings...
Large enough to tuck a vase in, out the studio if I'm right.
Kamisuwa Mikihiko (52)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Anyway, let's split up and search
carefully in the studio one more time.
It's still nowhere to be seen.
Tsuchiya Daisuke (45)
Director
So it really just vanished like that...
Vanished?
It's not like it's a magic vase.
There's no way it could have vanished on its own!
Kimijima Noburou (67)
Leading Figure in Enka
That's a vase from the Qing Dynasty with
an estimated value of 100 million yen!
Someone got dazzled by its worth and hid it
away with the intent to steal it, no doubt!
Now, now, we can't be sure about that at this point.
The sudden disappearance of an item...
That reminds me, last week Takikawa-sensei
conducted an interesting experiment in his lab.
A fake flower placed on top of a pot filled with rice...
Disappeared all of a sudden.
The truth was, a hose was inserted from underneath the flower pot.
When air was pumped out from it, the rice
grains about floated with a swoosh.
The force supporting the flower plummeted in an instant,
causing the fake flower to sink into the rice.
That's why it looked as if it disappeared...
But that trick is not applicable to this case.
As such, someone among us has to be the offender.
I have a request, Mouri-san!
Once and for all, can we rely on the great detective
Mouri Kogorou's deductions to flush out the vase?
Please kindly lend us your strength again!
But, even if you say so...
It'll be alright!
I'm sure Mouri-san can find the vase without fail!
Of course I will!
Roger then!
The great detective Mouri Kogorou...
Shall definitely recover Kimijima-san's
vase for you to see without fail!
Leave everything to me!
Will Dad be all right after blowing up a huge balloon of confidence?
Well, guess the show's on the road.
Now, according to the testimony of the
assistant director Hashimoto-san...
Hashimoto Yoshinari (22)
Assistant Director
Up until the rehearsal for first period was concluded...
The vase was definitely still there.
Yeah.
Since I was checking the props.
Ah, I also witnessed the vase at that time.
That said, if we assume somebody did steal that vase...
They would've had to do it during the second period rehearsal.
While we were paying full attention to the
puffed rice maker, they seized the opportunity...
Stole Kimijima-san's vase, and hid it
somewhere in this studio as quick as a wink.
However, we've searched high and low
just now and still couldn't find the vase.
Wrong.
There is still a place we haven't searched yet.
Yamazaki-san...
Let me ask you one thing.
Yamazaki Tetsushi (32)
Puffed Rice Maker Company President
What is it?
Regarding that puffed rice maker case...
You were the one who checked its content, weren't you?
Yeah...
Are you sure we won't find Kimijima-san's vase inside that?
Hold on a moment!
Are you suspecting me now?
Yamazaki-san...
You have a motive.
During my rehearsal for the first period, when
you were taking secret pictures of Yoko-chan...
I'm sorry...
I'm a fan of Ydko-chan, so I couldn't help...
If you're a fan, watch your manners all the more!
Kimijima-san, furious at your taking pictures
of Yoko-chan without permission...
Snapped your cell phone in half.
Holding a grudge against him for that, you went ahead and stole
Kimijima-san's vase in order to get back at him, didn't you?
What nonsense!
If you say so, why not show us what's inside your case?
When I was testing my puffed rice maker,
I remained in the set the entire time!
How on earth did I have the time to steal the vase!?
That's precisely where the blind spot is.
At that time, I believe nobody kept their
eyes on Yamazaki-san the entire time.
So why didn't he do the hammering
himself instead of asking Yoko-chan?
Everyone's eyes were fixed on the puffed rice maker in that instant.
As such, I believe no one was able to
witness Yamazaki-san's whereabouts.
That's just your assumption!
Uhm...
The reason why I did the hammering...
Was because it was written on the script.
Hey, hey, wise up, Uncle...
That's why we've been telling you to at least read the script!
But...
The fact that Yamazaki-san took photos of Yoko-san
without permission left a bad impression on you, Dad...
So you jumped into conclusions, didn't you?
You idiot!
I'm not as narrow-minded a man as you may think!
That man is definitely hiding something from us.
I have no doubt about it.
Guess I shouldn't be surprised that Uncle noticed it too.
What are you doing?
At any rate, we should be able to find
out once we see the inside of that case!
Yamazaki-san...
I'm sorry to ask this, but could you let us take
a look inside your case as a precaution?
That...
But...
Understood...
That's...
Mine...
Huh?
Yamazaki-san.
Would you care to explain what this is about?
I'm sorry!
My impulses got the best of me...
It was indeed as Mouri-san said, I was furious
because my cell phone was snapped into pieces.
As a grown man, how insolent of you
to take peeping photos of an idol!
Be ashamed!
But still...
You didn't have to go and break it!
Screw it all!
I'm going home!
Wait...
Please hold on!
After that...
I noticed the handkerchief Yoko-chan was using fell on the chair.
So I thought if I auctioned off the handkerchief and a
photo of Yoko-chan using it as a set over the internet...
I could maybe sell it for a high price to fans.
Bastard!
Screwing around like that!
Hold it, Dad!
Calm down!
But, wasn't the photo in question unusable since it was
destroyed by Kimijima-san along with the cell phone?
I bet he set it so that photos will be saved in a microSD card.
By doing this, his photos will remain
intact even if the cell phone is not.
I'm sorry...
This is a problem too, but for now we
need to focus on Kimijima-san's vase.
Where on earth did it vanish to?
Ah-le?
Honma-sensei, where are you going?
Honma Kentarou (70)
Antique Appraiser
What's the matter, Honma-sensei?
Nothing's the matter, but...
If problems keep surfacing like that, I'm sure
the filming for today is called off, right?
No, we haven't decided on doing that just yet.
I have a busy schedule.
Please do excuse me.
Please wait, Honma-sensei.
My apologies, but before you leave...
Would you mind showing us the contents of that large baggage?
Honma-sensei!
Are you the culprit?
How about it?
Honma-sensei!
You were pretty intrigued by that vase.
Remarkable...
Where did you get this?
Well, well, Honma-sensei.
I can see it caught your eye.
Plus, during the puffed rice maker demo...
Huh?
Honma-sensei, where are you going?
I'm not interested.
Didn't you leave the set all by yourself?
Are you saying I'm the culprit just because of that?
I merely think it's possible to conceal a vase
in baggage like that and nothing more.
I see.
Are you satisfied now?
Not there...
My vase is not there!
I apologize for doubting you.
No, it's true that if one carries such large baggage
out of the studio, suspicion will surely ensue.
Please don't give it another thought.
Well, excuse me.
Please hold on, Honma-sensei.
What else do you want?
It's not like we have decided to terminate our filming.
Forget Yamazaki-san's second period lecture for a moment.
As for your third period lecture, Honma-sensei...
If we recover Kimijima-san's lost vase, we
will still continue filming as planned.
As such, may I ask you not to go home just yet?
Even if you do manage to find the vase, I
doubt you'll be able to continue filming...
Pardon?
Oh, no.
It was nothing.
"You won't be able to film even if the vase is found"?
What does that mean?
Does this Sensei know something else?
Kamisuwa-san...
Even if you say so, we're already fairly behind schedule.
Enough is enough!
Hey!
The culprit is among us, no?
In that case, show yourself and return my vase at once!
Please calm down, Kimijima-san.
Barring Yamazaki-san and Honma-san...
Nobody in this studio has personal belongings large
enough to conceal your vase, Kimijima-sensei.
Then where the heck is my vase now!?
It's true that no one carried a container out of
the studio big enough to conceal the vase.
Having said that, we did search everywhere
in the studio but failed to locate the vase.
But of course it couldn't have gone with the wind.
I'm sure I definitely missed something.
Something...
Can't help it.
Let's call it a day and stop our filming.
Roger.
Apologies!
As for today's filming, we'll call it a day here.
With the art staff members please disassemble the set!
Dissemble... the set?
Hashimoto, lend me your cutter.
Oh, sure.
I see!
So that's how it was!
Dad, isn't it about time you got sleepy?
We still haven't located the vase!
Getting sleepy is not -
Something...
I should do...
Or I shouldn't do...
Monkey see monkey do...
Please hold on a moment.
We need to deal not with the set...
But the case first!
Then, do you know who the culprit is?
Yeah.
The whereabouts of the vase too.
Are you sure!?
Then, the Sleeping Kogorou's famous deduction...
We shall see its true worth with our very eyes!
The culprit still has the vase.
The culprit still has it?
"Still has it"?
But all of here are empty-handed, Dad!
Look closely, Ran.
Among us, two people are wearing waist bags.
When the staff said they were disassembling the set earlier...
I confirmed the insides of assistant
director Hashimoto-san's bag.
Please check it however you want.
I only have these things in it.
In that case...
There's only you left, Oki Shinobu-san...
Hold it right there!
What the heck are you saying?
That vase from the Qing Dynasty...
Could never fit into such a small waist bag!
Right, of course.
However...
It's more than possible if one shatters the vase.
What now?
The vase was...
Shattered?
That Qing vase valued at 100 million yen!?
Shinobu-san...
But, if the vase was shattered, wouldn't
everyone immediately notice the sound?
Nobody was able to notice that.
Everyone, please recall what happened during
the rehearsal for the second period lecture.
When all of us were focusing on the
testing of the puffed rice machine...
You secretly went through the back of the set...
And put the vase in a bag you prepared
beforehand so that the shards wouldn't scatter.
And then...
Yoko-chan used the hammer to bang on the puffed rice maker.
With that timing...
All right, here comes!
You shattered the vase from outside the bag.
Finally, you stuffed your waist pouch with a bagful of vase shards...
And reappeared at the scene like nothing happened.
I see...
She took advantage of the loud puffed rice maker
noise to cover the sound of the shattering vase.
Is that true?
Why did you do that!?
Why!?
Answer me!
That's it!
You!
You were always yelling at her like that.
Sensei, I bet she hated you for that, am I wrong?
Is that right?
But, wait...
Whatever hatred she might have had...
I still don't believe someone in their right
mind would smash a 100 million yen vase.
Sheesh!
It just goes to show how much she despises him!
Still...
I have one more thing I'd like to ask Honma-sensei.
That is...
Regarding the appraisal result of that vase.
You want me to reveal that now?
Yes.
But it doesn't seem she wishes for that.
True
But if this keeps up, Shinobu-san will be made into a bad person.
Isn't that her choice as well?
I know that too.
However...
There is always only one truth!
No matter how the results may be against Shinobu-san's will.
Very well.
On the subject of the Qing vase in
Mr. Kimijima Noburou's possession...
I deem it a remarkable counterfeit.
That can't be...
That can't be true!
That vase was a counterfeit?
No way...
Unbelievable...
Then, earlier today...
It's this one.
What do you think?
Quite a work of art, right?
This is...
If you'll allow me.
Remarkable...
You meant to say "it's a remarkable fake"?
That's correct.
As expected, you have seen through its fakery.
If I were to declare it a fake during filming,
Kimijima-san would lose face as a result.
Having that said, I cannot lie about my appraisal results.
Troubled by this, I...
Tried to leave the scene without a word before filming but failed.
I'm afraid she had the same feeling.
Shinobu-san...
Knowing how deeply on Kimijima-san is of his vase...
You couldn't bring yourself to let out the truth.
In comes the invitation to be on the show.
If the appraisal were to take place in the
show, it would be revealed that it is a fake.
Simply because you didn't break the news up to this point...
Your master was about to lose face on national television.
Worrying yourself over this...
You decided to make it look like a vase theft...
In order to halt the filming, didn't you?
Right, exactly as you said...
Shinobu...
When did you find out?
That the vase was a counterfeit.
A year ago, before your wife passed
away, she called me to her bedside...
Although that vase is a fake, it's still
an irreplaceable treasure to Sensei...
"So I would like you to keep Sensei from
finding out at all costs," she said.
But since I couldn't keep the promise
and things turned out like this...
I am unable to remain by your side, Kimijima-sensei.
With this, I will hang up my hat, give
up my singer dream and go home.
Thank you very much for all these years!
Shinobu...
Do not embarrass me any further.
It's true that my eye for vases is gullible.
However...
I believe my discerning eye for singers is unclouded!
Earlier, I received a call along with a reply.
Your debut has been approved!
Since the producer was rather indecisive...
I went ahead and gave him an earful.
Don't make me repeat myself!
I said there's nothing to worry about, didn't I?
Fiddlesticks!
Are you saying you can't trust my judgment?
Oki Shinobu is the real deal!
You have my guarantee!
Do you still plan to go home despite all this?
Thank you very much...
Thank you very much!
Congratulations, Shinobu-san!
Congratulations!
THE MOST USEFUL SCHOOL IN THE WORLD
Looks like I've somehow solved another case, but...
It's no good, I can't remember anything.
Mouri-san!
I forgot to mention, but your necktie...
So you've indeed noticed it?
I wore this just to attract your attention, Yoko-chan!
...Has gravy from your boxed lunch on it!
Have a nice day!
I'm gravely in shock...
Even a necktie can't save...
His neck from embarrassment.
Look out!
In that case is she really that real estate king...
Mr. Katayose Ouzaburou's granddaughter?
That freak car was your doing, no?
Weren't you the driver?
The garden fence!
You put a hole in it, didn't you!?
Where did the culprit disappear to?
SOLVING MYSTERIES AT THE RED LEAF PALACE
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Milk Tea
Next Friday (Nov. 25) is a broadcast of the movie "The Raven Chaser"!
Watch it at home!