That restaurant was surprisingly good.
And that kind of price for lunch...
It's a real bargain, right?
Look out!
Damn you...
Oh no!
Are you all right?
Yes, thank you very much...
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A Japanese manor with a multitude of contraptions.
Incidents have occurred at the Red Leaf Palace!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Wow, somehow I feel bad for troubling you guys!
To think you'd invite us to your house despite us not doing much.
Since we were saved by the renowned
great detective Mouri Kogorou-sama...
Our master insisted upon meeting
with you to express his gratitude.
Suzaka Eiko (48)
Katayose Family Chauffeur
Doesn't this road...
Lead to the Red Leaf Palace?
That's my grandpa's house.
In that case is she really that real estate king...
Mr. Katayose Ouzaburou's granddaughter?
No, they are not blood-related.
Her parents died in a traffic accident...
And he recently adopted her from her relatives living in Hokkaido.
My name is Nakakita Kaede, eight years old.
Nakakita Kaede (8)
Adopted Child of Katayose
Nice to meet you!
And you are?
Edogawa Conan.
I'm seven years old.
Please.
Red leaves everywhere, I see...
Who are those people, Suzaka?
Milady Nobue.
The truth is that they saved us from harm's way.
We were almost hit by a freak car.
Thanks to this fine lad who called out to us.
Katayose Nobue (32)
Eldest Daughter of Katayose
A freak car, huh?
I see.
Did someone drop by?
Big brother...
They say Kaede almost got into an accident with a freak car.
Accident?
Katayose Ogito (35)
Eldest Son of Katayose
Bet it's because you were walking carelessly.
And?
Who're you guys?
He's the one who saved us back then...
The great detective Mouri Kogorou-sama.
Mouri Kogorou?
The - ?
That freak car was your doing, no?
Weren't you the driver?
My car's still inside the garage!
We're talking about a cunning guy like you.
You could've used a stolen car!
The garden fence!
You put a hole in it, didn't you!?
What are you talking about?
On the other side of the fence is a deep valley.
She always likes to play around that place, right?
Kaede, that is.
Oh, my bad...
Since we came from different mothers...
We're both adopted children who survived our deceased mothers.
We aren't tied to our father by blood.
In a household like this, incidents are bound to happen.
That's what's on your mind, isn't it?
No worries, Mouri-sensei will help us capture...
The culprit who made a hole in the fence!
The driver behind the wheel of that weird car!
My sincerest apologies for your having
to bear with this awkward situation.
Oh, no...
Well, please come right in.
My master awaits your arrival.
Come on in, Conan-kun.
Still, this is a spacious manor.
I wonder how much further this corridor goes?
What's this?
This is a painting.
Peculiar, isn't it?
It's a hobby of my master.
They say it's called "trick art".
What..
The -!?
A maple forest growing inside the house?
Not quite.
While the trees immediately in front of us are real...
Those in the back are paintings.
What?
Now that you mention it...
Pretty meticulous, I see!
Huh?
Where'd they go?
Anyway...
Let's keep walking.
So I assume this door's also a painting?
Come on!
Maybe you need to push?
Oh, I see.
Come on!
Trick art again?
Maybe it's a sliding door that opens to the sides?
It opened!
Is Mr. Katayose's room over there?
Seems so.
This garden must be real, right?
Welcome.
Please let yourselves in.
I've been waiting, Conan-kun.
Huh?
Where's Mr. Katayose?
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Katayose Ouzaburou (68)
Head of the Katayose Household
Please have a seat.
I am indeed Katayose Ouzaburou.
Wow...
How should I put it?
Such extravagance...
No, I mean, a fine hobby!
Grandpa's "extravagances" are mostly fake!
You have lived in real nature after all, Kaede.
I envy you.
Due to circumstances, I adopted this child who lost her parents.
To tell the truth, I am regretful for that.
Master...
I heard you were in danger again today.
About that...
I'm truly sorry.
No, you have nothing to be apologetic for.
It's what I have sown after all.
I've agitated those children that have become the bad bunch...
That was some vapid talk from me.
Here, please take a sip.
That milk was delivered straight from
the ranch in Kaede's hometown.
Any spoons, or...
My apologies, but I don't use spoons.
Enjoying the-milk patterns drifting
about in the cup is my joie de vivre.
Call him stubborn.
He will never even consider putting sugar in.
My guests, please help yourselves to these.
Mouri-sensei...
I reckon you'd prefer-sake instead?
Well!
In fact, I have matters I really need to consult with you...
But unfortunately, I already have a meeting set for 3:00..
After that's over, how about we talk over a few cups of sake?
It would be my honor to join you.
Too sweet!
Please usher Sensei to the guest room.
Understood.
See, these are the real deal.
What a superb garden.
They don't call it "Red Leaf Palace" for nothing.
Please allow me to clean up.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
It's a good distraction for me to move about.
After all, my body cannot last much longer.
An illness is cutting him short.
He's preparing for it.
My master, I mean.
Is that so...
Over here!
Wait up!
Huh?
What's wrong?
I thought the mountains were still a bit away, but...
It's actually this close?
Grandpa's pretty proud of that.
He said he tried to mimic the Hachiman shrine in Kamakura.
Oh, the "dankazura"?
raised pathway
Since the width was designed to gradually narrow...
By using the forced perspective effect, the
pathway will appear to be much longer.
Conan-kun, look at that!
It's my tree house.
Grandpa made me that.
Kaede-chan, you're just like a boy.
You got it!
See?
All right!
Conan-kun, climb up too!
This was cut by a knife...
So it is true that Kaede-chan has been targeted.
Then, does that mean you're not
related to the Katayose family at all?
That's right.
Grandpa said my real grandma was his close friend.
Although I don't remember anything about my grandma...
Then, why were you adopted?
I don't know.
Grandpa can be forceful sometimes.
He adopted me despite my uncle at the
ranch agreeing to take care of me himself.
I'd like to go back home.
Conan-kun, teach me soccer!
You whipped a soccer ball up like magic earlier, didn't you?
I'm surprised you noticed at a time like that!
But that ball will go completely flat within ten seconds.
I also have a ball in my house!
I'll be the goalkeeper!
Might fall into the pond if you stand there.
I won't let it fall.
I don't mean the ball, I mean you.
I won't fall either!
She's a handful.
Kick it with more force!
Got it.
Give it all you got!
You're a boy, aren't you?
All right!
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, Grandpa!
He's with a guest, right?
Seems so since it's after 3:00.
What's wrong?
I heard a groan.
I'm coming in!
Grandpa?
Steam is still coming from the cup.
The culprit's still around here!
Ran-neechan!
Did someone come out from the annex?
No, nobody came out.
Where's Uncle?
He's sleeping in the guest room.
What's the matter?
Hurry up and call him!
This is...
He's dead.
Grandpa!
Someone should've been here, right?
Yeah.
Look, the cup is still steaming.
Looks like his death was the result of cyanide poisoning...
What's all this racket?
Pops!?
What's wrong with father?
Master!
Please refrain from contaminating the scene!
Is this a murder case?
Nobue, was it you!?
What the—wasn't it you?
You finally freaking did it!
Cut the nonsense!
I merely waited in my room!
You were the one he called out first, no?
-She was the one who did it!
-The culprit is this man!
Grandpa... is dead...
Kaede-chan...
Detective Conan Episode 638
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Where were you at the time of the incident?
I was in the garage fine-tuning the cars.
Is there anyone who can verify that?
No, because I was all by myself.
The guest who was meeting with Mr. Katayose from 3:00 onward...
You have no idea who it was?
That is correct.
Since the conversation seemed to be quite
a private one, I didn't dare inquire further.
Does that mean the guest was either Ogito-san or Nobue-san?
Or it could have been both of them.
Have you any idea what kind of conversation it was?
It would likely reveal my masters embarrassment...
Hello?
Yes, I'll definitely pay you next month.
You can't wait that long?
But...
Understood.
I'll figure out a way.
Damn!
It'll be too late if I have to wait for my share of the inheritance!
The hell should I do!?
Mirror, mirror, tell me now.
Which dress fits me better for the funeral?
No way...
I can't declare bankruptcy now!
At least give me one more month...
Those two immoral people...
Went after nothing else but the master's fortune.
Mr. Katayose, who had prepared for his death...
Would have to talk to those two in due course.
However, we have no idea which of them was called first.
Inspector, that was forensics.
The milk in the pitcher tested positive for poison.
It's a simple case then!
The son and daughter must have known well
about Mr. Ouzaburou's affinity to milk tea.
One or both of them took the chance
and mixed poison into the pitcher.
The only question is which of them did it.
But, Uncle...
How did the culprit escape?
What're you talking about?
Yeah...
I had been standing in the corridor for
twenty minutes prior to the incident.
Nobody came out of the annex.
Kaede-chan and I were in the garden...
And were watching the annex the
entire time, but no one stepped out.
In that case, the culprit had no place to escape to.
So was it a sealed room murder?
They must have concealed themselves
in Mr. Ouzaburou's hidden room.
It's behind that painting of the cottage door on that wall.
And when Conan ran away from the scene...
They secretly came out and fled, no doubt.
Kaede-chan was still in the annex though.
She was stunned by her Grandpa's
death and lost her composure, no?
She simply didn't notice them!
But, doesn't that door make a loud creaking sound when opened?
If a loud noise like that had sounded...
I bet even we could have heard it in the corridor.
That's because...
But then, where on earth did the culprit vanish to?
Miss, what's wrong?
Nothing...
Just thinking Kaede-chan's probably awake by now.
She was exhausted and cried herself to sleep...
There isn't a place in this house that's free from care.
Feel free to go check on her.
What do I do...?
Miss!
Let me go check on Kaede-chan with you!
Where does that key unlock?
Guess I really need to report this to the inspector.
So he really did have hidden assets!
Why didn't you turn the key in to me instead of the cops?
This is private information among the Katayose family!
Only after we deem it irrelevant to the case...
Will we abide to his will.
However, Mr. Katayose entrusted Suzaka-san
with that key discreetly, you know?
The master said he would like me to
hold on to this indefinitly if possible.
Now that Pops is dead, the entire house will become mine!
I'm still here!
Shut up!
Hey, open it up already!
Yes...
There's something!
Bet it's a check!
So Pops planned to give it to this woman?
That's not true...
I'll take a look!
I will!
Brat!
Hand it to me!
Huh?
Something weird's written on it.
What?
Let's see...
"Now, close the umbrella.
"Gaze at the evening sun setting in the east.
"Look at the two rods holding up the red leaves.
"Search for a longer rod.
"My dream of the red leaves shall lie dormant there."
What's that?
A code?
Could it be the location of the hidden assets?
The code...
Does it really lead to the location of a hidden fortune?
If so, why did he entrust Suzaka-san with it?
And...
The culprit who murdered Mr. Ouzaburou?
This sealed room mystery...
I need the inheritance right now!
If only I could crack the code...
Wait...
The meaning of that...
I see!
That was scary.
But it looks like that guy figured something out.
That's it—I'll just wait for Ogito to solve the code.
I'll simply take everything away afterwards.
Putting the puzzle-solving aside, we've got to protect Kaede-chan.
That's the east bridge to our premises.
Something's glowing...
Let's hurry!
Damn, another victim!?
Inspector, all the mysteries have thawed out.
What?
The culprit...
Is you!
SOLVING MYSTERIES AT THE RED LEAF PALACE
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Electric Current
I'll solve the code and get the inheritance!
Uncle!
Just joking...
That was a joke?