The person we saved from a rampaging car...
Was Nakakita Kaede-chan, adopted child
of the capitalist Mr. Katayose Ouzaburou.
In response to her invitation, we visited Mr. Ouzaburou's
mansion that bore the name "Red Leaf Palace"...
And were surprised by the numerous
trick art employed here and there.
Mr. Ouzaburou's two kids, son Ogito-san and daughter
Nobue-san, had been feuding with each other...
Katayose Ogito (35)
Eldest Son of Katayose
Katayose Nobue (32)
Eldest Daughter of Katayose
And Mr. Ouzaburou had become saddened by the two children.
Katayose Ouzaburou (68)
Head of the Katayose Household
That Mr. Ouzaburou then died by poison.
But, neither Ran nor I witnessed any suspects fleeing the scene.
Was this a sealed room murder?
Amidst the escalating altercation between
Ogito-san and Nobue-san over the inheritance...
Suzaka Eiko (48)
Katayose Family Chauffeur
Mr. Ouzaburou's letter consigned to the
chauffeur, Suzaka Eiko-san, was discovered.
"Now, close the umbrella.
"Gaze at the evening sun setting in the east.
"Look at the two rods holding up the red leaves.
"Search for the longer rod.
"My red leaf dream shall lie dormant there."
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A sealed room, a code, the real culprit...
Push through the red leaves and solve the mysteries!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Putting the puzzle-solving aside, we've got to protect Kaede-chan.
We don't even know the culprit behind that car.
About that, I have a rough idea.
Ogito-san did that to Kaede-chan!?
See, when he heard Kaede-chan "almost
got into an accident with a freak car"...
Accident?
Bet it's because you were walking carelessly.
Even though the chauffeur Eiko-san was with her...
Isn't it odd that he'd assume she was
walking instead of riding in a car?
Then, could the culprit behind Ouzaburou-san's murder also be...
Pardon me.
Yes?
Since it seems it will take quite a while until meal time...
Feel free.
Nakakita Kaede (8)
Adopted Child of Katayose
Smells good.
Black tea, right?
I'll go fetch Grandpa.
Grandpa...
Kaede-chan...
Was Ouzaburou-san well aware of his condition?
It did seem he was prepared for it.
Occasionally, he would mutter, "I cannot die just yet."
What does that mean?
It meant that, once he passed away, Kaede-chan
may find herself in much more danger.
Grandpa...
He promised to drink black tea with me forever, but...
Is it true that Ouzaburou-san never put sugar in his tea?
Never.
Funny, isn't it?
Well, all of us have our own preferences.
But everyone else puts sugar in theirs.
I need five spoonfuls!
That's too much.
Our spoons are small!
I see.
So that's how it was.
What!?
Katayose Ogito and Nobue vanished from sight!?
What were the guarding officers doing!?
You see...
Since this mansion does resemble a maze...
Don't tell me they've fled into the mountains.
There's no escape route in the mountains.
Take a look.
This place is fenced off along the boundary line.
They say an electric current is running through it.
Likely for the purpose of preventing an
invasion of large wild animals, like boars.
Isn't that dangerous for humans too?
No.
Normally only the weak current is engaged.
But, when something does make contact with
the fence, an alarm sounds from that shed.
I was informed that the alarm and the voltage
adjustment can be controlled from there.
Over there.
That's the east bridge to our premises.
Something's glowing.
That?
A mirror was erected on top.
Weird, right?
A mirror?
Help me!
Hey!
Did you hear a woman screaming!?
Aunt Nobue!
Over there!
Let's hurry!
Damn...
Another victim!?
Aunt Nobue...
Kaede-chan, it's best you don't look.
We're too late.
Seems the murder weapon was the arrow on her back.
Huh?
There's one more arrow.
What's the matter?
Eiko-chan, Aunt Nobue is...
I knew it...
Mouri-kun!
Inspector.
So it's Nobue-san this time?
The wound doesn't seem like a deep one, so...
There may be poison on it.
It's not an ordinary arrow.
This is a bolt from a crossbow.
Crossbow?
Do you know something about it?
Yes well...
It's one of Ogito-sama's hobbies.
But amidst the grove of trees, where
could this have been shot from?
If the shooter had approached her, she would've
taken notice and escaped into the woods.
If shot from a distance, the trees would
in turn interfere with the line of sight.
You can get a good view from there, right?
My treehouse!
So the culprit shot the bolt from up there?
All right!
Be careful!
Idiot!
Don't you look down on my athletic ski—
Dad!
Why—
Gotcha!
No mistake about it.
The owner is no doubt Ogito!
He climbed up to this terrace and shot Nobue-san!
Without using the rope ladder, how did he climb up there?
He must have notched the ladder after putting down his crossbow.
There wasn't a,crossbow there when you climbed up earlier, right?
Yeah...
Kaede-chan climbed up the tree trunk
earlier, and the notch was already there.
What now?
In that case...
I bet Ogito also climbed up the tree.
But to leave the crossbow—the murder weapon—there, isn't it odd?
Who knows?
That Ogito guy must just be really forgetful!
Yes.
Is that so?
Thank you.
Inspector, according to the forensic results...
Among the two bolts, the one piercing the victim tested
positive for poison from aconitine derivatives, but...
The other tested negative.
It was cyanide in Ouzaburou-san's case...
And aconitine this time?
One more thing.
On Nobue-san's left sleeve...
They've found a rip as if it was cut by something.
I'm certain that things went down like this:
The first bolt that Ogito shot from this
treehouse tore through Nobue-san's clothes.
Soon after Nobue-san noticed she was being targeted...
She let out a "Help me!" scream and fled into the woods.
However, the second bolt with poison
hit her, and resulted in her death.
Why wasn't the first bolt laced with poison, though?
That's because...
There was only enough poison for one bolt?
What's this?
Somebody must have come into contact
with the fence and set off the alarm.
By fence, you mean the one with an electric current?
Yes.
Don't tell me it was Ogito?
What's the matter?
Inspector!
Our missing suspect, Katayose Ogito,
was found having fallen off of a cliff!
What'd you say!?
Detective Conan Episode 639
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Where is Katayose Ogito!?
Sir!
In the mountain stream below us!
So he fell from here?
It was a full-on jolt!
I see!
That must mean the culprit wasn't Ogito!
Why's that?
Every occupant of this domicile knows
that the fence here is electrified.
I don't believe they would touch the fence by mistake.
In other words, someone pushed him off?
Hey, look at that!
What's that mounted on top of the pole?
Looks like a mirror.
It's true, but that mirror...
Where is it facing?
I've got it!
As long as it doesn't rain, the mirror
will directly reflect the setting sun!
So that's why it tells us to "close the umbrella"!
With that said, the remaining puzzle is...
Which is longer, the horizontal or the vertical one?
The vertical pole looks longer to me...
Looks like we need to investigate the inside of the poles.
Roger.
Inspector!
Officers who descended into the valley
have confirmed Katayose Ogito's death.
We shall commence the transport of his body immediately.
Inspector!
All the mysteries have thawed out.
What?
The culprit responsible for the murders of
Mr. Ouzaburou, Nobue-san, and Ogito-san...
Is you!
Suzaka Eiko-san!
No way...
I didn't do anything!
Presumably, Mr. Ouzaburou had
already prepared a will ante-mortem.
On the occasion of both Ogito-san's and Nobue-san's deaths...
You would become the beneficiary of his inheritance...
Or something along those lines, right?
Dazzled by the inheritance, you killed them one by one!
Enough of the silliness already!
No, that must be it!
Inspector!
Hurry up and investigate!
Before I do, are you saying you can
elucidate the sealed room mystery?
Nah...
I mean, that's...
Well, sooner or later...
I think I'll figure it out...
A tad bit irresponsible, aren't we?
Uncle, leave the rest to me.
Mouri-kun?
Even the blossoming flowers...
Will eventually scatter...
Mouri-san?
Apologies—pardon me.
Now, allow me to explain in a more responsible manner.
Let's start from the sealed room mystery.
Ran was in a position where she could monitor who was
coming and going from Mr. Katayose Ouzaburou's annex.
Beyond that, Conan and Kaede-kun were also in
a position where the annex was in plain sight.
The scene resembled a sealed room with iron
walls under the surveillance of those three.
Moreover, there isn't any secret underground tunnel, right?
Of course.
In that case, there is only one answer.
It would have been impossible for
any perpetrator to depart the scene.
What are you saying?
There wasn't anyone else at the scene
apart from the victim, Mr. Ouzaburou.
I'm saying that's the true answer.
What now?
If that's so, Mr. Ouzaburou...
Committed suicide?
What in the world are you saying?
The black tea belonging to a guest was inside that room, you know?
The cup was steaming too...
That black tea was a work of disguise from Mr. Ouzaburou.
In order to make it seem as if a guest had visited.
How can you be so sure of that?
There was no spoon.
Mr. Ouzaburou, lacking the habit of adding sugar.
had no need for spoons even for mixing milk.
That's why he carelessly neglected
to prepare a spoon for the "guest".
To think he went as far as to prepare a sugar pot
I can only say it was a gross oversight on his part.
No way...
The reason for suicide was inheritance troubles.
Ogito-san and Nobue-san both seemed to
be in extremely tight spots, financially.
But...
That's precisely why Master was worried
and thought he couldn't die just yet.
So why did he kill himself?
Remind me again of the reason why he "couldn't die just yet"?
He thought that, if he died, the two of them
would try to put Kaede-chan in harm's way.
But unfortunately...
Mr. Ouzaburou took the fact that he won't last long to heart.
"In that case, I shall expunge the two
from Kaede-kun once and for all."
What might happen if we assume that?
I see.
That's why he committed suicide and
disguised it as a murder by poison.
But even so, why would he go as far as to invite
Mouri-san if he planned to commit suicide?
No, on the contrary.
Mr. Ouzaburou is fond of tricks.
He likely intended to challenge me to the mysteries.
I see.
Then, what about Nobue-san?
What we saw earlier was supposed to be Nobue-san's acting.
Acting?
She tore her own clothes with one of Ogito-san's arrows
that she obtained somewhere, and let out a scream.
By doing so, she made it appear as if Ogito-san was attacking her.
But, Nobue-san was shot in the back with an arrow and killed.
According to Nobue-san's plan, she was supposed
to feign unconsciousness and wait for our arrival.
However, Ogito-san showed up before we did.
What!?
Then, don't tell me he saw Nobue-san faking unconsciousness...
Exactly.
And he stabbed her with the poisonous bolt.
Please hold on.
Why would he conveniently carry a poisonous arrow?
I think he prepared one beforehand.
Ogito-sama told me during a boar hunt, he would
apply poison derived from wild plants to his arrows.
I see.
Nobue-san orchestrated an attempted
murder all for the purpose of framing Ogito.
Upon doing so, she would be able to gain all of the inheritance.
However, Ogito took advantage of
that and killed her in return, right?
In that case, the one who put the
crossbow at the treehouse was...
Nobue-san.
After presumably tossing it up there from below.
Since she didn't use the rope ladder
she didn't notice the notch in it.
In short, the one who made the notch was Ogito.
Then, Ogito was following Nobue-san?
In order to kill her when the opportunity arose?
No.
If that were the case, he would've carried
the bow as well instead of just the bolt.
Ogito brought only the bolt with him upon leaving the mansion.
I gather that he already solved the code long before us.
The bolt was probably for probing the inside of the pole,
which is likely where the hidden fortune is located.
I see.
But, can you prove that he indeed stabbed Nobue-san at that spot?
Good question.
I believe Eiko-san can.
What?
You had a slip of the tongue, right?
After hearing about Nobue-san's death, you uttered "I knew it".
What did you mean by that?
That's, uhm...
You were suspecting Ogito at first.
That he was aiming for Kaede-kun's life, and
finally poisoned Mr. Ouzaburou to death today.
With that thought on your mind, you kept
a watchful eye on his actions, didn't you?
No, I would never!
It follows that you also saw the scene
in which Ogito stabbed Nobue-san.
Since you couldn't ascertain the situation from a distant view...
As soon as Nobue-san's death was
confirmed, you uttered "I knew it".
After finishing off Nobue-san, Ogito came here
and climbed up the fence to check the poles...
And fell to his death due to the electric shock, right?
I doubt that's the case.
Eiko-san...
When the alarm sounded...
You said, "Somebody must have touched the fence."
Why "somebody"?
Why not "something" like animals?
Monitoring Ogito's every move, you...
Witnessed him coming out of the shed where the
controls for the electrified fence and alarm were.
You entered the shed after Ogito's departure,
and found the electric current and alarm cut off.
Perhaps you already knew the meaning
behind the cipher from the very beginning?
Since, if Mr. Ouzaburou were to hide something inside the pole...
He would have required someone else's help.
Then, realizing Ogito must've also figured
out the code by turning off the current...
You turned the electric current back on.
Not only that, you also made the current stronger than normal.
What'd you say!?
Ogito, operating under a false sence
of security that the current was off...
Climbed up the fence in order to search the pole.
I'm truly sorry!
I confess that I did it!
I mistook him for the murderer who poisoned Master...
I'm truly sorry!
What are you doing, Inspector?
They're searching for the treasure.
Hold on a minute!
The code instructed us to "search for the longer rod"!
That's why we've been searching like this.
But as far as I can see, the vertical one looks longer...
But it's the horizontal pole that's longer.
They've already measured it.
I think it's called "Fick illusion".
One of Mr. Katayose's deceptions, which is his hobby.
If you place two lines equal in length in a "T" shape...
You'll think the vertical one looks longer.
They say it's an illusion discovered in 1851.
FICK ILLUSION
The poles are based on that illusion and purposely
have the horizontal one longer by a little.
Inspector, found it!
It's the treasure!
We police officers shouldn't call it a treasure...
According to Mr. Katayose, it's his personal dream.
This is...
A ruby, isn't it?
A treasure indeed!
There's a letter that goes with it.
It's signed by Mr. Katayose.
"Suzaka Eiko-sama...
"By the time you have read this letter, I
believe I will have already ceased to exist.
"To you, who have done so much for me,
please hear out my one last request.
"I would like for you to take care of Kaede after my death, who
shall be the beneficiary of my inheritance, until her adulthood.
"Please accept the enclosed ruby with this letter as my gratitude.
"As for the reason I fixated on that little girl so much...
"Instead of laughing at the unbecomingness of an old man,
please surmise the truth from the enclosed picture."
These two people...
Their names are written on it.
Katayose Ouzaburou...
Nakakita Momiji.
And everyone immediately realized...
The reason it was called the "Red Leaf" Palace.
Momiji
Although they couldn't marry due to various circumstances...
Katayose-san had never forgotten his
dream, Momiji-san, even to the very end.
Kaede-chan went back to Hokkaido.
Without knowing what happened, she enthusiastically
vowed to invite Eiko-san for a visit someday.
A postcard?
"Ossu!
"Conan-kun, how goes it?
"Today, Nakakita Kaede is as energetic as always!
"Conan-kun, come visit me some time.
"I shall make you my hubby!"
Your "hubby"...
You wish...
Next Episode
Wow!
As expected of Okayama—famous for its peaches!
Even the ladies are peachy-peachy!
Please find out about who I am and where I'm from!
A robbery at the jewelry shop?
My big brother firmly said to me...
That he's innocent.
I can't...
I can't recall anything...
"If you want to learn about your past, be alone"...
THE MEMORY TRIP OF THE EIGHT SKETCHES
(OKAYAMA PART)
ext Conan's Hint
water zither cave
Suikinkutsu
Look Forward to the Next Episode
The next story is the Okayama and Kurashiki Mystery Tour!
Even if you didn't go, you can still enjoy a real deduction experience!