Okayama, Okayama.
Okayama Station
Okayama Castle
We have just arrived in Okayama.
How high!
Nashida Teruyuki (35)
Town Magazine Reporter
Now, shall we move on the parfait?
Yes!
In Okayama, where fruits like peaches and muscat
grapes are considered local specialties...
A campaign with the slogan "The Cit of Fruit
Parfait—Okayama" is currently being held.
As such, cafes and restaurants all around
Okayama City are serving a variety of parfaits.
Thank you for waiting.
Here is your Castle Parfait.
Looks appetizing!
There is ample amount of white peach
pulp, making it very scrumptious!
Today, Ran was chosen as an amateur
reporter by the local town magazine...
And is here in Okayama to gather scoops.
All right!
The best five restaurants serving tasty octopus rice and alcohol...
I shall circle them all!
Wow!
As expected of Okayama—famous for its peaches!
Even the ladies are peachy-peachy!
Like fog clearing in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
A beauty we encountered in Okayama
and a trip down the lost memory lane.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What a pity...
I wish Mouri-san were here for our report as well.
"The Great Detective Cuts the Gordian Knot!"
The presence or absence of the Sleeping Kogorou's name...
Makes a huge difference in reader popularity.
Could it be that he chose me just because
I'm Mouri Kogorou's daughter?
Looks so.
If I turn this gourmet special report into a smash hit...
My future will indeed...
Okayama Korakuen Garden
There are turtles.
♪ ﻿Waiting for the person who...
Where?
 ♪ Never came in sight...
♪ Like the evening primrose...
Okayama is also the birthplace of the famous Takehisa
Yumeji, commonly known for his paintings of beauties.
I think I've heard that before.
Waiting for the person
Never came in sight
Like the evening primrose
Lonely am I quite
even the moon seemingly
Hides away tonight
There are lyrics written on it.
That's right.
♪  Waiting for the person who...
Right, right that song.
♪  Never came in sight...
Yumeji Art Museum
Fabulous.
Knock it off!
Conan-kun!
Hey, give it back!
Hey!
Please!
Let me listen once more!
Who the hell are you!?
Please!
It's the person from earlier...
Let go!
Or we'll call the police!
The police?
Wait...
It hurts...
My head hurts!
Are you all right?
No, stay back!
Were you chased by someone?
Chased?
Me?
No good...
I can't...
I can't remember anything!
My head hurts...
Miss, what's your name?
Where are you from?
Name?
I can't remember...
I don't know!
This person...
What's the matter?
Oh, the lady from earlier...
Ran-neechan, call an ambulance.
Okayama Central Hospital
Damn!
My plan for octopus rice just went down the drain!
What the hell's going on...
Post-traumatic amnesia?
I suspect it’s-a sudden onset of memory loss caused by trauma.
I also found bludgeon marks on her body.
Will her memory come back?
We cannot be certain.
Fortunately, since I didn't detect any lesions in her brain...
I can say that her prognosis is not bad at all.
Well...
Did she bring anything that we can identify her with?
Dad!
You're late, you know?
How was it?
She didn't have anything on her.
Not even a cell phone, an identification card, or a wallet.
And the police?
Of course we've contacted them and
reported everything we knew up to now.
But although they will investigate, they still have
doubts as to whether criminal activity is involved.
Which means it doesn't look like I'm needed.
Great, back to octopus rice!
But you have a request!
Request?
Mouri-san...
Right?
Yes, ma'am!
I am indeed the great detective Mouri Kogorou!
Please...
Please find out about who I am and I'm from.
I beg of you!
As such, Uncle officially accepted her request and
proceeded with the search of her past, but...
I've asked her to sketch out whatever images may come to mind.
It's uncertain whether they are correlated in any way, but...
I think it's safe to say that these are indeed parts of her memory.
Can't make heads or tails of them.
Is this...
A bird?
A crane?
I know!
A red-crowned crane!
It must mean the Korakuen Garden
It was the place where we first heard her
singing the Evening Primrose song.
And this...
Looks like a cat?
You're right!
Speaking of black cats...
I see, it's Takehisa Yumeji!
Right.
The Yumeji Art Museum.
You remember it, right?
Yeah, I do...
But, why was I at that place?
I see....
She still can't remember the critical fact that we seek.
However...
One thing becomes clear.
These sketches are no doubt representations
of places you've visited.
Places I've visited?
Yeah
Although lacking solid proof, there's a possibility.
As for other things we know...
This is a peach, right?
This is...
Grapes?
Maybe.
However, since both of them are famous in Okayama
we cannot narrow it down to a specific place.
There's one more clue at our disposal.
That cell phone.
Please!
Let me listen once more!
Who the hell are you'?
Please!
Yeah...
I remember that too...
But again...
I still can't recall as to why I did that sort of thing...
Just leave it to me.
Yours truly, Mouri Kogorou, will slice the
Gordian Knot and reclaim your memory!
Uhm...
I forgot...
I'm sorry, but I need to get back to the report...
About that, we have a slight change of
plan in our report per my editor's order.
Change of plan?
What is this about?
We're going to update our town magazine's
website with her photo and sketches...
As well as the fact that the great detective
Sleeping Kogorou is investigating her identity.
I bet we'll get results.
But is it all right?
What about your all-important report on sweets?
"Sweets" and "Mystery"...
We're doing these two topics now.
Although personally I only want to do that one report on sweets.
O﻿kayama Electric Tramway
Without further ado, we attempted to retrace her
memories with the help of her sketches, but...
Aside from the red-crowned crane and the black cat, we
failed to find places matching her other sketches...
And her memory still wasn't coming back.
We're being followed?
If I recall, that time...
Ran-neechan, call an ambulance.
The same person?
Fine.
Conan-kun?
We're not heading that way!
Oh no!
Damn...
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
Nah...
Nothing.
Is something the matter?
Did you recall something new?
Keep quiet.
Where is it?
Where's that sound coming from?
Here, we've recorded it pretty well, right?
It's beautiful.
Please let me hear it!
I beg of you!
All right...
If you say so...
Ma'am!
Where was that recorded?
It was from...
Former Residence of Nozaki Family
It was from the residence of Nozaki who made
a fortune through his saltern business...
And whose house is known as the "Salt Palace".
(Water Zither Cave)
Suikinkutsu
"﻿A suikinkutsu is"...
"﻿Composed of an urn buried underground with an open hole atop"...
"Allowing droplets from the water basin
to drip through and echo inside.
"It's a refined device uniquely found in Japanese gardens," huh...
So true , what a beautiful sound!
In that, are you sure it was here where you heard the sound?
Yeah...
I guess.
But...
You still can't remember when and why you came here, right?
Yeah...
Aren't you Mayuko?
Where were you?
I've been looking for you!
It's me, Kanae!
Your friend!
Kanae... san?
That's right, Mayuko!
Mayuko...?
Detective Conan Episode 640
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Kichise Mayuko (25)
Kichise Mayuko...
That's my name...
Right.
Nonomiya Kanae (25)
Mayuko's Friend
I'm Nonomiya Kanae, and you're my friend.
K﻿anae-san...
You're my friend...
Some comments are also posted on our website!
They say you're working at a cafe in Okayama
City; your name's Kichise Mayuko-san.
Customers and the staff from your shop posted these.
No doubt about it.
I also made Mayuko's acquaintances that place.
What about family...
And your parents?
She once said they died of illness when she was little...
And without relatives, she's all alone in this world.
How is it?
Have you recalled anything?
I'm sorry...
No good, huh?
Did you say you've been searching for her?
Mayuko-san, I mean.
Yeah.
But I can't believe she lost her memory...
What should I do?
If this keeps up, my big brother...
What happened to your big brother?
I beg you, Mayuko!
Please remember!
My brother...
Save my brother!
The night before yesterday, from this jewelry store in Okayama...
Three hundred million yen worth of valuables were stolen.
And the man arrested as a suspect was...
Nonomiya Keigo-san, elder brother of Kanae-san.
Nonomiya Keigo (28)
Kanae's Elder Brother
According to the news...
He was falling unconscious in front of the emergency
exit next to the store where the police found him.
They discovered a portion of the stolen
jewelry was on him at the time.
Since my brother has previous convictions for theft...
They arrested him on the assumption
that he was with the robbery group.
But, during my visit at the police station...
My big brother firmly said to me...
That he's innocent.
He said he only happened to walk past the nearby street.
The culprit assaulted him there...
And made him a scapegoat.
And you...
I...
Witnessed it?
"That was definitely your friend, Mayuko-san".
"No one other than her can prove that I'm innocent".
"Get her to testify for me," my brother said.
That's why I've been looking for you.
So that was why...
Mayuko-san, can't you remember anything?
I'm sorry...
Just leave it to me!
Leave everything to the great detective Mouri Kogorou!
It's possible that Mayuko-san's memory loss...
Was due to an attack from the real
culprit who planned to silence her.
I see.
That's something we should consider.
If we can manage to get that memory back
the robbery case will be good as solved.
Killing two birds with one stone!
Say...
Do you know where Mayuko-san used to live?
Yeah, of course.
There!
If we go there, maybe she'll be able to remember something!
Kanae-san briefed the apartment lessor on the situation...
Enabling us to investigate Mayuko-san's unit.
Huh?
This...
Could that be Mayuko-san's other earring?
Which means...
She tumbled down the stairs and suffered memory loss?
What's the meaning of all this?
Is that a badge?
Most likely...
The person in that picture ransacked this place.
That's safe to assume.
From the looks of the photo...
Is he her boyfriend?
My apartment...
My boyfriend...
Kanae-san, have you seen him before?
This man hanging around with her.
No.
Mayuko didn't seem to wish to discuss something like that.
I can't...
I can't recall anything...
My head hurts!
Are you all right?
Should we let her rest a little, Dad?
This is...
An order form for custom jeans?
The order was placed three days ago.
The day before the robbery?
That shop is quite famous.
We then headed to the famous place
where jeans in Japan were popularized...
The "Betty Smith Jeans Museum" in Kojima.
Betty Smith Jeans Museum
Yes, I remember her.
She indeed placed an order for a pair of original jeans with us.
Like this one-of-a-kind pair of jeans...
I shall live a life of my very own!
My very own life...
I've also heard you say that.
Even though you're mischievous by nature, you've been
quick to believe in people but are always lied to.
Old Shimotsui Shipping Agent Museum
Just as you were recuperating, people betrayed you again.
The cycle kept repeating.
That's why you vowed to toughen yourself up this time.
You determined to live your own life to the fullest.
That's what you told me, Mayuko.
I said things like that...
How about we break for lunch?
The octopus rice in this area is quite delicious.
Octopus rice?
Superb!
Welcome!
We'll seat youse in a bit, so please 'ang on!
Looks delicious!
Hold it, Dad!
Nashida-san!
Taira... san?
Yeah, Taira's right.
Taira Kenzou (40)
Patissier
It's been a longtime, Nashida-san.
My!
I can't even recognize you!
This is a little embarrassing.
It's not like I wanted to get a makeover, but...
To tell-the truth, I'm planning to start
afresh and open a new shop soon.
That's terrific!
I shall write a report about it next time.
Allow me to introduce.
This is Taira Kenzou-san, a famous patissier living in Okayama.
And Nashida-san...
Weren't you a famous sommelier yourself?
Thanks to the wine Nashida-san selected...
I was once able to complete the award-winning sweets.
Is that true?
I'm humbled by this.
Truth is, I aim to make a comeback while I'm in
charge of the gourmet reports in our town magazine.
Then, I'm on my way.
All right, see you later.
Hello?
Oh, Chief.
Right now?
Understood.
Apologies, but the editor-in-chief called me.
I will be back in about an hour, so please go ahead and dine.
All right!
I see!
This thing...
If you look closely, doesn't it look like a
traditional cauldron for cooking rice?
Now that you mention it...
Perhaps this is her memory of having a meal somewhere.
I'm sorry!
I just couldn't remember anything after all!
Mayuko-san, wait!
Dad!
Conan-kun?
This is...
If you want to learn about your past, be alone."
Conan-kun!
♪  Waiting for the person who...
Washuzan Observation Deck
♪  Never came m sight...
♪  Like the evening primrose...
♪  Lonely am I quite...
Mayuko-san!?
Damn...
Are we too late!?
Next Episode
I....
Definitely want to recall my true self!
The grapes vanished and the bananas become two bundles!
Changing the angle makes you see different things?
Such a beautiful moon...
Mouri-san, right now you should swiftly cut the Gordian Knot!
Actually...
The hint toour culprit was portrayed in Mayuko-san's sketches from the very beginning.
THE MEMORY TRIP OF THE EIGHT SKETCHES
(KURASHIKI PART)
Next Conan's Hint
Grapes
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Don't we have any way to get her memory back?
My own memory sometimes blacks itself out!
Right?