During our visit to Okayama...
We took on the quest of investigating the identity
of a woman we met there who lost her memory.
The clues provided to us were her eight sketches.
Amid our investigation, maybe unsurprisingly, we came across
her friend Nonomiya Kanae-san who had been looking for her.
Based on Kanae-san's Intel, we learned
that her name is Kichise Mayuko.
Kichise Mayuko (25)
And Mayuko-san happened to be the witness who could prove the
innocence of Kanae-san's brother, currently arrested for robbery.
Nonomiya Keigo (28)
Kanae's Elder Brother
If Mayuko-san cannot retrieve her
memory, his name will not be cleared.
As we continued on our search...
The fact that Mayuko-san's room was disarranged
and a suspicious shadow was following us...
Triggered a fishy y feeling.
In the meantime, Mayuko-san suddenly went missing.
This is bad, at this rate Mayuko-san will be in danger!
Like fog clearing up in a swoosh...
Let's see through both romance and cases!
The lost memory will be restored...
At the conclusion of the Okayama-Kurashiki tour!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Washuzan Observation Deck
Help me!
Somebody!
Take this!
Mayuko-san.
Mayuko-san, are you all right?
Mayuko-san!
It's so dangerous.
I think we'd better inform the police and petition for protection.
But, they're the police who treated my
innocent brother as if he were the criminal.
I just can't bring myself to trust them.
Right.
That's why I request that we continue like this.
Thank you, Mayuko!
I'm sure my brother will...
I'm not doing this only for your brother.
I just feel ashamed of myself.
Just as I was struggling to recall my past,
feeling down and helpless in tears...
That past back came to haunt me.
I think...
This is somewhat mortifying.
I...
Definitely want to recall my true self!
Understood.
How admirable, that Mayuko-san.
I have a feeling that she's actually a strong person.
So you came to visit a friend?
A coincidence again.
Fate is a curious thing!
Taira Kenzou (40)
Patissier
However, I am shocked.
To the she'd lost her memory.
If there's anything I can do to help, ask away.
Thanks for the offer.
Well then.
Later.
What's the matter?
That person...
I feel like I've met him somewhere before.
Really?
Of course you do.
It's because that man is like a god among local confectionery fans.
We've also done a report on him.
See?
Is this person Taira-san?
Nashida Teruyuki (35)
Town Magazine Reporter
Former Sommelier
Yeah
He looks completely different now, so I was surprised.
We only have five more sketches to check out.
I wonder what places these point to?
Still can't wrap my head around it.
Huh?
It just hit me, but could this be...
Referring to the boiling pot reading?
Boiling... pot?
A boiling pot reading is...
A ritual in this Kibitsu Shrine that's been
passed down from ancient times.
Kibitsu Shrine
By drawing upon the loudness and length
of the sound of rice boiling in a pot...
Good or bad omens are predicted.
Mayuko-san.
Could it be.
Your memory has returned?
Silence.
Huh?
You're that lady...
Do you recognize this lady?
I don't know.
Why did I cry?
Has she requested a boiling pot reading before?
Yes...
Three days ago.
It's the day before the robbery!
Did she say anything?
Well...
I want to turn over a new leaf.
Discarding my past.
It's high time that I got back on my two feet.
It seems you were walking around Okayama where you were
born and raised because you wanted to re-envision yourself.
I see...
We just found out the reason why you were
visiting the places depicted in your sketches.
More comments are posted on our website!
People witnessed her in Kurashiki.
We immediately journeyed to Kurashiki.
The Ohashi House
This picture...
Isn't it a match to that window grill?
I see.
So it actually meant the Kurashiki grillwork.
Kurashiki grillwork?
It's a characteristic design in Kurashiki.
You'll see a lot of it once we go to the Bikan historical area.
aesthetic
Bikan historical area?
Kurashiki Bikan Historical Area
Sure seems to me that Mayuko-san had been here.
What's wrong?
Just someone asking for directions.
Young boy, give this a try!
Handmade Sparrow-Shaped Pancake Workshop
Why do I have to...
Conan-kun, smile at the camera!
Kurashiki Ivy Square
Thereafter, we discovered subsequent locations
corresponding with the sketches.
Kurabo Memorial Hall
Mayuko-san's memory was also recovering little by little.
I...
Came here before!
Ohara Museum of Art
Yurinso Villa
I remember!
And thus we were down to two sketches.
That...
Could it be...
Momotaro Museum of Illusions
A hint to this place?
Spinning this disk will change the number of demons?
The grapes vanished and the bananas become two bundles!
It's because.
They painted a picture of grapes on the face-up
surfaces of this accordion-shaped object...
But on the surfaces facing down, they painted bananas instead.
I see.
So the mirror below that object.
Will reflect the bananas that are drawn on the downward surfaces?
Changing the angle makes you see
different things—how interesting!
Changing the angle makes you see different things?
♪ Waiting for the person who...
♪ Never came in sight...
Such a beautiful moon...
I don't see.
The moon anywhere...
No you don't!
I'm sorry!
Wait!
You all right?
Yeah...
Damn!
Not again...
Osanai Finance, Inc.
This is...
Detective Conan Episode 641
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Mayuko...
Could it be you've recovered your memory?
So you recalled where the jewelry is?
Finally.
You reveal your intentions.
Conan-kun!?
It was...
I who wrote that.
I have something to tell you.
Mayuko
Mayuko-san is already back in the hospital.
What's the meaning of this?
Kanae-san, you're actually...
Not the sister of Nonomiya Keigo-san—suspect
of the jewelry robbery—am I right?
No way!
It was a lie?
It should be apparent to us if we just think it through.
In the event that the suspect denies charges...
Relative visits are almost prohibited except for attorneys.
Despite that...
But, during my visit at the police station...
My big brother firmly said to me...
That he's innocent.
But that...
I really did...
I've already seen through your true identity.
Conan!
Here!
Look at this.
Isn't this a loan contract?
Ishida Kanae...
Ishida?
So it's just like you said?
The reason why she posed as his sister...
Was not to clear Nonomiya's name.
Your purpose was the jewelry, right?
You should've known that you'd get caught
posing as his sister once we investigated.
It shows how tight of a corner she was driven into.
Due to her debts.
Just like you said.
Some trashy man hoodwinked me into
getting loans to support him...
And the finance company turned out to be a loan shark to boot.
The night before yesterday, I went to Mayuko's
apartment with the intent to borrow money.
But then...
Where's the jewelry!?
I don't know!
Come!
Let go!
At that time, I didn't quite understand what happened in front of me.
But soon as I got wind of the jewelry robbery via the
news next morning, everything became clear to me.
The statement given out by Nonomiya-san
I saw on the news was not a lie.
That man conked Nonomiya-san and made him a scapegoat...
And the woman he claimed to have seen was in fact Mayuko.
Come to think of it, aside from the witness being Mayuko-san...
Everything you said was announced in the news.
I don't know what happened to the two of them...
But I gathered that Mayuko had betrayed the
man and hidden the jewelry somewhere.
If I played my cards right, I might even be able to get out of debt.
With that in mind, I hurriedly tried to locate Mayuko's whereabouts.
However, just as I found Mayuko, her memory...
I suddenly didn't know what to do at all.
Afterwards, President Osanai from
the loan company came to collect.
And I inadvertently told him about the stolen jewelry.
Osanai Norio (38)
President of Osanai Finance
And then...
He coerced you into posing as Nonomiya-san's
sister and getting in contract with us.
All for the purpose of drawing out the whereabouts of
the jewelry once Mayuko-san regained her memory...
And to usurp them.
Hello?
Yes, please hold.
Dad, you ave a call from the Okayama police.
They must've taken the man into custody
from the license plate Conan reported.
You're saying I'm the jewelry robber?
Give me a break!
I was only planning to con her out of the jewelry!
Because my company is in dire fiscal straits...
That's why...
He admitted that he was responsible for
grabbing Mayuko-san at the Bikan area...
But denied having done anything else.
He's definitely just trying to talk his way out!
The attacker at the observation deck
must've been that Osanai guy as well!
Well, I beg to differ.
Ran!
Yes?
Do you remember any characteristics of the man who
attacked Mayuko-san at the observation deck?
Characteristics?
Well...
Help me!
Somebody!
That's right!
That man was left-handed!
But Osanai is right-handed.
In other words, there were actually two people stalking Mayuko-san.
One of them is the right-handed man who was
working with Kanae-san and following us -
The finance company president, Osanai.
Then, the remaining left-handed man would be the jewelry robber...
So who was this man responsible for attacking
Mayuko-san at the observation deck?
Mouri-san, right now you should swiftly cut the Gordian Knot!
Actually...
The hint to our culprit was portrayed in
Mayuko-san's sketches from the very beginning.
What now?
Take a look at the last sketch.
Roger.
This picture of grapes?
You're saying this hints to our culprit?
That reminds me, Nashida-san!
Didn't you say you're a former sommelier?
Yes...
If I recall, a sommelier...
Wears a badge in the shape of grapes, right?
The man in the picture that was torn
off in Mayuko-san's apartment...
Had something shiny on his chest, was it a sommelier badge?
Plus, immediately before Mayuko-san was
attacked at the observation deck...
Apologies, but the editor-in-chief called me.
I will be back in about an hour, so please go ahead and dine.
You took off somewhere, didn't you?
What's with those eyes?
Are you suspecting me?
The man at the observation deck got conked by
Conan-kun with a can and injured his head.
Nashida-san, why did you suddenly decide to wear a hat?
What are you trying to insinuate?
It's not like I'm hiding any wounds!
Look...
Look!
Right.
It wasn't Nashida-san.
Is that so?
The sketch was in fact showing something else.
Conan!
Ran-neechan, the picture of grapes didn't
mean a sommelier badge, but this.
Huh?
Isn't this...
We need to look this way, right Uncle?
So this is...
Actually Taira-san's muscat parfait?
It's akin to that mirror trick.
Changing the angle makes you see different things.
Moreover, it's likely that Taira-san was left-handed.
Conan witnessed the moment when Nashida-san
and Taira-san were shaking hands at the hospital.
The reason why Nashida-san extended his left hand...
Was because he already knew Taira-san was left-handed, wasn't it?
Yeah...
That's exactly right.
Which reminds me...
The man from that time was also left-handed!
Taira-san.
Isn't it time for you to show yourself?
I already know you've been eavesdropping on us over there.
I'm too broke to open a new shop.
And since I gambled away my old shop
I couldn't get any loans from any banks.
That's why I recruited Mayuko and committed the robbery.
So Mayuko-san was an accomplice to the robbery?
I would imagine she was the lookout or the getaway driver, yes?
Yeah, you guessed right.
However, I was witnessed by that guy.
As such, you beat Mayuko-san to her apartment and dragged her out.
You tried to get the jewelry back...
But caused Mayuko-san to fall down the stairs.
You were then surprised by Kanae-san's scream and fled.
Afterwards, you learned about Mayuko-san's
amnesia from the town magazine website...
In addition to the fact that I was investigating the truth.
You then destroyed any evidence in Mayuko-san's
room showing the relationship between you two...
And attempted to get in touch with us in a disguise.
All for the purpose of getting the jewelry back.
Hello?
Yes, that's right...
Is that true?
Dad!
They said Mayuko-san went missing from the hospital!
Conan-kun!
As I thought, your memory has already returned.
Mouri-san?
Since you mumbled this at the Bikan area.
Such a beautiful moon...
Which means you were reminded of the
night scene you saw there in the past.
How many times have I tried to pull myself together...
However, each time the person I trusted would betray me!
I fell love with Taira and he bid me to co-own a shop.
Just as I thought this was my chance, that very
same Taira compelled me to rob the jewelry store!
Now that I can never regain my footing...
Defiantly, I thought I should just keep all the loot to myself.
Why not turn even more evil for the heck of it?
Why not fall deeper for all I care?
But you were crying.
After seeing the boiling pot ritual.
You requested a fortune reading with the
intention of discarding your past and start afresh.
Now that you've regained your memory, you
should be able to recall that feeling of yours.
Ran said something about you.
How admirable, that Mayuko-san.
I have a feeling that she's actually a strong person.
Ran-san did?
I believe she's now praying for you to straighten
yourself out this time with that strength of yours.
The next day, thanks to the testimony
of the now-arrested Mayuko-san...
Nonomiya Keigo-san was proven to be innocent and was released.
Finally...
Finally!
Octopus rice and.
Beer!
Dad!
We're going to be late for the bullet train!
Not fair!
Just come!
My octopus rice and beeeeer!
Next Episode
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
A cold, I have a cold.
Guys I don't know suddenly came to my home!
Hey, Masao!
If you don't behave, Daddy's gonna get angry!
What a wolf-crier he was.
However, despite the wolf-crier telling the truth in the end...
He was eaten by the wolf because no one believed him, right?
GRABBING KARUTA CARDS IN DIRE STRAITS
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Video Call
Look Forward the Next Episode
That's all for this year!
Be sure to root for that puny detective brat next year!
A Happy New Year!