Happy New Year, everyone!
Detective Conan celebrates its seventeenth year of serialization.
So far we managed to solve numerous tough cases.
This year shall present even more...
Suspensefully!
Actively!
Powerfully!
And mysteriously...
Upgraded contents and do our best!
So please continue your support!
All right, viewers!
I shall enumerate the 108 bagfuls of attributes
you will need to sail through the entire year!
The first bag being—patience!
The second, a sleeping bag...
Uncle, keep sleeping until the end of the year.
I Love You Miss Mystery —
the one now in an endless labyrinth
Let's embrace this love and solve the puzzle right now
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
The begging from a wolf-crier...
And the secret behind the coded karuta cards.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
GRABBING KARUTA CARDS IN DIRE STRAITS
(PART ONE)
Conan-kun...
Don't...
Don't move...
Wait...
It's all right...
Just stay still...
It sure feels like a fever.
Did you catch a cold?
Your face is all red too.
No, my face is red for a different reason...
Wait here.
I'm going to take your temperature with a thermometer.
I'm fine.
It'll completely go away even if I leave it alone.
See, you're coughing again!
It really is a cold.
You hear me?
Stay put until I'm back, OK?
Yes...
Going somewhere?
That's right.
To buy a thermometer since you stepped
on ours last night and broke it!
Geez, to think I'd catch a cold so early in the year...
My precious winter vacation is ruined.
My phone?
It's from Mitsuhiko.
A video call at a time like this?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
We made plans to meet at Ayumi-chan's
place to play karuta cards, didn't we?
We already ate the mochi!
Are you still sleeping?
A cold, I have a cold.
Well, I'm only coughing a little, so it's no big deal...
Then, let me see the back of your throat.
I'm going to inspect you.
Like this?
NO WAY, WHAT'S GOING ON THERE!?
The lateral pharyngeal bands medial to your
palatine tonsils are inflamed and swollen!
Isn't this an acute upper respiratory tract infection!?
Idiot...
"Acute upper respiratory tract infection" simply means a cold.
And to begin with, you can't possibly see
the back of my throat via a video call!
Bingo.
Well, if it's a cold, you'd better warm
yourself and rest quietly for today.
In that case, why not go check on him?
You're right!
Let's go visit!
Hey, you guys can't come!
I might pass it to you...
Damn, I really do have a fever...
Looks like someone's here.
Hey, anybody home!?
Uhm...
What's wrong?
Bad guys!
Guys I don't know suddenly came to my home!
Hey, Masao!
If you don't behave, Daddy's gonna get angry!
Excuse us.
You see, my child loves to play pranks just like my husband.
Well, his tendency to over exaggerate comes from his mother.
Wrong!
These guys really are people I don't know!
It's not a lie!
We're truly sorry i for the intrusion.
Help me!
Cut it out with that "help me".
Spraying nonsense like that in front of your parents...
You really are Mommy's child, born from my aching belly, you know?
Let me go! Let me go! Let me go!
And your slanted eyes came from Daddy.
Who was that kid?
Ayumi-chan, do you know him?
I don't, but if their place is on this floor...
Then I think he's the child of Urafune-san
who just moved into Room 2806 recently.
Well then, have you already met his Dad and Mom?
No, because our rooms are far apart.
You'd only socialize with your close neighbors if you live in a condo.
At any rate...
It sure looks like an infamous little prankster has moved in.
No...
Call the police.
The boy just now...
I think it's highly possible he got into some kind of trouble.
Police!?
How do you know such a thing?
They weren't even blood-related, yet they
acted like they were his biological parents.
Well then, call Detective Takagi and have him come.
Hold it!
This is bad...
It sure...
Seems to be a real cold...
Should we call the police?
Let's call, let's call!
Conan-kun said so too!
But, how did Conan know those guys weren't his parents?
Could it be that Conan-kun is an acquaintance of that child?
In that case the wouldn't refer to him
as "the boy just now", would he?
The source of his deduction was the voices
of those three and their conversations...
And the footage of those three captured
behind my back by this phone.
Can he really be certain that they're
not parent and child with just that?
He can't, can he?
Perhaps he's talking nonsense since his cold clouded his judgment.
But Conan-kun is a great detective!
At any rate, let's hear from the neighbors of
Room 2806 where the Urafune-san family lives.
Our call to Detective Takagi can wait until after that, no?
You're right.
Let's do that.
Urafune-san from Room 2806?
So they're my neighbors who just moved in two days ago...
But they haven't dropped by to say hi, so I don't know them well.
I do remember Uemura-san who lived in Room 2806 before, though.
The prior resident?
Yeah, it seems he was an employee from Isobe
Corporation that was in the news recently.
But he said he's moving out because he quit
his job and is going to another company.
Isobe Corporation?
The treacherous company that's under suspicion of tax evasion.
By "suspicion", it means they're
probably doing something bad, right?
So were those people just now really bad guys?
But she was talking about the person who lived there before.
It had nothing to do with that Masao-kun just now.
Masao?
You mean the boy about your age with slanted eyes and glasses?
Yeah.
If it's that kid, I know him.
So you mean only Masao-kun came by to say hi?
What a courteous child!
Courteous?
Far from it!
Yesterday, when I returned from shopping
and was about to ride the elevator...
That kid came out and said...
Wow, miss, you have so many things!
What floor?
I'll press it for you!
Twenty-eighth, please.
You're really helpful!
If it's 28th floor, it's the same as my place!
Oh, is that so?
Could it be you're with the family who moved in yesterday?
Yeah!
I'm Urafune Masao, nice to meet you!
Isn't he a great kid?
Right...
If only the elevator didn't stop at every floor!
I see...
He pressed all the floor buttons and fled.
Indeed!
What's more, he purposely left out the 28th floor one!
Reall now?
Say, we just saw Masao-kun taken away by
people he claimed weren't his parents...
if that kid said they weren't his parents...
They must truly be his parents, no?
What?
You want to know about Urafune-san who moved in next door?
Beats me...
I'm not the type of person who socialize with neighbors.
Then, did you see anyone weird around the condo?
I can't say he's weird, but...
I saw this Hida guy, a producer at Nichiuri TV.
You see, that guy's on TV sometimes.
Come to think of it, I did see that producer entering Room 2806.
Was this some kind of a case?
No way!
When did that happen?
It was about two weeks ago.
It has nothing to do with Masao-kun if it's two weeks ago.
I was pretty intrigued by that, so...
I asked the boy with slanted eyes who came
out of Room 2806 yesterday around noon.
I asked him, "The producer from Nichiuri TV went
to your home the other day, so what happened?"
Wasn't he Masao'-kun?
Was the kid wearing glasses?
Yeah.
And?
What did the kid say?
He said...
It's about a program airing Saturday nights on Nichiuri
TV called "Sudden Visit—Dinner Time Next Door"!
I heard that they're making a sudden visit to your place tonight!
Really now?
That's what he said, so...
My wife and I cleaned our place in a big
hurry and even prepared a feast...
But no one came no matter how long we waited!
We didn't realize the kid was lying until
after 8:00 PM when the live show ended!
I was so embarrassed since I even called
my friends to watch me on the show!
So you guys are that kid's companions!?
No...
Just leave already!
I won't be fooled again!
What a wolf-crier he was.
Then, what he said earlier must be a lie too!
Is that so?
Understood.
Ai-chan, who were you calling?
Nichiuri TV.
I thought they may have something to with this
bull couldn't get a hold of that producer.
Well, producers at the TV stations are all pretty busy.
No...
They said he had a traffic accident two weeks ago...
And was unconscious until yesterday.
Traffic accident!?
Could it be there's some sort of secret in Room 2806...
And somebody assulted him because he knew about it?
Under the guise of a traffic accident!
Then, maybe Masao-kun also found out about the secret...
But that kid kept crying wolf, didn't he?
However, despite the wolf-crier telling the truth in the end...
He was eaten by the wolf because no one believed him, right?
That's true, but...
We don't know whether he's telling the truth or not!
But, Conan-kun told us to call the police!
In that case, we have no other options but to confirm it directly.
Directly?
Indeed...
By letting ourselves in the room in question—2806.
Aw, shoot!
It's the children from before.
Why?
Because this kid said those things...
It can't be helped, let them in.
In exchange...
If you try anything funny...
You understand, right?
What will happen to your mother...
37.8 degrees Celsius, huh?
Your fever isn't going away.
Idiot, how could a fever go away in a mere hour?
You already gave the brat medicine, so just leave him alone...
And fix me some lunch!
Then, Conan-kun, I'll make you some congee.
Hey, can I ask something...
Did Mitsuhiko and the others call?
No, they didn't.
Did you make plans with them?
I made plans to play karuta cards with them...
Well, you'll have to pass that up today.
I'll bring you some delicious congee right away.
Well, I guess they didn't call back because they
don't want to disturb me due to my cold.
And this case can be easily resolved once they call the police.
It can't be that they're trying something risky like entering the
place where the weird folks claiming to be his real parents are...
Haibara would never allow it, would she?
Maybe no one's home?
Like Conan-kun said, it'd be best if we called Detective Takagi.
But if he's wrong, we're the ones that'll get scolded!
Well, if it isn't the children from earlier!
What's wrong?
Is Masao-kun here?
Yeah.
Could it be that my child...
These guys really are people I don't know!
Said things like that earlier and made you feel uneasy?
Hey, you need to apologize.
These children took-you seriously, see?
I am sorry for telling a lie...
Well, it seems my child is sorry about lying.
Please forgive him.
Goodbye, then.
Hold it!
We actually want to la with Masao-kun.
Do you mind?
I'm sorry.
My child and I will be going out this evening.
Then, how about karuta-grabbing?
Rule: When a proverb is read, players need to
grab a card indicating its first syllable.
Ayumi happened to bring the karuta cards here!
If it's karuta, we can play at home!
Let's play together until it's time for you to head out!
But, my child is not good at karuta...
I...
I'm very good at grabbing karuta cards!
I haven't lost to anyone yet!
Masao!
Then, if you'll excuse us.
Excuse us!
Wait, what are you guys...
Although it's the same condo as Ayumi's place...
It looks like a completely different room
when you have different furniture!
So true!
All right!
Let's play karuta over there!
Then, please go home after you've played one round.
All right!
Then let's get ready.
Who has the cards?
Ayumi-chan, right?
Here.
Thanks.
Well, who's reading the proverbs?
There isn't a single trace of the room being ruffled through.
So it looks like they didn't come to
his home to search for something.
However, why did Kudo-kun tell us to call the police?
What could he possibly discern from that video call?
Huh, this door is locked!
Isn't this the restroom?
My husband is inside!
His stomach has been acting up, so he's been inside for a while.
There's another restroom in the back.
Use that one instead.
Hey, Uncle!
Sorry, I didn't mean to rush you!
Oh, don't worry about it.
If I were to shoo those brats off, they'd
probably go and call the police.
So I'll just be patient and let them play one round of karuta.
However, if you try to make so much as a peep...
Instead of grabbing karuta cards, I'll be grabbing your life!
Well, let's move on.
The dog that trots about finds a bone.
inu mo arukeba bou ni ataru
Got it!
Ayumi-chan did it again!
How awesome, you've grabbed six cards already!
Last night I had my parents help me practice.
On the other hand, you still have zero cards, huh?
I just haven't gotten going yet...
Now, let's keep the ball rolling.
All right, I'm gonna grab the next one!
Haste makes waste.
seife wa-koto wo shisonjiru
Yes, this one!
Evidence speaks louder than words.
ron yori shouko
Add insult to injury.
nakittsura ni hachi
Got it!
On to the next one.
A hated child thrives better in the world.
nikumarekko yo ni habakaru
I was the first to take this!
Liar!
I was faster than you!
What was that—I was faster!
Well, why don't you guys sort it out by rock-paper-scissors?
No way!
I'll never let you have it!
Because this m card is my car!
You mean, "A hated child thrives better in the world" is your card?
Since this is Masao-kun's first card, why don't you let him-have it?
Fine.
A card he'd never let go...
Is he trying to form a message with
the characters on the karuta cards?
Take out that towel!
It's the towel with a horsehair crab from Lake Suwa on it!
ta o ru ke ga ni su wa ko
I see, so that's what he meant.
Hey, if we don't decide on a strategy soon...
They'll be back before we know it!
Whose cell phone is that?
Don't tell me!
GRABBING KARUTA CARDS IN DIRE STRAITS
(PART TWO)
Horsehair Crab
Next Conan's Hint
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Since crabs are
hard to eat...
Here, open wide!
Ahh...
No, no, I'll eat
it myself...