It's still early in the year and yet I caught a cold.
Sheesh, talk about bad luck.
Since we had made plans to play karuta cards at
Ayumi-chan's place, Mitsuhiko and the others called me.
At the same time, a boy named Masao, who's living on the
same floor in Room 2806, and his parents interrupted us.
After seeing those three via the video call, I saw
through the fact that they weren't his real parents...
And urged Mitsuhiko and the others to
contact the police before«ending the call.
Although Conan-kun said something
like that, is that really the case?
In order to confirm that, we have no
choice but to barge into that family.
Our excuse was to play karuta cards with Masao-kun.
However...
Despite the fact that he bragged about being good
at grabbing karuta cards, he couldn't grab any!
He finally grabbed his first card marked with
ni, but got into a tug-of-war with Genta-kun...
And insisted that "a hated child thrives better in
the world" was his card—how bizarre is that?
Wrong.
He was trying to use the karuta cards to tell us something.
What might that be?
I Love You Miss Mystery —
the one now in an endless labyrinth
Let's embrace this love and solve the puzzle right now
If all cases were men...
I suppose-the invisible mysteries would he women.
A message in dire straits.
What is the truth portrayed by the karuta cards?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
(PART TWO)
GRABBING KARUTA CARDS IN DIRE STRAITS
Now, on to the next one.
tsuki to support
Different/as chalk and cheese.
atama kakushite shiri kakusazu
To hide your head but not your rear.
There!
oni ni kanabou
Like carrying a big stick.
GET!
Next one...
ten shtru chi shiru
Heaven knows and earth knows.
Hiya!
uso kara deta makoto
Many a true word is spoken in jest.
This is it!
Only five cards left.
Let's move on.
hana yori
Praise is not pudding.
GET!
My seventh card!
There are only four cards left, and since you only have four cards...
It means you can't beat me!
No...
If Masao-kun manages to take all four of the remaining
cards, he'd turn the tables and win.
Mommy, restroom!
The game is about to end, so just hold it.
Restroom!
Can't hold it!
It can't be helped.
Fine, Mommy will go with you, okay?
Masao-kun...
You can't go to the restroom on your own?
Yeah...
My child has claustrophobia, so he needs me by his side.
Say...
Take out that towel!
ta o ru ke ga ni su wa ko
The towel with a horsehair crab from Lake Suwa!
I can't do it without that!
Geez...
Stop saying selfish things.
Well, let's get going.
What do you think about that mother and child?
I think they're really related.
Because he said "Mommy, restroom" like a spoiled child.
You wouldn't call a bad person "Mommy", after all.
It could also be that he was forced to call her that.
I do think it's unusual for that mother
to stick around Masao-kun nonstop.
Yeah.
As if she's monitoring his every move
so that he can't try anything funny.
So, were they indeed?
The key to support or reject that theory is what Masao-kun had...
The ru and ko and ni and te...
Those four cards might be our key.
But what on earth does "ru ko ni te" mean?
Maybe we should rearrange these to form a word?
I don't think we should.
The first card he took was ni, but he deliberately
placed it so that it's the third card from the top.
Then, you mean this is the correct order?
Yeah, I think...
His attempt to go to the restroom, as well
as evacuate the mother from here...
Could be an effort to buy us time in order to solve this code.
But I don't understand its meaning.
If we read it backwards, "te ni ko ru" won't work either
And to begin with, even if the mother and father are fakes...
I can't figure out the reason why they'd
be staying here, acting as his parents.
If they're kidnappers, they should've already moved to another place.
If they're robbers, they would've pretended
no one's home instead of letting us in.
In that case...
Let's call Conan-kun and ask him about this!
If we do that, wouldn't we be able to know the truth?
But, Conan-kun...
I bet he's asleep because of his cold.
However, if that mother is really a fake, wouldn't it be dangerous?
We have no choice.
In that case, let's text him.
If he still has the strength to get up
arid read my text, he'll reply soon.
And if he doesn't, it means he's still asleep.
What are you going to write in your email?
The sequence of events leading to our visit to Masao-kun's place.
I don't know why, but...
Edogawa-kun suspected that those three people weren't
biologically related just by looking at the video call...
And he told us to call the police.
But we had doubts about that deduction, so we asked the
neighbors of Masao-kun, who's living in Room 2806.
The lady in Room 2807 said...
Masao-kun's family just moved in and that she
hasn't met with his parents, didn't she?
She did say that she knew the previous resident of this room!
Yeah, formerly employed by the Isobe Corporation,
which is now under suspicion of tax evasion.
And the name was Uemura-san.
The mister from Room 2805 also said
he'd never seen Masao-kun's parents.
Come to think of it, he also said that he saw Producer
Hida from Nichiuri TV about two weeks ago.
He saw the producer going into Room 2806.
But, that producer later had a traffic accident...
And was in critical condition until yesterday.
The matching statement of the two neighbors was...
That Masao-kun is a prankster...
And a big liar on top of that.
As such, we came to Masao-kun's place to ascertain the truth...
With an excuse of playing karuta cards.
Then Masao-kun left us the four cards he took—ru, ko, ni, te...
While going to the restroom with the mother, and here we are now.
Shouldn't we write about the towel as well?
If I recall...
He said "I can't go to the restroom without the towel
with a horsehair crab from Lake Suwa on it".
That's right.
Sending...
However, that was a very mismatched towel.
Because you'll never find horsehair crabs in a lake.
Is that so?
Horsehair crabs only live in the sea, you know.
su u/a ko
Lake Suwa...
ke ga ni
Horsehair crab...
ta o ru
Towel...
I can't do it without that!
I see...
So that's what he meant.
Hey, Haibara?
Don't tell me...
You already figured something out?
How'd you know?
Because you just showed the same expression as Conan-kun!
How rude...
But, it's true that I've figured it out.
That he was right all along!
Conan-kun was right, you say?
So the man and woman just now really are bad guys?
Yeah.
Pretending to be Masao-kun's real parents...
They're up to no good, don't you think?
But, how did you figure that out?
It's the karuta cards Masao-kun collected.
The four cards—ru, ko, ni, and te—told us so.
Which means, in order to only collect those four cards...
He had positioned those cards beforehand so
that they would've been easy for him to grab.
Then he headed to the restroom with the
woman who was faking as his mother.
It was all to have the rest of us figure out...
The "ru ko ni te" code he had constructed!
Well, unfortunately the first ni card he tried to grab...
I was the first to take this!
No way, I'll never let you have it!
Because this ni card is my card!
Resulted in a tug-of-war with Kojima-kun.
But what does it mean?
The "ru ko ni te".
Masao-kun told us, didn't he?
The key to solving the code.
By saying "I can't do it without that!"
Could you mean...
The towel with the horsehair crab from Lake Suwa?
Yeah.
Lake Suwa, horsehair crab, and towel all have three syllables.
su wa ko ke ga ni ta o ru
Change the middle syllable of each—wa, ga, and o...
Into the particles wa, ga, and o...
And think along those lines.
What are "particles", anyway?
Do you mean "party girls"?
They are words between nouns or in connective sentences
that show relation or attach meaning.
For example...
GENTA-KUN IS A BOY
wa
Genta-kun Is a boy.
Like that.
I see!
"su wa ko" should be...
"su IS ko"...
So isn't it telling us that su IS represented by ko?
Then, "ke ga ni"...
Means to treat ke AS if it were ni, right?
In that case, "ta o ru"...
Means ta was changed INTO ru!
Yeah.
So taking that into account...
Try reading the four characters—ru, ko, ni, te.
Leaving the last te, which doesn't fall under any of the rules, as it is.
We make the first ru INTO ta...
And the next ko IS actually su...
And if we think of the third card, ni, AS ke...
It means ".HELP"!
That's right.
Those two pretending to be Masao-kun's real parents...
Are bad guys scheming who-knows-what.
So Masao-kun is appealing to us for help.
But wait...
This wouldn't be another lie again, would it?
He's got a point.
It's possible this could be an elaborate prank.
Fools.
Would he have used a code like this that he couldn't
be sure we'd be able to solve as a prank?
This is a code made so that the woman
faking as his mother wouldn't catch on.
Plus, that child...
When we were about to be turned away at the door...
He was frightened.
But...
Where could Masao-kun's real parents be, then?
I don't know about his father, but...
As far as his mother, I can make a fair guess.
For real?
Masao-kun...
Said something odd besides "the towel of the
horsehair crab from Lake Suwa," didn't he?
Something odd?
That's right, didn't he say he was good at karuta
cards, but turned out to really suck at playing?
The reason for that was just because he had
to collect those four cards and nothing else.
Could it be...
When he was going to the restroom and said,
"Mommy, restroom!" in a spoiled tone?
That was also only because he had wanted to get that
woman away from here and have us solve the code.
But, even if he hadn't deliberately said that...
Don't you think that woman would've
accompanied Masao-kun anyway?
That's true...
If she had let Masao-kun leave by himself,
he might've taken the chance and fled.
So he purposely said "Mommy, restroom!" in order to make us...
Connect that phrase with the "HELP" we figured out earlier.
Connect them?
Mommy...
Restroom...
Help...
Could it be!?
That kid's mother!?
They locked her in the restroom!?
No way!
Although we lack solid proof, if we think of it that way...
It'd make sense that the man faking as his father
has been inside the restroom this whole time.
Then, indeed...
We should've just called Detective Takagi in the first place!
Yeah.
Just as that cold-ridden detective...
Had instructed.
You must be sweating up a storm.
I brought a change of clothes...
Conan-kun?
But with that fever...
Where could you have gone!
Sorry,
I'll be back soon
Conan
Geez...
But then...
How are we going to save her?
The mother who is locked in the restroom.
No, before that...
We'd have to do something about that woman
who's pretending to be his mother.
Hey, if we don't decide on a strategy soon...
They'll be back before we know it!
It'll be fine.
There's no need to rescue or capture anyone.
All we need to do is finish playing this
round of karuta cards and leave.
So we won't do anything?
However...
Soon after we leave, we'll call Detective
Takagi and explain the situation...
And get him to come and save her.
Of course, if you all wanted to show Edogawa-kun up...
And have the four of us make a reckless
gamble, that's another story altogether.
No, no, no, no.
Say.
Whose cell phone is that?
Wonder whose it is?
It's not mine.
It's not Ayumi's, either.
Don't tell me!
Very keen.
That's my cell phone.
I left it there while the line was still connected.
Of course, I was on the other end of the line.
Thanks to that, I know full well...
That you aren't just normal brats...
But bothersome pests that can't be allowed to leave here!
And where is Masao-kun?
I don't see him.
As for that boy...
He's keeping his mother company as
I tied him up in the restroom as well.
Well, at any rate, you guys will soon
join them in that same restroom.
You, girl, with the hair band.
Tie your friends up withthat sticky tape.
After all that's done, I'll tie you up myself.
Well, if you don't like that idea...
We have other ways of rendering you immobile!
You'll be fine.
As soon as we finish our business here, we'll leave you all alone.
If you're lucky and the real man of this household
comes back from his business trip early...
He may even be able to save you!
My, what could it be?
That "business" of yours.
Well, there's no telling, is there?
Hey, hurry and answer it!
Hey, could that be...
Conan-kun, right?
Yes?
I'm from the post office.
Is this Uemura-san from Room 2806?
Yes, I am!
Regarding a registered mail you sent for delivery...
The addressee was unavailable, so we were unable to deliver it.
Yeah...
It seems they've moved...
In that case, since this is registered mail, may I have
your permission to directly return it to you?
Sure, I'm buzzing you up now!
So it wasn't Conan-kun...
I thought he'd come for us after he read the email we sent...
But, I've finally-figured it out.
That you two are trying to destroy evidence
pertaining to tax evasion!
The sender of that registered mail was the
previous resident of this apartment...
The one named Uemura, who was a former employee of the
Isobe Corporation, now under suspicion of tax evasion.
The contents of the registered mail are
probably whistleblower documents...
Or account books with evidence of tax evasion.
It was sent approximately two weeks ago—in exchange
for a reward—to a producer at Nichiuri TV named Hida.
The employee planned to move from here and go into hiding.
But that producer ended up in a car accident, and couldn't
receive the registered mail due to being hospitalized.
Since the post office holds on to mail for more or less ten days...
You calculated the time of its return...
And plotted to pose as Uemura-san who had lived
here before, and snatch away that registered mail.
Then, what happened to that Uemura-san?
Probably confined somewhere else, or already murdered.
And made to look like an accident,
similar to the Nichiuri TV producer.
My, look at you.
So I was right on the mark?
Hey, he's at the door!
Get it from him!
Anyway, as for what to do with you lot...
I suppose we'll decide after we've checked out the registered mail.
Hey, did something happen?
Hey!
Take that!
Hey, Conan-kun, you can't ente-
Cuff that woman, hurry!
Roger!
Co...
Conan-kun!
Where's the woman from before?
I put her to sleep with my tranquilizer watch...
And she's being handcuffed right now.
By Detective Takagi who's dressed in that postal worker getup.
By the way, if you're asking why Detective
Takagi is dressed like that...
You read the email I sent and deduced that they
were after the returned registered mail, no?
Never mind that, how did you figure it out?
That those two-people weren't really Masao-kun's parents.
Didn't you only see them through the video phone?
Ah,-it's because...
When I saw their hairlines, I noticed only
Masao-kun had a widow's peak.
The widow's peak is a dominant trait, so parents without
widow's peaks could never have given birth to him.
Hey, you guys all right?
The bad guys have been caught, so you can relax!
I hope you learn from this and don't tell pointless lies ever again.
Yeah, I'll never tell another lie as long as I live!
Hey, that better not have been a lie just now.
Oh, so the president was indeed arrested.
2 Days Later
Well, since he even went as far as to hire those two
to destroy the evidence, it only stands to reason.
And it looks like Uemura-san who had
been confined has also been rescued.
Isn't this great?
Hey...
Don't tell me you guys...
All caught a cold from me... did you?
My cold is completely gone, though.
Everyone, take care not to catch a cold!