I'm home!
What!?
Hey Ran!
What do you mean you'll be sleeping over at school tonight!?
Sorry...
The karate championship is drawing
near, so everyone's pumped up.
Since there's no school tomorrow, we
decided to stay over night and practice.
We just got permission from our teacher.
Hey, hey!
What about our dinner?
I'm so hungry I could collapse any minute!
Just go to Poirot downstairs!
Get your breakfast there too.
Hey, listen!
All right, I'll be back at noon tomorrow,
so take care of Conan-kun for me.
Hey!
Wait...
She said to eat at Poirot for dinner!
Guess we'll be having boxed meals
from a convenience store tonight.
Because today, Poirot is...
We will be closed
on the 4th and 5th
for personal reasons.
Poirot
That's right, Poirot's owner...
He did say he'd invited the neighborhood
association guys to a hot spring trip today.
I know, there's that Iroha Sushi!
Closed today
Iroha Sushi
And they're closed too?
Looks like he invited a lot of people.
Since there are a lot of shops with their lights off.
Damn, every single eatery in the neighborhood is blacked out!
As it is, there won't be food delivery too!
Just in case, I brought the flyers from all kinds
of eating places that were in our mailbox.
Shall we try them?
Anything that looks good?
Specialty Pizza "Colosseo"...
Miso cutlet "Tsubouchi"...
Hiroshima-style okonomiyaki "Kondou"...
None of which I'm in the mood for.
It's a bit of a distance, but why don't we give this a try?
I Love You Miss Mystery - the one now in an endless labyrinth
Let's embrace this love and solve puzzle right now
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
At a somewhat nostalgic ramen shop...
The smell of a case reerks to high heaven!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
(PART ONE)
RAMEN SO GOOD IT'S TO DIE FOR
So Good It's To Die For —
Ramen Ogura
It's quite a venerable shop, isn't it?
The picture on the flyer was a lot nicer, huh?
Should we look for another shop?
Idiot!
This kind of unvarnished shop is what we call a "hidden gem"...
It must be super tasty and well-loved!
Plus on a cold day like this it's best
to eat some ramen and warm up...
Damn it all to hell...
Guess you have a point...
Hey, c'mon in!
Brrr.
Chilly today, ain't it?
Yeah.
And no other customers?
Whew...
Oh, good sir!
Anywhere but that seat please.
It's the seat of one of our loyal customers.
Well, although he was a loyal customer, he passed away last month.
Ogura Katsumasa (49)
"Ramen Ogura" Owner
It's just my desire to reserve that seat in memory
of him until the 49 days of mourning are up.
Oh, if you say so...
Sorry 'bout that!
So that's why flowers have been left on the table...
A customer?
Two, even?
Guess I won our bet then, Sayo-chan!
Geez...
Oohashi Sayo (28)
Part-time Worker
My part-time pay is low enough already.
Cut me loose once in a while!
Anyway, give our guests some water.
Fine.
What kind of bet were you talking about?
It's about...
Whether the number of guests today
would go into double digits or not.
Dinner time's almost over, and we just finally
helped them make it ten customers on the day?
May I take your orders please?
Any recommendations?
Your best bet is...
Our pride and joy that's so delicious it's to die for:
THE DEATH LORD RAMEN!
We do have the plain o' miso or dipping
ramen on the menu just in case.
But if you somehow want anything other than...
THE DEATH LORD RAMEN!
We'll still serve you as you wish.
Then, I'll try some of that Death Lord ramen...
Me too...
Two orders of the Death Lord ramen!
Aye-aye!
So cold...
It's a good thing we chose ramen like Uncle suggested.
Scumbag, what the hell're you doing here!?
Screw off!
We don't serve ramen to the likes of you!
Hey, hey, what's with using that manner of speech to a customer?
made a special effort to come to this
seedy shop where business is so slow...
Saizu Tokumori (51)
Real Estate Company President
Just to give you fine folks some
much needed profit, you know?
We're losing customers only because those young jackasses
from your place are always causing trouble in my shop!
My bad, they're all brainless, energetic grunts.
But we should've already properly compensated
you for the tableware my boys broke.
That's not the problem!
Well, I did give those boys an earful.
Telling them they should've made sure to
seriously hurt the owner while they're at it.
The hell'd you say!?
I'm joking, joking.
All right, then.
hat seat...
Oops, my bad.
I knocked it over.
Wipe it for me, will ya?
You're the one who spilled it, so wipe it up yourself!
My, what an insolent shop.
It's your fault for putting out shabby
flowers as decoration in a spot like this!
Your order!?
If you're not ordering anything, please go home!
Immediately!
Then, I'll have that "so good it's to die for" thing...
Well?
Have you made up your mind yet?
General?
If you ask me, I won't sell this shop!
Since we and the Haido Shopping Street proprietors have
joined forces and made an unwavering pact recently.
I great example of "ignorance is bliss".
Your own shop is being called the black sheep, you know?
What!?
Before I came in here, I got a haircut from
Cut House Taninaka next door, and...
The owner of that barbershop was complaining too.
He was saying he'd -like for this beat up ramen shop to be
run out of this stylish shopping street since it just didn't fit.
Is that for real!?
My, spewing nonsense, are we?
I only said, "If he remodeled once in a while,
his business would've been more prosperous."
My shop and yours opened on this shopping
street at the same time twenty years ago.
Taninaka Atsushi (47)
Barbershop Owner
My shop has remodeled three times already,
yet this place has been the same, right?
I've been thinking about doing it,
but things are a bit tight over here.
I understand perfectly.
Instigating a falling out between friends in order to wreck
this shopping district was Mr. Land Shark's aim all along.
I'll have the Death Lord.
Aye!
Here!
Thanks for waiting.
Your Death Lord ramen!
What is this?
The bamboo shoots are piled sky high!
I see...
It's a pun on "Death Lord" and "bamboo shoots".
enma
menma
Let's see, the chopsticks are...
Hey mister, could you pass those chopsticks?
Here you are!
Thanks.
Well, anyway, give it a try!
I'll get right to it...
Let's... eat...
Here goes...
YUM-MY!
I've never tasted anything like this before!
Right, right?
These bamboo shoots are especially delicious!
The secret to its tastiness is in those bamboo shoots!
The recipe-is a trade secret, of course.
You're right!
I could get used to this flavor all the time!
Thank you.
We should invite Ran-neechan, the
professor, and the others here next time!
A run-down shop with a top-notch taste?
Guess it won't be closing down anytime soon.
Cheap, fast, and tasty is our motto.
We're definitely gonna keep on truckin'.
Well, that's good to hear.
In contrast, my company is going down in flames...
It makes me feel as if I want to die...
Then, why don't you fold up your fishy business...
And start a new trade instead!?
It's not that easy to make it in this world.
Huh?
Mister, you're left-handed?
Yeah.
But, earlier you wiped up the water
on the table using your right hand.
I was corrected by my parents when
I was a kid, so I'm ambidextrous.
But, I still use my left hand whenever
I eat, or else I feel uncomfortable.
"Ramen so good it's to die for", huh?
If only someone could die after eating this for my sake,
then this shop would go out of business immediately.
Why don't I...
Try poisoning this stuff?
Look here, you!
I've been listening this whole time, but you're
just spewing bullshit and being disrespectful!
Hey!
Let's take it outside!
I'll give you a piece of my mind!
Sir!
Hey, are you even listening?
Hey!
Hey...
An ambulance!
Hurry, call an ambulance!
Hurry!
Yes!
Screw him...
Idiot!
Think we're gonna fall for that same trick again?
Hold on, what are you saying?
I know this guy's game.
Bet he's just faking a collapse in my shop to raise
1 a big fuss about having gotten food poisoning.
Hey, Taninaka-san, give me a hand.
We'll throw this bastard out onto the street and wake him up.
YOU CAN'T TOUCH HIM!
It'd be best if everyone returned to where they
originally were without touching anything.
Also, in addition to the ambulance, call the police as well!
The police?
This man...
I'm pretty sure he's already dead.
"Ramen so good it's to die for", huh?
And immediately after eating it, he
collapsed in agony and passed away?
Yes.
Well, the ramen certainly was good, but...
Who would've thought he'd really die for it?
Don't be stupid!
People don't just drop dead from food that's too delicious!
And?
What's the victim's name?
Saizu Tokumori-san, 51 years old.
He was apparently the president of the real
estate business he managed in Haido City.
It seems he had wanted to buy up and raze the entire Haido
Shopping Street, and build a large shopping mall instead.
The people of this area considered shim to be a major nuisance.
He was considered a nuisance?
Yes.
In order to destroy this shopping street...
It appears that he would frequently use his
employees to purposely disrupt the businesses.
Yeah.
When they came here, they'd find some reason to
pick on one of our customers and start a fight.
Can't even count how many of my ramen bowls they've broken!
It was the same at your shop, wasn't it, Taninaka-san?
Yeah...
Purposely shifting while getting a shave
and causing their cheeks to get cut...
And then raising a huge fuss and demanding
we pay for the medical bill—it's their routine.
How did it go today?
Saizu-san said he had gone to your shop to get a
haircut before coming here to eat ramen, right?
Yes, today it went fine.
So this guy was a so-called land shark?
Yes.
It seems the whole shopping street got together and
planned to file a lawsuit over his outrageous behavior, but...
The attorney representing them died
last month, and the lawsuit was dropped.
He didn't just die!
You could say he was murdered!
Because my dad was trying to stop a fight here while eating his
ramen, and a heart a tack struck him due to his chronic disease...
He was taken to the hospital and died there!
By "dad", you mean you're the attorney's daughter?
That's right!
From when she was little, that attorney
would often bring her along to this shop.
She used to say she'd also open a ramen shop once she grew up.
But I never thought she'd really come and
ask me for any job, even a part time one.
Incidentally, what was your dad's chronic disease?
Hypertension!
His death of cerebral hemorrhage was probably due to
his over-agitation from getting dragged into the fight...
The doctor said so!
But isn't it bad for people with high blood pressure to eat ramen?
My father took medicine to control his blood pressure!
And he was even told by his doctor that it was OK
to eat ramen as long as he didn't drink the soup!
I understand...
The victim's cause of death was poison, right?
Yes.
According to the coroner...
He probably ingested the hydrocyanic poison
through his mouth as he was eating ramen.
So in short, having been in this shop at the time of the incident...
And possessing sufficient motive, the three of you
had the opportunity to poison the victim to death.
Please wait a moment!
Are you joking?
Are you saying there was poison in our ramen!?
We shall investigate that now.
So if you all would submit to body searches, and wait
outside until we finish our investigation inside the shop...
But...
Is it wise to restrict it to only the three of us?
What do you mean?
Before Saizu-san collapsed...
That customer grabbed him by the collar, you know!
Me!?
Oh, that did happen.
Is that really true?
I was just thinking I'd give him a good
talking to, since he was talking bull...
Then, you'll undergo a body search too, and then GET OUT!
Yes, sir!
Brrr!
Geez, on such a cold day, why did I have to be shut out too?
Uncle...
Do you know how ramen is made?
Why don't you ask the expert for that sort of thing?
But...
I see.
If he had laced poison somewhere during the
cooking process, there's no way he'd answer you.
Let's see...
What I usually see on TV is to boil the noodles
upon receiving an order from the customer...
And then add the sauce and stuff
like seasoning in the ramen bowl...
Then, after that, was...
You'd put soup into the bowl!
Next, you drain the noodles and put them into the bowl...
And then finish it off with garnishes such as roast
pork, eggs, bamboo shoots, and green onions.
Well, in the case of my shop, Sayo-chan
is the one who does the garnishing.
In short, if it had been you or Sayo-san...
Either one of you could have laced it
with poison at your leisure, right?
Well, I guess that'd be the case...
But we never laced anything with poison!
Oh, really?
Damned straight!
Say, say, mister...
Did you eat ramen with the late Saizu-san often?
Every once in a while.
In that case...
Is there anything Saizu-san really likes that he'd
definitely eat up before he even touched the noodles?
Like bamboo shoots or eggs.
Beats me...
I've never actually looked at how he ate.
Then, what about any habits he has when he eats ramen?
Habits?
Like, I was thinking if he always touches something out
of habit, it'd be easy to just apply the poison there.
Why are you asking me that?
Because you were the only one, mister.
The only person who didn't get close
to Saizu-san nor Saizu-san's ramen.
You're right...
Since you guys were sitting in the seats between me and him.
Yeah, and if I recall, the closest you ever got to Saizu-san...
Was when you held out the chopstick stand to us, but...
Saizu-san didn't use those chopsticks at all.
But, I wonder why we didn't have any
chopsticks in the stand in front of us?
Because there was a customer who dropped that
stand, and scattered the chopsticks all over the floor.
And before I could refill it with some
replacement chopsticks, you guys came.
Unsurprisingly, the customer was one of Saizu's subordinates.
We made sure to charge him for the chopsticks!
Then, is refilling the chopsticks your duty, Sayo-san?
That's me all right, but...
I never touched the chopsticks that man used.
Since that seat was my dad's reserved seat...
There weren't really any customers who sat there.
Then, that means the loyal customer
who died last month was indeed...
Yeah, it was that attorney.
Saizu-san sat in that seat without taking no
for an answer, does he always do that?
Almost always.
After he found out it was the lawyer's seat, he'd
purposely sit there as a form of harassment.
In short, Saizu-san sitting at that seat was something
that could've been foreseen to some extent?
If that's the case...
Among those three who were in the shop at that
time and had the chance to poison Saizu-san...
Who on earth did it?
A poisoning trick beyond our expectations...
I shall clear up our cloudy field of vision and expose the truth!
(PART TWO)
RAMEN SO GOOD IT'S TO DIE FOR
Glasses
Next Conan's Hint
Conan-kun, you look
exactly like little
Shinichi when you
take off your glasses!
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Of course...