Due to Ran's absence, Uncle and
I wound up eating out for dinner.
After seeing some flyers, we decided to
head to Haido City for some ramen.
Flaunting a "Good it's To Die For" slogan, will
this shabby-looking shop really be all right?
Not to mention that Saizu-san, a customer who arrived after us...
Was a real estate agent who plotted
to land-shark this shopping street.
Alienated by owner Ogura-san, assistant Sayo-san, and
the adjacent barbershop manager Taninaka-san...
Ogura Katsumasa (49)
"Ramen Ogura" Owner
Oohashi Sayo (28)
Part-time Worker
Taninaka Atsushi (47)
Barbershop Owner
He had soured the atmosphere.
Despite its shabby appearance and hostile atmosphere...
The shop's ramen was one-of-a-kind.
The slogan "So Good It's To Die For" was true to its words.
However, after eating some of the ramen,
Saizu-san suddenly let out an anguished cry...
And actually died.
The cause of death was hydrocyanic poisoning.
Was this murder?
If so, the culprit would have to be someone in this shop.
I Love You Miss Mystery - the one now in an endless labyrinth
Let's embrace this love and solve puzzle right now
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Inspiration hits me when I enter the shop...
The Death Lord ramen shall speak of the truth!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
(PART TWO)
RAMEN SO GOOD IT'S TO DIE FOR
Inspector!
How'd it go?
The investigation.
No poison was detected inside the ramen in question.
Neither was any found in the water the victim drank...
Nor on the decorative flowers at the victim's
seat, nor the glass they were arranged in.
Which means Sayo-chan and I are cleared from suspicion, right?
However...
On the thumb and index finger of the victim's left hand...
And on the chopsticks the victim used, and...
Atop the table at his seat, toxicity tests came back positive.
Well, the poison detected on the chopsticks
and on the table were but a trace amount.
Also...
We found the same toxic powder from
the inside pocket of the victim's jacket.
Would you have any clues?
Such as, if you had seen Saizu-san put his hand in his inside pocket.
Well, can't say that I have.
But if that's the case, wouldn't that man have applied
the poison on his finger himself and licked it?
That reminds me, Saizu-san...
He did say this before he collapsed.
"My company is going down in flames, it makes me feel like dying."
Now that you mention it, that bastard also went on about
how he should poison our ramen and destroy our shop.
That's it!
Bet he was trying to put poison in the ramen
but ended up accidentally ingesting it.
It seems the possibility this was a suicide or an accident still exists.
That's true...
Apologies, but Mouri-kun...
Yes?
Could you come inside and explain everything once again?
Yes, sir!
Then I'll go too!
You can't.
Kids shouldn't get in the way of adults' work.
But...
He's right just let the detectives do their investigation.
It's not something for a kid to see!
Then, if you all would stand by outside for a few more moments.
Wait!
So there wasn't any poison on Saizu-san's other
belongings, besides on his inside jacket pocket?
Right.
We examined his handkerchief, wallet, cigarettes, and lighter...
Even the glasses that had fallen to the ground, but got nothing.
Then, was there anyone among the three who had
anything suspicious on them from the body search?
Like a container that could've held the poison.
There wasn't.
All Manager Ogura had on him were
cigarettes, a lighter, and a portable ashtray.
The part-timer Oohashi-san had a cell phone,
a handkerchief, eye drops, and a purse.
Taninaka-san from the barbershop only had
his wallet, glasses, and the keys to his shop.
And the contents of the eye drops?
We did examine that, but they were just ordinary eye drops.
Incidentally, Manager Ogura's cigarettes were
just enough for a quick puff after closing.
And Taninaka-san's glasses are apparently
reading glasses he seldom wears.
And by the way...
When Saizu-san collapsed, Manager Ogura-san said "Idiot,
think we're gonna fall for that same trick again?" but...
Have there been other cases like this?
Yeah.
Seems it has happened twice.
A fuss over food poisoning at this shop.
The first time, Oohashi-san called an
ambulance and it caused a big commotion...
But it was deemed a malingering by the hospital.
The second time, Manager Ogura and Taninaka-san who happened
to be there threw a collapsed customer out of the shop...
And that customer picked himself up and cursed them out as he left.
Well, I was told that those two customers
were both hired by Saizu-san to cause trouble.
Then, I'll go back inside and continue with the investigation.
Hold on, wait!
I still have questions to ask yo—
Hey, not again.
It's not all right if you don't wait outside.
Boy, you've watched too many mystery dramas!
Think you're like the young Kobayashi of the Boy Detectives' Club?
No, rather than young Kobayashi...
I feel like the one who has seen it all...
Akechi Kogoro, that is.
According to our investigation...
There was no poison inside of the ramen the deceased Saizu-san ate.
Neither did the water nor the glass that was
brought to him before he ordered ramen...
Nor the decorative flowers on the seat where
Saizu-san sat, nor the glass they were arranged in.
Where poison was detected, however, was on the
left-handed Saizu-san's left thumb and left index finger.
Although there was also poison detected on the
chopsticks he used and on the tabletop where he sat...
We can exclude those due to the minuscule amount.
Also, out of Saizu-san's belongings, no poison was on his
handkerchief, wallet, glasses, cigarettes, or lighter.
But we found powdered poison in his inside jacket pocket.
Further, the fact that before Saizu-san died...
He said things like "I feel like dying," and "I'll destroy this shop
by poisoning the ramen," if we take those into account...
Saizu-san would've most likely touched the
poison he put in his inside jacket pocket...
And either committed suicide or was
plotting to lace the ramen with poison.
Thus, this case is not a homicide—
Uhm, Inspector...
Other than on Saizu-san's fingers, wasn't
there poison on the chopsticks and table?
In that case, wouldn't it be too early to
determine that it wasn't a homicide?
Saizu-san was sitting at the seat of the
regular customer who died a short while ago.
And it seems that Saizu-san often purposely
sat at that seat as a form of harassment, so...
Even if his seat could've been predicted
in advance, the conclusion is the same.
I already said this, but the amount of poison detected
on the chopsticks and table was insignificant.
We've no choice but to think he touched
those with his poison-laced hand.
Not to mention, the other chopsticks in the
chopstick stand had no poison on them, right?
It would've been impossible to pinpoint a place on
the chopsticks or table for the victim to touch!
Good point...
Ramen, chow mein...
If you'll excuse me, man...
Mouri-kun!
He's gotten into it his usual trance-like state!
It's just me putting him to sleep with my tranquilizer gun.
Hey, is he all right?
His dizziness looked pretty awful, didn't it?
Almost as if he was a puppet who'd had his strings cut...
Right, a puppet indeed.
I don't mean me, but Saizu-san did have someone pulling his strings.
From the time he entered this shop, it was
as if he'd been possessed by a devil...
To apply poison to his own finger, and then bring it to his mouth.
Just as the culprit among us expected!
Hey, are you telling me that one of these
three is a hypnotist or something ofithe sort?
No, to say that he had been possessed
by a devil was just a metaphor.
Thee truth is, the culprit took advantage of the
fact that people under a certain condition...
Would invariably do something specific upon entering a ramen shop!
"Invariably do something specific"?
Don't tell me you mean every customer that enters a
ramen shop will put their hand into their inside pocket...
The poison in his inside pocket was a fake planted
by the culprit, in order to make it look like a suicide.
The culprit probably prepared something very
similar to one of Saizu-san's belongings...
Applied poison on it, and switched the two
during the confusion after the incident.
By "switched," you mean...
Right.
I bet the culprit still has it on them.
Saizu-san's item with the poison on it!
Then, we'll check them again...
There's a way to figure it out soon even without doing that.
Just have them use those items the
same way Saizu-san did, right now!
I see.
If forced to use an item of Saizu-san's, which the culprit
wasn't used to using, they'd likely give themselves away, yes?
Right.
If I recall, all three people have something...
That duplicated what Saizu-san had.
Manager Ogura had cigarettes and a lighter.
Sayo-san had a handkerchief.
Taninaka-san had a wallet and glasses.
Then...
Let's have Manager Ogura light one of his cigarettes...
Sayo-san fold her handkerchief...
And Taninaka-san, for the time being, put on his glasses.
Of course, in the same manner as the left-handed Saizu-san...
With their left hands.
All right, everyone, if you would please.
But, see here...
You said the culprit would be revealed this away, but...
Since we're originally right-handed...
No way we could do it well with our left hands...
Ah-le-le?
What's the matter, sir?
Your glasses are crooked!
Like I said, I can't really put them on correctly with my left hand...
It's because you're not firmly holding the connective
point where the frame and temple meet, like this.
So can you try putting them on again?
I've got no choice...
There you go again!
You're grabbing onto the end of the temple!
Why aren't you holding over here?
It's just...
Or you just...
Won't hold it there?
Since that's where the poison is?
Takagi-kun, check those glasses.
Yes, sir!
If you would please.
But, isn't this strange?
Since Taninaka-san came into this shop, he
never even came close to that Saizu bastard!
That's right!
In between Taninaka-san and that man was the little boy's group.
No way he could've ever touched, or
even come close to that man, is there?
So, how on earth could he have laced poison onto his glasses!?
She's right!
True, it would've been difficult for him to do so here.
But if Taninaka-san did it in his
barbershop, it would've been an easy task.
Come to think of it, he did say this.
That Saizu-san had his hair cut at Taninaka-san's
barbershop just before he came here to eat ramen.
Yeah.
At a barbershop, it's only natural for the barber to hold
onto your glasses and jacket while your hair is being cut.
For Taninaka-san, there would've been enough opportunities
to poison his glasses and plant poison in his jacket!
No way...
We'll concede it to you for argument's sake, but how
the hell was he able to make Saizu touch there?
Since it wasn't like he was hypnotized or anything...
No way he'd so conveniently touch it...
He definitely would touch it!
Boy?
When in the world did you get outside?
Because when people with glasses...
Walk into ramen shops or warm places, immediately...
This will happen!
Condensation!
And, if your glasses cloud up...
Normally you'll do this.
I see.
If his glasses clouded up due to condensation, he'd take them
off in order to wipe it with a handkerchief or something.
That's when the poison got onto his fingers!
However, Saizu-san was left-handed.
If he took his handkerchief and wiped using his left hand,
poison should've also gotten onto his handkerchief.
Saizu-san was ambidextrous.
He said that his parents tried to correct his left-handedness.
That's why he used his right hand to
wipe the spilled water on the table.
But he wouldn't be comfortable without
using his left hand while eating.
In short, when Saizu-san entered this shop...
He took off his fogged glasses with his left hand...
And took out his handkerchief with his right hand and wiped them.
Not at all expecting that poison had been applied to his glasses.
But, if he had used his left hand to take out his handkerchief...
That's possible.
Since Saizu-san was ambidextrous, there's an equal
chance for him to use either hand to take it out.
No.
The handkerchief was inside his jacket's left chest pocket.
Since he's ambidextrous, he'd use his right
hand to take it out since it'd be easier.
As for the tabletop having traces of poison, it was because
he touched it with his left hand while seating himself.
Then, as he was ready to eat ramen and took chopsticks from
the chopstick stand, some poison also got onto there.
As he used his mouth to break apart those
chopsticks, poison stuck onto his lips and teeth...
As soon as he slurped up his ramen, the
poison entered his system just like that.
Incidentally, the reason Taninaka-san passed the chopsticks
to us is because he didn't want Saizu-san to do so.
If he had used his poisoned hand to pass the chopsticks
to us, we might have also been poisoned to death.
So you're saying that he came to the shop to make sure
no innocent customers would get dragged into it?
But wait...
Just when could Taninaka-san have switched the glasses?
If he hadn't switched them, the trick
would've been found out in no time!
Switching the glasses was done...
When Manager Ogura and Taninaka-san were about
to throw the collapsed Saizu-san out of the shop.
At that time, upon Saizu-san's collapse, the
glasses flew to the ground near his legs.
ForTaninaka-san, who had squatted near Saizu-san's
legs in order to lift the lower part of his body...
He had the opportunity to switch the
glasses and block our view with his body.
However...
Wasn't it only by chance that his glasses flew off?
If his glasses had remained firmly on his face,
wouldn't it have been difficult to switch them?
Of the two incidents of food poisoning
that had occurred in this shop...
The second time, Manager Ogura and Taninaka-san threw the
customer who had pretended to have
food poisoning out of the shop.
So this time, he could predict that Manager Ogura
would do the same thing when Saizu-san collapsed.
That the manager would ask him to
help throw Saizu-san out into the street.
This time, it was by luck that a detective drama obsessed
brat with glasses blurted out, "Don't touch the body!"
But had it not been for that, he would
have plenty of chance to switch them.
After they cast him out the shop, he could fetch
the glasses that had fallen to the ground...
Or he could rush to the unresponsive Saizu-san and do it.
Inspector Megure.
The glasses Taninaka-san had on him tested positive for poison.
It appears that we've obtained conclusive
evidence against you, Taninaka-san.
Hey, hold on!
There's some kind of mistake!
That's right!
Taninaka-san wouldn't kill anyone...
That's enough, you two.
I don't deserve the privilege of your defense.
To kill Saizu in this shop...
And hopefully thereby ruin this shop was my plan!
I thought that no one would come to a ramen shop
where someone had been poisoned to death.
But, why'd you do that?
Haven't we gotten by pretty well these twenty years as neighbors?
"Gotten by pretty well"...
In these past 20 years, just what have you achieved?
We worked our rears and souls off in order to raise money, all for
the sake of making this Haido Shopping Street a stylish place.
But you haven't remodeled your shop even once!
I told you, I don't have the money...
Horse-racing, boat-races, road races...
If you had only let up on those a little,
you could've saved up some, no?
That...
If you ask my opinion, your profit margin
on the ramen was way too low!
Without raising the price, you even hired a part-time worker!
You just don't have any business sense!
Saizu said it, right?
That the people of the shopping street
were calling this shop the black sheep.
That was actually true.
They asked me many times...
If I could be the one to tell you...
"Please either remodel the shop or leave!"
Then, why didn't you tell us that outright?
If you had, our owner could have...
I couldn't tell you...
Because I loved the ramen here.
Without regard to profit, you steadfastly
kept the same taste and price.
Your spirit as an owner radiated.
All right, we'll get the rest at the station.
This is my heart talking now, but I believed m you guys...
With your ramen, even if you moved elsewhere...
You'd definitely keep on prospering...
One month later...
Barbershop Taninaka and Ramen Ogura were both demolished.
And the ramen that was so good it was
to die for vanished from Haido City.
Then...
'Ello!
Hey, welcome!
Oh, it's you guys!
Welcome!
I hear you're a well-known detective here in Beika City!
Yeah, sort of...
Shouldn't I be well-known throughout the nation?
Your shop is new, but things look
exactly the same as they were before!
Something did change.
The signboard in front!
The owner arranged it to suit the latest trend!
The signboard?
So WICKED It's To Die For —
Ramen Ogura
Fo' Sho'
"So wicked it's to die for"...
A fatal fall incident at the haunted hotel.
Is this a suicide or a homicide?
That intriguing someone finally takes the stage!
DEDUCTION SHOWDOWN AT THE HAUNTED HOTEL
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Elevator
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Next time we have a
new detective-like
character!
But aren't I more
than enough!?
No, not at all...