But Ran, you really are unrivaled!
Having won the Kanto Karate Championship and all!
It was all thanks to the "Rounding Heel
Kick" Kazumi-senpai taught me!
I feel sorry for her opponent...
Well then, today I'll treat you to the cake buffet at
Haido Hotel as promised, so eat and get stronger!
I'll be sure to eat a lot and get super, super strong!
Won't you get fat instead?
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Yet another rival for Shin'ichi?
A handsome detective's mysterious appearance!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
DEDUCTION SHOWDOWN AT THE HAUNTED HOTEL
(PART ONE)
So?
What did Shin'ichi-kun say?
When you told him about your victory...
You also gave him your answer to that, right?
What answer?
Hel-lo!
The answer to that guy's confession in London!
I did inform him about my victory, but...
Not my reply to that...
Since I also only reported my victory through email...
I guess I just feel uneasy talking to him directly...
"WHAT THE FLIPPING HECK, LADY"
Don't you realize how many days it's been since then!?
Well, how many days...
I bet Shin'ichi-kun is now like...
That Ran, why hasn't she responded to my feelings?
Don't tell me she has someone else in her heart?
Oh no, if that's the case, I'm doomed!
No choice but to cry!
"Cry until these tears are used up!"
He's probably depressed with those thoughts.
No way...
C'mon, you think I'm like that?
If you take it too slow, Shimchi-kun may have a change of heart!
His attitude is kind of uh-uh, but he's surprisingly popular, see?
"Uh-uh"...?
One day, a powerful rival may suddenly appear, you know?
Pervert!
This guy's a groper!
No, I'm not...
Don't act all innocent!
You touched my butt just now!
Ran, it's payback time!
Wai—
I'm done for if I get hit!
As expected of Kanto's champ.
Great moves.
Jeet Kune Do...
Ran...
Sonoko, stay back.
This pervert is strong.
If you would let me explain!
I'm absolutely...
This person's not a pervert.
Because I saw it!
I saw how that person seized the hand
responsible for touching Sonoko-neechan's butt.
And then that's how Sonoko-neechan mistook that person's hand...
For this.
No...
So the pervert...
WAS YOU!?
I'm so sorry!
Forgive me!
Never show yourself again, dumbass!
I'm so sorry!
I almost kicked you without even making sure...
No problem, no problem.
I'm just glad we've cleared up our misunderstanding.
On second look, what a hot guy!
Besides...
Since you're my type...
I'll forgive you.
What the hell was that!?
The pervert's victim was me, you know...
Just joking.
Where you headed?
To Haido Hotel.
What a coincidence.
I'm headed to that hotel too.
Are you really?
You'd better not be making that up, jerk!
Thank you for earlier...
Little boy.
Haido Hotel
You have no vacancies?
How come, I made a reservation, you know
My sincere apologies.
We should have declined, but our oversight caused the problem.
Well, it sure seems he really has some business with the hotel...
Then, any other rooms available?
About that...
We are currently renovating our hotel annex, so we
have fewer rooms available and are now all occupied.
Isn't there anything you can do?
Say, let's hurry and go eat some cake.
I'm really hungry.
All Right.
Still, isn't he so cool?
And as strong as you, Ran!
If he fought with Makoto-san, I wonder
whose karate would be stronger?
That wasn't karate.
That was Jeet Kune Do.
Jeet Kune Do
Movie star Bruce Lee took the art of Kung
Fu he had been practicing as a child...
And combined it with boxing, judo, wrestling, savate, aikido
and other forms of fighting to develop this martial art!
But, it has a number of attacks that target vital points
such as the eyes and throat, so it's pretty fierce.
As usual, you know all kinds of weird things, don't you?
Regardless, where are they having the cake buffet?
We've come to a place where there's somehow nobody around.
On the net, it says it's at the cafe on the second floor.
Then, let's go to the second floor and take a look!
There are elevators over there.
Oh, where are you going, little boy?
To the cake buffet on the second floor.
Then, you can't get there using this elevator.
This one goes to the annex.
The annex?
But didn't they say the annex was under renovation?
Sorry for troubling you.
Not at all.
We should help each other when in need!
Hirukawa Toshiko (49)
Housewife
Hirukawa-san!
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
How'd it go with him?
At first he was drunk and shouting curses as usual, but...
After I scolded him severely, he started crying.
He cried?
Yeah.
He said that, after he had sobered up, he'd apologize to
everyone and admit his sins, so he'd like us to go to his room.
Really, now?
But
Could he just be planning to spew nonsense to dodge our question?
In order to get us off his back.
Good point...
He might say that he doesn't remember saying
anything of the sort if we ask him about it later on.
Then, why don't we record his repentance?
That way, the other victims could hear it as well.
But, I don't have any recording devices with me...
Me neither.
In that case, let's take my car and the three of us can buy one!
Since he said it'd be a while before he sobered up.
And we should be able to find at least
one electronics shop in this area, right?
You're right.
No way!
You're cutting off the line for the cake buffet!?
Yes...
More customers than we'd expected
came, so there weren't enough cakes...
Cake Buffet
All-you-can-eat and unlimited soft drinks for 90 mins
[ NOW CLOSED ]
If you're going to hold a cake buffet, you should
prepare a whole lot and go out with a bang!
A bang!
What was that sound just now?
From the parking lot?
Hold on!
This is bad...
Call an ambulance!
What just happened?
We were just backing up the car...
When this man fell from above!
Isn't this...
Him!?
It is!
It's Uesumi!
What's the matter?
Hold on, who's that over there!?
Someone suspicious was on the roof just now!
What?
Do you remember what that person looked like?
I saw the clothes...
It might have been an acquaintance...
Ran-neechan, call the police and keep watch
over this place with the security guard!
I'm going with these people to the roof to take a look!
So this elevator has both front and rear doors?
What are you doing, Hirukawa-san?
Can't I just stay here?
I'm so scared...
No way!
You're the one who saw them, Hirukawa-san!
Shoes on top of a jacket
Suicide!?
Then, what was the person's shadow that Hirukawa-san saw?
The wind making this jacket flutter...
Maybe that's what I saw.
It's all my fault...
I pushed him too hard with my words
No, this was most likely
A murder.
Isn't that right?
Conan-kun...
Murder, you say?
Are you saying you saw someone push him off from here?
No.
I just happened to overhear your conversation stating
that the man who fell to his death was quite drunk.
Due to my line of work, my ears are quite good.
Your line of work?
But, why isn't this a suicide?
Look, his shoes are even lined up properly.
That's just a preconception, you know.
I've seen innumerable jumper suicide scenes up until now, but...
Just about none of the bodies had been shoeless.
You've seen innumerable jumper suicide scenes?
Well, I guess the most influential theory would be
that it's a key plot device in movies or TV dramas?
"If you see shoes lined up on a roof, there's a suicide."
It would be a convenience condition for
dramas to strike that chord emotionally.
Nowadays not so much, but...
The same goes for detective dramas in the past that would show
blood gushing out of the mouths of people who hung themselves.
In reality, blood will not flow out...
But it's easier for viewers to understand
the death, and it packed more impact.
Although...
Having seen those sorts of dramas or movies...
There are cases of those who'd think they ought
to remove their shoes before jumping off, but...
Seeing as how the man who fell to his death had been
heavily intoxicated and requested time to sober up...
In such a groggy state...
There's no way he'd do things such as take his
jacket off and place his shoes neatly atop it.
And even the possibility that some random
person placed this here as a prank...
Must be rejected since the shoes are directly
above where the man fell to his death.
So that brings us to...
No other conclusion than, to disguise it as a jumper suicide
the culprit deliberately lined the shoes up here, see?
Right?
Little boy
Then
Where is the culprit!?
I bet they'll be arrested real soon now.
Since, before I came up here to the roof, I asked the
guard to keep watch over the elevator and stairs.
What's all this?
Who in the world are you?
My name is Sera.
Like this little boy here...
I'm a detective.
There wasn't anyone there?
Are you saying there wasn't anyone at all
except this fallen man in the annex?
Yeah.
According to the guard who had been
watching elevators and stairs...
You all were the only ones who had passed.
By the way, just who would you be?
A detective, it seems.
A detective?
Another one of these pain-in-the-necks?
But, why was this man there?
The annex was under renovation, so nobody should've been there.
The deceased Uesumi Teigo-san was the
son of the owner of this Haido Hotel.
They made an exception and let him use one of the rooms.
In order to avoid the media, it seems.
By "media"...
Is that person famous?
Sort of.
He was arrested in the past for being
the ringleader of a remittance scam...
But was acquitted on insufficient proof...
And is now creating trouble for the weeklies.
But the media caught wind of it, and a huge
uproar about it went on until last week.
Uesumi-san flew off the handle at his media interviewers...
And broke the sixth floor window with a fire extinguisher.
Because of that, guests stopped staying in the annex
and even the hotel couldn't abide him anymore.
There had been rumors that they were using the annex
renovation as an excuse to force him to move overseas.
Yes, we victims also heard that rumor
and that's why we came to meet him.
Before he could flee overseas...
We wanted him to at least give an apology.
Then, were you able to meet Uesumi-san?
Yes.
I was the first one to go to his room, but...
He suddenly burst into tears and said that
he'd admit to his crimes and apologize...
But said he wanted some time to sober up.
We thought we might as well record his repentance...
So the three of us decided to go and buy a
recording device from a nearby electronics shop.
We got into my car in the parking lot, but just as we backed up...
He dropped down right before our eyes!
Just as you backed up the car?
Inspector...
It might be that someone pulled a string or something
that tied Uesumi-san to the car and made him fall.
Was there anyone who touched your car or the body after he fell?
Dunno...
I don't think anyone did.
As soon as this lady said she saw a suspicious figure on the roof...
I immediately went up to the roof with her and the others.
And in the meantime, I told Ran-neechan's group
to help the guard and watch the car and the body.
Right?
It seems the suspicious figure was something I mistook, though.
In that case, there may still be traces of some sort of contraption.
Inspect it thoroughly.
Roger!
But, this is strange.
While I was waiting for the elevator...
I'm pretty sure it stopped on the sixth and second floors.
It stopped?
When did that happen?
When there had been a commotion about a fallen man...
Right after this little boy brought the lady and the
others to the elevator and headed to the roof.
The elevator went nonstop to the top floor
but took its time coming back down.
But, if I recall, there should have been two elevators.
It appears that only one had been working.
Since they figured Uesumi-san was the only one staying there.
Then, it may be that someone else is still lurking in the annex.
Yeah.
The scene investigators are searching every nook and cranny, but...
No reports of anyone having been found yet.
The surveillance cameras?
They're in the elevator and the hallways, right?
About those...
When Uesumi-san wreaked havoc, he
sprayed paint all over the hotel annex...
And even the surveillance cameras were all sprayed over.
They're all blacked out and nothing can be seen.
In short, the inside of the annex is a blackbox...
No one can tell for sure who did what inside of it, I see...
This just got exciting, right, little boy?
Please watch what you say!
A person just passed away, you know?
Sorry...
Anyway...
It seems it's necessary for us to check it out.
The second and sixth floors where, for some
reason, the elevator supposedly stopped.
That had to have been the case!
But, even if you tell that to the police detectives...
Let's just tell them anyway!
What is it?
You see...
It's just a rumor, but...
They said it will come out in this annex...
Come out?
What will?
A ghost, it's a ghost!
At night, people have seen an unoccupied wheelchair that
belonged to an elderly man roaming around the annex!
It could be that ghost was the one who pushed the elevator button...
Now see here...
If no one was sitting in the wheelchair...
How could you know it was an elderly man's ghost?
It was my father.
The one who fell victim to the remittance scam was my mother...
But she collapsed due to the shock and had to be hospitalized, so...
My father deliberately booked a room in the annex so that
he could beg in front of Uesumi-san's room every day.
Saying, "I won't ask you to return the
money, but please apologize to my wife."
But when my father found out about my mother's
death in the hospital, on the evening of that day...
He committed suicide in the room he was staying.
My father had been using an electric wheelchair
on loan from the hotel due to his disabilities...
I guess that's how the rumor started.
Incidentally, what room did your father stay in?
It was on the second floor.
This graffiti certainly is terrible.
No choice but to renovate, huh?
Chiba-kun!
You found anyone?
No, not yet.
Why is there a wheelchair here?
I don't know.
When I found it, it was still moving.
It was moving?
Since there was weird fishing line attached
between the wheels, I checked with the hotel.
They said this was the electric wheelchair that
the fallen Uesumi-san had been borrowing.
So did he have bad legs?
No, it seems he was just using it to cruise around the annex.
What an unbelievable guy...
It's possible that Uesumi-san was the one
behind the aforementioned ghost commotion.
If he had planned to scare the three victims who came to
visit on 2F where the elderly man committed suicide
By manipulating the unoccupied wheelchair
with a fishing line - if we think of it this way...
That would certainly make sense.
Even so, this fishing line is extremely long.
And there are some broken rubber bands at the tip of this.
The footrests have marks indicating they've bumped into something.
The man who fell to his death...
Was the ringleader of a remittance fraud group that
had caused a public uproar —
Uesumi Teigo-san.
Hirukawa-san and other victims from
his scam visited this Haido Hotel...
While waiting for Uesumi-san, who had weeped
and admitted to his crimes, to sober up...
They decided to go buy a recording device for his
confession, and just as they started driving...
Uesumi-san came tumbling down.
On the roof, we found Uesumi-san's
clothes and shoes lined up perfectly, but...
It was actually a setup to disguise this as a suicide...
According to the testimony of this self-proclaimed detective...
After we had rushed up to the roof, he saw the elevator
stopping at 6F and 2F before coming down to 1F.
And a wheelchair still in motion was found on the second floor.
A long line had been tied between the wheels
with broken rubber bands attached at the tip.
Doesn't this mean that the culprit utilized this
wheelchair to make Uesumi-san fall to his death?
But, how did they do it?
Moreover, just who is this guy calling himself "Sera"?
Will Sera's careless deduction send
the whole case down a blind alley?
My last resort is to use Shmichi's voice to solve this!
Why, are you jealous?
He's such a handsome chum!
Next Conan's Hint
I wonder...
Paint Cans
You'll find out next week!