After accepting Sonoko's invitation, Ran and I
headed toward Haido Hotel for a cake buffet.
We encountered a Jeet Kune Do user on the bus en route.
With combative skills that evenly
matched Ran's, who is this person?
At Haido Hotel, the fact that the cake buffet offer
already came to an end disappointed Ran and Sonoko.
Then came a resounding scream.
A man had fallen to his death at the
parking lot behind the hotel annex.
Hirukawa Toshiko-San, a housewife who happened
to be there, said she saw someone on the roof...
So we rushed there as fast as we could.
However, all we saw on the roof were men's shoes and clothes...
Was this a suicide?
No, this was a murder disguised as a suicide.
One more person saw through the disguise.
It was the Jeet Kune Do user from earlier, Sera.
That wannabe claimed to be a detective.
The man who fell to his death was Uesumi Teigo-San.
He caused a public uproar for being
the ringleader of a remittance scam.
And Hirukawa-san's group were victims from that scam.
In this hotel annex where Uesumi-san was hiding...
Rumors regarding an old man's ghost
on a wheelchair were flying about.
Apparently, Hirukawa-san's father who
had been using the wheelchair...
Lost hope at the news of his wife's death
due to her suffering from the scam.
And committed suicide in this hotel annex.
Don't tell me, Uesumi-san was pushed off by a ghost?
Or was it...
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
The truth behind the ghost will betray any expectations.
And the identity of Sera, our new detective, is...
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
DEDUCTION SHOWDOWN AT THE HAUNTED HOTEL
(PART TWO)
This graffiti certainly is terrible.
No choice but to renovate, huh?
Chiba-kun!
You found anyone?
No, not yet.
Why is there a wheelchair here?
I don't know.
When i found it, it was still moving.
It was moving?
Since there was weird fishing line attached
between the wheels, I checked with the hotel.
They said this was the electric wheelchair that
the fallen Uesumi-san had been borrowing.
So did he have bad legs?
No, it seems that he was just using it to cruise around the annex.
What an unbelievable guy...
It's possible that Uesumi-san was the one
behind the aforementioned ghost commotion.
If he had planned to scare the three victims who came to
visit on 2F where the elderly man committed suicide...
By manipulating the unoccupied wheelchair with
a fishing line - if we think of it this way...
That would certainly make sense.
Even so, this fishing line is extremely long.
And there are some broken rubber bands at the tip of this.
The footrests have marks indicating they've bumped into something.
Say, Inspector.
Couldn't the culprit have used this?
Take a look out the window
This is the opposite side from the parking lot where Uesumi-san fell.
They couldn't have accomplished anything even with the wheelchair.
Why is Conan-kun with us?
Conan-kun was among the ones who
came to the annex after the incident...
So I brought him along just in case.
Looks like there's an unfamiliar young man in the mix...
Yeah, a detective it seems.
A detective, huh?
Could it have been your misunderstanding?
Regarding this elevator stopping on the second and sixth floor.
If you think I'm lying, ask the guard and find out.
Because we both saw it when I asked
him to keep watch on the elevator.
So the doors on this side open too?
Yeah.
This elevator has both front and rear doors.
When I asked the hotel staff...
They said'that this side of the annex's 1F and 2F were made
into a Grand Hall-used for occasions like weddings...
And that by making the elevator entrance
and exit on the opposite side...
It was more convenient and freed up more space, so that's why.
Still, it seems that the graffiti here is even more obnoxious.
Yes.
Since this apparently was the floor Uesumi-san had been staying on.
By the way, the renovation workers had been scheduled
to come in one hour after the time of Uesumi-san's fall.
So this is it...
The window Uesumi-san broke using the fire extinguisher.
Looks like it.
Hey, that's dangerous!
The sticky tape on the sheets that had been
covering it has been blown through by the wind.
But, this place is...
Directly above the place where he fell, right?
Don't you think this means something?
On the border between the wall under the
window and the floor, there's a lot of paint.
What's more...
It's entirely dried up.
And these marks seem to indicate
something had been placed atop the paint.
This paint can, perhaps?
There's a dent on it caused by collision.
And there's one more paint can with the same condition.
As far as having marks from having bumped into something,
the bottom parts of those elevator doors have them too.
Hold on, hold on...
An elevator with both front and rear doors...
An electric wheelchair with fishing line attached...
Rumors of ghosts...
And the paint marks beneath the broken window...
I see, so that's how it was!
No doubt the culprit was the only one to have
entered the annex before the incident...
It was that lady named Hirukawa.
Our culprit.
If you would set things up per my instructions now...
And bring Hirukawa-san over here?
You said the case is solved...
So then, you've realized that he committed suicide after all?
No.
Uesumi Teigo-san's jumper suicide was a trick.
And that's why we deliberately had you come to this 6F via
the elevator which was out of service at the time of crime.
Because the culprit used the elevator
in order to disguise it as a suicide...
Or so he says.
He?
I'm...
You're Sera-kun, right?
I mean...
Anyway!
Can you tell us?
Your deduction, Sera-san.
We'll listen and let you know if there are any erroneous parts.
All right, you'd better watch and learn.
Because the trick I'm going to speak of
will be put it into practice right here!
But, why right here?
Even if it was a murder, didn't he fall from the roof?
I've said this before, but Uesumi-san's
jacket and shoes found on the roof...
Were placed beforehand in order to make
this incident look like a jumper suicide.
They were fakes planted there so that we wouldn't know
the actual crime scene was here on the 6F of the annex.
Hirukawa-san...
You did that in order to hide the fact that you used the
elevator and wheelchair to fling Uesumi-san out from here!
Hold on a minute!
When he fell from above, Hirukawa-san was inside
the car in the parking lot with the two of us!
That's right.
So tell me, how could I have controlled
the wheelchair and the elevator?
Sure thing.
Once you pressed the buttons on the elevator
beforehand, you didn't need to stay there...
To be able to transport Uesumi-san in the electric wheelchair from
2Fto 6F, drop him, and then return the wheelchair to 2F.
Although, you did need to have prepared a long fishing
line with several rubber bands attached to one end.
Fishing line and rubber bands?
Well, why don't we hear it from you then?
How one could automatically cause someone to fall to their death...
With this witchcraft-like trick.
Yeah.
First, you met with Uesumi-san who was staying on this
sixth floor, and fed him alcohol until he was inebriated.
Next, you set the completely smashed Uesumi-san up in the
wheelchair he borrowed, in a way that he was hugging his knees...
And brought him in front of the elevator while opening the door...
So that you could wrap the rubber bands attached to the long
fishing line around the mirror near the elevator's ceiling.
Then, you pushed the button for the first floor from
outside the elevator to send the empty cab down...
So that you could measure the length of the line between 1F and 6F.
You then brought the elevator back up to 6F and
at a length about 30 cm shorter than measured...
You tied the fishing line in between the front wheels
of the chair, so that your trick could start.
After reeling the fishing line in so that
it wouldn't catch on anything...
You rode the elevator with Uesumi-san on the wheelchair.
On the second floor, you pushed the wheelchair out the elevator
and steered the wheelchair toward the elevator doors.
You then closed the doors and descended to 1F.
The one who ran into Hirukawa-san as
she got off on 1F was this little boy.
It seems you told him, "This one is for the
annex, so don't get on" or something.
But that was to prevent the little boy from using the elevator.
Because if he did, the fact that a weird line was dangling
down from the mirror above the elevator doors...
And that the other end of the line passed out through
the opposite doors would be exposed.
Plus, the fact that the buttons for 2F and 6F had been pushed...
Would have become an obvious clue.
The second and sixth floors?
Well, "seeing is believing".
Let's go ahead and reenact it!
Ready, Inspector?
Chiba!
Are you ready?
Yes, sir!
I've pressed the buttons for 2F and 6F on the elevator.
I'm sending it up now.
As the elevator reaches the second floor, what's waiting for it is...
The electric wheelchair, which is still moving
forward while being blocked by the doors.
When those doors open, it'll go inside the elevator...
And keep going straight into the doors on the opposite side.
As you already know, this elevator has both front and rear doors.
The doors that open on 2F are on the opposite
sid las those that open on 6F.
Which means the wheelchair that entered on the second floor
Will automatically come straight out when it reaches this sixth floor.
Afterwards, if you use the paint cans and cardboard boxes placed
around the elevator to guide the wheelchair's path...
The wheelchair will keep going in a
straight line parallel to the wall...
Toward the glass window that Uesumi-san
had broken, hit the wall below it, and...
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
No way!
The reactive force from hitting»the wall should
have already sent the dummy flying out!
Perhaps, when the wheelchair headed back to the
second floor, the force of the turn threw him out...
But, according to your previous deduction...
You said the culprit only returned the wheelchair
to the second floor after Uesumi-san had fallen.
Did I say that?
Hey, hey, don't tell me this wannabe truly didn't figure it out?
But I'm in a bind.
It's too abrupt to call Sonoko now and
put her to sleep for my deduction.
And making Inspector Megure or Detective Takagi the target
of my tranquilizer watch will create problems down the road.
The only one who can appear here unannounced
and yet convincingly shine light on the truth...
And later be able to explain away their
involvement, is none other than...
I got it!
She used her car!
She tied Uesumi-san, who 'was brought here by the
wheelchair, to her car with a fishing line and backed it up...
Sorry to say, but we didn't find any sort of
device or trick at all on Hirukawa-san's car.
And frankly, if she had tied Uesumi-san to her car using the line...
She could've just left him sleeping near the window
instead of moving him with the wheelchair, no?
You have a point...
Look what I've done...
I was too careless...
Indeed, an interesting trick it was.
But it was just an empty theory.
I'm disappointed in you police officers.
To think you'd take a whippersnapper's fantasy as truth!
It was the paint cans.
The culprit used the two paint cans near the window
in order to toss the victim out the window.
That voice... is that Kudou-kun?
That's right!
Once I told Shinichi-niichan about the case
over the phone, he said he figured it out!
Kudou Shinichi...?
Detective Conan Episode 647
Funsub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
Kudou Shinichi...?
And then?
How exactly were the paint cans used?
Kudou-kun?
There is a huge stain from spilled paint beneath the window, right?
And some marks indicating something had been put there.
So please set the paint cans on their
side and align them with those marks.
Do they match up perfectly?
Both of them match up exactly!
Then please hold those two cans in place
from either side with your feet...
Pull the wheelchair away from the window
and set it in motion once more!
Well, the wheelchair...
All right, I'll handle this.
Will it work if I start from around here, Kudou-kun?
"Around here"?
I'm not at the crime scene, so there's no way I could ascertain that.
I suppose so, huh.
All right, I'll let 'er rip!
The wheelchair Uesumi-san had been placed in exited
the elevator on 6F, and headed toward the window.
And when the footrests hit the paint cans that
had been glued against the wall by paint...
The footrests would slip under the cans
tilting the wheelchair forward.
The armrests would then hit the wall,
sending the victim flying due to recoil.
And the culprit, having confirmed the
victim's fall with her own eyes...
Made up an excuse to go up the roof
by mentioning a suspicious figure...
And brought the elevator down from the sixth floor to the first floor.
Chiba, call the elevator down to 1F.
Roger that
Doing so pulled on the fishing line that
had been attached to the wheels.
The wheelchair did an about-face and moved toward the elevator
And crashed into the elevator doors.
As the fishing line that was 30 cm shy kept being pulled down...
The rubber bands wrapped around the
elevator mirror stretched to the fullest...
And snapped.
That's how, when the culprit got onto the
elevator, nothing was left inside of it.
Afterwards, when the elevator reached the
rooftop, she made up some reason...
What are you doing, Hirukawa-san?
Can't I just stay here?
I'm so scared...
No way!
You're the one who saw them, Hirukawa-san!
And she only had to push the 6F and 2F buttons before she left.
Having done so, the elevator would bring the wheelchair
from 6F down to 2F in the same manner as before.
Even if the police found it later...
They would only see it as a random wheelchair that was still
running for some reason, away from the crime scene.
Incidentally, the reason why the paint cans were not stuck to
the wall under the window when Conan-kun got there was..
Because the collision from the footrests
knocked them loose from the wall...
And when the wheelchair turned around, the force bumped them off.
At any rate, if you find fibers from the clothes the victim was
wearing on the clothes the culprit has on, it'd be decisive.
Since, in order for a woman to put a grown man in a wheelchair
she had to have held his body tightly against her.
Of course, if you testify that the man whom you
saw as the remittance scam ringleader...
And you, the surviving family member of his
victim, had hugged in joy after reconciling...
That'll be a different story.
If I had to commit that sort of nausea-inducing
perjury, I'd rather just confess to everything!
That I was the one who put that man in the wheelchair...
And wheeled him straight into hell!
Then, could it be that the haunting rumors were the
result of your having tested this trick out repeatedly?
No.
I only came up with the idea of setting the paint
cans under the window that man broke.
The one who tested it out repeatedly wasn't me.
Before, when I had gone to that man's room to call on him...
It was that man who showed me...
An unoccupied wheelchair coming out from an empty elevator.
Don't tell me, the victim came up with the trick himself?
Yeah.
That man, as he was laughing and ending the call
with his friend who had sent the elevator up, said...
It was a plan to drive out all the pesky media and hotel
annex guests, dubbed "Operation Old Geezer's Ghost"'!
That's why I had him sit in the wheelchair...
In order to make that man understand...
How my father had kept begging for his
apologies even while riding in a wheelchair...
That heartrending feeling of his...
Afterwards, Uesumi Teigo-san's hidden bank account was found...
And by following the money trail, more
scam groups were subsequently arrested.
The case against the remittance scam leader was sent
to the prosecutor even though the suspect had died...
And thus the curtain closed on both
the scam case and the murder case.
Huh?
It was Shinichi who solved that case?
That's right.
Detective Takagi spilled the beans after my interrogation!
How he had seen through the truth like it was
nothing after getting a call from Conan-kun!
Wouldn't it be great if he would also take
the time to give his lovely dear wife a ring?
That reminds me, that Sera person was
also a detective, according to Conan-kun
That person also said "We'll see each other soon" before we left...
I wonder what that meant?
Dunno.
Maybe he's just interested in you. Ran?
All right, everyone, be seated!
Let me introduce to you...
Someone who's joining our class as of today.
Sera-san!
Sera-san?
A transfer student?
What the, she's wearing a skirt!
A girl?
My name is Sera Masumi.
Nice to meet you all!
Gun, bombs, and three suspects.
THE CASE OF BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
(OUTBREAK)
Next Conan's Hint
Signed Books
Look Forward the Next Episode
Next time, I'm taking the leading role.
Please root for me, Sera Masumi!
No, the leading role is...
Mine, you know?