All right, everyone, be seated!
Let me introduce to you...
Someone who's joining our classas of today.
Sera-san!
Sera-san?
A transfer student?
What the, she's wearing a skirt!
A girl!?
Му name is Sera Masumi.
Nice to meet you all!
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
The Detective Mouri Agency is being targeted.
What is the request from the hold-up culprit?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE CASE OF THE BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
(OUTBREAK)
So, hey...
Sera-san, where do you live?
Well, for right now l'm living at a hotel, I guess.
Where are you from?
I'd been living with my parents in America since three years ago...
But I rebelled, saying that l'd rather live in Japan
where I was born and raised, so I came back to Tokyo.
It's easier to be a detective here, too.
So you're a detective, Sera-san?
A female Kudou, then!
Kudou?
The pride of Teitan High here, he's a high school detective!
A renowned detective!
Although, right now he's on leave of absence.
Sera-san sure is popular, right?
You're right.
She's cheery, sociable, boyish, and cute.
On top of that...
She's a Jeet Kune Do-using female
detective who's evenly-matched with you.
Maybe the fact that she's a tomboy too!
Well, the only thing that's left to be desired are her small breasts.
Yo!
I'm sorry for being flat-chested then!
But you see...
My mom's bosoms are pretty huge, so
mine should eventually develop, right?
I guess...
You're right...
Anyway, is it true that Conan-kun is living at Mouri-san's place?
It's true...
But why?
Then, is it all right if I come over?
Sure, but if I recall, today Conan-kun is...
Не just left now?
Was it to that Professor What's-his-name's house?
Yeah.
Since they're going camping early tomorrow morning...
Не said he's staying over there with the other brats today.
Damn, by the slightest of margins?
Who is this girl?
Sera-san, a transfer student.
She said she's a detective!
A female high school detective?
Then, have you heard of the Great Detective Mouri Kogorou here?
Yeah.
Sleeping Kogorou-san, right?
When I checked the Japanese news via the
internet, your name came up frequently.
Sera-san said she was living in America up until recently.
I read that you've resolved tons of difficult cases.
Yeah, got that right!
And the one who's always with you...
Was that Edogawa Conan-kun, isn't it?
Well...
I know, why don't you have Dad tell you all about his cases?
You'd think so, but I can't remember most of them...
As a detective, l'd love to hear some stories...
But it can wait until next time.
Once Conan-kun is around, I'll have you tell me a whole lot!
Then, about your stories...
If you would please tell us every single detail!
The three of us are popular female mystery writers.
Mitsui Tamami (41)
Amateur Novelist
Ans we're friends who met via SNS.
Yuchi Shinobu (36)
Amateur Novelist
We were told that we could hear the Great Detective
Mouri-san's stories if we came here today...
Nihef Sumika (39)
Amateur Novelist
But you didn't hearabout it from Sawaguri-san?
First of all, what is "SNS"?
Social Networking Service.
Those things on the internet where you can
communicate with a variety of people.
Uhm, could that Sawaguri-san you're referring to...
Be the mystery writer Sawaguri Miku-san
who passed away last month?
Yeah, she was also one of our SNS buddies, but...
The one who invited us here today was...
Her elder brother...
Right.
Sawaguri Isao (37)
Sawaguri Miku's Brother
Yours truly.
Oh, Sawaguri-san!
What's going on?
It seems they haven't heard of the arrangement.
But of course.
'Cause I never made an appointment.
Each of you will put your cell phones on
the desk and go to the far wall now!
What's this...
All about?
Don't mess around!
Do it now!
Yes...
I'll take the feet.
You, the gun.
And we'll overpower that guy.
ОК?
Неу!
Once you've put it down, get your ass moving!
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, you!
What the hell is this about!?
Better let go...
I did hear you have a daughter who knows karate, but...
Never thought there'd be two of them.
I was right to come with these strapped on, then.
Now, why don't I hear your brilliant deduction...
Sleeping Kogorou-san!
Then, that detective named Sera...
Knew both your name and that you were a detective?
Yeah.
Well, could just be a fan who became interested
after learning about you from the papers and such.
Besides, you were the one who figured out
the truth of the case in the end, weren't you?
So much for being a "detective".
You're right...
But somehow...
I feel as if that wannabe already figured out the truth, but
got it wrong on purpose in order to get me to deduce it.
Hold on!
You went ahead and began your deduction using Kudou
Shinichi's voice in frontof someone that suspicious!?
Well...
I couldn't think of anything else to do.
Besides, rather than being an enemy...
Somehow it feels like we've met somewhere before.
Perhaps that person resembles someone I know...
That's why the feeling that we've met is on my mind.
What's on your mind, exactly?
No...
Speaking of on my mind: the high school student Ran-san was with!
Yeah, some guy we don't know, right?
Ran-neechan was with a guy you don't know?
We saw them across the street from us when we were coming here.
But, wasn't that person a girl?
Was it or not?
If that's on your mind...
Why don't you call and find оut?
The loud noise just now was from a detective drama on TV...
The volume got stuck for a bit, but we got it fixed...
Yes, I do apologize for the trouble...
All right, that's fine.
Now, Great Detective...
You'll grant my wish.
That's my cell phone...
Shit!
You didn't turn it off!?
If you make the wrong move and turn it off, they'll suspect you.
The other side knows it's turned on and ringing.
So if no one picks it up, they may worry and come to check on her.
I think it's best to just give the appropriate answers and hang up!
Guess so...
But in exchange, if you even let slip one word...
We know already!
Hello?
Ran-neechan?
It's me.
Did I call at a bad time?
It's all right!
It's just that I was in the restroom...
Well it's not a big deal, but Genta and the others...
They said Ran-neechan was walking
with some guy they didn't know...
Walkjng with some guy they didn't know?
I guess you mean the one who just transferred today...
It was me!
Why is this person-!?
So now you know, just enjoy your camping tomorrow!
That should do it, right?
Put the phone back on the desk and move back.
Sure thing.
Regardless...
The request you just spoke of...
Can you tell it to us again?
It was kinda complicated, so I couldn't
quite catch it by hearing it only once.
Hey, so who was that guy?
Please tell us!
Conan-kun!
The cell phone...
Is still connected...
Geez, very well.
I'll explain it once more, so you'd better listen up.
My sister, Sawaguri Miku, was a bestselling author who
won the Naomoto Award when she was still young.
But last month she killed herself by slitting her wrist at
a Gunma hot spring inn, or so the freaking police said.
However, I swear it wasn't a suicide.
She was killed by one of these three
who went to the hot spring with her!
As for something that might be evidence...
I've brought it here!
So I want you to solve it, Sleeping Kogorou-san.
With your brilliant deduction.
Well, you don't have to worry.
Once the culprit is found, I'll kill that bitch and
disappear to the other side myself as well!
What!?
Although, there is a limit to how long I can stay awake.
Come tomorrow morning, these bombs will go off!
What now!?
Detective Conan Episode 648
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
So what the man wanted solved was the truth behind the
suicide of his sister, mystery writer Sawaguri Miku-san?
What's more, that man has bombs on him...
And intends to commit murder-suicide with
the culprit once he finds out who, right?
Yeah.
Also, that man said the explosion will happen the
next morning, so they may be timed bombs.
No way!
Ran-oneesan is there too, isn't she!?
Aren't they in big trouble!?
Haibara, does it say online what hot spring inn it was where
Sawaguri Miku-san supposedly committed suicide?
Yeah.
The date of the incident was last month on the 4th.
And there are photos of the three novelists who went there with her.
Huh, that inn...
It seems that man holding the detective
agency hostage was there as well.
Since the primary discoverer of the body
was him who-was staying next door.
Не got an emailifrom his sister saying "goodbye", thought it
strange and went to knock on her door, but received no response.
Without a choice, he broke the window
via her balcony and entered her room...
То find that it had been enshrouded in steam...
And with her slit wrist soaked in the bathtub, his sister was found
holding tightly onto her room key and cell phone without breathing...
According to his testimony.
The entrance door to the room was not an autolock type,
but the one that requires the turning of the key.
So basically it was a perfectly sealed room...
Then, why did that man insist it was a murder?
Could the name of the inn happen to be Furitsukaya?
Yeah.
So it's the same hot spring inn the owner of Poirot went to
last month with people from the neighborhood association!
Do you know who's in the neighborhood association?
Because the owner sent me the photo
of everyone while they were there.
Then, you guys go and find the people in
the professor's photo except the owner...
And ask about what those three were
up to before and after the incident!
But, what about the owner?
The owner is in the coffee shop Poirot, which
is directly beneath the detective agency.
We'll call the police to evacuate the owner and the customers
so do not go anywhere near there no matter what!
But isn't she something?
Your girl at the detective agency.
She stuck her strap mascot in her cell phone and
pretended that she'd hung up the phone...
In order to keep the connection, right?
No, it wasn't Ran who did that.
Somehow that person is also at the detective agency.
The one we spoke about...
That detective named Sera!
All right, Mouri Kogorou.
Isn't it about time you enlighten me
about the truth behind this case?
Which of these three people here killed my little sister!?
But look here...
According to this copy of the newspaper
the scene was a perfectly sealed room.
What's more, the one who proved that was
yourself, the primary discoverer of the body.
Where are you getting that it was a murder?
I heard a sound...
When I found my sister passed out and called an ambulance
with my cell, I heard a crunchy sound near the window.
So, I checked out the window, and saw some small
glass fragments on the balcony outside of the window.
But I broke the glass on the window
from the outside in, so isn't that weird?
That must be proof that the culprit had hidden somewhere
in the room, waited until my attention was on my sister...
And snuck out from that broken window!
But are you sure those fragments weren't from your
stepping on them before going outside the window?
Since you were in a rush to look around.
The police said the same thing, but I
know I never stepped outside then!
Are you the type to act without considering
the consequences when things get intense?
Yeah, my buddies often say that l'm a quick-tempered guy.
In that case, your deduction may not be completely off the mark.
For these ladies who knew about you...
They could have taken advantage of your apparent personality.
Plus, just take a look.
At the photo I took before the police came.
You see the bloody finger marks on the
bathmat there in front of the bathroom door?
Sure looks like it...
That's probably since my sister had her
wrist slit by the culprit in the bathroom...
And struggled with all her might to
escape and left those bloody marks!
Otherwise, how would the blood
have gotten all the way over there?
But, to suspect those three just from that...
Before the incident occurred, all three
of them had been to my sister's room!
Isn't that right!?
Including Miku-san, the four of us had made a pact...
That the first person who hit one million sales
would treat the others to a hot spring trip.
Since it was Miku-san who had become a bestselling author...
We were hyping over SNS about how we might as well have her sign
the first edition books she'd given us of her debut work at the inn.
That's why we each went to visit her at her room that day.
Though, it seems that the three of us
coincidentally missed each other in passing.
You've brought those books with you, no?
Yes...
Incidentally, how did you get them to bring those books here?
I lied to them about how you and my sister were acquaintances.
Saying that if they wanted to hear about your stories, they'd have
to bring those books as proof they were my sister's close friends.
Here, take a look.
She even dated her autograph.
It's proof that these three met with my
sister on the date of the incident!
In addition, my sister posted live updates via
SNS of what was happening at the time.
Here's а copy of those posts.
However, if these people were all SNS buddies
wouldn't they have seen those posts?
No, my sister used my ID to post them discreetly.
So that those people wouldn't see them.
That reminds me, when I went to her room...
She kept texting on the phone...
So she was actually posting.
Anyway, read it!
Let's see...
"The first one to come pester me for an autograph was Elephant.
"Even though my hair a yet tо dry from
the bath... that pesky Elephant."
What is this "Elephant"?
My sister made a hobby out of comparing people to animals!
Just read on, will you!
"Next to come was Fox.
"Trying to stir up an argument again, freaking annoying.
"I've signed my autograph, so why can't she just leave!"
"Last one was Rat who can't take a hint.
"I'll take short work of the autograph and shoo her away ASAP."
"WTF, she's still here...
"Oh snap, l'm getting sleepy, what should l do..."
And it seems the post send there...
So, you get it, right?
That my sister, who left such posts, wouldn't
have any reason to commit suicide...
And that one of these three here was the
last to see my sister, put her to sleep...
And kill her while making it look like
a suicide —
that goddamned Rat!
Elephant, Fox, and Rat?
We gotta figure out the criteria the deceased Miku-san
used to assign those nicknames or else.
If you want the profiles of those three novelists
there are details along with their photos.
Are those three people that famous?
No.
All three of them merely upload novels online as a hobby...
And are amateurs who occasionally create doujinshi to sell.
They call themselves "novelists" and list
information about them on their homepages.
Mitsui Tamami-san is 41 years old.
Never married, and has been helping at her family's
stonemasonry business; a Taurus, blood type A.
Yuchi Shinobu-san is 36, divorced once.
Has been working at her neighborhood
bakery for close to 20 years; a Pisces, type B.
Nihei Sumika-san, age 39.
Her husband is a seal craftsman; and in her spare time
as a housewife she writes mysteries; a Leo, type O.
Incidentally, I also looked up Miku-san's elder brother Sawaguri-san.
Turns out he was the leader of a survival games team.
The team's name is Green Cap.
A parody of the US Army's Special Forces —
Green Berets, huh?
Just going by how these three people look...
I'd say Elephant would be Mitsui-san, Rat would
be Yuchi-san, and Fox would be Nihei-san, but...
It's too early to say for sure.
Not a lot of info to go on.
As far as those three...
We've brought some answers!
The whole scoop!
You should be thankful to these children.
They bustled about the whole town in the Beetle, gathering info.
So, what'd you find out?
The lanky woman with the glasses is an extremely polite person.
We heard that she willingly tidied up after some kids she
didn't know who spilled shampoo and conditioner all over.
The short woman with the overbite loves hot springs.
It seems she went into the hot springs many times a day!
The most suspicious one is the fat woman.
She was rushing out of the dead lady's room with a pale face...
According to a guy who saw her from his slightly-opened door.
Was the guy who witnessed that in the room
directly opposite from the late Miku-san's?
No, he was in the room next and next
and next to hers on the same side.
When he was about to leave his room, he said that
woman was running towards him with a scary look...
So he immediately shut the door.
We even brought a picture of the
commotion that happened after that.
We're told that it's a picture of when the police
arrived to the scene of the suicide, Room 205.
So no one told this to the police?
Apparently people did, but they were told, "Since the scene is
a sealed room, that was irrelevant" by Inspector Yamamura.
That's right...
The Gunma Prefectural Police have that hack on the force...
Hey!
Why is this phone still connected!?
Damn, he found us out!
Shit...
Trying to play smart with me, little bitch...
You've got quite the nerve, huh!?
You do know what's gonna happen, right!?
Hold on!
It wasn't her; the one who did it..
It was me.
I was the one who made her do it.
I...
Kudou Shinichi, did.
Next Episode
Elephant, Fox, and Rat.
The mystery behind the nicknames.
The blurry truth is at the other end of the gun scope!
THE CASE OF THE BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
(SNIPING)
Next Conan's Hint
Bush Warbler
Excuse me, but plase show me your Sleeping Kogorou thing!
Huh? How could I...
You're on your own.