At the Mouri Detective Agency, a man who
dropped by after following the three ladies...
Intimidate everyone with his gun and
bombs, and besieged the entire place.
Uncle and Ran who were at the scene...
As well as Sera, who we met during the
haunted hotel case, all became hostages.
The man's name: Sawaguri Isao.
Sawaguri Miku's Brother
Sawaguri Isao (37)
He's the elder brother of a mystery writer who killed herself
at a hot spring inn a month ago named Sawaguri Miku-san.
This Sawaguri-san, who refused to believe
that his sister committed suicide...
Ordered the great detective Sleeping
Kogoro to shed some light on the truth.
The three ladies he brought here were all amateur
mystery writers and friends with Miku-san.
Unmarried and helping her family's stone-
masonry business, Mitsui Tamami-san.
Mitsui Tamami (41)
Amateur Novelist
The once-divorced who now works at her
neighborhood bakery, Yuchi Shinobu-san.
Yuchi Shinobu (36)
Amateur Novelist
A homemaker and the wife of a
seal craftsman, Nihei Sumika-san.
Nihei Sumika (39)
Amateur Novelist
Sawaguri-san suspected that one of those three
killed his sister and made it look like a suicide.
The three stayed at the same hotel with Miku-san...
And visited her room in succession to have her
autograph their books just before her time of death.
Although Miku-san had been posting
about what had transpired via SNS...
She had nicknamed the three Elephant, Fox, and Rat, leaving
us wondering who was who and the order of their visits.
The last to have visited Miku-san's room and thought to
be responsible for disguising her murder as a suicide...
Was the Rat, but who was it?
But then, Sawaguri-san announced that once the culprit
is revealed, he would kill her and commit suicide...
How am I supposed to rescue Ran and the
others without having any fatalities?
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Adrenaline races at the detective agency...
Where Ran takes action in a surprising manner!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE CASE OF THE BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
(SNIPING)
Shit...
Trying to play smart with me, little bitch...
You've got quite the nerve, huh!?
You do know what's gonna happen, right?
Hold on!
It wasn't her —
the one who did it...
It was me.
I was the one who made her do it.
I...
Kudo Shin'ichi, did.
Kudo Shin'ichi, you say?
Shin'ichi?
Conan-kun's...
Using someone else's voice again...
Yeah...
All right, it's getting pretty late...
Time to get to bed, you guys!
Just keep going, hurry!
I thought it'd be best if I could also hear the details of
the case, so that I'd be able to answer your request.
Unless, you have any objections against my involvement?
Nah...
With a famous high school detective
coming aboard, I'm all the more assured.
Then, please tell Detective Mouri to take camera phone pictures...
Of all the case-related materials you brought
and send them to Professor Agasa's computer.
You should also send along pictures of
the three books Miku-san autographed.
Also, it'd help if you could put me on speaker phone.
Hey, hustle up and take them!
I know!
Shin'ichi...
Why is he on Conan-kun's phone?
Judging from the monitor here...
The page appears distorted only on Nihei-san's autographed сору.
Does it actually look that way?
Yeah, only the autographed page is wrinkled
as if it were wet once and then dried!
Don't tell me...
It was you!?
It wasn't me!
Plus, if it had gotten wet then, wouldn't
the entire book have become wrinkled?
Suppose so...
Next, about Yuchi-san's autographed book...
It looks like a brand-new сору without any fingermarks or creases.
Is it really a first edition?
Yeah, it does say here that it was from the first printing.
It's because I made sure to keep it safe
given that it's a precious signed сору...
And as for Mitsui-san's, it's a bit torn, isn't it?
It is.
I see the tear mark.
That's because
After Miku-san had finished autographing my book
she was being mean and wouldn't give it back to me!
Being mean?
That day, I upset my stomach and even though I really had to
unload, Miku-san wouldn't let me use the toilet in her room!
She refused, telling me it was because she was going to use it soon.
But I knew she was just trying to bully me...
Since she also lied about having taken a bath in her room
even though she'd just come back from the large baths.
How'd you know what she posted was a lie!?
Because, when I was leaving Miku-san's
room, I accidentally put her slippers on...
And they were soaking wet and warm.
Oh?
When I went to her room, I lined up her slippers as well, but...
They were neither wet nor warm at all.
Are you sure you didn't put your own slippers on?
Since it looks like you have greasy skin.
How rude!
I have dry skin!
What a noisy bunch of old women...
Cheeping and chirping like a bunch of lil birds!
Well, I admit I've also been called annoying by my sister...
So she gave me the weird nickname of "Bushwarbler".
Bushwarbler?
Bushwarbler, Elephant, Fox, and Rat...
I see, I've got it!
The nicknaming scheme of Miku-san!
It seems this'll come to an end even
without having to trouble Kudo-kun.
If that's the case, no doubt the culprit is that person.
Looks-like you've got that face you always
get when you've figured it out, but...
What now?
Even if you've come up with the right culprit...
There'll stili be two corpses hitting the floor in that detective agency.
Hey, what do you mean?
What you just said about how this might come
to an end without having to trouble Shin'ichi...
The reason I propped your cell phone open with
the strap mascot and preserved the connection...
Was so that Conan-kun could learn
about the case and investigate it for us.
The incident happened last month on the 4th, the same day your
neighborhood association went on their hot spring trip, right?
What's more, the inn they stayed at was...
Furitsukaya, where that bomber man's sister, novelist
Sawaguri Miku-san, supposedly committed suicide.
Is that so?
Yeah.
There was a fax with Information about the neighborhood
association's hot spring outing on your papa's desk.
The fact it was left out meant that your papa didn't go on that outing.
Since there were details such as a map to the inn and meeting
places on the fax, he would've brought it with him if he had gone...
And wouldn't have put it back on his desk upon his return, right?
That's why I left the phone connected, hoping that Conan-kun
would get the story from those who went to the hot spring trip.
But for some reason, Kudo Shin'ichi-kun
answered Conan-kun's phone.
Well, I don't know what sort of connection Conan-kun has with that famous high school detective, but...
That bomber guy is convinced that his sister didn't commit
suicide, and that someone among these three killed her.
Не plans to commit murder-suicide
with the culprit once he finds out who.
So at this point, I have no choice but to have him
negotiate with the bomber man and talk him down...
Or so I had thought, but now that's not
necessary anymore —
that's what I meant.
How come?
You see that light outside the window?
That's probably proof that the police have
arrived at the building across the street.
Sniping Support Unit in position.
We've got eyes-on.
And the Takedown Unit?
In position at the agency entrance.
Ready to breach on your order.
Сору that.
Attention, all units.
Suspect is acting alone, however we have intel to the effect that
he has a handgun and a large number of bombs in possession.
Until I give the order, standby but be
ready to move on a moment's notice.
So the police are here?
First to come was the Special Investigative Team made up
of the Criminal Investigative Department First Division...
Abbreviated as SIT.
When hostage-taking incidents occur, they roll out with heavy
equipment, and if the culprit isn't responding to persuasion...
They force their way in and take decisive action.
So even now, they should be on the other side of that
door, on the watch for an opportunity to rush in.
The fact that they're on the roof with the intent to snipe means
the Special Assault Team, SAT, has also come in support.
Did Shin'ichi call for them?
Well, even if he didn't, they'd still come.
Since in order to evacuate the customers from the shop
downstairs, he'd have to explain the situation to the police.
But, judging from how the police
have yet to start talking him down...
It appears they have extreme confidence...
In your boyfriend.
Не likely requested the police not to make any moves and
guaranteed to talk the bomber man down himself, I'd wager.
After all, we're dealing with a crazy man who has bombs
strapped to himself and his finger hovering over the switch.
if they make the wrong move and barge in or snipe
somewhere that isn't a vital point, it'd enrage him and...
He'd press the switch and we'd be blown to smithereens.
In order for that not to happen, he'd either need
to be talked down, or taken out with one shot.
Hey, what's the hold up?
Haven't you figured it out yet, Kudo Shin'ichi!?
I know we already sent them to your computer!
My little sister's posts on SNS just before she was killed!
Those posts told of how my sister let each
of these three people into her room...
And how she autographed first-edition
copies of her debut work for them!
And the posts were...
"The first one to come pester me for an autograph was Elephant.
"Even though my hair had yet to dry from
the bath... that pesky Elephant."
"Next to come was Fox.
"Trying to stir up an argument again, freaking annoying.
"I've signed my autograph, so why can't she just leave!"
"Last one was Rat who can't take a hint.
"I'tll take short work of the autograph and shoo her away ASAP."
"WTF, she's still here"...
"Oh snap, I'm getting sleepy, what should I do..."
And her posts end there.
In short...
It was one of these three people!
The last to come, the one guilty of killing my
sister and making it out to be a suicide...
That freaking Rat!
Hey, you guys...
Didn't I tell you to go to bed already?
Вut, we're so worried that we can't sleep!
And there was something we forgot to mention.
When we went to ask people about the case, most
of the neighborhood association members said...
That about two or three days ago, a brown-haired man in
camouflage had come around asking the same things we did.
That man had shown them a book and
some photographs while asking...
Whether they had seen any of the three women loitering
around the inn with his sister's debut book in hand.
I see.
So he'd already gone around asking for information.
It seems you've also done your own research.
How far have you gotten?
Well, I did sniff out a whole lot about these three.
Nihei Sumika is high-strung and even went as far as to
line up all the slippers of guests she didn't know...
And didn't get along with my sister who was sloppy in comparison.
And since Yuchi Shinobu had been in the hot springs all the time...
Perhaps she was in fact washing the blood
splatter she got from cutting my sister's wrist?
And Mitsui Tamami was seen rushing out of
my sister's room with her book in hand...
By a guest from a room three doors down!
So, hurry up and tell me!
Which one was it!?
The murderer who my sister nicknamed "Rat"!
How is it?
Can you take the shot?
Negative.
The "Detective Agency" sign on the window glass and
Detective Mouri behind it are blocking the target.
Shin'ichi...
Perhaps you're thinking...
"Shin'ichi, why haven't you solved it yet?"
It's all right.
I'm sure he's already figured everything out.
That the Rat who killed Sawaguri Miku-san was
Her*
Namely Mitsui Tamami-san!
There's only one reason why he's not saying it.
Once the bomber man knows who the culprit
is, he'll commit murder-suicide with her.
Looks like we'll have to use an alternative
method in order to prevent having two victims.
Although, it'll only turn two into one.
Say...
That cell phone's been connected for quite a long time.
How's the battery doing?
Shouldn't we connect it to the AC adapter?
You're right...
If I recall, it's in the drawer of Kogoro-san's desk, right?
Did I put it in there?
Hey, take it out now and connect it!
Huh, are you sure?
You don't want to do it yourself?
If Kogoro-san has a weapon or something hidden in that drawer...
Не could counterattack, y'know?
This guy...
Don't tell me!
Out of the way!
I'll find it!
Suspect has moved towards us!
He's in our sights!
It's possible to snipe now!
What?
Do we shoot?
Shoot...
Shoot!
What the hell are you doing?
You wanna die!?
It's chilly tonight, so I think it's best to close the curtains.
Also, the AC adapter is inside the cabinet.
I'll go get it for you.
The curtains are dosed...
Sniping the target is no longer possible!
You...
What were you thinking?
I'd hate to see someone die in front of me is all.
You'd hate?
Plus...
Shin'ichi would never allow anyone to die.
Never!
Now, Kudo Shin'ichi!
I've sent everything you need for your deduction!
Who the hell killed my little sister?
If you still don't know, then I've got no choice.
Hate to do it, but I'll blow this agency to smithereens!
Although all I really want to do is to ice
that freaking Rat who killed my sister!
It's all right.
Please calm yourself.
Because I know the identity of the Rat.
Really?
Yeah.
Don't tell me, he's going to name the culprit!?
Shin'ichi...
I'll start with Elephant, who was the first to
visit Miku-san's room for an autograph.
If her hair hadn't dried from the bath, her
body should've been hot and humid too.
If she were to autograph in such a state, the heat
and dampness would wrinkle the paper, right?
So that means, the Elephant who came first is...
Got to be the one who has the book with the
autographed page wrinkled, or Nihei-san.
Nihei-san has a methodical personality
to the extent of being too high-strung.
Unless something like that happened, I bet she'd
never treat the book roughly nor crumple it.
And when Nihei-san went to the room, she said
she lined up Miku-san's slippers too, right?
The fact that those slippers were neither wet nor warm means...
That Miku-san didn't go to the large baths, but
without a doubt went to the one in her room.
Since taking a bath in her room would
not require her to wear slippers.
Why, then, were the slippers accidentally worn by Mitsui-san
as she was leaving Miku-san's room soaking wet and warm...
Causing Mitsui-san to mistakenly think that
Miku-san had come back from the large baths?
The deal with the slippers was that Yuchi san
came there shortly after taking a bath...
And inadvertently wore Miku-san's slippers on her way out.
Yuchi-san's remaining warm and dampened
slippers were then worn by Mitsui-san.
In short, Elephant was Nihei-san.
Next to show up was Fox, or Yuchi-san.
Leaving Mitsui-san to be Rat, the last one to come along.
I see, so it was you?
The freaking Rat who killed my sister!?
What the...
You're only basing that decision off some slippers?
It wasn't just the slippers.
The nicknames Miku-san gave you
all were in fact based off of colors.
Colors?
In Japanese, there are colors bearing the names of animals, right?
Like camel-color or kite-color.
Are you sure?
If you keep talking, we'll really end up
with two dead people here, you know?
Moreover, right in front of her, who believes in you!
The fox color, or golden brown, would be on
the bread Yuchi-san bakes at her workplace.
Elephant means ivory-color, the color of
the seals Nihei-san's husband carves.
Incidentally, Miku-san's brother Isao-san's nickname
"Bushwarbler" would resemble olive-green.
Taken from the name of the survival games team
Isao-san serves as the leader of - the Green Cap.
And Rat of course means the grayish rat-color.
The color of the stones Mitsui-san's family
stonemasonry business deals with.
In other words, the "Rat" that was the
last to show up to Miku-san's room...
Mitsui-san...
It сап be none other than you.
As expected from the high school detective Kudo Shin'ichi!
Well done.
The dirty Rat who freaking killed my sister
Miku and made it look like a suicide...
Mitsui Tamami!
He's made it clear that you were the one!
No...
I would never kill Miku-san...
Don't play dumb with me!
The famous high school detective is saying you're the culprit!
Вut it really wasn't m—
Any excuses you have I'll hear you out on the other side...
For my sister's waiting...
In the other world!
Well, don't forget, you two karate kittens...
About the fact that I've got bombs strapped to my body!
And that as long as I can kill this bitch, I won't mind dying!
Damn...
Kudo Shin'ichi...
What the hell are you going to do!?
Shin'ichi, please...
Stop Sawaguri-san!
Shin'ichi!
A suicide or homicide?
Or a punishment from the death god?
The signed books shall reveal the truth!
THE CASE OF THE BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
Toilet
Next Conan's Hint
Shall I take the stage from here?
No, it's all good.
What'd you say!?
Let Shin'ichi handle this!
Not you too!