At the Mouri Detective Agency, a man who
showed up after following three ladies...
Intimidated everyone with his gun and bombs,
and besieged the detective agency.
The man's name was Sawaguri Isao.
Sawaguri Isao (37)
Sawaguri Miku's Brother
He's the elder brother of Sawaguri Miku-san, a mystery
writer who killed herself at a hot spring inn a month ago.
Sawaguri-san, who refused to believe
that his sister committed suicide...
Ordered the great detective Sleeping
Kogoro to shed some light on the truth.
The three ladies were all amateur mystery
writers and friends with Miku-san.
Sawaguri-san suspected that one of them murdered
his sister and made it appear to be a suicide.
Soon after Sawaguri-san found out that Ran's
cell phone connection was still alive...
I, having no choice, introduced myself as Kudo Shin'ichi
and formally accepted his request to solve the case.
From the materials and testimonies pertaining to the case
sent my way, I had uncovered the truth behind it, but...
I couldn't and wouldn't reveal it right away.
For Sawaguri-san had already announced that he would commit
murder-suicide with the culprit once he found out their identity.
I had to somehow solve the case without having any fatalities.
However, the police had been steadily waiting
in preparation to snipe down the gunman.
Thanks to Ran's quick thinking, we were able to halt
the sniping, but we couldn't dawdle any longer.
Because if the mystery were still
unsolved by the next morning...
Sawaguri-san planned to blow up the
agency, taking everyone with him.
Thus, I took extreme measures.
It's all right.
Please calm yourself.
Because I know the identity of the Rat.
Really?
The Rat that was the last to Show up to Miku-san's room...
Mitsui-san...
It сап be none other than you.
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
As the path to the truth twists and turns...
Shin'ichi passes down his final judgment!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE CASE OF THE BESIEGED DETECTIVE AGENCY
(RELEASE)
As expected from the high school detective Kudo Shin'ichi!
Well done.
The dirty Rat who freaking killed my sister
Miku and made it look like a suicide...
Mitsui Tamami!
He's made it clear that you were the one!
No...
I would never kill Miku-san...
Don't play dumb with me!
The famous high school detective is saying you're the culprit!
But it really wasn't m—
Any excuses you have, I'll hear you out on the other side.
For my sister's waiting...
In the other world!
Well, don't forget, you two karate kittens...
About the fact that I've got bombs strapped to my body!
And that as long as I can kill this bitch, I won't mind dying!
Damn...
Kudo Shin'ichi...
What the hell are you going to do!?
Shin'ichi!
Please wait.
Shin'ichi?
I did say that the person whom Miku-san
nicknamed "Rat" was Mitsui-san, but...
I haven't said one word about Mitsui-san
having killed your sister, you know?
What?
But, didn't you just say it?
That the "Rat" who went to my sister's room last was this woman!
Yeah.
Then, why!?
If I recall, your conjecture was as follows, right?
The culprit drugged your sister to sleep, slit her wrist, positioned
her over the bathtub in the bathroom and staged a suicide.
After confirming her death, the culprit sent you an
email saying "goodbye" using your sister's cell phone.
Thinkingthe email odd, you knocked on your
sister's door but there was no answer.
You had no choice but to climb over the balcony from your room
next door, and break in your sister's room from the window.
That was when you found her body in the bathroom.
In short, the culprit had predicted in advance
that you would do so, hid inside the room...
And while you were distracted by your sister's body, fled
through the window you broke, according to you.
Yeah, that's exactly right!
Then, after that, where did the culprit
pass through to make an escape?
Of course the culprit went into my room
next door, and just went out the door!
I was in my sister's room after all!
Since when I first went to knock on my
sister's door, I ended up raising-hell.
A lot of bystanders were already there at that point
it would've been easy to mix in with that crowd!
But, didn't you say you heard about it as well?
That a guest three doors down witnessed Mistui-san coming out
from your sister's room in a big hurry with a book in hand.
In other words, the room that Mitsui-san
came out of wasn't yours, but your sister's.
That doesn't seem to fit in with your theory, though.
Не must have mistaken it!
Since that guest's room was three doors away from my sister's, right?
Не must have confused her coming out of my
room instead of my sister's room next door...
No, that wouldn't be the case.
That witness's room was on the same side
as your sister's and was three doors away.
Plus, he said he was about to leave his room...
But as soon as he saw Mitsui-san running across
in a a big rush, he immediately shut the door.
If he saw her from that position, the angle would've been
too narrow, and he only saw her for a split second.
Не wouldn't have been able to distinguish
at all which room she had come from.
In that case, how come that guest knew for
sure she came from my sister's room!?
That's because...
The door to your sister's room Mistui-san
came out of had been wide open...
And he had seen the room number affixed to the door!
Mitsui-san was in such a rush because she
had wanted to use the restroom at once.
The fact that the open door had been closed
later on proves that your sister was still alive.
The doors at that inn are not auto-lock doors.
If your sister hadn't locked the door from the inside...
You wouldn't have gone through all the
trouble to break the window in order to enter.
Then who was it!?
Who was the culprit that killed my sister!?
According to my sister's posts, someone should've been there!
The murderer who was still in my sister's
room until she had gotten drowsy!
About your sister's debut work...
Have you happened to read it?
Nah...
I'm not much of a reader.
I haven't read that yet.
The title is...
The Death God's Funeral Procession".
The main character was a police detective who was
desperately pursuing the shadow of a serial killing fiend.
One day, the detective was visited by a Death God at his bedside...
Who told him, "You won't ever be
able to catch him in your lifetime."
It was only natural...
Since that detective had been the serial killer who unconsciously
wandered the streets night after night and committed the crimes.
The detective, upon realizing this fact,
became tormented by his conscience...
And took his own life following the Death God's lead.
Неу, you're not saying...
Right.
Your sister laid her hands upon her "Death God's Funeral
Procession" for the first time in ages in order to autograph it.
If she uncontrollably put herself in the
place of the main character she created...
And saw a hallucinated image of the Death God in her room...
You сап imagine what your sister might have done afterwards, right?
Don't tell me...
My sister...
K—
Killed herself!?
No way...
It can't be...
That's gotta be...
A lie!
Breach!
Breach the area!
Oh my!
Secured!
All's well that ends well.
Good for you.
Well, that remains to be seen.
What do you mean?
All right, we will be contacting you for
details regarding the case in a few days.
Please take care of yourselves.
Yes.
Understood.
I'll be on my way.
Good work, everyone!
I'm worn out!
Still, you really had me going there, Kudo-kun!
I almost thought you were really goingto-namej
the culprit and have that bomber man kill her.
Well, I сап understand if you figured out that it was a suicide, but...
Since I've never read Sawaguri Miku's debut
work, I wouldn't have been able to solve it!
Sorry, but I haven't read "The Death
God's Funeral Procession" either.
What?
That was just a bluffl used for the situation at hand.
In order for that bomber man to truly
believe his sister had committed suicide.
Otherwise, for someone who had been leisurely posting on SNS to
suddenly see a hallucination of a Death God and commit suicide...
Is an illogical deduction I'd never give
even with my mouth pried open.
Hey, you don't mean to say...
Right.
Now on to our main topic.
It really exists.
The Death God who killed Sawaguri
Miku-san and made it seem like a suicide...
Is among those three people over there!
It really exists.
The Death God who killed Sawaguri Miku-san
and made it seem like a suicide...
Is among those three people over there!
Don't tell me...
Were we wrong about the nicknames
Miku-san assigned to those three people?
No.
They were indeed as I've said...
Mitsui-san, whose family stonemasonry business
deals with the rat-colored stones, was Rat.
Yuchi-san, who works at the bakery and sells bread
that are fox-colored or golden brown, was Fox.
Nihei-san, the wife of a seal craftsman who
carves ivory-colored seals, was Elephant.
Those were all true.
Then, was the order in which the three
people went to Miku-san's room wrong?
No, the order was indeed Nihei-san, Yuchi-san, and Mitsui-san.
Given that Miku-san's posts on SNS said the
orderwas Elephant, then Fox, and finally Rat.
In that case, since the last one to visit was Mitsui-san...
Was Mitsui-san the culprit after all?
You're wrong!
I see!
She left the room but returned afterwards and committed the crime...
No, that wouldn't be the case.
Mitsui-san was seen coming out of Miku-san's room in a big hurry.
Despite having been seen exhibiting such odd behavior...
The conjecture of her returning there again
to commit murder is highly unlikely.
Especially so if she were a premeditated murderer who crafted
a sealed room and set it up to look like a suicide.
Then, who the hell was the culprit!?
Ran...
Sorry, but could you read those for us again?
The posts from Miku-san right before she was murdered.
"The first one to come pester me for an autograph was Elephant.
"Even though my hair had yet to dry
from the bath... that pesky Elephant."
"Next to come was Fox.
"Trying to stir up an argument again, freaking annoying.
"I've signed my autograph, so why can't she just leave!"
"Last one was Rat who can't take a hint.
"i'll make short work of the autograph and shoo her away ASAP."
"WTF, she's still here...
"Oh snap, I'm getting sleepy, what should I do..."
Then, Mitsui-san, I'll ask you.
Then you went to Miku-san's room, she
didn't let you use her restroom, did she?
Right...
Like I said!
She was only being a little mean to
Mitsui-san with an upset stomach!
Well, was it really like what you said?
What!?
Could it be!?
Right.
The one who was still lingering in her room wasn't Rat...
But Fox, the second to come.
Yuchi Shinobu-san.
It was actually you!
Yuchi-san is...
The culprit!?
How come?
See, Miku-san posted about it, right?
That Fox came to pick a fight and just wouldn't leave.
Unfortunately, Mitsui-san came by in the middle of that argument.
So she hid Yuchi-san in the restroom for the time being
and intended to make Mitsui-san go away quickly.
Of course she had Yuchi-san take the slippers with her.
Since it'd be obvious that someone else
was stili inside if there were two pairs.
But at that time...
Instead of Yuchi-san's own damp slippers she had worn from
the baths, she accidentally took Miku-san's slippers instead.
And the remaining Yuchi-san's slippers were then worn by
Mitsui-san, causing her to feel something was wrong.
Was that the case, Kudo-kun?
Yeah.
What happened afterwards was just
as the bomber man Isao-san said.
After killing Miku-san in the bathroom
while disguising it as a suicide...
She induced Isao-san to break the window glass
and enter the room by the cell phone email.
From that broken window, she crossed over
the adjoining balcony to Isao-san's room.
And then snuck out from that room via the door
and mixed in with the gathered bystanders.
But...
Couldn't we also assume that Nihei-san, who came by first
might have been hiding in the restroom the entire time?
Miku-san posted about the Fox who was
stili there and called her "annoying".
If Fox had left, she would've happily posted about
it without a doubt, but we saw nothing like that.
Also, Nihei-san has a methodical personality and is high
strung to the extent that she would line up people's slippers.
It'd be hard to imagine that she would mistake
someone else's slippers for her own.
But, isn't that merely circumstantial evidence?
I do have concrete proof.
As Miku-san was struggling to escape from the bathroom...
She grabbed the bathmat with her bloody hands—there's a photo.
Although the two marks near the door clearly indicated handprints,
the blood marks further were those from her fingertips.
That's proof she was grasping something.
And now I'd like to direct your attention to
Yuchi-san's signed book from Miku-san.
Depending on the printing method, the side of a book also known
as the fore edge—would either line up neatly or appear jagged.
But the method would never change
between copies of the same first printing.
However, for some reason, only Yuchi-san's
signed book had its fore edge neatly lined up.
It's likely because Yuchi-san filed the edge down with sandpaper.
То conceal Miku-san's bloody handprints she left
by grabbing onto the book in her last moments!
That's the unshakable proof.
She bought another copy and replaced the cover with
the new one to make it look like nothing was on it.
But the book warped when it was grasped, causing her to be unable
to hide the blood marks that adhered further into the pages!
But, why would the signed book be on the bathmat?
While I was carrying her to the bathroom
after drugging her to sleep...
It felt out from my bathrobe.
Afterwards she bloodied the book, but I didn't care much.
Since I was going to toss away such a book anyway.
But I couldn't bring myself to do so.
Because inside that book was the most popular
story out of all the ones I had written.
"I had written"?
Don't tell me...
Miku-san stole your work!?
Well, since we wrote it together, I suppose it'd be a joint work.
She asked me for a favor.
"I got invited to publish a book, so do
you mind helping me out?" she said.
Then that debut work turned out to be a hit, and before
we knew it, she had become a Naomoto awardee.
And I wasn't jealous at that time.
Since I only helped her with that one, and she had
earned the award through her own hard work.
I was even proud to be her friend.
And I thought it was my turn to shine...
Until I was told this by the publisher I brought my own work to!
This is indeed interesting, but...
It's just too much like Sawaguri Miki's literary style.
One Sawaguri Miku is enough.
How about if you try becoming her ghostwriter?
I didn't realize it until then.
That she had limitated my writing style
and taken it as her own since her debut!
So of course I told her:
"At the very least, please announce to the public
that your debut work was a joint work with me!"
But, she retorted...
"Are you trying to smear a Naomoto Award
winning author?" and denied my request.
If things went on like that, I'd become a non-existent ghost!
That's why...
I decided to make her the ghost instead!
But in the end, I really should have thrown that book away.
Since now, even if I wanted to read "The
Death God's Funeral Procession"...
It'd just bring back memories of our late nights, conjuring up ideas
and racing to put them to paper, and I could never read it like this!
A book I'm unable to turn a page...
There'd no point even if I kept it...
So Shin'ichi-kun just left without even saying anything?
Despite having the nerve to butt in and
give a deduction right in front of you?
I picked up the phone again after the police came to take
the culprit Yuchi-san away, but he'd already hung up.
Wearing a skirt...?
But after that, I got ari email from Shin'ichi.
Не said thanks.
At that time, Shin'ichi had gone back to his house for some files
and just so happened to stop by at the professor's house.
Не could've at least shown his face to his wife, I say!
Perhaps there was a reason he couldn't show his face.
Well, thanks to what just happened, I really get it!
That Conan-kun and Kudo-kun are on
super good terms with each other...
And that you're really tougher than I thought!
Is this about karate?
High school detectives of the East and West...
An all-out battle will decide who's better!
DEDUCTION ВATTLE BETWEEN THE
DETECTIVES OF THE EAST AND WEST
Next Conan's Hint
Kansai Dialect
Dad's here's a case!
What happened?
Surprise, it's a one-hour special next week!
Ya dun' say!