A female detective, ya say?
So was she the one who's
sniffin' around about ya?
Yeah.
Her name is Sera Masumi.
It seems she had been living with her parents
in America for the past three years, but...
She decided to return to Japan alone.
And?
Ya used Kudou Shimchi's voice in front
of that chick to solve some case?
Sorta...
I couldn't think of another way.
Don't tell me that girl...
Is related to the ya-know-what organization?
Nah, she doesn't give off that kind of vibe.
However...
I got the feeling that I've met her somewhere before.
Really?
Bein' ambiguous, are we?
Fine.
I've also got some business I need to head yer way for.
Why don't I take a look at her face myself?
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Today, I'm having an all-out deduction
battle with Heiji in a 60-minute special!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
CONAN vs HEIJI
DEDUCTION BATTLE BETWEEN THE
DETECTIVES OF THE EAST AND WEST
What have ya been doin' all this time?
Actin' clearly like a suspicious person or country bumpkin!
I can't help it!
The retort-pouchicurry my mom wants me to buy...
It's sold exclusively in Tokyo family restaurants, y'know?
Ya don't hafta look for it right now!
Why not later?
Precisely because of that kindaimentality, in the end we
forgot to buy Shinshu miso when we were in Nagano!
Can't afford to miss the chance this time...
I'm gettin' off, gettin' off, gettin' off, gettin' off!
What now?
I just saw the family restaurant!
I'm gonna go and buy it now, so go to
Kogorou-san's place first, Heiji!
Driver, stop the bus!
This ain't a taxi, how do you expect
the bus to stop wherever you want?
Hey, Kazuha!
See ya then, Heiji!
Hey, wai-
What's wrong with her?
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan are coming here?
Yeah, I got a call from him.
Wonder why they're visiting?
Is it about a case again?
Dunno.
He said things like he'd tell us once he
arrived and something about curry, though.
Curry?
Hattori-kun did?
Did someone scurry and score a hat-trick?
Sera-san!
The son of the Osaka Police Chief, huh?
And on top of that, a high-school detective—isn't that amazing!
His name is Hattori Heiji-kun.
According to Hattori-kun...
People collectively dubbed them "Hatton
of the West and Kudou of the East".
Then, he's a rival of Kudou-kun's!
But they only had a showdown in the beginning.
Recently it seems they've been working together to solve cases.
Well, it takes their two brains to make up a whole.
A far cry from Japanis greatest detective prodigy-
this highly ranked Sleeping Kogrou-sama!
"Sleeping Kogorou" is actually a two-man act too, you know...
And?
What's his reason for coming here?
Dunno...
He said he'd tell us when he arrived, though.
I bet he's just bringing us yet another bothersome case, no?
Just let them play as East VS West in their detective games.
East VS West?
Then, tell me straight up, which is the greater
detective between the East and West?
I'm sure they're the same...
But...
If I had to pick one...
I'd have to say the East...
The West!
This high school detective of the West, Hatton Heiji
is the greater one by a billion times, ya moron!
I kept quiet for one second and yet ya
went ahead spewin' out nonsense!
So you were eavesdropping?
Anywho, where is she?
The female detective that came out of nowhere
and started sniffin' around about Kudou.
She's right here!
This is Sera Masumi-chan.
I wouldn't say I've been sniffing around.
Yer actually a girl?
However
Aren't yer boobs a little bit lackin'?
Well, they're due to pop out any day now!
Besides, my mama's also skinny but she still
has large breasts, so I'm not worried at all!
Right, Ran-chan?
I've never met her, though...
Oh, where's Kazuha-chan?
Wasn't she coming along with you?
Well, she's runnin' an errand.
A little while ago, Kazuha's mother got some retort-pouch
curry as a souvenir and got super addicted to it.
Since that curry is apparently only sold at Tokyo family restaurants...
She was asked to buy-some if she's goin' to Tokyo.
She happened to see a restaurant on the way.
So she'll come right after she gets done there?
And?
Why was it you came here, Heiji-niichan?
Actually...
Pardon me.
It's from Kazuha.
What's up, Kazuha?
Did ta buy curry yet?
Help me, Heiji!
What happened?
Aren't ya at the family restaurant?
I did go to the family restaurant, but...
People said that someone died in the
restroorm and raised a big commotion!
Ya said someone died!?
A murder?
I dunno about that, but...
A huge strange foreign man told everyone not
to leave the shop, so I can't get outta here!
Got it, I'll be right there so just hold on!
Ya heard what happened, so I'll be right back
How about we do this?
Which is better between the West and the East...
Shall we find out once and for all with this case?
Hattori-kun will of course represent himself.
For Kudou-kun, if we have Conan-kun explain the situation
to him over the phone, it'll be a fair battle right?
Well, if you and Kudou-kun are such good buddies
that you don't want to compete with each other...
I won't force you.
What are ya talkin' about?
It's the perfect opportunity.
Between me and Kudou, which is the real awesome detective?
Let's make it clear once and for all!
Detective Conan Episode 651
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
So this is what happened, right?
Kazuha-chan, you were buying curry at the register here when...
A male foreigner came out of that restroom all of a sudden.
And said that someone died and to call the police, right?
He also said to seal off the restroom and
to not let anyone leave, just in case.
Did the foreigner say all that in English?
It was in Japanese.
He was the first to discover the dead person.
A foreigner who can speak Japanese fluently,
and the first to discover the body?
He's more suspicious to me.
Well, if you ask us...
You lot who barge your way into crime scenes
all the time seem the most suspicious to me!
Inspector Megure!
Nah, nowadays I simply come to the scene...
And the police would mistake me as being called by the inspector...
And just let me enter through!
Well, what was the cause of death?
It was poison.
There was a piece of candy coated with cyanide
poison found in the corpse's mouth.
And from the corpse's pocket, we found
more of the same sort of candy.
So it could have been a suicide?
Yeah.
The foreigner who was our primary discoverer also said as much.
Who the heck is he?
The foreigner, I mean.
He seems oddly accustomed to crime scenes.
Well, I suppose you could say he's kind of related to the police...
Great... you're here too?
A foreigner with a huge build and speaks fluent Japanese...
He's familiar with crime scenes like this
and is sort of related to the police...
Could that foreigner by any chance be...
Yeah.
I guess it's part of my reflex.
As I thought, it's Special Agent Camel!
A special agent?
This mean-lookin' foreigner is an acquaintance of yours?
Heiji!
You're being rude by saying he's
mean-lookin' even if that's the truth!
Kazuha-chan, that's kind of rude as well...
Anywho, what's this special agent thing about?
Of the FBI!
FBI?
Yeah.
He just happens to be taking a vacation
and traveling around Japan, right?
Yeah.
And, I'd eaten here with my friend before and
couldn't forget the taste of their curry...
So I came to eat on my own but encountered this case.
Is the curry here really that good?
Then, if you don't mind...
I'd like to know the details about when the
body was discovered in the restroom.
Normally I'd refuse, but since we're always indebted to you...
Camel-san!
Could you explain it once more to them for me?
Then, let's go to the restroom crime scene.
Oh?
The FBI, huh?
Wasn't Camel-kun accompanying you?
About that, he said he'd like to go eat the curry at
a family restaurant he'd found delicious before...
So we split up.
Is it that delicious?
That curry.
Beats me, I've never eaten it.
Speak of the devil.
An email from Camel.
What's wrong?
It seems...
Geez...
Why'd he have to go and commit suicide in a place like this?
And so?
Have you figured out who this pops here is?
No, he didn't have anything indicating his identity on him.
And the cell phone that might have been
our clue was submerged inside the toilet.
Where were you, Agent Camel?
I was using the toilet there, two stalls down from here.
Then...
What's your basis for deeming this a suicide?
I heard his voice.
"Even though we're childhood friends
I can't consider your request.
"The one who killed Abe-san with poison was me.
"So it falls to me to take the responsibility."
After he said that...
I heard a sudden groan.
As I rushed out from the toilet to see
what happened, this is what I found.
Then, you hurried out from the restroom and sealed it up...
And kept all the guests in the shop, huh?
Yeah.
From the conversation I just quoted...
He was talking with someone here...
And he was going to confess to the police and reveal
about how he had poisoned that Abe person...
So that someone proceeding to silence him was a possibility.
But, I recalled that he'd been eating alone here.
And adding to the fact that I didn't hear the other person's voice...
Perhaps he was talking on the phone.
The other part tried to talk him outor
committing suicide but he refused to listen...
And that he felt regret over the murder
and committed suicide was my conclusion.
Was the voice ya heard really from this pops?
No doubt about that.
This man's seat was night in front of where I was sitting.
And he ordered something in a fairly loud voice.
Then, it seems pretty certain it's a suicide.
Yeah...
But, an incident where someone named Abe was
poisoned to death hasn't been found, at least in Tokyo.
So our men are now investigating whether
such case occurred in another prefecture.
I think that Abe person was on pretty
close terms with this dead man.
Since he used "-chan" to address that person's name.
Then, he called them "Abe-chan"?
Yeah
Was there anything else you noticed?
Maybe you're unable to discern it...
But if he had an accent or...
That reminds me!
He spoke just like this boy does!
Me?
Are ya sayin' de guy spoke in a Kansai dialect?
I don't know if it's called Kansai dialect, but...
But he used a lot of "ya" and "de".
In that case, this...
"Abe-chan Poisoning Case"...
Might have been an incident that happened in the Kansai area.
Check it immediately!
Roger!
What?
Is there something on my face?
No...
If you're wondering whether I'm a boy or girl...
The correct answer is girl.
It's just my breasts haven't developed yet!
This kid...
Where have I...
Oh no, what's going on here?
Dunno, could be a murder case.
I'm hungry...
Yeah...
Looks like it's gonna take Heiji a while...
Maybe.
And I can't help but to salivate just by looking at the menu...
In that case, want an ame-chan?
"Ame-chan"?
I'm talking about candy!
amedama
Say, Kudou.
How far have ya gotten with solvin' this case?
Still haven't got a clue.
Well, if we find out more about someone named Abe
who was poisoned to death in the Kansai region...
I might be able to progress...
That so?
In that case, I'm one step ahead!
Don't tell me, you-!
Yeah, I've got de story.
That de pops didn't commit suicide but was murdered...
And that de culprit is still inside this
family restaurant is clear to me!
Detective Conan Episode 651
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
He didn't commit suicide?
how'd you figure that out?
That's because, Kudou...
I, unlike you...
Am the great detective, ya moron!
Fine, I'll admit you're the better one
so just tell me your deduction!
What'd ya say?
You were speakin' so softly I couldn't quite hear!
I said, tell me your deduction!
Before that part.
I'll admit...
You're the better one...
Damn right you are!
If yours truly, de better one, don't explain it...
Ya'll never understand, right little kid, right'?
This bastard is so ticking me off...
All right.
Why don't you recount what had transpired in this incident?
What had transpired?
Agent Camel was using the toilet in this family restaurant.
Then a man's voice suggesting suicidal thoughts
came from the toilet two doors down.
When he rushed to check the situation...
He found the man dead with candy in his mouth that
had been coated with cyanide poison, right?
What was the voice of "suicidal thoughts" exactly?
Let's see...
"Even though we're childhood friends, I can't consider your request.
"The one who killed Abe-san with poison was me.
"So it falls to me to take the responsibility."
It wasn't Abe-san, but Abe-chan!
Don't get it wrong!
What's the difference anyway?
Just tell me already!
You heard the guy was speakin' in a Kansai dialect, right?
Yeah
If we render the words into Kansai dialect, we get...
"Even tho' we're childhood friends, I can't consider yer request.
"De one who killed Abe-chan with poison was jibun.
"So it falls to jibun to take de responsibility!"
That's it, that's his speech!
What I heard were those exact words!
Right?
Like I said, the deceased man claimed, "The one
who committed the poisoning crime was me (jibun)"...
And resorted to suicide in order to
take responsibility, isn't that right?
Oh, no...
That was probably...
In Kansai dialect, what he meant by "jibun" was actually "you".
How come?
InJapanese,doesn't "jibun" mean "me"?
How would it mean "you"?
Take "temae" for example, the phrase "tamae-domo will
take full responsibility" means we contextually, but...
As an insult, "temee" would mean you
bastard it's the same situation here.
Japanese is a difficult language, you see.
In short. if we replace "jibun" with "you"...
The one who killed Abe-chan with poison was you.
"So it falls to you to take the responsibility!"
This would be what he really said.
Then, the dead man wasn't confessing
to a crime he himself had committed...
He was likely condemning the other party's crime
and even suggesting them to turn themselves in.
By the way, the "killed" in "The one
who killed Abe-chan with poison"...
Could it have been "coated" that you heard?
Yeah...
But I thought it'd be weird to "coat" someone with poison...
So I probably misheard them saying "killed".
In that case, "Abe-chan" doesn't refer to a person.
"Ame-chan".
It refers to candy!
amedama
Candy!?
This ame-chan is tasty, right?
Since that man who died in the restroom
had poisoned candy in his mouth as well!
I see.
So you're saying that he misheard ame-chan as Abe-chan?
Their pronunciations do sound similar.
But, why would you address a candy with chan?
That's because Japanese is a difficult language!
Ame-chan is only a Kansai thing, no?
But in that case...
Doesn't that mean there was a culprit in the restroom who
made the man take the poisoned candy into his mouth?
Yeah.
The fact that this FBI pops didn't hear the culprit's voice means...
Most likely...
The culprit had arranged to meet at this restaurant with
this man who was telling him to surrender, but...
Without sitting at the same table, they called the
man to the restroom and poisoned him to death.
After fast talking him to the restroom over the phone
they simply had to stick the poisoned candy in his mouth.
No need for them to say anything.
And the data from the cell phone would be
gone once it was dropped into the toilet water.
But what the culprit didn't count on was that an FBI
agent would have happened to be in the restroom...
And immediately locked all the customers inside the shop.
In short...
The murderer is still inside this restaurant.
All right, narrow the suspects down to men in
their 30s and 40s, and question them individually!
Since they'd have to be around that age in
order to be childhood friends with the victim.
Roger!
That's why...
As of now, I'm one step ahead of this dude here!
"This dude here"?
Aren't you competing with Kudou-kun?
What I mean is, I'm ahead of Kudou-kun that this dude represents!
This brat, whenever he hears Kudou's deduction over
the phone, he starts talkin' it out with a smug face...
So I basically get the feelin' that he's almost like Kudou...
Well...
Sorry, but on this case...
I'll be takin'the win.
If the culprit was childhood friends with that murdered man...
Then the culprit's likely from Kansai too.
So anythin' a Tokyoite like Kudou can't comprehend...
Will be clear as day to someone from Kansai like me!
For crying out loud, that Camel
sure gets rolled up into cases often.
Yeah.
All while we don't have permission from the Japanese police
and are conducting investigations in absolute secrecy...
Is it from Camel?
Yes.
But what he sent was just a picture message...
A boy?
Detective Conan Episode 651
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
Three people?
You've narrowed the suspects down to three people?
Yeah.
There were seven male customers that fit the criteria, but...
Four of them were with companions, and when Camel-san
came out from the restroom yelling someone's dead...
All four people were either in the middle of ordering
food or cleaning up the mess their kids made.
They all had a waitress involved.
Those without alibis had all come here by themselves
and were dining in the smoking section...
It seems it was just those three.
In that case, why don't ya let me do the questionin'?
Don't be ridiculous!
Why would we let a high-school student...
The culprit could be a Kansai person, right?
Then it'd be easier for me from Kansai to find
anythin' out of place in what they're sayin'.
Sugai Rakutoshi (39)
My name is Sugai Rakutoshi...
I live in a condo in Beika City.
And?
Where's yer hometown?
I was born and raised in Tokyo, why?
What is this?
Detectives, who on earth is this boy?
Just, don't mind that and answer the questions you're asked.
You... have been sweatin' a storm this whole time.
I dun' suppose you're hidin' secrets, are ya?
No, it's just...
The curry I ate was surprisingly spicy.
It's been an hour since the incident occurred, y'know?
Shouldn't you have finished it a longtime ago?
I just finished it!
Since they wouldn't let me leave from
here, I started getting hungry...
So I ordered it then.
A person just died, so they shouldn't have kept takin' orders!
Amakasu Tooru (36)
I'm Amakasu Tooru.
My buddies call me Ama.
Right now I'm living in an apartment in Haido, sa.
And, I was born and raised in Tokyo.
Are you satisfied now, Osaka bloke?
It looks like you're sweatin' too.
Are ya nervous 'bout anythin'?
I'm not nervous, sa!
Don't say weird things like that...
What's wrong with him, gettin' jumpy all of a sudden...
Is he actually faint-hearted?
Gotcha!
It's just that the ramen I just ate was kinda spicy is all!
Hey, you.
The way ya talk like that...
What's strange about it'?
Just your ordinary Tokyo dialect!
Nothin' strange 'bout it, but...
It irks me, ya moron!
Spicy ramen, huh...
My house is in Beika City...
Toujou Sanpei (45)
And the name is Toujou Sanpei
This interview is voluntarily, right?
Why do I have to divulge as much as my personal history?
On top of that, to be asked such by a random boy...
If ya don't wanna talk, we won't force ya.
Just that we'll suspect ya is all.
Unlike you, I'm a third-generation true Tokyoite!
What's this?
Looks like you're sweatin'as well, no?
You're not gonna tell me that you're sweatin' coz of that
Mapo Tofu that you've barely even touched, are ya?
I'm prone to perspire a lot!
Plus, I'm not so senseless as to go on eatingas
if nothing happened when someone has died.
That's why I even cancelled the juicy sweets
I wasiplanmng to have after my meal.
Weipt's a good thing you've cancelled it.
Since sweets will fatten ya up!
Well?
Were any of those three people from the Kansai area?
Dunno...
"Dunno"?
Wasn't that the whole point of having you do the questioning?
Well, what I do know is...
You do know what?
Just that all of them ordered spicy dishes!
Hey...
Oh snaps.
Now that we're talkin' 'bout food, I'm hungry.
That's right, we haven't had lunch yet...
Then why dontcha eat some too, Heiji?
The food here at this family restaurant is super delicious!
You guys!
While we're workin' our asses off investigatin',
you're just leisurely havin' a meal?
We couldn't help it!
Our stomachs'were growlin', y'know.
And we're not just eating aimlessly.
Right, Dad?
Yeah.
We're eating the dishes those three
suspects ordered to investigate them.
And'then?
Figure anythin' out?
Well, they're tasty, at least...
So you're just eating.
Are those really the dishes those three asked for?
Yeah.
Kogorou-san asked the waitress, so there's no doubt 'bout it.
The three dishes were the curry I'm eatin'...
And the salt ramen that Kogorou-san's eatin...
And the Mapo Tofu that Ran-chan's havin'!
Are those three dishes really the right ones?
Yeah...
Well, to be precise...
The two who ate the curry and the salt ramen ordered
and had either coffee or cake before then...
And I was told that the one who asked for the Mapo Tofu
ordered fruits as dessert, bufccancelled it suddenly.
I see, so that's how it was.
In that case...
That guy's weird speech and strange behavior would make sense.
No doubt about it, the culprit is that person!
Looks like we have a winner.
Detective Conan Episode 651
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK
Inspector...
I've just now received word from Chiba that he
found out about the identity of the male victim.
Is that so?
At a construction company in Saitama...
He was working there part-time, and
his name was Shibamiya Kengo-san.
Shibamiya-san was...
The primary discoverer to the company president's body when
the poisoning murder case occurred in Saitama last week.
When Shibamiya-san returned after lunch with his part-time
coworkers, the company president had been murdered.
Similar to our case here, a candy laced with
cyanide poison was used to commit the murder.
Judging from how the room was almost undisturbed
and only the money from the safe had been stolen...
The fact that the president loved candies, and that he had cooped
up in his room counting the money in the safe during lunch...
Would only be known by someone in his company, and the Saitama
Police have been running down leads based on the pretext.
I see.
So the culprit, who heard of the president's preferences and
behavior patterns from the now deceased Shibamiya-san...
Possibly used that information in order to commit the crime.
Incidentally, it seems the president had an appointment
to meet with a new male employee that day.
If the two of them were childhood friends, the culprit
was probably recommended by Shibamiya-san.
And, was Shibamiya-san's birthplace
indeed in Kansai like we surmised?
Yeah.
Seems like he told his friends he was born and raised in Osaka.
But he'd only vaguely given his age to be
around 40, and his name could be an alias.
In short, as far as their ages go, all three of
those suspects are still on the hook, huh?
Like I said, I know that one of ya guys
is the culprit from the Kansai region!
If you're a Kansai person, you should act
like one and man up for yer crimes!
Heiji, you're out of yer mind!
Why're a so worked up?
Of course I'm worked up!
I'm fanally takin' the lead now, y'know?
"Lead"?
If I don't solve this soon, he's gonna
take the win away from me again...
You know who the culprit is, Shinichi-niichan?
Got it!
I'll go and tell everyone that deduction!
Is that call from that detective brat?
Yeah.
Let me talk to him, Conan-kun!
Sorry...
Already hung up.
Geez!
Well, what did Kudou-kun have to say?
All three of those suspects said that they
were born and raised in Tokyo, but...
Actually, someone among them was hiding
the fact that they're from Kansai...
And that someone is the culprit, he said!
Oh, as expected from Kudou-kun!
Hey!
Wait a minute!
You're a Tokyoite, arencha!?
How the hell'd ya know anythin' 'bout Kansai!?
You know it wasn't me, it was Shinichi-niichan who said that...
"This will be the game-winning home run, you know!"
Bastard...
Knowing' almost nothin' about baseball and yet...
That's right!
Shinichi-niichan said to ask the family
restaurant-staff to make a certain dish!
A certain dish?
It seems like...
We'll find out who's from Kansai once they drink...
This magical dish!
Magical...
Dish?
Miso soup...
Am I right?
Do we really have to drink this?
Well, if sampling this will reveal the culprit, I'll drink it...
Make sure to drink it all down in one gulp!
I also asked them to make some for everyone,
so go ahead and drink it as well, Heiji-niichan.
What is he up to?
No way we'd learn who the culprit is with somethin' like-this!
SPICY!
What's with this miso soup!?
Really!
I knew Tokyo food was flavorful, but this is just...
It's just as they said!
It's so spicy, I can't drink another drop!
What?
You guys don't think it's spicy?
Well...
While I do think they put too much salt in it...
I wouldn't call it spicy, but...
"Salty".
Right?
"Salty"?
While people from Tokyo also call dishes like curry and
Mapo Tofu which are prepared using hot spices "spicy"...
Dishes that are fully salted would be called "salty"!
That's why Amakasu-san, who described both
the miso soup and salt ramen as "spicy"...
Is actually from Kansai!
Is that what it is!?
Then, you guys won't call the sea water "spicy"?
We'd say it's briny or salty.
Something like that—I merely picked the wrong word!
I actually was gonna say it was "salty", but was
misled by that Osaka bloke and girl is all, sa!
Oh right, about your speech ending with sa...
Isn't that normal Tokyo dialect like you just said yourself earlier!?
People from Tokyo don't refer to their speech as "Tokyo dialect".
Only Kansai people would refer to it as such, right?
We don't say that, right?
To be honest...
I never realized that adding sa to the end
of speech is actually a Tokyo thing...
Same here...
I thought it was normal, casual Japanese.
Well, it seems that most people in the Kant** region
do add sa to the end of what they're saying.
If you're going to pick on my speech...
That guy also said something weird!
He said he was planning on having some
juicy sweets after his meal, but...
You actually ordered a fruit platter, didn't you!?
No way it could've been sweets!
That's what I was talking about, fruits.
Huh?
Don't you say that?
Referring to fruits as juicy sweets?
I don't use that term, but I understand what you mean.
Since at some traditional Japanese restaurants, "juicy
sweets" is written in the last part of the menu.
Is that a Tokyo dialect too?
It's an old Edo term.
Only'true Tokyoites still use it nowadays.
Heiji-niichan, since you thought it was sweets and
commented on how it's sweet and fattening...
People don't use it in Osaka, right?
So that's why, sa...
Amakasu-san, no matter how I look at ya...
It seems ta' me dat yer an Osaka person through 'n' through!
Not ta' mention...
You were holdin' dat cigarette with yer left hand, pops.
But arencha really right-handed?
Since ya have put de ramen chopsticks on yer right-hand side!
Hey, stop your funny accent alr-
De reason ya deliberate did dat is a simple 'un!
I bet ya were scared, nah?
Of usin' de hand ya touched de poisoned candy ta' hold yer cigarette!
Hey!
Cut it o-
Cut it out already, will yal?
All of a sudden spoutin' bizarre Kansai dialect!
What de hell's ya problem, ya moron!?
Ka-
Kansai dialect!
Nah...
I was just imitating the angry words I often hear on TV...
This brat just irked me with his over-the-top weird speech is all...
That's it.
Getting irritated when people speak bad Kansai
dialect is also characteristic of Kansai people.
Because, there aren't many Japanese people who get angry
over foreigners speaking broken Japanese, are there?
Plus, the reason you ordered ramen after the crime was because...
You wanted to get a hand towel, right?
Since they'd give you one if you said you'd spilled some soup.
After poisoning that man in the restroom, you
couldn't wash the poison off your hand...
So you needed the hand towel to wipe it off!
You didn't wash it off in the restroom because...
You heard a toilet flushing, and realized
that someone else was there.
You flushed the toilet, right?
Yeah.
I did it right before I left my stall to check
on the man after he let out that groan.
I see.
The flushing sound also drowned out the
sound of footsteps from the culprit leaving.
But, why did he hold his cigarette in his left hand
even though he already used the hand towel?
Because he wasn't sure whether he'd
gotten all the poison off or not, right?
Since the poison is invisible.
The fact that the hand towel isn't on the table means
that you've hidden it in your pocket, right?
If the police investigate that hand towel
thoroughly, I'm sure they'll figure it out!
That Amakasu-san, you were the culprit who used the
poisoned candy to kill that man in the restroom!
That's what Shmichi-niichan...
Told me over the phone!
Move it!
Outta my way!
You'd better not go that way...
Move!
Better not do that, either...
This girl with the ponytail is something, too!
That's why we told you...
Ya better not do that...
Case closed!
My, that was surprisingly quick, Camel.
Has the case been solved?
Yeah.
Looks like the culprit was a man who poisoned a
company president somewhere for some money...
And since his friend seemed ready to reveal his crime...
He called that friend to the restroom and silenced him.
That seems to be what had transpired.
And, what's wrong with this teenager picture you sent me?
Seems to be a high-schooler who came to the crimes
scene with Conan-kun and the others, but...
Any recognition, Jodie-san?
For me, I get the feeling that we've met somewhere before...
Dunno.
James, seem familiar?
No.
That girl there is someone I've never seen.
Girl"?
That's right!
I thought she was a boy, but she turned out to be a girl.
How'd you figure that out, that she was a girl?
Well, an old man's wisdom I guess.
It took a lot of work to cultivate such eyes, you know.
Huh,this girl...
Looks just like someone...
How come it's a tie?
Wasn't the one who named the culprit
and solved the case Shinichi-niichan?
Were they competing?
Heiji and Kudou-kun...
Sounds like it.
Well, it was only thanks to Hattori-kun from Kansai that
we'd been able to obtain the first clue for the case.
And building upon that, only Kudou-kun the Tokyoite
would have been able to reach the truth.
So isn't it fair to deem it a tie?
But, was what Conan-kun said earlier really true?
That only Kansai folks would get angry
over people imitatin' their accents...
Ran-chan, won't ya get angry too?
Like if I started sayin' things like
"look here, sa" or "Ran-chan, sa"?
I won't get angry over it at all.
In fact, I'd actually be glad.
So does it really mean that Kansai people are just narrow-minded?
Not at all!
It simply shows that Kansai people cherish
their dialect that much, right?
What ya said!
Ya see, I'm right!
Ran-chan, ya talked in a Kansai dialect just now!
However, since that detective brat wasn't even at the scene...
Shouldn't he be the better one after all?
You're right!
Hey, I'm really gonna tell!
That you're actually Kudou!
Don't forget!
Kudou's the one who should really get a minus
for usin' bizarre Kansai dialect, freakin' moron!
But, that Hattori-kun...
Cares about it too much...
And?
Why'd you come to Tokyo anyway?
You got a letter from a dead person?
Addressed to Hattori-kun?
Yeah.
That person was my mom's acquaintance...
The company president of a design company
in Tokyo, and his name was Wakamatsu.
I also had met him a number of times.
But it seems he was murdered at his villa in Karuizawa last month.
He was murdered?
Yeah.
I had Ootaki-han from the Osaka Police investigate it.
It seems they happened to be throwin' a birthday party
for Wakamatsu-san's wife at the villa that day.
The local police surmise that he might've been killed
when he unfortunately encountered the culprit...
Who had slipped in lookin' for money.
But, why would that person send you a letter, Hattori-kun?
Could it have been he sent it before he was killed?
No.
The postmark-on the letter is ten days after that incident...
So it couldn't have been from him.
It says the sender is Wakamatsu Kouhei, but...
The contents seem to have been written
by the culprit who killed Wakamatsu-san.
The culprit?
Yeah.
This is what was written in the letter.
"Dear Hattori Heiji-sama...
"I would sincerely wish to meet with a high school detective
such as yourself, and confess to the crime I committed.
"However, I have doubts whether you would be
able to properly see me when we do meet.
"After all, my distorted existence is something
thoughtlessly conjured up by you humans.
"To see me directly is a dream that cannot be realized.
"Should you insist to meet me, then
on the next night of the full moon...
"I shall be waiting in the home of the man I murdered."
And then, on the bottom of the letter there's the address
of the late Wakamatsu-san's family home in Osaka...
And with it...
The key to that house was also enclosed.
That key would later unlock the door to another new case.
The door to a chilling serial murder case...