Huh, you got a letter from a dead person?
Addressed to Hattori-kun?
Yeah.
That person was my mom's acquaintance...
The company president of a design company
in Tokyo, and his name was Wakamatsu.
I also had met him a number of times.
But it seems he was murdered at his villa in Karuizawa last month.
He was murdered?
Yeah.
It seems they happened to be throwing a birthday
party for Wakamatsu-san's wife at the villa that day.
The local police surmise that he might've been killed
when he unfortunately encountered the culprit...
Who had slipped in looking for money.
But, why would that person send you a letter, Hattori-kun?
Could it have been he sent it before he was killed?
No.
The postmark on the letter is ten days after that
incident so it couldn't have been from him.
It says the sender is Wakamatsu Kouhei, but...
The contents seem to have been written by
the culprit who killed Wakamatsu-san
The culprit?
Yeah.
This is what was written in the letter.
Dear Hattori Heiji-sama.
I would sincerely wish to meet with a high school detective
such as yourself, and confess to the crime I committed.
However, I have doubts whether you would
be able to properly see me when we do meet.
After all, my distorted existence is something
thoughtlessly conjured up by you humans.
To see me directly is a dream that cannot be realized.
Should you insist to meet me then
on the next night of the full moon...
"I shall be waiting in the home of the man I murdered."
And then, on the bottom of the letter there's the address
of the late Wakamatsu-san's family home in Osaka...
And with it...
The key to that house was also enclosed.
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Delivered to Heiji was a letter and key...
And the mystery of words engraved on tiles!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE DESIGN OF POISON AND MIRAGE
(EYE)
And so?
Did you go to the house where that ghostlike bastard was waiting?
Of course I wanted to go and reveal who it was...
But I didn't since I caught a cold.
And then this girl here just took the key without my knowing.
I went there in Heiji's place!
Kazuha-chan, you went to that haunted house all by yourself!?
No way.
I brought Three friends along.
I thought it'd be fine since it'd be just like some sort of dare.
Plus, it didn't look like a haunted house.
It seemed the deceased company president would
occasionally use the house upon his return to Osaka...
So it was neatly maintained.
The electricity was working as well.
And then?
Was someone there waiting, at that house?
No, we rang the doorbell but there was no answer.
So with no other choice?! took the liberty
of using the key/and went inside...
And found the interior extremely dashing!
We had intended^to*beta test of courage, but
instead it felt like a visit to a fancy mansion.
However, we started to wonder what the bathroom
looked like, so we went and took a peek...
You took a peek and...?
A creepy person with long hair...
Was sitting in the bathroom leaning against the wall!
Did you talk to that person?
We didn't even get the chance, since right after
we found that person, the lights went out.
As my friends and I were discussing,
What do we do, should we call the police?"...
We heard this eerie rustling sound.
Right after I said, "This is scary, let's get out of here!"...
The lights suddenly came back on.
And that person who had been right there just disappeared!
Bet they just used remote control to induce a blackout and fled.
Well, I wouldn't have come all the way here to
Tokyo if it was only that person who disappeared.
A piece of paper was left in the bathroom
where that person disappeared.
Paper?
A message was typed on it that says...
What disappeared was but my body, not so for the letters".
Letters?
What does that mean?
On the tiles near the head of the person who was leaning
against the wall, something was carved with possibly a knife.
Right?
Yeah...
Three letters of the English alphabet...
E-Y-E," largely carved.
E-Y-E?
Eye...
Eye, huh?
Both those letters and the person disappeared, but
on the paper it said that the letters didn't disappear.
Then, didn't they just switch the tiles
with some that weren't scratched?
It's true that on the tiles near the bottom
of the wall were a lot of scratches...
So that's what I thought too at first...
But the color of those tiles got gradually
lighter from top of the wall to bottom...
So even if someone had swapped the bottom tiles with the top ones,it would've been immediately apparent due to the color difference.
Did you go and take a look at the tiles as well, Heiji-niichan?
Yeah...
But a whole mess of construction workers were there, saying
the house was scheduled to be rebuilt starting that day.
They wouldn't let me into the house!
Then, for about how long were the lights out?
It was probably less than five minutes.
In that case, they probably had them prepared...
Tiles with the same colors as those that were carved.
It's safe to assume that they switched them in the darkness, and
took away with them the tiles that had the letters engraved.
But it's just a dumb trick, so what?
Normally you'd think so, right!
But here's the real issue at hand.
The crime scene where Wakamatsu-san was stabbed to death
in Karuizawa was a bathroom with the same kind of tiles.
When the body was first discovered, there should've been a
dying message there that he had written with his blood...
But from what I heard, it had completely
disappeared when the police came.
The dying message...
Disappeared?
Wakamatsu-san's finger had blood adhered to it, so
it's clear that he should have written something.
Don't you find the absence odd?
Wouldn't the culprit have just snuck back
into the scene, noticed it and wiped it off?
If that was the case, the tiles around Wakamatsu-san's
finger should still have reacted to the Luminol, right?
Then, was it just like the person Kazuha-chan saw, the
tiles were switched out with the ones without blood?
Well it just happened that Wakamatsu-san had
been re-tiling his bathroom himself at the time...
It appeared that the adhesive had not yet dried,
so it's possible that they may have been switched.
But those tiles were just like the ones Kazuha saw, with
their color gradually getting lighter from top to bottom
It'd be obvious if they were switched, or so I heard.
If the culprit had used the same trick as the one Kazuha saw
to make the words disappear, wouldn't that intrigue you?
Totally.
So that's why I had my mom arrange for us to visit Wakamatsu-san's primary residence here in Tokyo to ask them about that case.
You guys are coming too, right?
Then, can I come along too?
Sorry bout that, but only the five of us were invited.
It's better for ya this way, right?
I suppose...
Tsk.
Sorry about that...
Oh my!
So you're Shizuka-san's son, Heiji-kun?
I believe this is the first time we've met?
That's right.
I often heard stories about you from my husband.
Wakamatsu Serika (43)
Victim Kouhei's Wife
That although you were young, you were very bright.
He would speak of how you would be good competition to
another well known high-school detective, Kudou Shinichi-kun!
Well, if you ask yours truly, the great detective Mouri Kogorou...
Both are just eye goop and boogers
competing to see which one's better.
Hey, is dinner not ready yet?
Ikurou-san.
I'm starving to death here, so how long
do I still have to wait until dinner!?
Wakamatsu Ikurou (25)
Victim Kouhei's Son
I apologize.
The housekeeper has gone out to buy soy sauce,
so if you would wait just a little longer?
Well, make sure you tell her when she gets back!
That I want my portion of food to be way larger than everyone else's!
Is that your son?
Yes...
Although he's my husband's son, not blood-related to me.
We both remarried, you see.
Oh, these are our guests?
This is the detective! spoke to you about
the other day, and his companions.
Is that right?
But to think there'd be so many...
Is something the matter?
Ah,no.
Shiina Masashige (56)
Senior Managing Director
It's just that as usual, I bought some baumkuchen
the president always liked...
But perhaps one cake is not enough.
We'll be all right, I think?
Fujinami Sumio (30)
Chief Designer
Since that president up and died, he's
not even here at the house anymore.
And I already taste-tested some earlier, so I won't need any.
Watch it Fujinami-kun.
Uhm, these gentlemen are?
Our company's Senior Managing Director, Shiina Masashige-san...
And Chief Designer, Fujinami Sumio-kun.
Hey, Satake-san, are you around?
Yes ma'am.
Ikurou-san was hungry and in a sour mood.
I imagine he shall calm himself if he eats some
baumkuchen, so would you serve some black tea?
Understood.
For the blend of black tea, would it be fine if I
chose Imperial Wales which the president liked?
Satake Yoshimi (32)
Secretary
Yes, that's fine.
Right away, then.
And the lady just now?
She was my husband's secretary, Satake Yoshimi-san.
Although she's now my secretary.
Well then, since we have everyone who was at the villa on the date
of my husband's death gathered here, sans the housekeeper...
Shall we head to the living room to
speak about the events of that day?
Your husband was a do-it-yourself enthusiast then?
Yes.
That's why on that day, he said "Since I designed these tiles
and I had them custom-made, I'll re-tile them myself!"...
And completely ignored my birthday party.
Well, I'm sure the president never thought that he'd
end up having his^fate sealed because of that.
Fujinami-kun!
Yeah,yeah.
So, who was the primary discoverer of the body?
It was...
Me!
I went to the bathroom, thinking I could assist the Master...
Yonehara Sakurako (23)
Housekeeper
But found the Master on the ground, covered in blood!
Pardon me!
I overheard your voices...
This is our housekeeper, Yonehara-san.
Then, the one who saw that vanishing dying message was also?
Yes.
Well?
What was written there?
If you saw it before it vanished, you must remember it, right?
Yes.
If I recall correctly, it was the alphabet...
Haven't we had enough of that sort of talk already!?
You'll ruin this baumkuchen for me!
Now, hurry up and cut it!
Yes sir.
Ah, it's my job to cut it...
Then Yonehara-san, please divide it evenly.
I'll dish them up later.
On another note...
Since we have all of the major players
in the company gathered here...
Let's talk about who the next president will be!
Right now Mother,- as the vice president, is
temporarily standing in for the president.
But why not send me straight to the top and make me the president?
I'm an average employee now...
But eventually, I'll become president
anyway since I've got my father's blood!
Isn't that right?
Mother?
Yeah...
Then it's a simple matter.
Make me the president now!
I bet my dead father had hoped that to be the case, too!
Hold on, please don't eat it before it's properly dished up...
Idiot eating it this way tastes bett-
Ikurou-san?
Ikurou-san!
Don't move!
Until I the great detective Mouri Kogorou
give theokay, nobody can move!
Ah, but...
These young boys have already...
No good.
He's already gone.
Seems like some sort of cyanide poison.
That means, it was inside the baumkuchen this man was eating...
Ran-neechan, you two!
Don't eat the baumkuchen that was just passed out!
Kazuha, make a call!
To the police?
Yeah.
Tell em there's a freaking moron here who had
the gall to kill someone in front of a detective!
Detective Conan Episode 652
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
The victim was Wakamatsu Ikurou-san, 25 years of age.
He was the son of Wakamatsu Kouhei-san, a design company
president who passed away in Karuizawa last month.
That's correct isn't it?
Yes.
However, when did the poison get into the baumkuchen?
I don't know when it happened...
But it seems the poison was in a capsule.
See, something that looks like a capsule
has sunk into the bottom of this black tea.
Most of it already melted, though.
The culprit probably broke open the capsule they had prepared
and sprinkled the poison over the baumkiichen...
And then dropped the capsule into the black tea
while all our eyes were focused on the body.
Since once it's dissolved, there wouldn't be any fingerprints.
Does that mean the person near the black tea is the culprit?
Most likely, but after everyone was told to get away
from the body, they all gathered around this table.
So for you lot who were in this room at the time...
Any one of you could've dropped the
poison capsule into the black tea, no?
It was not me!
I never once went near the baumkuchen back then.
And first of all, that cup of black tea was mine.
Then, who was responsible for cutting the baumkuchen?
I was the one who cut it...
But Satake-san helped me serve it onto the plates.
And it was she who told me to cut it into eight equal pieces.
Eight equal pieces?
We have five guests, adding the mistress and her son Ikurou-san...
And Director Shiina who is extremely fond of sweet food,
I thought it'd be best to divide it into eight portions.
The one who bought the baumkuchen was the Director, after all.
And if we were to cut it for more of us, each
piece would be too tiny, hence my decision.
So you were the one who bought it?
Yes.
Both the late president and I loved the baumkuchen from
that shop, so I always buy some whenever I come here.
Even today as Fujinami-kun and I were coming
here by car, I had him stop by the shop.
That reminds me, you said you'd already
stolen a bite of the baumkuchen?
It was just a tiny morsel!
When I was waiting in the car in front of the shop...
The Director handed me the baumkuchen box.
Then he said he'd forgotten to get the
receipt and went back inside the shop.
So, half as a joke, I tasted just a bit as I was waiting.
That's right!
Mine had a little piece missing.
So that means, you would've been able to sprinkle
poison all over the baumkuchen in advance, no?
Then, you're saying that the poison was
all over the entire baumkuchen...
And it just happened that Ikurou-san was the first to eat it?
No, it was a certainty.
Since Ikurou-san was quite famished, you see.
But if that were the case, there wouldn't have been
any need to put this capsule into the black tea, no?
That's a fake lead.
Fake?
It was all in order to make it look as if
the poison were laced from here...
And to clear you of suspicion since you
never went near the baumkuchen.
Am I wrong?
Then, would I have told you that?
That I stole a bite?
Plus, while I was parking the car in the garage after we got here,
it was the Director who went on ahead with the baumkuchen.
So the Director would've also had the chance to lace the poison.
And first of all, I didn't know that idiot son was hungry.
So why the hell would I have sprinkled the
poison over the entire baumkuchen?
If anyone else had eaten it first they'd have been the one to die!
Incidentally, why was lkurou-san hungry.
I went to buy some soy sauce since we had
run out so I was late in preparing dinner.
Who was aware that he was hungry.
Myself, Secretary Satake-san, and housekeeper
Yonehara-san could have predicted that correct?
I recall that Ikurou-san grabbed one of the remaining
two pieces of baumkuchen from the tray and ate it.
Did he always eat that way?
Yes, he said it tasted better that way; he
wouldn't even use a fork for shortcakes.
Could it be that you cut a slightly larger baumkuchen piece and
poisoned it, thinking that gluttonous Ikurou-san would take it?
I definitely cut it into eight equal pieces!
Weren't the portions you and the others received of the same size?
At any rate...
We shall now conduct a thorough investigation into
the remaining baumkuchen and the black tea.
So we'll have.all present undergo a body search,
and then standby in a separate room.
But this is a problem.
The deadline at the end of this month for the design
that we were commissioned to do is looming...
And yet to have Ikurou-san taken away from us...
At this rate, it seems we won't be able to go home tonight.
Seriously?
But I still have some unfinished work!
I have documents that await the vice
president's signature and seal as well.
One more thing, I sent some font colors and designs
that require your selection to the computer here.
Have you had the chance to look them over?
Have I not told you to print out those
sorts.of things and show them to me?
I apologize.
The president had always asked me to do it in such a way.
This computer here has a different OS than the one I use.
So I can't operate it!
Well, I'll look on this monitor with the Director and
the others later, so do let me know which file it was.
Yes ma'am.
Speaking of the president...
Was what that idiot son of his spouted earlier the truth?
That he'd be the one to inherit the company eventually
since he had the president's blood in him?
I was surprised as well.
Me too.
Well, wouldn't it appear that child had merely assumed so?
Whatever, given that I've no intention to work
under that idiot son, I guess I've been spared.
Hey, you lot!
Please behave appropriately!
A person-has just died, you know!?
I know Ikurou-san was shunned by everyone, but...
It's a fact that he was poisoned to death by someone!
What's more, that someone may be one of us, you know?
Please consider the situation at least a little!
Shouldn't you be the one to consider the situation!?
We just have a case of death by poison, and
you're bringing the freaking black tea again!
I had the police accompany me as I was preparing it!
If you still think there's poison in it why not just leave it?
Say that again?
Say, you hadn't finished telling us about that story.
That story?
You know, last month when the president was
murdered in the bathroom at the villa in Karuizawa...
Weren't you the one who first found him, Ms. Housekeeper?
Yeah...
At that time, even though there was supposed to be a
dying message the president wrote with his blood...
When the police came, it had vanished, right?
That reminds me, you did say that you
remembered those letters that had vanished.
They were letters of the alphabet you said.
Don't tell me those letters...
Were "EYE"?
"E-Y-E"?
Probably means "eye", in English.
I saw them too!
I was called out to the president's house in Osaka
by the .culprit who supposedly killed the president
And I saw those three creepy letters before they disappeared!
At that house in Osaka?
That's why we came all the way here today to ask you about that
But, what I saw was...
The letter S in the alphabet!
And it seemed it was followed by something else,
but I couldn't see since his hand blocked it.
"S" was it!?
Hey, hold on here!
The Director, Shiina Masashige-san...
The Chief Designer, Fujinami Sumio-san...
The secretary, Satake Yoshimi-san...
And the president's wife, Wakamatsu Serika-san...
The initial of either your first or last name...
Would be an "S", all of you!
Uhm, my first name is Sakurako, so it's also an "S".
What'd you say!?
The dying message that had vanished..
What in the world did the bloody "S" represent?
Next Episode
Wouldn't that one-eyed police detective we
met during the Fuurinkazan case be there?
Yeah, you mean Inspector Yamato Kansuke.
No one told me...
That the tiles at the scene were like this!
That day when the case was resolved, it looked like Yui-san had confessed to Inspector Yamato.
Since it's practically impossible that there'd
be no progress after she confessed!
THE DESIGN OF POISON AND MIRAGE
(S)
Next Conan's Hint
Tiles
Look Forward to the Next Episode