A peculiar letter was delivered to Hattori Heiji
It was from the culprit who had murdered Wakamatsu Kouhei-san,
president of a design company, a month ago at a Karuizawa villa.
Due to Hattori's cold, Kazuha went to visit Wakamatsu-san's
home in Osaka per the letter's instructions in his stead...
But she encountered an eerie person with long hair
That person disappeared amidst a temporary blackout.
But bizarrely, the characters "E-Y-E"
carved on the wall tiles vanished as well.
In fact, in the Karuizawa case, the words written by the victim
with his own blood on the floor tiles had gone missing as well.
In order to unravel the truth,,we went to visit Wakamatsu san's
surviving parties in Tokyo, but in front of our very eyes...
His son Ikurou-san was poisoned to death.
Kazuha, make a call!
To the police?
Yeah.
Tell 'em there's a freaking moron here who had
the gall to kill someone in front of a detective!
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
The dying message left by the company president...
What's the meaning behind the letter "S"?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Last month when the president was murdered
in the bathroom at the villa in Karuizawa...
Weren't you the one who first found him, Ms. Housekeeper?
Vonehara Sakurako (23)
Housekeeper
Yeah...
At that time, even though there was supposed to be a
dying message the president wrote with his blood...
When the police came, it had vanished, right?
That reminds me, you did say that you
remembered those letters that had vanished.
They were letters of the alphabet you said.
Don't tell me those letters...
Were "E-Y-E"?
"E-Y-E"?
Probably means "eye", in English.
I saw them too!
I was called out to the president's house in Osaka
by the (culprit who supposedly killed the president
And I saw those three creepy letters before they disappeared!
At that house in Osaka?
That's why we came all the way here today to ask you about that.
But, what I saw was...
The letter S in the alphabet!
And it seemed it was followed by something else,
but I couldn't see since his hand blocked it.
"S", was it!?
Hey, hold on here!
The Director, Shiina Masashige-san...
Shiina Masashige (56)
Senior Managing Director
The thief Designer, Fujinami Sumio-san...
Fujinami Sumio (30)
Chief Designer
Satace Yoshimi (32)
Secretary
The secretary, Satake Yoshimi-san...
Wakamatsu Serika (43)
Victim Kouhei's Wife
And the president's wife, Wakamatsu Serika-san...
The initial of either your first or last name...
Would be an "S", all of you!
Uhm, my first name is Sakurako, so it's also an "S".
What'd you say!?
In other words, the only one whose initials don't have an "S"...
Wakamatsu Ikurou
Is Ikurou-san, who was murdered this time?
And so?
After you found the body, what did you do?
For the time being, I went to fetch the
mistress, who was in the villa's living room.
Yes.
The two of us went to check on my husband's body...
Quick, call an ambulance and the police!
Yes ma'am!
Use the telephone in the study!
Since a cell phone may occasionally have
difficulties connecting in this area.
Ah, and I shall be the one to inform Ikurou san!
Since I imagine he's probably still sleeping in his room.
Ensure the others don't find out about this as much as possible!
I do not want them to see my husband in such a state.
Understood!
And when the police came, the dying message had
completely disappeared, is what you're saying?
Yes.
After I made the phone calls, I hurried back to the bathroom
and found Ikurou-san clinging to the master and crying.
But at that time, ibseemed the letters had already disappeared.
And mistress, did you not see those letters?
Right...
My eyes were focused solely on my husband's body.
Then, is it true that the tiles in that villa's bathroom and
the ones in the Osaka house's bathroom are the same?
Yes.
Both had tiles my husband had specially made.
However, construction to rebuild my husband's
family home in Osaka has already started...
And for the villa in Karuizawa, once it's no longer off-limits for
crime scene preservation, it's also going to be demolished.
It may well be that you won't be able to see them any longer.
Then, when the president was killed, where were you lot?
In the living room with the vice-president.
Actually, there were many more people present
for the vice-president's birthday party.
And as the party wrapped up, we were about to leave with
the other guests when the president asked us to stay.
He said he had important things to discuss.
We were told by the president to wait until
he had finished retiling the bathroom.
So the four of us were waiting in the living room.
Playing poker for about two hours.
That's what you'd call an airtight alibi!
Due to the letter "S" that the housekeeper said
she saw, we had become the primary suspects...
So the police also questioned us persistently.
However, due to the facts that the president's wallet
¦ was missing, the weapon hasn't been found...
And there were traces of someone having
infiltrated from the outside...
They concluded that the housekeeper
probably had just imagined the words.
It seems that the Nagano Police are currently investigating
the crime as one perpetrated by an outsider.
Mouri-san, a minute.
What?
There wasn't any poison detected?
On the other portions of Baumkuchen?
Right...
Only that black tea the capsule had
been dropped into tested positive.
Even so, the toxic reaction we obtained
from that black tea was considerably weak.
So either the capsule was dropped into the black tea to
dispose of the evidence after the poison inside was used up...
Or as you suggested it was possibly a fake
intended to confuse our investigation.
If that's the case, we have to assume the poison
was only on the baumkuchen Ikurou-san ate...
But that's odd.
At that time, Ikurou-san grabbed one of the two
slices that were still on the tray and ate it right?
How did the culprit get Ikurou-san to
take the poisoned baumkuchen slice?
Could it be the slice was indeed a little bit larger?
Guess so.
Ikurou-san was an eating machine, after all.
Actually, we thought that as well.
So we bought a same-sized baumkuchen
from the same shop and brought it here...
And set the seven remaining portions from the crime scene atop it
But they turned out to be exactly eight equal portions.
Then what the hell?
Does it mean that even though the culprit sprinkled the poison
onto Ikurou-san's baumkuchen after he grabbed it, no one else noticed!?
That can't be...
It's not like the culprit was an invisible person.
That reminds us of the letter that was sent to your place.
Yeah.
My distorted existence is something thoughtlessly
conjured up by humans such as yourself.
To see me directly is a mirage that cannot
be realized, is what this means?
Is that really true!?
Only the baumkuchen slice Ikurou-san ate had poison on it?
Yes.
What's more, we stacked the remaining seven
slices of baumkuchen from the scene...
On top of an uncut baumkuchen for comparison.
And found that it had indeed been divided into eight
equal portions, including the piece Ikurou-san ate.
Well, even if they were the same size, it'd be a different story if the
poisoned slice had been placed closer to him for easy-grabbing.
He didn't pick the closer one!
Ikurou-san reached over and took the farther piece.
Isn't that so, Satake-san?
Yes.
I saw it as well.
However, you two were the ones who cut and
served the baumkuchen onto the plates.
Not convincing for you two who could've
easily introduced the poison to say so.
I saw it too!
What?
When Ikurou-san grabbed the farther baumkuchen piece.
She's right.
I saw it too.
I thought it was strange that he deliberately
took the one farther from him.
So Ikurou-san had quite a bit of attention on him at that time, huh...
He said things like I'll be the next company
president" so it was attention-getting.
So I couldn't help but to follow his movements with-my eyes.
It might be possible that the culprit took a fifty-fifty chance on it.
Hey, hey!
If that were the case, what if Ikurou-san
had chosen the piece without the poison?
Then the culprit might have just pretended to have lost grip on
the remaining poisoned piece when serving it on the plate...
And drop it onto the floor so that no one could eat it.
On top of being an eating machine, Ikurou-san was hungry, so
the culprit would have known he was going to sneak in a bite.
I see.
Or, it could've been that the intent was for Ikurou-san
to take the unpoisoned piece in the front.
And the one who should've eaten the remaining piece...
Director Shiina, could've been who
the culprit really wanted to poison!
Which means, if the culprit who killed the
president at the villain Karuizawa last month..
And the one who killed his son or intended to target
the director's life this time were the same person...
Then the motive would probably be
due to this house or the company.
Any of you have any clues?
No way we'd have something like that.
That reminds me...
I saw the master get into a verbal disagreement with Ikurou-san!
Saying, "Aren't you the one who's been
embezzling my company's money? Confess now!"
But Ikurou-san furiously retorted,
"You don't even believe your own son!?"
When did that happen?
I believe it was about a week before the
master passed away in Karuizawa.
Then that day, what he was trying to tell us by
making us stay in the villa was indeed...?
About the embezzlement of our company's funds?
That matter has already been resolved, you know?
Because we realized it was due to an accounting error on my part.
Well, regardless of what the motive of murder
or who the intended target may be...
We'll still have everyone recreate the circumstances of the scene
during which Ikurou-san ate the baumkuchen and collapsed tonight.
While it's still fresh in your memory.
All right we'll call you as soon as our preparations are in
order, so please stand by in this room for a little longer.
They want us to recreate it, huh?
Well, since we have to wait at any rate...
Satake-san, would you show me those font
designs you said you sent to this computer?
Yes, ma''am.
And, Yonehara-san.
Yes, ma'am?
Can you refill the black tea for me?
Understood.
Say...
Speaking of the Nagano Police who
have jurisdiction over Karuizawa...
Wouldn't that one-eyed police detective we
met during the Fuurinkazan case be there?
Yeah, you mean Inspector Yamato Kansuke.
Then, why not give him a call?
He might tell us something about the case, you know?
But how can I call if I don't know his number?
I do know Yui-san-'s, who's on close terms with that police detective !
Then, we might be able to ask about the case!
Since Yuirsan got reinstated as a police detective.
Really?
But, why do ya even have her number?
I pressed her to tell me afterwards!
That day when the case was resolved, it looked like
Yui-san had confessed to Inspector Yamato.
So I wanted to know what happened afterwards!
Since it's practically impossible that there'd
be no progress after she confessed!
And?
What happened with those two then?
It seemed tie hadn't confessed back yet...
And I haven't gotten any any further calls or e-mails.
In that case, those two might've gone
ahead and done stuff without tellin' ya!
Moron!
She said she'd tell me fight away if he confessed.
There's no way she'd do something as cruel as that!
Kazuha-chan!
There's something I've go to tell you...
What?
Not here, though...
Say, say, hurry up and try calling Yui-san already!
Who knows, she might be able to tell us what type of tiles were
in the bathroom where the company president was murdered!
After all, it seems there aren't any tiles like
that besides his villa in Karuizawa anymore.
Detective Conan Episode 653
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
A family member of the president who was murdered in
this Karuizawa villa was murdered in Tokyo tonight?
Is that really true, Kazuha-chan?
Yeah.
It just so happened that we were here
when it turned into such serious matter.
But it could be the same culprit who's responsible for
that case and this case, that's what Heiji was sayin-
That's why I'm asking you to show us the tiles
in that bathroom the president was killed in!
Oh, that voice...
You're the young, dark-skinned detective from that time!
Are Conan-kun and Mouri-san with you?
Yeah, they're here!
They're saying that if this is a serial murder, they need more clues.
It could well be that someone else is being targeted.
I just happened to arrive at that villa now.
It's the first time I'll be seeing the crime scene as well.
But you know that normally I can't give this kind of
information out to an unauthorized person, right?
Hey, Uehara!
If it's a personal call, take it later!
We're going in!
Yes, sir!
But, oh well, since it's a request from you
young detectives who helped us a lot...
And seeing how urgent things are, I'll ask Kan-chan...
No l mean Inspector Yamato, for you.
Alcohol for the Young
(wakoudo no sake)
This one looks good, doesn't it?
It meets our client's requirements, too.
But don't you think it's kinda plain?
The design three samples back struck me more.
You mean this one?
This is too flashy, no?
Then how about we go back two more?
Vice-president are you all right?
If it's eyestrain, want to use my eye drops?
I just bought this, so the package is unopened.
Thank you.
I shall take it if you don't mind.
You must be getting tired.
There's so much going on today, after all.
That's true.
All right our preparations are in order.
If everyone would go to the scene, the living room.
Well, would it be all right for the vice-president
to not participate in that?
She seems super tired, man.
But...
Plus, back then, the mistress was sitting down the whole time...
And she never once went near the Baumkuchen Ikurou-san ate.
That's right.
There'd be no point even if she went, no?
As such, I wonder if I could be excused and stay here?
After everything that happened, l would like to be alone for a bit...
If you say so..
Then while you are waiting, the contracts
are inside that drawer of your desk.
Could you please sign and stamp those?
Ah, these?
However, the ballpoint pen on this desk ran out of ink.
Then, please use my fountain pen.
I received it from the president a long time ago, you see.
Thank you, that helps.
Well then, let's proceed.
No choice here...
I'll have two officers standing by in front of this room.
Let them know if you need anything.
Sure.
Uhm...
What's the matter?
The mistress talked about the tiles in
the Karuizawa villa's bathroom...
And said that you may not be able to
see them again, but the truth is...
What!?
You're saying the bathroom in this house has the same tiles!?
Why didn't you tell us that earlier?
Because, the mistress exuded a sort of don't-say-a word vibe...
Anyway, take us to that bathroom!
Yes.
You heard that so I'm gonna borrow the housekeeper for a bit!
You guys go ahead to the living room without us!
Hey!
To be precise, the tiles here have a
slightly different hue than the villa's.
But the shape of the tiles and the way
they are colored are almost the same.
This is -!?
Hey, Uehara!
No one told me...
That the tiles at the scene were like this!
But isn't it just as was reported, the color gradually
gets lighter from the top to the bottom as a whole?
No.
It seems that way as a whole due to an optical illusion!
I believe this is...
The Crosshatched Diamond Optical Illusion.
Also known as...
Crazy Diamonds.
Crazy Diamonds?
The top and bottom of each diamond shape are
at an angle between 30 and 40 degrees...
And a slight gradient is applied, that's all.
But the shading on the boundary lines of each
diamond where it lies adjacent to another...
Will be perceived as separate points by human eyes.
And upon focusing on that part, your visual
system will react to it as a whole...
Causing you to perceive the diamonds on the top as having
a different color than the ones on the bottom.
In short, your brain goes ahead and misinterprets the information.
As for evidence...
This tile and the one above it are the exact same color, right?
Truly, amazing!
Koumei!
What the hell are you doing here?
Headquarters is on this case, not the local police like you!
Have you not heard?
Effective today, I've returned to the Prefectural Police Headquarters.
Through my own effort.
Anyway, about this newfound fact, let's notify Mouri-san and
the others who're at the house of the murdered president!
They've also had a murder there, and are
saying that it may be the same culprit.
No.
We shall contact them after we get forensics in here to examine this.
Yeah.
If I recall correctly about this case, didn't the dying
message the president left here disappear somehow?
If so, it's highly likely that the culprit used
the optical illusion and switched the tiles!
We might as well contact them after we've restored that message.
If those letters were written in blood, the Luminol
reagent will resurrect them even if they were erased.
Crazy Diamonds, you say?
What is that?
What that means is, it's an optical illusion...
Kazuha-neechan's cell phone is ringing!
Hello?
Oh, the detective kid from Osaka?
That voice, you're Inspector Yamato!
We've just found out what that company
president's dying message was.
Really?
It had three letters of the alphabet...
S-O-N!
S-O-N, you say!?
S-O-N...
Son...
His son?
Yeah.
If the case here and your case there
were the work of the same culprit...
Then tie up the president's son!
And the cases will be closed!
We can't do that.
What?
The one who was killed here tonight was...
That very same son.
What'd you say!?
So does that mean the culprit who killed the
president and the culprit who killed the son...
Are completely different people!?
Next Episode
THE DESIGN OF POISON AND MIRAGE
(POISON)
Next Conan's Hint
Slippers
During Golden Week, go watch the movie "The Eleventh Striker" and drink beer at a soccer stadium!
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Sure you'll drink...