Following the murder of design company president
Wakamatsu Kouhei-san in his villa in Karuizawa...
His son Ikurou-san was poisoned to death in his Tokyo residence.
Bizarrely, the poison was not found anywhere else other
than on the piece of baumkuchen that Ikurou-san ate.
So what method did the culprit use to poison Ikurou-san to death?
Meanwhile, the tiles in the bathroom where president
Wakamatsu was murdered were so-called Crazy Diamonds...
Whose patterns would have induced an
optical illusion, and were noticed by...
Nagano Police Inspector Yamato Kansuke and the others.
They managed to reconstruct the missing dying
message left by president Wakamatsu, and...
It had three letters of the alphabet...
"S-O-N!"
Son...
His son?
If all cases were men.
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
We now have the mysteries behind the Crazy
Diamonds and the newfound poison trick!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect o an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE DESIGN OF POISON AND MIRAGE
(POISON)
Hey, are you sure about that?
That the one who was murdered tonight in Tokyo...
Was the son of the company president who was
murdered here at this villa in Karuizawa a month ago?
Yeah, no doubt about it!
Could it be that the culprit deliberately left those
letters in order to place the blame on the son?
If that were the case, it should have been
left in a manner much easier to find.
The culprit would not have gone through the trouble to
use the Crazy Diamonds illusion to hide the message.
In that case, there's a strong indicator that hatred was involved.
Yeah.
Knowing that the son was the.one who murdered the president...
It would be appropriate to surmise that the culprit took revenge.
Well, we can't rule out an accomplice
who did it to silence him, but...
Being that the message was only "Son",
it would-be apt to consider it a solo crime.
You heard hat!
Since we're going through the trouble of giving
you this info, try not to let another victim turn up!
Which means, the one who deliberately called
us to the president's family home in Osaka...
And showed us the trick of the disappearing letters...
Might be the culprit this time, the one
who murdered the son, Ikurou-san.
That's right.
It seems they had wanted to tell us to hurry up
f and figure out the Crazy Diamonds illusion.
And Ikurou-san, being the culprit himself,
wouldn't have given such a hint.
So the question is, why did the president's wife hide the fact that
the tiles in this bathroom were the same as the ones in the villa?
If the culprit had wanted the Crazy Diamonds to be noticed...
Then it means the mistress had tried to work against their cause.
Say, little boy.
Isn't your manner of speaking different from before?
Because when you were with everyone
you spoke normally like a kid...
Vonehara Sakurako (23)
Houskeeper
But now it's almost as if you're a detective.
No, that's...
He s just playing pretend!
And I'm just here to watch over this brat's play-detective game!
Little boy, you can't get in the way of the investigations.
Because this big brother here is an
extremely capable high-school detective!
Fi-i-ine.
But had the president been talking about me like that to everyone?
Yes, and all the time too.
Saying "How nice it'd be if only I had
a son like Hattori-kun to be my heir...
And why, as far as my son is concerned, is he so inept?"
As far as his son is concerned?
So did he have any daughters?
No...
I'm sure he just meant in comparison to Hattori-kun...
I would like to confirm once again.
When Ikurou-san ate the poisoned baumkuchen and collapsed...
You all were in your current positions, correct?
Yeah.
Ms. Housekeeper!
Where were you at that time?
Yes, sir...
I was right about where you are now, Inspector,
holding the tray with the baumkuchen.
You're too loud!
The culprit who murdered the president was his son, Ikurou-san!?
Keep it a secret.
Because everyone thinks that in the president's
and Ikurou-san's murder cases...
The same person who held a grudge against
both of them was the culprit right?
In that case, isn't it better to keep this a secret for now?
That's right.
It's possible that the culprit of this case had a different
motive than the one from the president's case.
They may have a grudge against whoever murdered the president
So, Detective Takagi, ask everyone on the sly!
Specifically, whether there was anyone
who really loved the president.
And to keep this a secret from the inspector?
To fool your enemies you must first fool your allies.
That Heiji, I wonder what he's whispering to Detective Takagi about?
Beats me.
Speaking.of which, what was that earlier?
You said there was something you had to tell me, right?
It's not really the right time to say this, but...
Actually...
KUDOU-KUN DID!?
What?
Don't mind us...
Geez!
Hey, hey...
What are you girls gossiping about at a crime scene?
And so, with the exception of Satake-san?and
Yonehara-san, none of you touched the baumkuchen?
Did Kudou-kun really confess his feelings to you?
A while ago, I went to London on a trip.
Shinichi happened to be there too.
And suddenly, in front of Big Ben...
How dashing, Ran-chan!
Dashing!
That's so romantic!
And then?
What happened afterwards?
Actually...
Nothing...
But you two probably met up and called each other, right?
In particular...
Well then, Ran-chan, you should give him a call!
But I kind of feel like I forced him into confessing...
And...
I kind of want to hold on to this happy
feeling for just a little while longer.
I get the feeling that if I call him...
lill end up crashing back to reality from this dream-like event.
Too naive, Ran-chan.
You've already pushed him to the edge of the
ring and he's wavin' the white flag, you know?
Why won't you give that one final push and claim the victory!?
"Victory," huh?
Then, let's do this!
I'll also gather up my courage and confess to Heiji!
Then Ran-chan, you'll also brave up and confirm
with Kudou-kun whether it was a dream or not.
What do you say!?
Hey, you two!
What've you been chattering about this whole time?
We're in an on-the-spot investigation!
And we're in an investigation meeting!
Could you please not interrupt our conversation?
All right, Ran-chan?
It's a promise!
All right!
For Ran-chan's sake, I have to show her how it's done!
Heiji...
Prepare yourself!
Scary!
That girl...
What's she glarin' at me for?
Inspector.
There is no point in doing this any further, is there?
Shiina Masashige (56)
Senior Managing Director
That's right.
The question isn't where everyone was
standing at the time of the incident...
Fujinami Sumio (30)
Chief Designer
It's how that idiot son was made to take the poisoned
baumkuchen piece between the two, right?
If that mystery isn't solved, no matter how much
you conduct this on-the-site inspection...
No.
Satake Yoshimi (32)
Secretary
This isn't an on-the-site inspection, but a
voluntarily conducted on-the-spot investigation.
For an on-the-site inspection, you would need
to have a court-issued warrant in hand...
And present it to us before commencing.
So that you could make us take in the meaning of it.
Have in hand before commencing"?
Make someone take in"?
That's it!
That kind of trick is still possible!
Inspector.
I'm borrowing the housekeeper again!
And, we're borrowing the forensics officer outside too!
Sorry, but do pass on the word.
Geez, doing as they please...
So it's positive?
Yeah, powdered poison was sprinkled over the doorknob.
There's no doubt this was Ikurou-san's room?
Right...
But why would poison be at a place like this?
Ikurou-san didn't happen to choose the
poisoned piece of baumkuchen out of the two.
Before he took it the poison was already on his hand!
He already had it from when he left this room
and grabbed the knob to close the door.
That's why, for Ikurou-san who always
eats cakes and things using his hand...
No matter which baumkuchen slice he took,
he would've taken in the poison anyway.
I see...
The question is who put the poison on the doorknob.
Say, is there poison on the floor too?
Yeah.
In between the boards.
Could it be there is about a ten-centimeter
hollow in that powdered poison?
Yeah...
There's an open gap about that large in
the poison found in between the boards.
But how did you know?
So that's it.
With this, as to who applied the poison...
It'd be possible to find out!
What?
You'd like to investigate their slippers!
What've you been up to this whole time?
We're in the middle of questioning!
Don't be so rigid.
This is important!
Of course, we'll take yours and the others' too, Inspector.
And from those of you waiting in line outside the room as well!
Put the slippers you have on now into
the bags marked with your name!
Well then, you have no clues as far as anyone who possesses
a particular grudge against the president or Ikurou-san?
Right.
I don't care about the son...
But I'm sure everyone liked the president.
Although the president was a workaholic
to the point of ignoring his family...
And was divorced twice as a result.
Divorced twice, huh?
Then, on the other hand, anyone who
particularly loved the president?
Not who particularly hated him?
Yes, for reference purposes...
I guess that'd be Director Shiina.
It seems they've been together since the company started.
Yes.
The president and I were colleagues
in college, and we go back a long way.
A few years ago, to celebrate my 30 years of continuous
service, he even gifted me a bronze fountain pen.
Was that...
The fountain pen you lent the mistress earlier?
Yes.
I believe he gave each of the other
employees a bronze wristwatch instead.
By the way, was there anyone who loved
the president more than yourself?
Probably the secretary, Satake-kun.
She was so devoted to him, to the point
his previous wife would even get jealous.
As a secretary, isn't it only natural to
be devoted to the company president?
But how is this question related to anything!
Just to know how well-loved the president was.
In that case, I suppose the housekeeper
Yonehara san would be the most?
After all, her mother was also a,housekeeper for this household.
Her mother was a single mother who died of an illness and left
her without any means, but he took her in as his own child.
And afterwards, he employed her as his housekeeper.
Yes.
I am so grateful to the master that I cannot thank him enough.
He even paid for my tuition.
But, probably the Chief Designer
Fujinami-san would rank the highest.
That crude mouth of his caused him to have
gotten fired from many different companies...
But the master expressed faith in his
talent and took him in, or so I was told.
Even-at the master's funeral, that
person was the one who cried the most.
I see, I see.
Hey, mistress, aren't you in there?
Your slippers are the only ones untested!
Everyone else's slippers didn't test positive for poison.
The powdered poison would get on the slippers...
When the culprit sprinkled the poison on Ikurou-san's doorknob.
Since the poison would also fall on
the slippers the culprit was wearing...
There was a gap about ten-centimeters wide
in the poison on the floor under the knob.
Which means, if we inspect your slippers,
we'll find out that you're the culpri-
Detective Conan Episode 654
Fansub Release by DCTP
Ripped by DJ VK & Innushka
Mistress?
Mistress!
No way...
The cause of death was a cyanide based poison again?
Looks like it...
But wouldn't this be a suicide?
When we all left this study, the last one to
close the door was the Inspector, right?
The vice-president was still alive then.
If the first ones to open the door to this
room under police surveillance...
Were the Osaka detective brats who
found the vice-president's body...
Then there's no way it wasn't a suicide!
That's right.
If it was a murder, it would be a sealed-room murder.
Which means it'd have to be an impossible crime.
That's certainly so.
I wouldn't say it's impossible, you know!
Because, there are all sorts of suspicious
things on top of this desk here.
The black tea brought by Housekeeper
Yonehara-san has been partially sipped.
The fountain pen Director Shiina-san
lent to the mistress has its tip left out.
With the cap attached to its rear end.
For the contract that Secretary Satake-san asked the
mistress to sign and stamp, she had started to work on it.
And the eye drops that the mistress-received
from Chief Designer Fujinami-san...
Have been removed from the box and looks like some was used.
Don't you think they're strange?
In short...
If something from the desk was used in a clever way..
It would mean that someone could have poisoned the
mistress to death even if they weren't in this study!
And that thick Japanese dictionary that had fallen to the ground
next to the mistress along with its case are also quite suspicious.
It seems to have been opened to the "Wa" entry page.
Judging from the circumstances...
It's highly probable that she.came into contact with the
poison as she was looking something up in this dictionary.
For example, if there was a kanji character
she couldn't read, and wanted to look up.
So that means, the contract the mistress
was asked to sign and stamp, and...
The instruction guide on the eye drops would be fishy.
Yeah.
The culprit knowing that there would be
difficult-to-read kanji characters or words in the text...
Likely induced the.mistress to grab
the poison-laced Japanese dictionary!
Hey, now hold on!
I'm sure there aren't any kanji the vice-president can't read.
The vice-president passed the Level 1 kanji aptitude test.
What's more...
Would you save your suspicion of us until after you have read the
vice-president's sealed letter she had placed in safekeeping?
A sealed letter?
I was asked by the vice-president
That if anything were to happen to her, I was
to present that sealed letter to the police.
That sealed letter was stored inside the house safe.
The contents of the letter was the mistress's written confession.
At the villa in Karuizawa, when she rushed to the bathroom
after hearing about how the,president had been stabbed...
The truth was the son had been hiding behind
the door, blood-stained with a knife in hand.
Without thinking, she ended up covering for him, and
that was written in the mistress own handwriting.
The reason she covered for him was because her son had caught
wind of the fact that she was the one embezzling company funds.
And before the police arrived, she manufactured traces of
it having been an outside crime and hid the weapon...
And disposed of it afterwards.
She also made use of an optical illusion to
hide the president's dying message, but...
She feared that her son would someday murder her
in order to silence her knowledge of the crime
If that were to happen, she would like that dying message
submitted to the police as a piece of evidence
And with that sentence, the written confession ended.
Was the only one to know of the existence
of this sealed letter you, the secretary?
Yes, probably.
But it seems the vice-president opened the safe every
night in order to check that the seal had not been broken.
So perhaps the others may have found it odd.
I also thought the mistress had been hiding something...
Because when I came into this room to do some
cleaning, I found the mistress in front of the safe...
Yelling, "Knock the door before entering the room!"
And got extremely upset with me.
But about that, I think the others may have noticed as well.
Since the mistress often invited the company
personnel over to this house for conferences.
In short, you all at least had some inkling
of this sealed letter's existence, right?
Inspector!
Traces of poison were found on the mistress's slippers.
What?
It seems that it was the mistress who sprinkled
powdered poison on the doorknob of the son's room.
Some poison remained in between the
floorboards under that doorknob...
And the width of the interval in between matched
up with the width of the poison on the slipper.
I see.
Unable to withstand the threat of possibly being murdered by the
son, the mistress taking the first.move was what happened here.
Noway...
That certainly is plausible.
It's quite impossible for the culprit to have made someone else
exchange their own slippers for the ones with poison, after all.
In addition, the Japanese dictionary on the ground next
to the mistress's body also tested positive for poison.
The poison was only at a spot to the
bottom left of the fore edge of the book.
But deep inside the case in which the dictionary was housed,
a packet with poison had been affixed, and was slightly torn.
So it may be that someone had hidden the poison
there, and by some circumstance the packet tore...
Unwittingly getting poison onto that part of the dictionary.
Then that means, the person who hid
it there may have been the mistress.
Makes sense.
After poisoning the son, she concealed the packet of poison there.
But even if he was the president's son from
another marriage, he was still her son.
Thus, tormented by the feeling of regret for having killed him...
It's plausible that she may have taken the poison that came out
from the packet, and put it into her mouth to commit suicide.
Perhaps, the mistress's non-participation
in the on-the-spot investigation was...
Because she wanted to be alone, having
already decided to commit suicide.
Say, so nothing came from the things
on top of the desk in this study?
Right.
No poison was found.
And neither the contract nor the instructions for the
eye drops contained any particularly difficult kanji.
Then who was the one who called me to
the president's family home in Osaka...
And wanted me to figure out the Crazy Diamonds illusion?
Well, maybe the mistress was using you in order to test you.
Thinking that if you, who was deemed by the
president as a skilled detective, couldn't figure it out...
Then the optical illusion trick would never come to light.
Never in her wildest dreams could she have imagined that you
would bring along yours truly, a genuine great detective!
In that case, are you saying she deliberately decided to
commit a murder in front of such a great detective?
How should I know!
Maybe she'd already set up the poison and
couldn't forestall it after the fact, no?
What ever the case...
If you've decided that the vice-president
is the culprit could we go home?
The last train will be leaving soon, after all.
I must return home and discuss with my wife regarding the future.
I'll stick with the investigation as long as it takes!
Well, we do wish to hear from you all regarding
the mistress's state of mind before she died.
Please bear with the investigation for just a short while longer.
This talk about baumkuchen makes me
want to eat some half-moon fish cake.
Next Episode
I see!
So it was "an eye for an eye"!
If that's the case, how'd the culprit make that
idiot son take the poisoned baumkuchen?
Then why don't you try taking one, Uncle?
So pretend[you're lkurou-san who's starving to death!
Like I'm starving, huh?
This is!?
THE DESIGN OF POISON AND MIRAGE
(ILLUSION)
Next Conan's Hint
Wristwatch
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Today (5\5) is Boys' Day!
Conan-kun, how old are you now after yesterday?
A secret...