Say, Kudou...
Are you thinking the mistress was the culprit too?
Yeah.
I was convinced that was the case...
Up until we entered that study where the mistress died.
Me too.
I can't imagine someone who was preparing to commit suicide
would do things like ask for the tea to be refilled or apply eye drops.
Plus, she already started on signing the contract,
and the fountain pen was left uncapped as well.
That's right.
It's almost as if, right in the middle of her signing the
papers, a ghost-like someone had entered unnoticed...
And utilized poison to kill the mistress.
Yeah.
Like the one who sent that strange letter to you...
Someone whose distorted existence cannot be seen directly.
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
Don't be fooled by appearance on any occasion!
The trick deployed by the true culprit was...
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
(ILLUSION)
However...
Since no one entered this study until we came...
To assume that someone might've secretly phoned
and directed the mistress to fall into a trap...
But all four suspects were in the on-the-spot investigation.
It wouldn't have been possible.
Besides, those slippers with the poison...
If someone had wanted to place the blame on the mistress,
they would've had to switch those at some point, but...
There's no way that could've been
done without it seeming suspicious.
What's wrong?
Why are these slippers here!?
They're Kazuha-chan's.
Since there are slippers inside for restroom
use you'd normally leave yours outside.
I see, the restroom!
That's how the switch could've been done!
What's going on?
Gathering in front of an occupied restroom...
Hey, Kazuha!
You immediately went to the restroom when we got here, right?
And, when you came to the living room where we'd been waiting...
You said there was a line for the restroom
so it was quite an ordeal, right!?
Right, so?
Because I also had to use the restroom back then.
Then at that time, did the mistress use the restroom too?
No.
The one who was in the restroom ahead of us was...
Ikurou-san.
He headed immediately to the living room after he came out.
Asking us, "I heard Director Shiina's voice, so
does that mean he brought the baumkuchen?"
Is that for real?
Yeah.
While wiping his hands...
In an exultant voice.
If that's the case, the poison left on
the doorknob of Ikurou-san's room...
Was a fake.
That means there had to be something indeed...
Some sort of way to make only Ikurou-san
take the poisoned baumkuchen slice!
But at that time, there were two baumkuchen slices on the tray.
Their shape and size being the same,
how did the culprit make him take it?
Not really the right time for this...
But I sure am hungry...
I know, right?
This talk about baumkuchen makes me
want to eat some half-moon fish cake.
Why half-moon fish cake?
Since their shapes are similar!
They both have a bit of a curve.
I see!
So it was "an eye for an eye"!
So about the mistress's murder...
It's highly probable that it was done in a similar fashion.
Hey, wait!
That's weird.
Dad said that the case had already been solved, and yet...
No, it's not over yet.
When Heiji has the brim of his cap faced forward,
he's still in the midst of his investigation!
Is that so?
That's right and when he returns the brim
to the rear, his switches turned off!
And that means it will be my cue!
Before the mistress passed away...
Alcohol for the Young
(wakoudo no sake)
She was looking at these font designs, huh?
Yeah.
There were about fifty patterns in total, and it seemed she was
choosing the best among them with Shiina-san and the others.
I think you two probably heard the rest, but just in case...
While looking at them, the mistress held her hand to her eyes and
appeared to be tired, so Fujinami-san handed her eye drops.
And if I recall afterward the housekeeper
brought the black tea refills...
Followed by the arrival of me and the inspector, in order
to bring everyone to the on-the-spot investigation.
But, since the mistress had never gone near
the baumkuchen, we let her stay behind.
Then Satake-san asked her to sign and
stamp the contract while she was waiting...
And Shiina-san lent her his bronze fountain pen.
That's the flow of what transpired.
Made of bronze?
Yeah.
It seems he received it from the president
in celebration of thirty years of service.
I think he said the other employees were presented
with wristwatches also made of bronze.
And during the questioning, Fujinami-san and
Satake-san were both wearing something to that effect...
So I think those were the watches in question.
Let's wrap things up!
We'll continue the investigation tomorrow.
Yes sir!
Was my input just now enough?
Yeah, it was perfect!
With that info, both the trick and the culprit are revealed, but...
There's no evidence.
Well then, at a later date, we would like
to conduct a formal police questioning.
It's finally over.
My throat is so dry.
After all you never touched that black tea in the end.
Fujinami Sumio (30)
Chief Designer
Shiina Masashige (56)
Senior Nanaging Director
Then do you want to drink the oolong tea I
bought when I went to buy the soy sauce?
Yonehara Sakurako (23)
Housekeeper
Satake Yoshimi (32)
Secretary
Since it's in a plastic bottle, no one could've poisoned it!
No kidding!?
It's already 1:00 AM!?
No way—the last train's already left!?
Then would you like to ride along with me
in Fujinami-kun's car and be dropped off?
But don't you live in the opposite direction from the director?
True, but...
Then, how about staying over at my apartment?
It's relatively close by.
Guess so...
Well, it looks like we're finally able to see it directly!
Yeah.
That whose distorted existence we
humans thoughtlessly conjured up...
The proof, that is!
Hey, hey, hey...
Are you serious?
You're saying you figured out the culprit who killed that idiot son?
Yeah.
As well as exactly how that culprit made
Ikurou-san eat the poisoned baumkuchen.
But, wasn't that the vice-president's doing!
He's right.
The vice-president sprinkled powdered poison
on the doorknob of Ikurou-san's room.
And after getting the poison on his-hand, Ikurou-san used it to
take and eat the baumkucherif is that not what happened?
Also, didn't you say you detected powdered poison
on the slippers the vice-president was wearing?
That means she got the poison on her slippers when
she was sprinkling it on the doorknob, right?
That was a fake.
F-Fake?
Right.
It was a strategic setup designed to place the blame on the
mistress, and wrap the case up with her supposed suicide.
So, you're saying the mistress's death
wasn't a suicide either, but a homicide?
Yeah.
No doubt it was the same culprit.
However, where's the proof of that?
Because Ikurou-san went to the restroom and washed
his hands right before he picked up the baumkuchen!
Even if he had poison on his hand when he left
his room, it would have all been washed off, no?
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
He even wiped his hands on his handkerchief.
But, no way anyone could have gotten the
mistress to wear the poisoned slippers so easily!
The restroom.
They were switched when the mistress went to the restroom.
By switching the mistress's slippers she left
outside the door with the poisoned slippers.
If that's the case, how'd the culprit make that
idiot son take the poisoned baumkuchen?
If Ikurou-san didn't have poison on his hand in the
first place, then what other method was there to...
It was simple!
The culprit just placed iit so that the gluttonous
Ikurou-san would subconsciously pick it up.
If he was starving, all the more so!
Idiot!
The baumkuchen was sliced into eight equal portions,
and each slice was the exact same size, you know!?
It wouldn't have mattered how they were placed!
Then why don't you try taking one, Uncle?
There are two pieces on the tray, just like what the culprit did.
So pretend you're Ikurou-san who's starving to death!
Like I'm starving, huh?
This is!?
Hey, hold on a second!
It's plainly obvious that the one further away is bigger!
You're right!
If this were the case, any human with a voracious
appetite would pick the one further away, but..
But like I was saying, the two pieces of
baumkuchen were exactly the same size...
They still are, okay?
Because we used the exact same baumkuchen the
police prepared for the on-the-spot-investigation!
That's ridiculous!
You'll see this is bigger if you stack them...
It stacks up perfectly!?
What the hell!
It's the Jastrow illusion.
When people visually compare the sizes of objects, they unknowingly
end up comparing the length of the closest adjacent parts.
So when things that are fan-shaped like
the baumkuchen pieces are lined up...
They would compare the longer side with the shorter side.
And even though they are the same size, they'd
mistakenly think the one away from them is bigger.
Is that right Heiji-niichan?
Yeah, that was one of the optical illusions the psychologist
named Jastrow discovered over a hundred years ago.
I see.
The culprit placed the poisoned piece so that it
would appear larger, and made Ikurou-san take it.
But if that was how it's done...
Then at that time, the ones dividing the
baumkuchen and placing them onto plates...
The housekeeper, Yonehara-san...
And the secretary, Satake-san...
In addition, the ones standing near the
tray the baumkuchen were placed on...
The chief designer Fujinami-san, and
Director Shiina - all four of them...
Could have done it if no one happened to be looking, no?
But as for the mistress's poisoning murder...
Only one person out of them could have done it.
So, why don't we go to the study
where the mistress was murdered?
What's the meaning of this!?
Just when I thought that we'd begun solving the mystery,
you go and make me look at these sorts of images!
Keep looking at them!
Since there are fifty patterns.
Before she died, wasn't the mistress also
looking at these images along with you lot?
Right.
Ah-le-le?
Are you tired?
Of course I am!
Making me continuously look at this flashing stuff!
Well, then...
Can you write the "Waka" kanji as in "Wakamatsu-san"?
Huh?
Such a simple kanji...
Let's see...
If I recall...
No cheating, you know!
Not to mention since the mistress wasn't used to operating
this computer, she wouldn't have been able to open this file!
Hey, Takagi.
In the "Waka" kanji, what was below the grass radical again?
You mean you don't know?
But you've been staring at that kanji to death!
Exactly since he'd been staring at it to death...
That he ended up experiencing the Gestaltzerfall phenomenon!
Gestaltzerfall
Gestaltzerfall?
Right.
You've also experienced seeing wall stains
or cloud shapes as faces sometimes, right?
That's because the "face neurons" inside your brain
activate, and you subconsciously perceive them as faces.
Similarly to those face neurons, there are
character neurons" in your brain too.
It's said that continuously seeing the same character over and over...
Will tire those character neurons out,
causing their functionality to decline.
Basically, even a character you know super well, you'll become
confused and start wondering, ".Was it written like this?"
That's called the Gestaltzerfall phenomenon.
I see!
The culprit showed the phrase "Alcohol for the
Young" to the mistress many times over...
And induced the Gestaltzerfall phenomenon...
And then asked the mistress to sign the contract...
With the mistress's name—Wakamatsu Serika!
Then, when the mistress couldn't recall how to write the kanji
"Waka", she took the Japanese dictionary from the shelf...
Touched the "Wa" index where the poison had been
applied, and ended up bringing the poison to her mouth?
Yeah.
The "Waka" kanji is one of those characters
that are prone to Gestaltzerfall.
And the mistress had the habit of licking her
thumb when she was about to turn pages.
So that means, the one who committed this crime was...
Yeah.
The one who showed the mistress the "Waka" kanji
many times and asked her to sign the contract was...
The secretary, Satake-san!
No one else could have committed this crime besides you!
Was it really Satake-san?
Unbelievable...
But...
Couldn't it have been a coincidence that the evidence
happened to be unfavorable toward Satake-san?
Since the reason Ikurou-san was hungry was
because the soy sauce happened to have run out...
I don't think it happened to have run out.
When Satake-san was asked by the mistress to prepare black
tea, she replied by asking which blend she should serve.
That means she was familiar with what was
where in the kitchen of this house, right?
So, she could have secretly dumped out the soy sauce, couldn't she?
Well, as the secretary...
You could've been able to guess that Ikurou-san would've gotten
hungry just as the director and the rest of us were to arrive.
The director bringing baumkuchen was
something that always happened.
Knowing how many guests there were, it was
easier for you to suggest dividing into eighths.
You were the one who said to cut it into eighths, right Satake-san?
Since it'd be hard to cut them equally if it were sixths or sevenths.
And then, pretending that you were putting the cut baumkuchen
onto the plates, you sprinkled poison on one of the two pieces.
Then, when was the poison on the doorknob and the slippers set up?
Likely before we arrived.
When we came here...
Satake-san was already inside the house, and had probably already
finished her preparations for the mistress's murder in the study.
However, I was the one who suggested that since the
vice-president was tired, she should stay in the study.
If you hadn't said that Satake-san would have simply said it herself!
And afterwards...
For an on-the-site inspection, you would need
to have a court-issued warrant in hand...
And present it to us before commencing.
So that you could make us take in the meaning of it.
The reason why she said that was to mislead us towards the
fake clue - the poison on the doorknob of Ikurou-san's room!
The one who called me to the president's home in Osaka...
And got me interested in optical illusions so that
I would come to this house was also you, no?
Since "my distorted existence is
thoughtlessly conjured up by humans"...
And "to see me directly is a dream"
both referred to optical illusions.
And for this trick to work, you need to
play the role of misleading people.
Thus, for those two who covered up the
president's murder using an optical illusion...
You killed them using optical illusions—it was an eye for an eye!
It certainly sounds like a trick worthy of a crime novel.
But all of it is circumstantial evidence.
You don't have anything like concrete
evidence to back up your deduction...
Ah-le-le?
Satake-san's wristwatch...
There are shiny spots here and there!
How come?
No, this...
That's the unshakable concrete evidence.
Most likely, when you were sprinkling powdered
poison onto the Japanese dictionary...
You accidentally got some on your left wrist
when you were holding the dictionary.
At that time, the cyanide-based poison which got into
the nooks and crannies of your bronze watch...
Caused a redox reaction with the water you used to wash your hands
in the restroom or somewhere, and that's when the rust came off.
You didn't notice that until the time you
said the last train was about to leave.
The last train will be leaving soon, after all.
You were looking at your watch then.
Isn't that why you held the plastic bottle in that weird way later on?
It was understandable for Fujinami-san to switch hands holding
the plastic bottle since he wanted to look at his watch.
But normally, people wouldn't hold a plastic bottle
with the same hand they used to take off the cap.
I see...
So that's how you caught on to the fact
that I was only using my right hand.
If I had used my left hand, my sleeve would've
slipped off and my watch would've been seen.
But how ironic...
To think this watch I got from my father gave me away.
Your father!?
So you're the president's daughter!?
Yes.
I'm my father's daughter from his first marriage.
Initially I planned to get hired and destroy the
company of the man who left my mother.
But when I realized he was just a pitiable man who was
absorbed in his work and clumsy at displaying his affection...
I joined him instead of beating him.
Not to mention he somehow already knew I was his daughter.
Did you know that my father had actually planned to
announce that I was his daughter at the Karuizawa villa?
I also heard that from the master.
But before that could happen, my father was killed by
Ikurou-san, and the evidence hidden by the vice-president.
I don't really know why my father was killed.
But after all, even I hated him before I really understood him.
Then, you read the contents of that sealed letter?
Yes.
But even afterwards, the vice-president didn't say anything.
So I suspected that she had deliberately entrusted the letter
to me for the purpose of having me kill Ikurou-san.
However, calling Hattori-kun here was a failure.
Even though i had intended to mislead you, you were a cut above.
No...
Perhaps I should say "you guys" instead?
Well, being that the trick was optical illusions.
sakushi
I guess this is what they call the tactician being played by the tactic.
She's got a way with words.
Hattori-kun just turned the brim of his hat to the back!
Your chance, your chance!
Maybe I should hold off for today after all?
Heiji must be tired from using his noggin for the case...
I'm borrowing Conan-kun for a bit.
Kazuha-chan, go for it!
What's with her?
I still have things to discuss, and yet she went
ahead and took him away as she pleased...
Don't ya get it?
She tactfully left the two of us alone.
Ya might have already heard this from Kudou-kun, but...
In London, Kudou-kun...
Apparently confessed his feelings to Ran-chan.
That's why, though I wouldn't have said this...
The truth is...
The truth is, I also...
Since a long time ago...
I...
I LIKE YA VERY MUCH!
He's not here!?
Heiji!?
If it's about Hattori-kun, he ran off in
the middle of your conversation...
At which part!?
Around the "The truth is" part...
Hey...
Kudou ~!
Don't ya have something to tell your
closest friend that is yours truly, eh-eh-eh?
No, of course not!
Just tell me, I bet ya have!
They're really like buddies...
So jealous of Conan-kun...
Out with it, don't hide from me ~
Like I said, there's nothing!
Haibara-san?
The one in the professor's house the seemingly gentle and short-haired girl?
Have you met her before?
No, I only saw her briefly recorded along
with the professor on a video site online.
But that's strange...
I thought for sure I wasn't in that footage at all...
Don't tell me!
THE PROFESSOR'S VIDEO SITE
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Eyeglass Lenses
Have you already watched the movie "The Eleventh Drunkad"?
Don't you mean "Striker"?
Own goaled...