This vase is my pride.
Would someone please appraise it for me?
I believe it's worth a fortune!
So this person is Professor Agasa?
I found this in my storage room when I was cleaning the place.
If you'd like to take my request...
If all cases were men...
I suppose the invisible mysteries would be women.
The professor's house is being targeted?
Ayumi's disappearance and the organization's shadow!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The curry's turning out to be very appetizing!
Yeah!
With this much, Genta-kun can have as many helpings as he wants!
You're right.
All that's left is to just cover it and let it simmer!
Let me see.
Before we do that, why don't I sample some?
Ow!
Can't I?
I will not allow someone with a plate
full of rice at the ready to sample any.
Poor me...
Just hang tight for a little longer, Professor.
Guess I don't have a choice...
At any rate, did you figure it out, Edogawa-kun?
The value of that vase.
No.
Only that it's fairly ancient-looking...
I still don't know which period it came from or who fired it.
Well, before Genta and Mitsuhiko come
back, I'll get to the bottom of things.
Today, we'll have curry~
Curry for lunch~
And for dinner, curry again~
Hey, Genta-kun...
Even though it's the professor's money
don't you think we bought too much?
After all, we were only asked to buy drinks.
It's all right!
Nothing beats having Yaiber chocolates and Yaiber snacks with us.
And Conan asked us to buy a soccer magazine for him, too.
I even bought the yogurt you like, Mitsuhiko!
Thank you very much!
Hey, you guys.
Are you acquaintances of Professor Agasa who lives at this house?
Yeah...
You're the one who was with Ran-neechan the other day!
So you were a woman after all!
Yeah.
The name's Sera Masumi.
But it's a bit weird since you don't have any boobs.
That's true.
Well, they're due to pop out any day now!
That's right, thank you for the other day.
You guys also helped us out on that besieging case, didn't you?
I was one of the hostages, you see.
So that happened to you?
Yeah, it was thanks to us Detective Boys who
went around investigating everywhere!
That, and thanks to Kudou Shinichi-kun.
The professor mentioned that.
He said a high school detective he knew
happened to show up and solve the case.
But Haibara-san reminded us to keep that a secret, so...
Haibara-san?
Could that be the one in the professor's house
the seemingly gentle and short-haired girl?
Actually, she's not gentle at all...
Have you met her before?
No, I only saw her briefly recorded along
with the professor on a video site online.
According to him, he was cleaning his storage room and
recovered an expensive-looking vase; so he was showing it off.
He was asking if anyone could appraise it for him too.
But, how come you have to keep Kudou-kun a secret?
That's his house right next door, isn't it?
Well...
He's always away from home.
But it seems that day he returned to pick up something
he forgot, and stopped by at the professor's house.
Isn't there someone in there right now?
I just saw the curtain shift slightly.
That must be...
That guy named Subaru!
A guy named Subaru?
His apartment burned down, so it
seems he was allowed to stay there.
And I thought someone had just settled in without permission, but...
It seems I was worried over nothing, huh?
It smells quite delicious!
Can we chow down already?
Not yet.
In about thirty minutes!
I still have to wait thirty minutes?
Does it really take that long?
But, there is such thing as a small dish you
eat before you get to the main course, right?
Hors d'oeuvre...
You mean an appetizer?
Yeah, yeah!
So I can eat a bit of curry as an "or-derve" and
then have a lot more curry as the main dish?
You can't!
Geez, Genta-kun and the professor, you both are terrible big eaters!
I've gotta do something or else I can't stand it!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
I'm researching this vase that the
professor dug out from his storage, but...
Looks like it'd be best if we asked
an appraiser to properly examine it.
Oh, they say the professor was showing it off on a video site...
Hey, Professor, you really don't remember?
Where you bought the vase from?
Well, all I can remember is that I bought
it at a flea market many years ago.
Along with that rug you're sitting on.
With this old and stale-looking rug?
Yeah.
I decided to spread it out since it also turned up in the storage.
Watch it, Genta!
Don't kick the soccer ball around inside!
I can't help it, can I?
I'm so hungry I feel like I'm gonna die, y'know!
Yes ma'am, I regret my actions...
Say it again like you mean it!
Yes ma'am, I swear I super regret my actions so much...
Come now, isn't that enough already?
Not at all!
Because of him, we have to go out and buy more
ingredients in order to make the curry again!
But I said to just let us go and buy them
so you could stay at home, didn't I?
IF I LEAVE IT TO YOU GUYS, YOU'LL GO AND
BUY USELESS JUNK AGAIN, WONT YOU!?
Sorry...
Then, I'll go and buy some meat from a shop that's having a sale!
Let's meet up at the supermarket later!
Haibara-san.
Please, stop being so mad already...
You know, you're scarier than my mom...
I'll make it clear.
Kojima-kun, you won't be getting a second helping of curry.
Wait...
Don't be like that...
I'm begging you, it's my once-in-a-lifetime wish!
No.
Stingy...
Ayumi-kun, I've put some clothes in the basket for you!
All right!
These are Ai-chan's clothes!
And Ai-chan's scent!
Professor, I'm done with my bath!
What!?
You're saying that footage of Haibara
was being shown on a video site!?
Is that for real?
Yeah.
In the footage where the professor was showing off
that vase from earlier, Haibara-san was also there.
That's what that neechan called Sera said.
Sera, you say!?
Where did you meet Sera?
In front of the professor's house.
Earlier when we were coming back after buying the drinks.
But that's strange...
I thought for sure I wasn't in that footage at all...
Then, call the professor and have him confirm it!
I'm calling now, but...
But... what?
No one's answering!
Hey, Conan!
Could it be...
Could it be!?
Don't tell me!
Professor!
Ayumi!
Everything all right!?
Hey, Professor!?
Hey, hang in there!
Professor, are you all right?
What happened?
The doorbell chimed so I went to answer it...
But suddenly I was knocked out with a zap...
A stun gun?
Could it be, someone was after the
vase that's the pride of the professor?
No, the vase is still here.
Spilled coffee on the floor...
And, traces showing something was on top of it.
Hey!
Ayumi is nowhere to be seen!
That ancient rug is also gone.
And the fact that spilled coffee stains are
next to where it had been laid out means...
When Ayumi was attacked by someone, she was pinned
down on top of the spilled coffee and restrained...
And it's highly probable that she was
wrapped up in the rug and taken away!
Why wrap her in the rug?
Instead of in a large bag, if they wrapped
her in that and left the house...
They'd look like movers or renovation workers
taking away a rug and would appear less suspicious.
Then, she was kidnapped!?
But, why pick Ayumi?
She was only here by chance!
Hey, Professor.
The video you uploaded onto the site, can you play it now?
This vase is my pride
Would someone please appraise it for me?
I believe it's worth a fortune!
But the Professor's the only one in it.
I found this in my storage room when I was cleaning the place.
No, wait.
Something's in the professor's glasses...
If you'd like to take my request...
Perhaps their intended target...
Had been Haibara instead!
So, do you mean to say...
The culprit mistook Ayumi-kun for
Ai-kun, and kidnapped her instead?
Yeah, that's highly probable.
If we think that they saw this footage on the video site...
Realized that Haibara was at this house and
planned on taking her away, it would make sense.
Perhaps the culprit saw us leaving to go
shopping earlier, decided to pay a visit...
Knocked down the professor with the stun gun...
Then wrapped Ayumi-chan, who was in the
house, into the rug and carried her out.
So the culprit had been watching this house?
Yeah.
But, if they were watching us, shouldn't they
have seen Haibara-san go out with us?
Haibara was wearing a cap back then and
had her hair done up inside of it, right?
It's safe to assume the culprit missed that it was her.
Also, the clothes I gave Ayumi-kun to change into...
Happened to be the exact clothes Ai-kun's wearing in that footage.
If she had her hood on, they would've thought she was Haibara.
It's all my fault...
If I hadn't played soccer inside the house
we wouldn't have had to go shopping!
It's not-your fault.
I was the cause...
This was all brought about because of my wretched circumstances...
No, that's not it.
It's not your fault at all.
If it had been them, they wouldn't have mistaken Ayumi-chan for you.
But!
Besides, think this situation through for a bit.
Right how, I'm checking the footage of you
on the professor's computer, right?
If this had been the work of those men in black, they would have
killed the professor, and ambushed you upon your return.
The data on this computer would've already been destroyed...
With the house set on fire, and any and all
traces that you had been here eradicated.
But, what if this is a trap?
Since I the intended target wasn't here, they could've
disguised as kidnappers and took Yoshida-san with them...
What if they intend to lure me out, knowing I'd be frantic!?
Perhaps, they abducted Yoshida-san in order to
interrogate her about how much she knew about me!
If they wanted to know that, they would've
kidnapped the professor instead.
No way would those guys risk doing something like kidnapping.
They'd rather secretly sniff around and devise plans...
And before you knew it, everything
would be gone—isn't that their M.O.?
Hey, you two!
What've you been whispering about all this time!?
Ah, no...
If it's about Ayumi-'chan's location, Conan-kun
can't you find that out using your glasses?
Because Ayumi-chan always has her
transmitter-equipped detective badge on her.
No.
I had checked earlier, but the badge's location is inside this house.
She probably left it in the clothes she changed out of.
Anyway, let's call the police...
What's that sound?
A cell phone ringtone!
It's coming from that vase!
It's Ayumi-chan's cell phone!
"Read the email, and follow the instructions"?
There's one email received...
From the professor's email address.
Don't tell me...
They stole my cell phone!
What are the instructions?
"Find this cat!
"It should be around your area.
"Once you've found it, send an email to this cell phone!
"Your girl will be released in exchange for the cat.
"Of course, if you contact the police, your girl will not live."
What's the meaning of this?
It's all because of that gray cat that Ayumi had to be taken!?
Seems like it.
Anyway, it seems certain that if we don't hurry and
find that cat soon, Yoshida-san will be in danger.
All right, I'll forward the image of this cat to all of your cell phones.
Let's split up and search!
Damn...
Can't find it anywhere!
Any contact from the culprit?
Nothing yet.
Since we can't tell how big the cat is just from this
image, I've been sending emails trying to ask them.
So why aren't they answering!?
Don't tell me, they gave up on trying to
find the cat, and Ayumi-kun's already...
Idiot!
Would someone who'd go as far as to kidnap a child
in an attempt to locate a cat give up so easily?
From the professor's address...
An email from the culprit!
What's it say?
No way, is that for real?
Yeah.
You guys are searching around the housing
complexes in the 3rd district, right?
Yes, that's right.
The culprit's email...
Says the following.
"Found the cat!
"Your girl will be released at the trash collection
point for the complexes in the 3rd district."
Hey, Ayumi!
Ayumi!
She's nowhere around though!
Could it be...
Yoshida-san!
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
You're safe now.
But how fortunate!
That Ayumi-kun was returned safely...
And looks like you don't have any injuries at all.
Yes, I'm fine!
My cell phone was also wrapped in the rug along with Ayumi-kun.
And although the back of the rug is a little dirty,
it too has been returned without any stains.
But what a horrible culprit!
Yeah.
Asking us to find the cat, andthen not even apologizing when it
was found, instead throwing Ayumi-chan away with the trash!?
They said it was some sort of precious cat.
So you heard the culprit's voice?
Yeah.
They sounded high-pitched and creepily strange, though.
So they inhaled helium gas to change their voice?
And then, did the culprit say anything else?
Well, they seemed really frantic.
They were saying how it was their master's
precious cat, so it'd be bad if they couldn't find it
Was it the cat of a really wealthy person?
I don't know about that...
But it seems they thought that it ran away somewhere nearby, and
were sure that professor took it in and kept it as pet in his house.
Even i elled, "If he'd been keeping the cat, there should be a cat litter
box, water tray, and food dish somewhere there, so go look for it!"
So it wasn't just one culprit!?
Yeah.
It seems there were two people.
Both had strange voices, and were wearing hats
with holes cut out for their eyes and mouths.
So a twosome wearing ski masks?
Super bad people then!
But, they let Ayumi out of the rug once, and let me drink some water!
And after they wrapped me up in the rug again
they even asked me whether I can still breathe.
Plus, they said that they had to wrap me in the rug because
they didn't bring anything other than a carrybag for cats.
In other words...
Some caretakers for a wealthy person's pet cat
somewhere accidentally let that cat escape...
And in order to get that cat back, they were in a frenzy
and even went so far as to commit kidnapping.
But in the end, they were able to find
it themselves—what a stupid story!
But if that were the case, they could've just told us truthfully,
"It's our master's cat, so if you took it in, please return it to us."
Well, maybe they thought if we knew the owner was well-to-do...
We'd request a huge reward, and the fact that
they lost it would be revealed to the master?
No, I don't think this case is that straightforward.
It doesn't matter that we left to go shopping.
If they didn't know for sure that the professor and
Ayumi-chan were the only ones in the house...
Normally they wouldn't have just barged into
the house with just a stun gun, right?
Plus, it hadn't been thirty minutes from the time
we left to go shopping to when we returned.
If it had been their first time in this house...
Then, in such a short time span, for them to knock the professor
out, confirm that the cat wasn't anywhere in the house...
And wrap Ayumi-chan in the rug and take her
away—do you think it would've been possible?
What's more, they were even able to find the
professor's and Ayumi-chan's cell phones.
Then, could it be the culprits were...
Yeah.
They were knowledgeable.
About the fact that the professor and Haibara
were the only ones living in this house...
That your friends, the four of us, would often come here to visit...
And that all of us have cell phones!
But how did the et all that info?
Have any strangers come to this house recently?
That reminds me, they have.
There were three groups.
Three groups?
You see, those people came here after watching that video site.
It's likely that the culprits were among those three groups.
I'll definitely seek you out!
Next Conan's Hint
Ear
Watch our next episode! Right 'ere, 'ere, 'ere!
Professor... is that a pun?