An old vase turned up in the storage
at Professor Agasa's residence.
The professor posted a video on a video-sharing
site in order to get an appraisal on its value.
But who would've thought it would lead to this case?
While we were out buying ingredients for curry
the professor was knocked out with a stun gun...
And Ayumi-chan, who had also been at the house, was kidnapped.
We thought the target was the vase
but the vase was left at the scene
And instead, the rug which was found along with the vase was gone
Looks like it was used to take Ayumi-chan away
Soon, we received an email from the culprit.
It ordered us to search for the cat in the attached
photo, and exchange it for Ayumi-chan.
We split up and searched for it, but couldn't find it anywhere.
As the sun was setting and our anxiety rose
we received another email from the culprit.
Saying that they had found the cat
themselves, so they released the hostage.
We found Ayumi-chan safe and sound
but what are the culprits scheming?
If all cases were man...
I suppose the invisible mysteries wold be women.
The lingering shadows from the organization...
Are they targeting the case, the cat, or Haibara?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
In other words...
Some caretakers for a wealthy person's pet cat
somewhere accidentally let that cat escape...
And in order to get that cat back, they were in a frenzy
and even went so far as to commit kidnapping.
But in the end, they were able to find
it themselves—what a stupid story!
But if that were the case, they could've just told us truthfully,
"It's our master's cat, so if you took it in, please return it to us."
Well, maybe they thought if we knew the owner was well-to-do...
We'd request a huge reward, and the fact that
they lost it would be revealed to the master?
No, I don't think this case is that straightforward.
It doesn't matter that we left to go shopping.
If they didn't know for sure that the professor and
Ayumi-chan were the only ones in the house...
Normally they wouldn't have just barged into
the house with just a stun gun, right?
Plus, it hadn't been thirty minutes from the time
we left to go shopping to when we returned.
If it had been their first time in this house...
Then in such a short time span, for them to knock the professor
out, confirm that the cat wasn't anywhere in the house...
And wrap Ayumi-chan in the rug and take her
away—do you think it would've been possible?
What's more, they were even able to find the
professor's and Ayumi-chan's cell phones.
Then, could it be the culprits were...
Yeah.
They were knowledgeable.
About the fact that the professor and Haibara
were the only ones living in this house...
That your friends, the four of us, would often come here to visit...
And that all of us have cell phones!
But, how did they get all that info?
Have any strangers come to this house recently?
That reminds me, they have.
There were three groups.
Three groups?
You see, those people came here after watching that video site.
Then, about the three groups, what did they look like?
Let's see, the first group was a pair of young sisters.
They lifted the vase, knocked on it, and gazed at it for a while...
But asked me to sell it to them for 500 yen.
For 500 yen?
So is that vase such an worthless item?
I asked them about that too, but...
It seems they were thinking, "We don't really know, but
we can make it a good flower vase if it's for 500 yen."
I asked them to examine it more thoroughly, but they said
their legs were falling asleep so they were going home.
You had the vase placed on the floor?
Yeah, on top of that rug.
Thought it'd look nicer this way.
Next to come were a middle-aged couple.
Without touching the vase once, they used a
magnifying glass and thoroughly examined it.
And?
What'did they say?
They said that it might be a really valuable vase, so they
recommended that I take it to a professional appraiser.
And they also said it'd be a good idea not to show it to the others
since there might be bad people who'd want to drive down its value.
What about the third group?
They were an extremely rude father and son!
Having only touched the vase and peeked
inside for a split second, the son asked me.
"How much do you think this is worth?"
while grinning like a Cheshire cat.
So I snapped and spat out "About 500,000 yen! If you
buy it now, I'll even throw in the rug as a bonus!"
But the father wryly smiled and said, "You humor me."
Then both of them laughed and snorted, "People
without a discerning eye are pathetic, no?'
That's why I got so mad that I ran them out!
And?
Was Haibara nearby at those times?
No, all three groups came here while Ai-kun was at school.
Come to think of it...
There was someone who asked a lot of questions
such as Ai-kun's time of return, her friends...
And what we do on Saturdays and Sundays.
That must be the culprit right there!
So you don't remember who that person was?
Well, I'm surest was among those three groups, but...
Among those three groups, was there anyone who spoke of cats?
Especially about this Russian Blue.
Our conversations were almost all about the vase...
Russian Blue?
If I remember correctly, the cat Ran's
mother has is also a Russian Blue.
Speaking of vases and cats, they remind me of the vase cat videos!
What are those?
About cats going inside vases, and they're very cute!
Hey, Professor!
What was the title of your video?
Let's see...
"The cat's out of the bag—help me appraise
this vase", or something like that.
In that case. I'll search the videos using
"cat" and "vase" as keywords...
Found it, Ran's mother's video.
It's the one right above the professor's video?
Wow, it's Vase Cat!
No no, you can't get in there!
How cute!
Goro-chan, say hello to everyone!
Hey, that cat...
Doesn't it look like the culprits' cat?
You're right!
Even the background is exactly the same.
But why would Eri-san's cat be...?
After all, there's no reason Eri-san would
knock me out with a stun gun, is there?
Wait.
Why didn't the culprits use the stun gun on Ayumi-chan?
If they'd knocked her out like they did to the professor, they
wouldn't have had to change their voices using helium gas.
So why?
Huh?
You've got something on your ear.
This is...
When I was running away from the culprits, the coffee spilled out...
And I was pinned down on top of it,
so the coffee got all over my hood.
It does look like the coffee stained the hood a lot.
When I was wrapped in the rug, the coffee soaked all over my ear.
It felt really uncomfortable!
Sorry Ai-chan, for getting your clothes dirty.
It'll come right off in the wash.
I see.
So that means the culprits' target wasn't
Haibara, nor the vase, nor the cat...
And so?
What are we going to do about this incident?
Do we report it to the police just in case?
Good point, since Ayumi-kun was indeed kidnapped.
But do you think they'll believe us?
Something like two people in ski masks
suddenly broke into this house...
Used a stun gun to knock out the professor,
wrapped Ayumi-chan in the rug, and took her away?
What's more, that their purpose was to have us search
for their master's pet cat that had run away nearby?
True.
The email those two kidnappers sent ordering us to find the
cat was from the cell phone they took from the professor.
And the receiving end was Yoshida-san's cell
phone, which they had placed inside that vase.
What's more, both the kidnappers changed their voices
using helium gas, so we have absolutely zero clues.
Not to mention Yoshida-san, having been wrapped in the rug...
Likely didn't know where she had been
taken or which way she was returned.
But, didn't Ayumi say this?
That they let you out from the rug
once and let you drink some water.
Wouldn't that be at the culprits' hideout?
Nuh-uh.
It was dark so I couldn't really see, but I think
it was the inside of a car that was running.
The only possible clue we have would be this image
of a cat that the culprits sent and asked us to find.
But judging by how it looked exactly like the footage
Eri-san uploaded to the internet of her pet cat...
It appears that they likely borrowed an image of a cat of the same
breed and sent it to us in order for them to not be tracked.
But, perhaps someone saw those suspicious people
moving the rug, so let's contact the police just in case!
Say, can we contact them after we make the curry?
'Cause I'm super hungry right now...
Me too.
In that case, Ayumi will go take a shower.
Since my ear is still dirty because of the coffee stain.
Hold on a moment.
Sorry but I'll have to ask you to take a
shower after we've caught the culprits.
The stain was there since Ayumi-chan was pinned down
on the spilled coffee and restrained by the culprits...
Then wrapped in the rug and taken away
which is a piece of critical evidence!
So until the culprits are caught, Ayumi can't take a shower!?
No worries, just bear with me for a bit.
For we'll be marching right up to where the culprits are soon!
Then, are you saying you know who the culprits are?
Yeah.
The professor probably knows them too.
They're someone I know?
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me you're trying to say Eri-san is the culprit!
No way!
That picture of the cat was just like you said, Professor, it
was something the culprits randomly chose and sent to us.
And it was only chance that it happened to be Kisaki-sensei's cat.
Randomly?
Didn't the culprits kidnap Ayumi-chan in order to search for that cat?
No, anything would have sufficed.
As long as they could roll Ayumi-chan up in the rug and take her
out from this house, any plausible excuse would have worked!
In other words, their ordering us to find the cat was just an excuse?
Yeah.
First of all, don't you find it weird?
That the professor was knocked out by the stun gun all of a sudden...
Yet Ayumi-chan only had her mouth covered with sticky tape?
Although thanks to that, from the culprits' conversation...
We were able to gather that they were trying
to search for their master's lost cat...
And that they had no choice but to kidnap Ayumi-chan by
wrapping her in the rug in order to make us find the cat.
But If they had knocked Ayumi-chan out like
they did to the professor in the first place...
They wouldn't have had to change their
voices using helium gas, would they?
That's true...
So the only reason they would've done that was...
That the culprits wanted Ayumi-chan to hear their conversation.
In order to keep us from realizing that their real
target was the rug, wrapped around Ayumi-chan!
The rug, you say?
So is this old, rubbish-looking rug expensive?
No, this is probably cheap stuff.
Then why?
Didn't the professor just mention it?
That although the back is a little dirty, it had
been returned without any stains on the front.
But during the time Ayumi-chan was wrapped in the rug, the coffee
that soaked into her hood even got so far as to stain her ear, right?
That being the case, shouldn't there be
coffee stains on here somewhere?
And yet, the fact that there aren't any stains on here means..
I see.
They switched it.
When they gave Yoshida-san water to drink.
Yeah.
The reason why they let Ayumi-chan out of the rug in the
dark for a while was so that she wouldn't notice the switch.
And they probably had this rug that has a similar pattern
already in that car, so that they could swap them quickly.
But, if that's the case, they didn't have to go and kidnap Ayumi-chan!
He's right.
Why couldn't they just come and steal the rug?
I see!
If it had been stolen, we would've filed a theft report...
And they wouldn't have been able to sell it, right?
Yeah.
Since the pattern of that rug is recorded
plain as day in the professor's video.
However, I don't believe there are such nefarious
characters within my acquaintances...
Even if I call them your acquaintances
you've only met them once recently.
Recently?
Do you mean those who came to appraise that vase?
Yeah.
The sisters who lifted the vase, knocked
on it, and looked at it for some time...
And the couple who used a magnifying glass and
thoroughly examined the vase without touching it...
And the father and son who laughed after being told that the
professor would sell the vase and throw in the rug for 500,000 yen.
So the father and son who came last were suspicious?
Yeah, I bet they knew the value of the rug, and
were trying to knock the price down further!
No, it's the opposite.
It's because the Professor quoted too
low of a price that they laughed.
The culprits wanted it so much that they'd even kidnap a child...
Means that the professor's rug is probably a Persian rug.
No two have the same design, and depending on the
rug it could even easily sell for over ten million yen.
Ten million yen!?
It's true that looking at the inside and outside of a vase
to ascertain its age is also a method of appraisal.
So the father and son were such connoisseurs that they could tell the
vase's value just by briefly touching it and peeking at the inside.
They likely immediately realized that the rug
was a Persian, but they're not the culprits.
Why not?
If they would go so far as to commit this sort of
crime in order to get their hands on the rug...
There's no way they wouldn't have taken the 500,000 yen offer.
So, the sisters who came first are the culprits?
Why not the couple who were the second to come?
Of course not them!
Since that couple kindly advised me that it may be something
really valuable, so I'd better have an appraiser look at it.
Wasn't that about the vase though?
And to be accurate, they suggested you to "take it to a
professional appraiser and have them take a look," right?
Yeah...
In other words...
We could infer their meaning to be, "It'd be bad if anyone else
realized it was a Persian rug, so don't invite anyone else here!"
Plus, in contrast to the sisters who picked
up the vase and gazed for a while...
The couple never touched the vase once, and only
checked it with magnifying glasses, right?
That's right...
It was natural for the sisters who only focused on the
vase to do what they did, but not so for that couple.
If the vase was placed atop the rug, they should've been
able to see it on their magnifying glasses, right?
I get it!
What that couple was examining was...
The pattern of the rug.
They weren't just checking if the rug was a real Persian rug or not...
But they were confirming whether or not it
was the rug they had been searching for.
It was probably a rug they had seen somewhere
before, and wanted so much they couldn't stand it.
Otherwise, there's no way they'd be so tenacious over
a rug they happened to come across at a video site.
So, they came here to make sure of the rug
under the guise of appraising the vase...
Found out about the professor's lack of knowledge
about not only the vase but also the rug...
And that you and Haibara were the only two living
here, that's when they hatched the scheme.
But, how are we going to find out where the culprits are?
The fact that they didn't want Ayumi-chan to hear their real voices...
Means it's highly probable that they
run a shop somewhere in the area.
So if we narrow them down to shops that
handle rugs, I bet we can quickly...
Aye-aye, already working on it.
Found it.
Interior Shop Kanbe in the 3rd district.
Looks like they also handle rugs.
The shop president's face is on the homepage.
Is this the right person?
Oh, that's right!
It's this person!
No doubt about it!
Bingo.
Oh my, aren't you that...
I'm surprised that you found my house!
We stopped by your shop earlier, and they told us
that their president was resting at home with a cold.
But looking at you, it seems you've
already recovered from your cold, huh!
No.
I still have a bit of a cough...
Anyway, what brings you here?
I heard that your shop also handles rugs, so I was
thinking of having you take a look at my rug.
Oh.
And, who are these kids?
I couldn't transport it on my own, so I got them to help out.
It's well-made, but...
It does appear to be a fake.
So it's indeed like that?
Well, there are quite a number of fake
Persian rugs on the market, you know.
Then, is this rug propped up here a real one?
That one's the real deal.
Ah-le?
There's something caught within the rug!
Looks like a photo.
What kind of photo?
This is
A photo of a rug!
Looks just like the professor's!
But, why would such a photo be here?
Ah, no...
Since my wife is a scatterbrain...
Right?
Yeah...
I often roll up newspapers and such into it...
Oh really?
Here I thought you had spread out the rug you stole...
And were in the middle of comparing it with the
photo when the professor came calling...
So you accidentally rolled the photo up with
it in a rush, but was I thinking too much?
Let's spread it out and take a look!
Yeah!
Hold on!
My, looks exactly like the professor's rug!
But the pattern's a bit different, right?
It sure seems the rug in the photo is this one.
Ah-le?
There's a stain in the shape of an ear!
Judging from the odor, it appears to be coffee.
That's also my wife...
You see, I'm so careless that I, in a hurry...
Don't you know?
Ear shapes are also called earprints.
And just like fingerprints, no two people
in the world have the same shape.
So if we compare the stain with Ayumi-chan's
earprint, I think we'll find out right away...
That you wo were the culprits who rolled
Ayumi-chan into this rug and kidnapped her!
What the heck?
Who the hell are you!?
Edogawa Conan
A detective.
The police arrived shortly afterward, and
took the kidnappers into custody.
It seems the professor's rug had belonged to a wealthy person.
When that rich person passed away...
It was left to one of the heirs, but after multiple changes
of hands, it came into the professor's possession.
The culprit couple had done the interior
design for that wealthy person's home...
And after having heard that the heir who received the rug sold it
without knowing its value, had been on the hunt for it ever since.
What brought the rug to their attention was...
Because the wife was obsessed with vase cat videos.
Taking advantage of the girl reflected in the professor's glasses...
And the cat in Kisaki-sensei's video which
was the one above the professor's...
They hatched this plot as a means of getting their hands on the rug.
Woo-hoo!
Incidentally, the professor was overjoyed
at finding out that it was a Persian rug.
Boo-hoo
But was let down to hear that since it was case evidence...
The police can't return it until the investigation
and trials are concluded in some months...
So the professor's dream of replacing his Beetle with
a new car seems to have been put on hold for now.
But, will it be alright?
Will what?
The footage of me reflected in the professor's glasses.
Hasn't that been distributed all over the world?
It's fine.
We already deleted that video.
And the kidnappers also said it was only by chance they-saw you
when they blew up the image to look at the pattern of the rug.
Hold on...
How come that wannabe was able to find the footage of Haibara?
Delete...
Delete, delete...
Deleted.
If only things were like data and could be instantly deleted.
If you eat it with the person you have a
crush on, your love shall be fulfilled...
Hidden behind such rumored chocolat
is a bitter, scorching trap of hatred.
No use showing a sweet and naive face.
I shall solve the fiery trick!
THE HOT TRAP OF CHOCOLAT
Next Conan's Hint
Table Cloth
Look Forward to the Next Episode