I'm so excited!
We'll get to eat chocolates made by Yukihiko Tsujimoto,
who won first place in the world championship!
And the shop's producer, Mayuko Sakura-san, is so young and beautiful!
So much that they say Tsujimoto-san's success would've been impossible without her!
And the two of them are together!
They make quite a couple.
Ahh... Made by a world-renowned chocolatier...
and a beautiful shop producer...
Love Romance Chocolate!
If you eat it together with someone you like, your love will come true!
That's great!
Full-on girly talk, huh...
Ah, I wanted to eat it with Makoto-san...
Don't worry, eating something tasty with anyone will make you happy.
You may say that, but didn't you want to eat it with Shin'ichi-kun?
It's not like that...
We are going to eat it together though...
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Chocolate is the fuse that wraps the case in the flames of love!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Mayuko-san, it's been so long!
Thank you for inviting us.
Welcome to Le trésor de fruits. We've been expecting you.
What a wonderful shop.
The Suzuki Financial Group have given me their complete support,
Mayuko Sakura (25)
Shop Producer
so everything here is first-class.
The store opens tomorrow,
so you're our first customers.
Can we eat Tsujimoto-san's chocolate in the shop too?
The concept behind our shop is to allow you to eat freshly-made chocolate.
Hey, are those bottles liquor?
That's a fruit liquor called nalewka,
made by pickling fruit in strong liquor.
Wow! They all look lovely and tasty!
They do! So much so it makes you feel bad if you don't eat them...
The chocolates in this store are each shaped like jewels,
as the name of the store means the treasure of fruits in French.
What are these fruits?
They're pieces of the fruit in the fruit liquor on the rack made into chocolates.
So would you like to try one?
I can't drink liquor yet...
Don't worry. The alcohol in it has been burnt away.
Then by all means I'll take a taste of adulthood...
Delicious!
Your love may come true too, Ran-san.
Then so will I...
Delicious!
Yukihiko Tsujimoto (41)
Chocolatier
Welcome to my atelier, Le trésor de fruits.
This is the chocolatier, Yukihiko Tsujimoto.
Congratulations on winning first place!
It's an honour to meet you.
Thank you.
I too am honoured...
that such cute girls consider me so highly.
What a snob...
I'll introduce you.
This is Ran Mouri-san.
Nice to meet you.
And this is Sonoko Suzuki-san,
a lady from the Suzuki Financial Group.
Nice to meet you.
I'm charmed, milady.
As I expected, you have the elegance of nobility.
Go ahead.
I must prepare, so please wait here.
Please enjoy yourselves to your heart's content.
Well, I should start preparing.
So that you can enjoy the first-place winning work that will be introduced at tomorrow's opening event.
Go for it!
Do you intend to announce your wedding tomorrow too?
That's a secret.
I'm getting more and more jealous!
Lady my ass...
She's just a high school brat.
Ah well... if she's interested in me,
it'll make it easier to get money from the Financial Group.
Hey, Sonoko, what're you doing?
A photo to commemorate the end of bachelorhood.
Tsujimoto-san's just so great after all!
Really? He's different from how I thought he'd be.
Mayuko-san's better than him.
Well, shall we begin?
Now, Le trésor de fruits's opening ceremony hereby begins.
And, the chocolatier who was honoured with the first place at the world championship,
Yukihiko Tsujimoto enters!
Beautiful...
This is the first Japanese showing of the chocolate titled de l'espace, to the stars...
The ingredients are the top-class Criollo cacao and cocoa butter,
and a fruit liquor containing fruits carefully selected to bring out the fullest flavour of the chocolate.
It's almost like a sculpture...
It's really great!
But the main show has yet to come.
And now, beyond your dreams...
Let me take you to a faraway galaxy.
So these are the flames of love!
What the...
Run!
Sonoko!
Ran-néechan, call the fire brigade!
Conan-kun, run!
Yukihiko-san!
Everyone, get out!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun...
So, have you found what started the fire?
We're still investigating, but it seems like the bottles that fell from this rack
contained a strongly alcoholic liquor, which caught fire and and caused it to spread.
Inspector Yuminaga.
This is the co-manager, Mayuko Sakura-san.
How would you say the fire started?
Suddenly, the fruit liquor around the chocolate caught fire,
and surprised, Tsujimoto bumped into the rack and the bottles fell...
and then, then Tsujimoto was...
It seems that inside was a fruit liquor called nalewka, made by placing fruit into spirytus.
Spirytus? That's a vodka with 96% alcohol.
Inspector, we've determined that Tsujimoto-san's clothes were made from velvet pile, which burns very easily.
It's my fault...
I'm the one who chose the fabric for his new cook's coat... I never thought this could happen...
Mayuko-san, let's go sit down over there...
Is that okay, Inspector Yuminaga?
S-Sure.
Inspector, have you considered that the fire could've been caused by static electricity?
The volatile alcohol in the fruit liquor
gets ignited by static electricity in his clothes.
Surprised, Tsujimoto-san collided with the rack,
the liquor that spilled out of the bottles spread on the floor, and at once flames rose up.
Also, since he was wearing fabric which burns easily,
the fire spread to Tsujimoto-san, you mean?
Inspector, isn't it too early to decide that it was an accident
caused by static electricity just because you can't find anything else?
Brats shouldn't stick their noses in investigations!
Hey, kid!
No... when the fruit liquor caught fire, a big flame rose up straight away...
A pistachio shell?
Why would one be here?
And here, too?
Could the pistachio shells have been left under the nalewka bottles to make them easier to topple over?
I'm only going to say this once, kid.
A crime scene's not a playground.
Mayuko-san, does it hurt?
What happened?
When the fire spread, some flames got onto Mayuko-san's sleeve.
I'm fine.
I quickly put it out myself.
Hey, why did Mayuko-san's clothes get burnt too?
Nothing happened to any of us.
Just to be clear, could you tell us exactly what happened?
When the fire spread,
and Sonoko-san and her friend tried to run, my sleeve suddenly caught fire...
I think it was probably a flying spark.
Then Sakura-san, you were far away from Tsujimoto-san?
Yes.
If I remember correctly, after handing the silver pot to Tsujimoto-san, she was next to Sonoko.
Certainly, after that, Mayuko-san never left Sonoko's side...
Ah, come to think of it, after Tsujimoto-san poured the water into the chocolate's bowl, he had an odd expression.
As if something unexpected had happened...
Inspector, this thing was found near to the corpse.
What is that?
The remains of burnt steel wool.
Huh? Steel wool?
Why would that be there?
Well, there was a scrubbing brush made from steel wool in the kitchen.
Hey, mister, what do you think this is?
What?
What is it this time?
It looks like non-woven fabric.
It's used as an ingredient in packing materials.
It's used a lot in deodorant bags, right?
Kid, you sure know a lot...
But don't you think it's weird?
Why would a deodorant be here?
There were deodorants found in the fridge in the kitchen too.
This is probably the same thing.
It wouldn't be odd for something from the kitchen to be here.
Now, go back over there!
Right!
No, he's wrong... If that was a deodorant bag, then...
There're some sort of crystals in the pot?
Salt?
So that's it, salt, deodorant, steel wool, and...
if I can just find the one missing piece...
Inspector.
Inspector! It seems like it was static that caused the fire.
Tsujimoto-san's scarf was made from nylon.
I see.
When nylon is combined with a cotton fabric like velvet,
it easily develops static electricity.
So then it was just a static accident, huh...
You should go and have it looked at in hospital...
I'll be fine with something like this.
But...
Hey, inspector! How long are you gonna keep injured people here?
Well, the cause of the fire has been found, so it should be fine.
Oh no... At this rate they'll decide it was just an accident!
Let's go, Mayuko-san.
If my deduction is correct, it should still be here...
Oh, no! Ants are getting into the chocolate in the evidence!
Really?
Huh? There aren't any ants.
That's odd... I saw black things moving...
Before the ants come back, shouldn't you collect and hold onto it?
Yes, I should.
I was right... This was no accident. It was a skillfully engineered murder!
Here, Mayuko-san.
Okay...
Come to think of it, where did that brat with glasses get to?
Chocola-li-la-la...
Wait a minute.
Sonoko?
I've figured it out. The trick that murdered Tsujimoto-san!
Hey, girl, this was an accident.
An accidental fire caused by static electricity.
amai
How naïve, Inspector.
Amai?
amai
Sweeter than chocolate with lots of milk.
Then why don't you tell me about this trick of yours.
You don't have to ask.
First, I'll start explaining the fire by identifying its real source.
Among the evidence found at the crime scene, there are three key pieces.
Deodorant, salt crystals, and aluminium foil.
Salt crystals and aluminium foil? What do you mean?
There are salt crystals inside the silver pot.
Aluminium foil was recently recovered by the officers.
Along with the melted chocolate.
It is.
Indeed.
And now I'll provide you with some entertainment.
Conan-kun, bring it out.
Okay!
This is what Sonoko-néechan asked me to make.
Ran-néechan, could you pour water from the teapot into each of the aluminium cups except the top one?
Sure.
That much is fine.
What!?
This is a reproduction of the ignition method used in the case.
What just happened...
Hm? Beneath the origami crane, there's bright red steel wool...
Is that what burned the crane?
There is charcoal placed in the cup beneath.
And the water in the pot is salt water.
I see, you made an air battery.
Using the phenomenon that electricity is created by a chemical reaction between aluminium and salt water.
The materials of that air battery are the same as the items found at the crime scene.
That explains the fire's power, but how did the fire start?
Inspector, when electricity flows through steel wool, it catches fire.
Basically, the cause of the fire was not static, but an ignition switch comprised of those materials.
Mayuko-san, what was that chocolate swan supposed to do when water was poured on it to begin with?
It's...
When doing so, Tsujimoto-san said
Let me take you to a faraway galaxy.
Probably, dry ice was supposed to have been in there.
When water was poured on it, a white mist would flow out, creating the illusion of a galaxy.
The killer replaced the dry ice with an ignition switch made from an air battery.
Not knowing that, Tsujimoto-san poured in the salt water himself,
electrifying and igniting the steel wool, which set the fruit liquor on fire.
But if Tsujimoto-san hadn't knocked the bottles off the rack in surprise,
then the fire wouldn't have risen up too much, right?
Those bottles had pistachio shells placed beneath them beforehand,
to make them lean over and be easier to knock down.
Indeed, pistachio shells had been found on the rack.
But the killer's trap didn't end there. It was planned from even earlier.
What?
Ran, think back.
When Tsujimoto-san saw the fruit liquor had caught fire, was he that surprised?
Wait a sec, when the fruit liquor caught fire, Tsujimoto-san bumped into the rack...
Ah, that's right! Just before that, a huge flame rose up!
What!? Are you sure?
Yes. After that, the bottles fell and the fire grew larger,
and I must have muddled up my memories.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
In such a dangerous place, it can't be helped.
But how was that huge flame she mentioned made?
Beneath the table, the murderer set up a paper container full of spirytus.
By doing so, the air beneath the tablecloth was filled with volatile alcohol.
So by pulling up the cloth just before the show, part of the alcohol was released.
That was ignited by the burning fruit liquor.
Mayuko-san, just before the show started, you fixed up the tablecloth, right?
Yes... Mayuko Sakura-san. You did it!
That can't be... Mayuko-san!?
Sonoko-san, stop joking.
I'm suffering from being burnt too.
No, that itself is what proves your guilt.
The reason your sleeve caught fire is because when you set up the liquor beneath the table,
part of the alcohol splashed onto your sleeve.
So that's why only her sleeve was burnt.
That's just distorting events!
Sakura-san, will you tell me why you did it?
It can't be... even the police suspect me!?
To begin with, that ignition switch is nothing more than things from the kitchen!
It's obvious you'd find them at the crime scene!
It certainly is obvious.
That's why you intentionally aimed to use such an intricate device.
This shop opens tomorrow!
Contractors, administrators, many people have been in and out!
Couldn't any of them have done it too!?
No, it cannot have been anyone but you.
Ran, take my mobile out of my pochette.
Uh, sure.
Show Mayuko-san the photo I took earlier.
The photo... this one?
Just before the show started,
Tsujimoto-san drank water from the pot.
If it had been full of salt water, he would've noticed.
The only one who could've put salt in afterward... is you.
I was... nothing more than a tool to him...
It's almost here... our dreams are finally coming true.
Right, in setting up a shop in the best district in Tōkyō,
I've come to be Japan's topmost chocolatier.
It's about time you should think about our wedding too.
Wedding?
So you've been deceived by the media too?
I'm grateful to you.
You gave me various ideas to help me succeed.
You're my greatest tool.
Tool...?
But my dream came true.
I have the greatest status and the greatest shop.
I don't need any old tools anymore!
No way...
You'll be fired at the opening.
Thanks for everything.
I loved and devoted myself to him.
But he discarded me as if I had worn out...
Mayuko-san...
If I was going to lose everything anyway, then I wanted it to burn.
Him... this shop...
and my... love...
Well, I guess if mysteries need the Great Deduction Queen Sonoko,
toke
then even I can solve a case once in a while.
Ah! The love crystal chocolate I wanted to eat with Makoto-san melted!?
Ah... too much toke is a crime in itself...
And in the end, I didn't even get to eat a bite...
Die!
It's called the Red Oily Pssht case.
Was it someone who has it in for the police...?
Hey... haven't we seen that policewoman somewhere?
Isn't she Officer Chiba's first love?
That's...
On the next Conan: Co-Investigating with a First Love (Part I)
Next Conan's Hint: Airbag!
Next time, those officers get their own love story!
Ran, what do you think about that?
Huh? Nothing...