Well, 'The Giant Monster Gomera: Ambitions' sure was fun!
Yeah! Gomera was super-cool!
He even almost crushed the National Dieters' Building!
It's not Dieters', it's the Diet Building...
And even though the last Gomera was called 'final'
they've managed to continue it well.
They plan to release 'Revolution' in half a year too.
Though I sorta wanna see that too...
Well then, let's go eat lunch at a family restaurant...
Huh? Where'd the kids go?
Hm? They were just here.
Hm? Hey, you guys, what're you doing?
Conan-kun, come and see!
Awesome!
Whoa... it's filled with plastic models and figures...
There's even a doll of Emera, the fairy from Gomera!
It must be a big fan's car!
Around the keyhole... scratches?
Could someone have...
...broken in?
Conan-kun?
Whoa! What's this paint thinner smell?
Where... where is it coming from...
Die!
What's this!?
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
While co-investigating car break-ins,
an officer's love takes a sudden turn!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Co-Investigating with a First Love
(Part I)
Hmm? What is it?
Did something happen?
W-Wha...!?
This is...
That's horrible!
What're you brats doing!?
Don't just get into someone's car!
W-We're sorry!
It's been vandalised!
Someone's written 'Die!' in red spray paint on the ceiling!
Hey, this is a police officer's car.
Officer?
Huh?
If it isn't Conan-kun.
O-Officer Chiba!
So this fanatic's car is Chiba's?
Fanatic?
We saw lots of boxes of figures
and stuff lined up against the rear window.
So when you said you forgot something in the car,
you really just wanted to unbag and line them up?
Sorry... since I'd finally bought them I thought I'd show them off...
Though, writing 'Die!' on the ceiling is nasty...
Could it be someone with a grudge against the police...
Wouldn't it be someone with a grudge against Officer Chiba himself?
Since you can't tell this is an officer's car.
Well, I'll contact Yumi-san from the Traffic Dept....
Huh? There've already been three cases this month!?
All of them similar car break-ins?
Yeah, and yours is the fourth.
It's called 'the red oily Pssht case.'
'The Red Oily Pssht?'
It's because oil-based spray paint goes 'pssht', right?
Really, officer or not,
if you go out buying this sorta stuff you're still gonna get targeted.
I'm off-duty today! I only met up with him to help go shopping!
But don't you like these sorta things too?
W-Well I can't deny that...
See, even the rookie's laughing at you.
S-Sorry!
You haven't changed a bit, Chiba-kun...
Hey, haven't we seen that policewoman somewhere before?
Really?
But Yumi-san called her a 'rookie',
so wouldn't that make her a new policewoman?
Kamen Baiya...
Ba... Baiya?
Isn't that the title of the tokusatsu drama that Officer Chiba made back in primary school?
At the end of the video, right?
Thank you, Kamen Baiya!
Oh, right!
The girl with the two pigtails!
Isn't she Officer Chiba's first love?
But didn't Chiba say he got rejected by her?
Yeah...
I remember he said that she was 'finally together with her love'
and didn't even come to the class reunion.
Did she get married or something?
Nope, from seeing her here, what she meant by 'together'
was that she'd become a police officer under the same police district,
and she probably didn't come to the class reunion
because she thought Officer Chiba had forgotten about her.
Then, Officer Chiba just mistook it as a rejection?
Yeah.
And it seems he himself hasn't even realised that his first love,
Naeko Mi'ike-san is right in front of him.
Really... just like Officer Takagi and Inspector Shiratori...
How come all the officers we know
have to be such slow, annoying, blockheaded morons?
Well, I guess they have their hands so full with investigations that nothing else even enters their minds...
Really?
Don't ask me. How would I know?
Anyway, rather than us tactlessly meddling,
we better wait for her to reveal the truth,
or for Officer Chiba to remember.
Then, there really wasn't anything stolen?
Nothing we noticed...
Right?
Right.
Which means we can't ignore the possibility that they're targeting otaku cars.
Eh? All the victims were otaku?
Show them the photo of the first victim's car.
Right!
This is the car.
itasha
A painmobile, huh?
It's pretty well drawn.
Yeah! It's Emo-chan from Magic JK48!
Eh? What about this car is Italian?
It's a Japanese car, right?
Ah, well, not that itasha...
itai
itasha
It's a painmobile because it's a painful car.
Since it has a moe character printed on it,
itaitashiku
ordinary people would feel pity for the car, so it's called an itasha, right?
Yeah.
Were the other victims' cars painmobiles too?
It doesn't look like that's it.
Nothing happened to the car in the back of the photo...
And the 2nd and 3rd victims' cars were...
Ah, here!
the car of a salaryman returning from playing golf
and a flashily modified street racer's car.
Could it be a prankster doing it randomly for fun?
But for them to go so far as to write 'Die!' on ceilings,
there must be something in common between the victims...
These are photos of those three victims.
Have you seen them before?
Hmm...
In that case, why not have Officer Chiba go out with you to help investigate the car break-ins?
Me?
He might remember something important during the investigation.
We'll help out too!
That's right... Since it's your day off, you've got free time...
Well, I wouldn't say that...
Hey, did the other car break-ins happen around here too?
Yeah, they all happened at parking lots in Beika...
Well then, we'll go with Yumi-san and look around the parking lots on the west side of town,
and Officer Chiba can take care of the parking lots on the east side with that policewoman.
T-Take care of...
Well then, leave them to their work...
Over here!
Umm... what should I do?
Well, Officer Chiba's car will need to be checked by forensics, so it can't be used right now...
So walk back home without a fuss.
Right.
Hey, why're we following those two?
Weren't we supposed to look around the parking lots on the west side of Beika?
If you talk too loudly they'll notice us!
You're not being a very good policewoman, are you.
Now look...
They're going into a building!
It's a department store's underground parking lot...
What now? Do we follow them?
Don't be stupid. If we go through the same entrance,
we'll run into them and be done for.
Oh well, we'll have to go into the parking lot through the department store.
Doc, stay here and watch over the entrance.
Hey...
Hmph... you don't need me either then...
Hmmm... they're not here.
Maybe they already left?
No, the doctor hasn't contacted us yet,
so they should be somewhere in the parking lot...
Hey, what're you doing!?
This isn't a playground!
Tokuko Shigei (36)
Housewife
If you want to play hide-and-seek, go to a park!
Here you could be run over by cars pulling out!
Sorry...
What school do you go to?
What're your names!?
Ah, well...
Come on... something like hide-and-seek can't cause trouble.
Aketoshi Fukuchi (41)
Company Employee
I've got a daughter the same age too, it's just a playful phase.
It's parental attitudes like that that put kids in danger!
Hey!
What're you all doing around my car!?
Takerō Meiwa (22)
Part-Time Worker
Don't touch my car with your dirty hands, you brats! Beat it!
Ah, here it is. I've got your phone.
I'll bring it now.
That's some modified car...
Why don't we leave for now.
It'd be wiser to just wait for them to leave with the doctor.
Hmm... they're sure taking a long time.
It's already been 30 minutes since you came back...
Could this mean that Officer Chiba remembered that policewoman?
I see!
So talking about their love kept them busy?
Chiba blushing in surprise... I'd have liked to see that!
What was that sound?
It sounded like a collision...
Was it from the parking lot?
Smoke?
You all right?
Officer Chiba!
What happened?
Well...
We heard a loud sound and when we rushed here, this guy had collapsed.
It seems like he was rear-ended by the car behind him.
Is this a car break-in!?
Hey, Conan! What happened?
We don't know any details yet...
Huh?
This is the kind old man who stood up for us before, right?
It seems like he's regaining consciousness.
Are you all right?
Can you tell us what happened?
Ah, yes.
I wanted to buy my daughter a doll she wanted,
but when I got to this department store, it was sold out, so I figured I'd try a different shop.
Then just as I was about to leave the parking lot, my car got rear-ended, so I got out to complain,
but I got dizzy, and must've lost consciousness.
I probably hit my head against something when my car was rear-ended.
Hey! What's going on here?
My friend says that they're not letting him into the parking lot!
We sealed off the parking lot for the time being.
Eh!? Why would you do that?
Isn't this just an accident?
It's one of the two drivers' fault, right?
Except there was nobody in the driver's seat of the car that collided...
Hey, what's going on!?
I just came back for my purse. Why do I see smoke coming out of my car!?
Is that your car?
Yes! A brand new car just bought last year!
Who could've done this?
Ah, wait!
What? Even the airbag's deployed?!
Don't! You can't touch your car yet!
I see. So this is what happened?
Chiba-kun and the rookie were searching this parking lot to investigate those car break-ins and heard a loud crash.
When they ran over, Fukuchi-san had collapsed near that rear-ended car,
the other car was already empty,
and had the car break-in case's signature red 'Die!' spray-painted onto the windscreen, right?
But did someone really break into and drive this car?
There are picking marks on the keyhole, but...
The key's in the ignition.
That's probably the spare key, which we leave in the sun visor above the driver's seat.
Your fault for keeping it there.
That and the underside of the bumper are the first places car thieves check.
Oh?
You sound rather knowledgeable on that.
Oh, no...
I saw a scene like that in a movie.
And you didn't see the driver of the car that rear-ended you?
Well, I lost consciousness right after I got out of my car, so...
Hopefully they were recorded by the security cameras.
It seems that it happened while they were being inspected.
It's all right, though.
After rushing here, I asked this policewoman to not let anyone through the passageway
connecting the parking lot and department store.
I also asked the doc and Haibara to watch over the entrance and see if anyone left.
So the one responsible...
is probably still in this parking lot.
Right, Haibara?
Yes.
Nobody left the parking lot so far.
And of course, nobody entered either.
I see. So basically, if we, the police can't find anyone else in the parking lot,
then the vandal must be one of you three.
One of us three?
I'm the victim who got rear-ended by the vandal!
I'm a victim whose car was wrecked too!
And isn't it strange?
A car break-in is something you'd do stealthily without alerting anyone, right?
What would the vandal gain by doing something as conspicuous as hitting someone's car?
Who knows?
Maybe the vandal wanted to take the car given the key was inside it,
but panicked and hit Fukuchi-san's car, as he was trying to leave.
'Die!' was written on the windscreen though, so I don't think that's the case...
And if it was for money, the vandal would've taken the purse in the car.
Besides, I don't think the criminal could get out of here without a parking lot ticket.
How should I know?
That's the sort of thing you ask the criminal!
By the way, did you two see anyone suspicious?
Nope, nobody...
By the way, what were you doing here so long? You took over 30 minutes.
You two were all alone, right?
What did you talk about?
Talk?
I was just searching the parking lot with her, that's all!
She suggested checking all the cars to see if any of them'd been vandalised.
'Her, she', haven't you asked her name yet?
Good point.
I haven't yet.
R-Right!
M-My name's...
Hey!
Does the vandal always write 'Die!' in a different place?
Huh? Uh, no...
So far, it was always on the ceiling.
This is the first time it's written on the windscreen.
Then could someone have copied it?
No, it's not a copycat.
We found a spray can of the same brand as was used in the other cars,
and we still haven't announced that the vandal's been writing 'Die!' in the cars.
Hey, Conan-kun!
It was a great moment!
Why'd you have to ruin it!?
Read into the situation!
But why was Shigei-san's car targeted?
There's nothing otaku-like in the car.
Otaku?
I mean stuff like toys and dolls...
Why would I buy something like that!?
If you want dolls, there's tons in the car over there!
It's true!
It's full of stuffed toys!
But they're all scattered around.
That's because I got hit.
My daughter usually keeps them all neatly lined up so that they can be seen.
But I don't understand...
If the same person did this,
why target this car?
The vandal even changed the location of the spray message...
Moreover, the car was moved and rammed into another one,
so did the vandal have that deep a grudge against this car?
The sunburn marks on the back seat...
Are they why this car was targeted?
Well then, here are the results!
We throughly checked the parking lot,
and there's nobody else here other than you three.
This means one of you three did it.
No way...
I was rear-ended! Why am I in the suspect list too?!
Isn't it obvious?
You could've smashed into your car on purpose and pretended to lose consciousness just to get out of the suspect list.
Give me a break...
My wife and daughter are waiting for me at home.
I've got to get dinner ready for my husband, too!
If I don't get home soon, my parents are going to yell at me!
You actually care about your parents yelling at you?
Yeah... They're both school teachers.
Then, didn't they say anything about the flashy spoiler on your car?!
There's no way that'll pass a vehicle inspection!
No...
I kept it a secret from them.
Come to think of it, the third car that was vandalised had a spoiler too, right?
Yeah.
But his car wasn't vandalised, right?
Why was that?
How would I know?
If it's about the flashiness, your car's spoiler is flashier.
The wing's higher, too...
If we could've looked more closely at the other vandalised cars, maybe we could've figured out something.
Then would you like to see the photos taken from other angles?
I brought them with me in the mini patrol car parked outside.
Then I'll go get them.
Thanks.
Hey, shouldn't you go with her, Chiba?
Why?
If there's lots of photos it'll be hard to carry them all, right?
Helping ladies is a gentleman's duty!
Geez, you're so slow!
Hurry up!
Overwrite
Those two are each other's first love?!
Are... you serious?
Of course.
Don't you remember...?
Not something like that...
I guess you're right...
I'm sure of it. The vandal...
...is that person!
On the next Conan: 'Co-Investigating with a First Love (Part II)!'
Co-Investigating with a First Love
(Part II)
Next Conan's Hint: Rear-window!
Look forward to the next episode!
We'll get those two...
...together!
I think it's useless.