'The Red Oily Pssht Case.'
That's what Yumi-san from the Metropolitan Police's Traffic Dept. called a serial car break-in case.
After picking the lock and breaking into the cars,
this vandal spray-paints the word 'Die!' on the ceiling.
It was a vicious case.
Officer Chiba's car was also attacked.
So he called Yumi-san, who came by along with a rookie policewoman
who turned out to be Naeko Mi'ike-san, Officer Chiba's first love.
We had at one point searched with Officer Chiba for the video letter she left at Teitan Primary School.
Officer Chiba apparently didn't notice that the policewoman before him was his first love,
so we came up with a plan that involved pairing them together to investigate the break-ins.
We figured that if they worked together, he'd be sure to notice.
Meanwhile, in the underground parking lot they entered to investigate,
there was a rear-end collision.
Furthermore, the car that caused the collision had the word 'Die!' sprayed onto the windscreen from inside with red paint.
Was this caused by the same serial vandal?
There were three people in the parking lot during the accident:
The driver of the rear-ended car: a company employee, Aketoshi Fukuchi-san.
The owner of the car that caused the accident: the housewife, Tokuko Shigei-san.
And a man waiting for his friend to come: a part-time worker, Takerō Meiwa-san.
Is the serial vandal, as well as the culprit of this collision, among these three?
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
The true culprit and your first love;
perceive them both, Officer Chiba!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Co-Investigating with a First Love
(Part II)
Well then, here are the results!
We throughly checked the parking lot,
and there's nobody else here other than you three.
This means one of you three did it.
No way...
I was rear-ended! Why am I in the suspect list too?!
Isn't it obvious?
You could've smashed into your car on purpose and pretended to lose consciousness just to get out of the suspect list.
.
Aketoshi Fukuchi (41)
Company Employee
Give me a break...
My wife and daughter are waiting for me at home.
I've got to get dinner ready for my husband, too!
.
Tokuko Shigei (36)
Housewife
.
Takerō Meiwa (22)
Part-time Worker
If I don't get home soon, my parents are going to yell at me!
You actually care about your parents yelling at you?
Yeah... They're both school teachers.
Then, didn't they say anything about the flashy spoiler on your car?!
There's no way that'll pass a vehicle inspection!
No...
I kept it a secret from them.
Come to think of it, the third car that was vandalised had a spoiler too, right?
Yeah.
But his car wasn't vandalised, right?
Why was that?
How would I know?
If it's about the flashiness, your car's spoiler is flashier.
The wing's higher, too...
If we could've looked more closely at the other vandalised cars, maybe we could've figured out something.
Then would you like to see the photos taken from other angles?
I brought them with me in the mini patrol car parked outside.
Then I'll go get them.
Thanks.
Hey, shouldn't you go with her, Chiba?
Why?
If there's lots of photos it'll be hard to carry them all, right?
Helping ladies is a gentleman's duty!
Geez, you're so slow!
Hurry up!
What're you staring at each other like you're in some romantic comedy for?
Here. Hurry up and get those photos.
Right!
Geez...
Don't ogle the newbie.
'Ogle...?'
We should probably explain what's going on.
I suppose.
Honestly...
Huh? Those two are each other's first love,
and Chiba-kun hasn't realised it yet?!
S-Seriously?
Of course!
Hold on...
Miwako with Takagi-kun...
and Shiratori-kun with Miss Kobayashi...
and then...
if something happens and those two get together...
See ya, Yumi!
I must go.
I'm leaving now!
I have to stop this...
There certainly are photos from lots of different angles,
but adding in my car, I can't find any common link between the victims' cars...
Could it be something like the mileage gauge?
What was my car's reading...?
Um... Don't you remember...?
Not something like that...
I guess you're right...
Huh? Did I just say that about the mileage gauge out loud?
Jerk...
Come on, let's hurry up and show Conan-kun the photos!
That kid may notice something interesting again!
Yumi-san's openly interfering now...
It seems it had the opposite effect.
Indeed...
the wing's lower than the spoiler on Meiwa-san's car...
so why was it targeted?
This is the 2nd vandalised car, right?
Yes, the car of a company employee returning from playing golf.
How come there are so many golf bags?
Ah, it seems he was carrying his friends' bags too.
Hold on...
Could it be...
Hey, have there been any traffic accidents involving children around here recently?
There was one last month.
I heard that a high school teacher caused the accident,
but they admitted it was their fault, and settled out of court.
What sort of car was it?
An ordinary estate car.
Looks like they were on their way to an amusement park.
Since the car was packed full of rubber rings, beach balls,
inflatable boats and so on.
I'm sure of it.
The vandal who tried to pry open the drivers' closed eyes...
...is that person!
So, Conan-kun?
Have you figured anything out from those photos yet?
Huh? Figured out what?
Like I said, who's the serial car vandal who sprayed 'Die!' in red paint
on that car's windscreen, drove it to try and escape,
but ended up rear-ending the car in front,
therefore abandoning the car and escaping?
And since straight after the accident, the parking lot was sealed,
the only three people in the parking lot were
Fukuchi-san, who says he was driving the car that was rear-ended,
Shigei-san, who as well as having her car vandalised, also had it driven into Fukuchi-san's car,
and Meiwa-san, who claims to have been waiting for a friend.
Now, Conan-kun!
Which one of them is the car vandal?!
Even if you ask me, I don't know!
I'm just a kid.
You're not just hiding it from me, are you?
Hey, Yumi-san...
Um... the department store
are asking whether they can let customers into the parking lot yet.
It can't be helped. Let them in.
Then can we go too?
No way! The vandal is one of you three!
Then how about this?
Have those three go to the police station, and have Yumi-san ask them for their names, addresses, and the reasons they came here;
and have that policewoman deal with Officer Chiba, who had his car broken into before this happened.
That's right.
Young ones should stay with their own.
That's a good idea!
Agreed!
Yup, yup!
W-Well...
I'm off-duty today so I don't mind...
I don't mind either...
NO!
You're in the Second Violent Crimes Investigation Division's Section 3, right?
Go off and chase some killer!
But you told me to help out earlier...
That was then, this is now!
She's interfering again.
Yeah...
Go tell the department store they can unseal the parking lot!
Right!
And you're in the way, so hurry up and go home!
In the way...?
Hey! Do you know anyone who prints painmobiles, Officer Chiba?
Yeah, I do.
How long would it take to print one?
Well, since it's somewhat like a sticker, if it's just one character in one window, I guess about 2 to 3 hours.
In that case...
What is it?
Let me hear too!
Me too!
And me too!
Yes, let them in.
But please inform your customers that they can't pass through the site of the incident, so they have to detour around it.
Umm, I passed along the message to the department store.
Then let's have those three come with me to the police station,
and start taking their statements one by one.
In 2 to 3 hours...
...it'll probably be over.
Hey, Takagi-kun.
Do you know where my car keys are?
Ah, that.
Yumi-san took them a while back.
Yumi did?!
'Thanks, I'm off to do some decorating,' she said.
Decorating?!
Don't tell me she's going to prank it by putting a weird sticker on it again!
Sticker?
Like those rookie drivers' stickers...
...saying stuff like 'a rookie at love is driving'...
The other day, I drove to a murder scene without realising that sticker was on there...
It was embarrassing!
Well, if it's something like a 'rookie driver' magnet or sticker, you can easily take it off...
Hey! That's far enough!
Miwako'll get angry at me if you mess it up.
We finally know...
...what all the targeted cars have in common.
The painmobile drawing in the first car...
The golf bags in the second car...
The spoiler in the third car...
The toy boxes in the fourth car...
And that FD, decorated like a painmobile.
Right. Every targeted car had its rear-window obstructed!
And that's why Meiwa-san's car wasn't targeted, isn't it?
It had a flashy spoiler, but it was so high that the rear-window wasn't blocked.
And when you saw Fukuchi-san start up his car, with a ton of stuffed animals lined up in the rear-window, right in front of you...
You rammed into his car with your own without even thinking about it.
Isn't that right, Tokuko Shigei-san?
After you rear-ended him, you came to your senses...
...and to try to absolve yourself, you sprayed 'Die!' on your own car to make it look like you were vandalised.
You figured we'd think the vandal wouldn't vandalise their own car!
Did I get anything wrong?
There's no point in running!
While you were being questioned by the police, we surrounded the entire area!
Right. This street goes from the train station to your house.
In other words, we knew that after seeing this painmobile,
you'd go and get the spray paint and lockpicks from your house and bring them here.
Well, since this FD was a trap we set for you, we can overlook it...
You're going to confess to the other ones, right?
That you kept doing this for your son's sake, who died in a car accident last month...
An accident caused by lack of caution...
The field of vision for the rear-view mirror was obstructed by rubber rings and inflatable boats...
...so unluckily, the driver didn't see you pushing your stroller behind their car.
That's why you targeted every car that had its rear-window obstructed...
...and wrote the word 'Die!' as punishment.
What an unbearable case this turned out to be...
To think that a victim of such an unfortunate accident would end up committing crimes...
Yeah...
The regulations for rear-windows are pretty vague.
There's no set legal limit...
But Conan-kun, how'd you figure it out?
That Shigei-san had a son who'd died?
Because of the sunburn marks in the back seat of her car.
I figured it out when I saw it in the parking lot.
It's the mark for a child seat, right?
If there's a mark like that in a car bought last year, then she must've had a child until last year.
But she could've removed the seat because her child outgrew it...
If the child had recently needed a child seat, then that child would have to be younger than us.
And after being stuck in this long an investigation, wouldn't she be worried about that child?
Now that I think about it, she said...
I've got to get dinner ready for my husband, too!
She was only worried about making dinner for her husband...
That's right! Even though the man said his daughter was waiting for him...
I see!
That's why she got so upset when I asked her if she had toys or anything like that in her car...
Right. Since she didn't need to buy that kind of stuff...
But how did you know the old man had dolls lined up in his car?
Yeah. We saw he had lots of them scattered around on the back seat, but...
Because he said as much.
'My daughter usually keeps them all neatly lined up so that they can be seen.'
The only way to do that was to put them behind the back seat, lined up against the rear-window.
I see.
That's why she got so angry that she rammed into his car.
There's no way she could've gone into a car to write 'Die!' in it if there was somebody inside...
Right.
Even if she couldn't write it, she at least wanted to open up the driver's field of vision,
since the stuffed animals would fall out from the crash.
But why was that car the only one with it written on the windscreen?
Up 'til now, all of the words were sprayed on the car ceilings, right?
Because of her lipstick.
Due to the shock, her face fell onto the airbag, and her lipstick got on it,
so she tried to hide the lipstick mark with the same-colour spray paint.
She wanted to make it look like it was an extension of the message.
Though, if her lipstick was on the airbag, then so was her saliva,
so the vandal's identity could be uncovered with DNA analysis.
Then even without this trap...
No. This was the right thing to do.
Because we don't want her to commit more of these sad crimes...
Hey, Yumi-san.
I'm going home now.
Okay!
We'll probably have to do questioning after this, so bye!
Well, I guess I should tell Miwako I borrowed her car...
See you later, Officer Chiba.
Yeah.
Oh, right. I have to take Miwako's FD back to the Police HQ, so...
Take the mini patrol car back, okay?
Okay.
Since it's on the way, how about you give Chiba-kun a ride home?
Yes!
Somehow, I feel like I'm being arrested. Makes me kind of nervous.
It's the first time I've been in a mini patrol car, after all.
Really?
Though...
Though it doesn't feel like it's the first time...
...that I met you.
Sorry if I'm wrong, but...
Would you happen to be...
Yes?
Overwrite
Would you happen to be...
Yes?
The one who gave me a parking ticket in Haido City a while back?
Y-Yes.
I transferred to HQ last month.
I knew I'd recognised you from somewhere!
So that's where it was...
Officer Chiba's still totally clueless.
Seriously?
Even after Yumi-san gave them a break...
Geez...
Should've known. 'Pearls before swine' and all.
Hey, hey...
More like 'coins before cats.'
Nah... couldn't be.
Hey!!!
What's with this?!
Please don't get angry...
Kogorō Mouri-san a very nice young man!
Coming!
Who are you?
Don't worry.
Because the great detective Kogorō Mouri-san is right here!
Hey, hey...
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
On the next Conan: 'Kogorō-san is a Nice Guy (Part I)'
(Part I)
Next Conan's Hint: Key!
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, the old man becomes a nice guy!
That's impossible.
Indeed.
Guess so.