You're going to be late tonight, so I shouldn't make dinner?
But Dad, didn't you say the same thing the day before yesterday?
Sorry, but some urgent business came up so I gotta take care of it.
Then what about the client who asked you to find his first love?
Weren't you supposed to give him an update tonight?
You moron!
Do you really think the Great Detective Kogorō Mouri would bother with such a trivial case?
Just call him and tell him I couldn't find her yet!
And don't forget to leave the chain lock off the door.
Wait, Dad!
Geez.
What's gotten into him lately?
He only ever comes home in the middle of the night!
Maybe he found himself a lover?
Well, isn't it normal to come home late while investigating affairs and stuff?
He's probably been going to the beer garden in Beika Department Store which opened last week.
Because in the mornings after he comes home late, his toothbrush has green laver pieces from that shop's famous yakisoba.
Since you'd yell at him if he came home drunk, he sneaks in during the night so you won't see him.
You mean he's skipping work and neglecting his family just to drink beer and enjoy himself?!
W-Well, I'm sure Uncle has some friends to hang out with, too...
Some "Great Detective."
Some "Sleeping Kogorō."
He's just a lousy old man!
No.
Kogorō Mouri-san is a very nice young man!
A random schoolgirl shouldn't be speaking ill of him.
Takae Kiritani (70)
Apartment Landlady
Random schoolgirl?
I'm Kogorō Mouri's daughter.
Daughter?
Are you really Kogorō-san's daughter?
Yes, my name's Ran.
Then he must be hiding it from you.
Every week, he comes to visit this old woman and solves cases for me for free.
My father's working for free?
No way...
Guess that moustached old man isn't so bad after all.
But what kind of cases does he solve for you?
Some trivial cases like finding lost things.
Then how about you come to my home and see for yourself?
Since Kogorō-san's visiting me today, too.
Okay...
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
A fake Kogorō appears?
A big case involving a grim reaper!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
(Part I)
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
(Part I)
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
(Part I)
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
(Part I)
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
(Part I)
-
So you're an apartment building's landlady?
Yes, of the apartment next door.
But my husband, my son and his wife all died before me,
and my remaining granddaughter doesn't seem interested in taking it over,
so I'll probably be selling it soon.
I see.
Kogorō-san loves my okonomiyaki.
He always eats at least two of them.
Sorry for having you make our portions as well.
So those green laver pieces are from this old woman?
But I'm surprised that Dad's been secretly helping out old people like her.
No, there's got to be some ulterior motive...
Looks like he's here.
Then I'll get the door and surprise him.
Coming!
Who are you?
Same here.
Welcome, Kogorō-san.
I happened to run into your daughter on the street and invited her here.
'Kogorō-san?'
D-Daughter?
No, miss. This man's not...
The old lady's granddaughter asked you to do this?
What are you to her granddaughter?
I'm her boyfriend.
We're in the same class at the university.
I started doing this three months ago when I heard the grandmother couldn't sleep due to some burglaries around the neighbourhood.
Ryōhei Onda (21)
University Student
I suggested installing two locks and gave her some information on crime prevention.
But you didn't have to pretend to be my father to do that, did you?
She said I'd be more convincing that way, so...
Plus, it seems grandmother'd been sending letters to Detective Mouri, so...
But that burglar was caught last month, so you don't need to come here anymore.
That's true, but...
After that, she started asking me for stuff like turning down odd solicitation calls
and finding her neighbours' lost cats.
You wouldn't happen to be trying to swindle her by pretending to be Kogorō Mouri, would you?
No way...
I don't think so.
If it were so, he'd have run away when he met you, his supposed daughter.
Uncle Kogorō has lots of friends in the police force, after all.
S-So please cover for me just this once.
If she learned I'm an impostor, grandmother would be shocked.
This is the last time I'll come here.
Oh geez...
Have you finished your father-daughter conversation?
Yes, my daughter's surprise caught me off-guard.
Then please solve this case too, as usual.
Sure!
My daughter, pay attention to how your dad works.
I'm so sorry...
So that means the real old man's there after all...
Draft beer is awesome!
Zapping?
You mean flipping quickly through TV channels to choose a programme to watch?
Yes. Last night while I was watching TV, it suddenly started doing that even though I wasn't touching the remote...
Well, what was it called?
Something like poster east...
Poster east?
You mean a poltergeist?
Yes, yes!
I thought a ghost could've appeared so I got scared.
And then I called Kogorō-san without thinking.
Did you figure out why it happened?
It must've been done by your husband who died last year...
There is no such thing as a ghost.
Ghosts only exist in manga, drama or novels.
Right, Uncle?
Of course!
So this couldn't have been a ghost...
So basically...
Hey, Conan-kun, give him a hand.
You've figured it out, right?
Yes, but should I really tell him?
He doesn't look like a bad guy.
I feel bad for him.
Geez, I guess I'll have to.
Say, granny.
You were watching TV in this room, right?
Y-Yeah...
Is that desk always piled with books like that?
Yes, when I get curious about something, I like learning about it right away.
Then your TV remote's probably buried under them, right?
Yes, it was quite hard to dig it out, so...
Higo scores a goal!
Big Ōsaka's star player!
No way... it came on!
The channel button on the TV remote under the books
was probably occasionally held down,
making it look like it's zapping on its own.
Right, Uncle Kogorō?
A-Ah yes, that's right.
Thank you, Kogorō-san.
Thanks to you, the mystery has been solved.
W-Well...
This means you should keep your desk tidy.
If it makes her so happy, we might as well play along with him, huh?
Right.
Well...
It's not like this is an important case.
Hey, isn't he dead?
N-No way... Why?!
Call an ambulance!
No, call the police!
I-It looks like something happened next door...
Next door? That's my apartment building!
Conan-kun!
The door's busted!
This is...
Is that the room key?
Hey...
Why's the door busted?
Who are you, kid?
Just answer.
The bell on Denkawa-san's alarm clock wouldn't stop ringing...
Kumi Ban'nai (22)
Apartment Resident
so we came up to his door and asked him to shut it down.
Ken Ishigame (64)
Apartment Resident
But he didn't answer, so we had no choice but to bust through the door and go inside.
Junji Hyōdō (28)
Apartment Resident
Something like this happened last night too, didn't it?
Something like this?
All of a sudden, he started watching TV really loud!
What's more, he was just zapping through the channels the whole time!
It was very annoying.
Z-Zapping?
But when the three of us came to his door to complain about it last night, it stopped.
But the room key's next to the corpse.
And he is holding a kitchen knife.
Did he slit his throat and kill himself?
No, it's a murder.
And the killer...
...is one of these three.
Well, we better leave the rest to the police.
Don't worry.
This case will be solved in no time!
T-The landlady!
Because the great detective Kogorō Mouri-san is right here!
Hey, hey, hey!
The deceased is 44-year old Gensuke Denkawa-san.
Gensuke Denkawa (44)
Apartment Resident
He's been living at the apartment for over ten years.
He was a construction worker.
Is this correct?
Yes.
If you could've asked my husband, he'd tell you more.
I started helping my husband take care of this apartment building 10 years ago.
And I officially took over as landlady after my husband died last year.
By the way, is it true?
That the alarm clock in Denkawa-san's room kept ringing nonstop
so his neighbours Ban'nai-san, Ishigame-san and Hyōdō-san broke into the room?
Yeah, we kept knocking on the door and told him to stop it but...
Since he didn't answer, we didn't have a choice...
When we came into the room, he was already...
And then that kid came into the room.
I was at the landlady's house and saw those people causing a commotion through the window, so I came here.
Through the window?
Yeah, the landlady's house is right next to this room.
But what were you doing at the landlady's house, Conan-kun?
I'm an acquaintance of her, so he came with me.
Anyway, Ran-chan and Conan-kun aside...
Who are you?
No... I-I...
Hey! How can a police officer not know the Great Detective Mouri?
I know him.
You're his daughter, tell her something!
Umm, well...
Thanks for always taking care of my father!
Huh?
What's going on?
I see.
Her granddaughter asked him to cheer up the lonely landlady,
so the guy with the fake moustache, her boyfriend, is pretending to be Mouri-san.
Please!
The landlady really bought it.
If she finds out he's a fake, she's going to be so sad...
Well, as long as he doesn't interfere with the investigation, I guess I can go along with it.
Thank you.
If Inspector Megure finds out about this, he's gonna yell at us...
Now back to our topic...
Busting through the door just because the alarm clock wouldn't stop is a little too much.
Isn't that right, Detective Mouri?
Umm, well... yeah.
Same goes for me!
Denkawa busted through my door too.
He left a note saying 'Because your phone wouldn't stop ringing,
I unplugged the cord.'
And he once sealed my door with duct tape from the outside,
so I couldn't get out of my room.
I later learned that he'd done it, and when I asked why,
he said 'I sealed it because it stinks!'
'Stinks?'
I was cooking kusaya!
So I guess it could stink a little.
He also broke my window.
It seems that Denkawa-san had a grudge because my grandson
broke his window with a baseball on an earlier visit.
Did you inform the landlady about this?
Yeah, we informed the former landlord.
He told us to negotiate it out since we were somewhat to blame too.
And after that, he started living peacefully without causing us any more problems.
By the way, the TV volume was really loud last night.
Out of the blue, he started watching TV really loud.
On top of that, he was zapping the whole time, too.
We did knock on his door just like today,
and asked him to turn down the volume since it was bothering us.
And then? Did he do it?
Yeah.
He turned off the TV...
...without saying anything.
But why did Denkawa-san do something like that so suddenly?
Who knows? Maybe he thought that we were out already.
The three of us were about to go out.
All three of you?
Y-Yeah.
Our friend's parents run a hot spring inn in Izu,
and they said they'd let us stay for cheap, so...
You three seem to get along well.
Well, we always complain about Denkawa to each other.
We were trying to find a way to get him out of this building.
We were discussing it at the inn.
Then when we came back a while ago,
the alarm clock was ringing.
We put our luggages in our rooms
and waited for a while but it didn't stop ringing.
So we came to complain again!
Then you broke through the door and found the body?
What time was it when you set off for the hot spring?
About 6 o'clock, I think.
By the way, where are the other residents of this apartment buliding?
It's just us.
Everybody else moved out because they got fed up with Denkawa-san.
So after you three left,
there was nobody in the building other than Denkawa-san.
If I recall correctly, forensics put the estimated time of death between 5 to 7 PM last night.
Right.
And according to these three's testimonies,
Denkawa-san was alive around 6 PM,
the room key was near the body,
and he was holding a bloodstained kitchen knife.
Judging from the situation,
it seems that he slit his own throat
after those three went out between 6 and 7 PM.
Yeah. Even though we couldn't find a suicide note, we can't really consider this anything other than a suicide...
I don't think it was suicide.
I wonder if a grim reaper did this?
Look, the key's on the blood,
but there's no blood on it, right?
True, but when they broke into the room,
someone could've kicked the key accidentally.
So it ended up there.
But, when I came into the room,
I touched the key a little.
It was slightly warm!
What?
I'm sure the grim reaper took his life,
and wanted to take away his body.
But those three broke the door so loudly, that when they came in,
the grim reaper was surprised and dropped the key onto the dry blood.
Oh, but that's weird.
A grim reaper's hands should be cold.
So why was it warm?
That's probably because someone hid the key in their palms,
and threw it near the body when they entered the room,
to make it look like the room was sealed.
One of you three who broke the door and entered this room did this.
What?!
One of you must've thought that after murdering Denkawa-san,
by making it look like a sealed room and going off somewhere,
you'd make a perfect alibi, right?
Wait a minute!
Then what was the loud TV sound the three of us heard before setting off?!
I'm certain it was coming from this room!
Someone probably recorded the TV sound ahead of time
and used a timer to play it.
But the first thing we heard were the 6 PM news,
and the date, the weekday and the contents were all from yesterday.
He started zapping two or three minutes later though.
Maybe he used a DVD or TV recorder.
Nowadays, TVs can turn on automatically if you schedule a time for a programme you want to watch.
And using several extra devices you can make it look like it's zapping through channels.
I don't think that's possible.
Huh?
There's only one TV in this room.
Doesn't look like there's a timer, either.
All we have is an alarm clock near his bed
and two electric fans, huh?
One of the fans fell over.
I tripped on it and knocked it over.
I wanted to stop the alarm as soon as possible.
The room was kind of dark when we came in.
And I tripped on the legs of the body and skinned my elbow!
When I pulled on the cord to turn on the light, the room was like that.
But why are there two electric fans in one room?
Some people do that.
One for cooling themselves down, and one for keeping the air circulating in the room.
Kamen Yaiba!
It's so loud!
You can record a programme with this TV, but it doesn't seem like you can set up zapping through channels.
This is weird.
Though the room's quite tidy,
the laundry was left undried,
and there are clothespins scattered all over the place.
The newspaper leaflets on the futon also look off.
What's more, there is only one TV,
so why are there two TV remotes?
This one's universal.
So did he lose the original remote, buy this one, then later find the original one?
There's a bloodstain on this side of the remote.
It's spread a bit, too...
Don't tell me this is...!
The killer really is one of the three who found the body.
He tried to commit a perfect crime by making it look like Denkawa-san commited suicide, but he can't fool me.
Whoever it was, I will find the killer!
Overwrite
.
It's been a while, grandma!
It's been 3 months since we last met
when I went to Tōkyō for
my high school reunion. But thanks
to my husband's schedule,
we'll be back in Tōkyō next month.
We'll bring our son
and look forward to seeing you ♥
Your granddaughter in Kyūshū (^^)/
No way...
Her granddaughter's married!
Then who is this guy?
We should leave this case to Detective Mouri, the crime-solving pro!
It's all right.
Because the real Sleeping Kogorō is right here!
-
Kogoro-san is a Nice Guy
On the next Conan: 'Kogorō-san is a Nice Guy (Part II)'
(Part II)
Next Conan's Hint: Clothespin!
Look forward to the next episode!
Even Mouri-san's imposter can solve a case, huh?
Indeed...
Wait, you mean me?