Old man Kogorō is helping an old woman for free?
From what Takae Kiritani-san, an apartment landlady, says,
the old man visits her every week
to help solve problems and neighbourhood troubles for her.
Ran and I couldn't believe it,
so we decided to wait for him in Kiritani-san's house.
But the guy who appeared was someone named Ryōhei Onda,
Ryōhei Onda (21)
University Student
who doesn't bear the slightest resemblance to the old man.
He explained that he was the boyfriend of Kiritani-san's granddaughter,
and he was pretending to be the old man to go and check on her,
as her granddaughter was worried about her.
So the case of the fake old man was quickly solved,
but it was then that the real case began.
We heard sudden screams from the neighbouring apartment.
I ran over, and the apartment's resident,
Gensuke Denkawa-san had bled to death,
and the screams were from the other residents who found the corpse.
The time of death was last night.
From the situation it was thought to be suicide, but no...
This was a murder!
And the killer is one of
the three residents who discovered the corpse.
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Even a fake Kogorō can have great deductions...
The truth behind the grim reaper case is revealed!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Junji Hyōdō (28)
Apartment Resident
Hey, officers! Can we go yet?
Kumi Ban'nai (22)
Apartment Resident
You know that Denkawa-san had to be alive to change the channel!
Ken Ishigame (64)
Apartment Resident
Let us go back to our rooms already.
Ah, but there's still the matter of the key...
Who cares?
We just got back from the hot spring, so we're tired!
So please...
That's enough, you lot!
If you interrupt someone when they're talking,
you're just trying to start a fight!
Takae Kiritani (70)
Apartment Landlady
If there's something you want to say,
wait for them to finish talking first!
Hey! Clear a path.
And what sort of police officers are you?
There's a great detective right here,
so why don't you ask his opinion!?
Ah, well...
You won't solve anything with such a conceited attitude!
Ah, no, wait, mum...
Mum...?
Ah... I meant granny.
I still haven't put together my deduction...
The landlady speaks loudly, doesn't she.
Yeah, a lot of old people do that.
But isn't that because age makes them hard-of-hearing?
It seemed like she could hear us fine in our normal voices.
Right...
Well, some old people raise their voices to show they're still young and healthy.
You see?
Ah, it sounds like your phone's ringing.
Hello? Hello...?
That's odd, nobody's there...
Maybe it's an e-mail? Let me see.
Here.
My, aren't you skilled, little boy.
I had my granddaughter teach me how to use it once
but can't remember which button does what.
If you were younger,
you could've learnt to use it like you did a piano keyboard.
I guess...
Piano?
An e-mail from her granddaughter, huh?
No way!
'Thanks to my husband's schedule...'
Doesn't that mean her granddaughter's married?!
She even has a kid, and it doesn't look like she's a university student...
which means that when this guy said she was his girlfriend...
it was an outright lie! So then, who is he?
It was an e-mail from your granddaughter.
Ah, from her...
G-Granddaughter...
But never mind that, about the zapping last night,
do you remember around when it happened?
I'm not sure... sometime around twilight, I think.
And when it happened, the channel changed several times quickly, stopped for a while, then started changing again?
Yes, it was like that.
That's why I was sure it was some malicious presence from outside.
Since it stopped when I shut the curtains.
So it's just as I thought... I've solved the trick.
And the one who did it was likely that person.
But there's no proof.
If my theory's right, the killer should still have the evidence...
Hey, it doesn't look like they're gonna solve it anytime soon,
so why not...
have the crimesolving pro, Detective Mouri, solve it for us?
That's a good idea.
I agree.
Yes, let's leave it all to Detective Mouri.
Ah, no... no, no no...
So how about it,
Sleeping Kogorō-san?
If this was a murder, isn't it odd to claim that the killer is one of us?
Yes!
How do you explain the loud noise we heard coming from the TV in this room just before we left for the hot spring?
It wasn't just noise either, the channel changed too,
and he turned off the TV when we told him to.
Isn't that proof that Denkawa was still alive then?
Denkawa-san's time of death was last night, right?
Then there's no way the killer can be one of us,
since we just got back from the hot spring!
If you want to keep us here any longer,
then you have to solve those mysteries for us!
Do your 'prideful deduction'!
I still haven't yet...
Hold on!
Even if Detective Mouri can't solve this case yet,
we've got no intention of letting you three go since you're suspects.
When you three broke down the door, one of you threw the key next to the corpse
to make it seem like it was a locked room.
None of you are cleared of that suspicion yet.
Isn't that odd too?
How come the police, who are always following Kogorō Mouri's instructions,
are ignoring him this time round?
Don't tell me you brought out a fake Kogorō Mouri,
in order to put mental pressure on us so that the police can solve this case quickly?
What are you saying?!
This man is the real Detective Mouri!
Should we tell them that he's a fake?
But we promised Ran-san...
Don't worry about the promise!
This guy saying that he's pretending to be my dad for the landlady's granddaughter was a blatant lie!
I don't know what he could be plotting!
Ah, no...
Then, as you wish, the great Kogorō Mouri shall reveal the truth behind this case!
Hmm? How interesting.
Ah, no... that wasn't me...
Hey, don't get carried away just because you're pretending to be him.
Then I'll help you with various things, Uncle Kogorō!
Don't worry.
I just called the real Uncle Kogorō
and heard the truth behind the case from him.
Just go along with what I say, okay?
Conan-kun!
Okay, I got it!
I'll tell the officers to do what you asked!
I'll leave it to you.
No, Conan-kun, this guy isn't...
Ran-neechan, you help out too!
There's lots of things he wants us to borrow and bring here!
C-Conan-kun?
It's all right.
Because the real Sleeping Kogorō is right here!
Hey, how long are you going to keep us waiting?
It looks like you brought a lot of stuff into the room...
If you use tools that were never in the room to begin with, you're not proving anything!
Everything brought into the room was already there.
We were just told not to use the actual objects for the trick experiment.
It's what the forensics officer who took the body told us, so...
Trick, you say?
You're still going on about that nonsense?!
What's your deal?
Ah, no, that's...
Don't worry.
Just tell them what I said and you'll be okay.
Make it look impressive!
Act as if you were Sherlock Holmes!
What is the meaning of this?!
Good evening.
This is the 9 o'clock evening news for Monday, July 2nd!
Who turned on the TV?
I don't know.
But it certainly wasn't one of us, right?
There is still someone in the next room, right?
No, there isn't.
Well, you can turn on the TV if the timer's set...
What are you even saying?!
And now, the third question!
Hit! It's high! He's going for a home run!
It's zapping!
W-What is going on?!
There has to be somebody in that room!
Ah, hold on!
It's like a dream world...
Not even miracles are mysteries today.
...and until the onions turn brown...
Higo scored right after the game started...
This is a homicide.
There's a TV remote on top of the electric fan?
I see!
The channel button was pressed down by a clothes peg,
and the TV remote was fixed on top of an electric fan facing downward!
And as the fan moved and pointed to the TV,
it caused the channels to change, making people think it's zapping!
I see.
The TV was turned on by its programme timer.
If it was set to the news, it'd be easy to tell it's a live programme.
If after two or three minutes of that,
the timer on the fan had been set to make it move,
it'd sound as if he started zapping, right?
Then how did the TV turn off?
We certainly heard the TV turn off.
Couldn't it it have been done with the TV's sleep timer?
Nonsense.
For the programme timer to turn the TV on,
the TV must've been turned off.
And if the TV was off, the sleep timer wouldn't work!
And how do you explain that?
Uh, well...
It's alright.
How was that done, Mouri-san?
Well, as you can see,
another fan was used alongside the rotating one.
At the base of that fan,
a TV remote with its power button held down with a clothes peg was placed facing towards the TV,
and a newspaper flyer was placed in front of it.
And if this fan's timer was set to start a few minutes after the rotating one,
the flyer blows away due to wind from the fan,
and since the obstacle blocking the infrared signals of the TV remote disappeared, the TV turns off.
This is how this was set up, making it look like someone had been zapping,
and turned off the TV due to the complaints.
That's how the flyer got on the bed!
By the way, the first fan kept moving even after the TV was turned off,
and the TV remote happened to be of the same brand as the landlady's TV,
so when the fan turned to the landlady's house,
it caused the TV in her living room to start zapping too.
Then it wasn't the books on the table after all?
Right.
It was just the side effect of the killer's trick.
But who set up this trick?
When we came into the room, there wasn't any setup like that...
Can't you see it?
The TV remote has been stuck to the fan with plasters.
If I recall correctly, earlier you said you tripped and fell over the leg of the body, didn't you?
What of it?!
Don't tell me you pulled the plaster off the electric fan, and stuck it on yourself...?
I put on this plaster because a mosquito bit me at the hot spring!
Didn't I show you on the train ride home?
But it doesn't mean this is the same plaster...
You stuck it on with a plaster because you thought that's what was used in the crime, right?
No.
The time between you breaking down the door, and turning the light on and finding Denkawa-san's body, was probably around 10 seconds.
Let's find out whether it's possible
for someone to restick plasters onto their body without being suspicious
in such a small amount of time...
Well then, Officer Takagi, I'll turn around for ten seconds,
so would you try doing that?
Right.
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0!
Hold on!
Well, did you do it?
Not really... They're stuck on, but they're all wrinkled as I was rushing.
Maybe there was more time than that...
Ishigame-san took his time turning on the lights.
Even if there was more time, it'd still turn out the same.
It would've been dark before the lights came on.
And from seeing her use her cell phone,
Ban'nai-san's likely right-handed.
It would've been hard for her to use her left hand
to neatly stick plasters on her right elbow and finger.
Ishigame-san's compress is also firmly attached to his right shoulder.
Although a compress and plasters could be used the same way,
it'd be impossible for someone to remove them
and re-stick them onto their body so quickly.
Of course, it'd be perfectly possible for the killer
to just crumple up and hide the item on themselves, but...
It's unlikely that someone would do that
knowing they might have to go through a police body search.
Which leaves us with something that's not suspicious even when on a person's body,
and it's easy to retrieve.
Hyōdō-san, the rubber band you used to tie your hair!
With that, you could do it like this...
Seems to be holding it up well.
And to make it hard to investigate later, you tied your hair back straight away.
T-that is...
He's totally into it...
He's a pretty good impostor...
No. Since he's not sleeping, he seems even more like a detective.
And to complete the trick...
When you entered the room, you had to remove all traces of the trick as fast as you could,
and retrieve the items you used.
Therefore, since you were the one who came into the room first
to turn off the alarm...
You used the impact from 'tripping' over the fan
to knock the remote away from it.
Finally, if you squatted down to stop the alarm clock,
you could've taken the clothes pegs off the remotes without looking suspicious,
as well as grabbing the rubber band you used to tie your hair.
B-but...
Did you actually see that?
Do you have any proof that I used my hair tie to set up the trick?
Proof?
Oh yeah, I didn't tell him that yet.
Hey, there was blood on one of the remotes, right?
Yeah, as well as some traces of it having spread around a bit.
In other words, if the blood mark
is from when the remote was attached to the fan,
the blood spatter from slicing Denkawa-san's neck
should be on your hair tie, right?
Hearing that, as if the channel had suddenly been changed,
Hyōdō-san confessed to the crime, heartbroken.
It started when Denkawa-san, fed up with Hyōdō-san's phone constantly ringing,
broke down his door and went into his room.
That's when Denkawa-san found that Hyōdō-san had a case full of drugs in his room.
It seems that Hyōdō-san was a courier for a drug smuggling syndicate,
and Denkawa-san threatened him to hand over half of what he earned
in exchange for not going to the police.
Hyōdō-san decided to kill Denkawa-san, so an hour before the three left for the spring,
he got Denkawa-san drunk and killed him by slicing his neck with a kitchen knife.
He then set up the trick, left the room, and locked the door.
After making it look like Denkawa-san was still alive, thanks to the sound of the TV, he left to go to the spring.
Finally, to stop the alarm clock he set up to go off right as they got back from the spring,
he broke down the door, threw the key next to the body, and disposed of the evidence.
Exactly as I thought.
And thankfully for the landlady,
she didn't find out this guy's a fake Kogorō Mouri.
Oh, wait. There's still one person who's not quite happy with this...
Hey, you!
What are you trying to do by pretending to be my dad?
I told you already!
My girlfriend, the landlady's granddaughter, asked me...
That's bull! Her granddaughter's married!
It may look like you solved the case pretty nicely thanks to Conan-kun,
but you can't trick me!
Well, that's...
She was your teacher, right?
That landlady was your primary schoolteacher.
How did you know that?
Despite being such a kind person,
the landlady didn't help her husband with the apartment
until ten years ago,
so she must've had some other job before, right?
And when I heard her scolding everyone,
speaking louder than normal, I thought it might've been a habit that carried over from when she was a teacher!
Of course... A teacher would have to raise her voice...
And if she was a primary schoolteacher, she'd have to have known how to play the piano...
If you were younger, you could've remembered it like a piano keyboard.
I guess...
...which she apparently does.
And what finally convinced me
was when he called her 'mum'!
Ah, no, wait, mum...
For primary school students, their teacher's almost like a parent,
and some students actually do call them 'mum.'
I'm sure that sensation must've come back,
causing you to blurt that out.
Conan-kun, how do you know all of that?
Shin'ichi-niichan told me in an email!
You asked Shin'ichi about this?
'He was probably one of her granddaughter's high school classmates.
After hearing about the landlady's problems
at their high school reunion three months ago,
he decided to pretend to be Kogorō...'
Yeah. I couldn't just leave my teacher like that.
In that case, shouldn't you just be honest
and tell her the truth?
She yelled at me a lot to not lie,
so telling her the truth after all this time would be complicated.
Well, true, you shouldn't lie, but...
If you're lying for her sake,
I'm sure she'll forgive you.
A few days letter, we got a 'thank-you' letter from the landlady with a photo.
The letter said:
'Mouri-san, the apprentice you introduced me to
is a very nice young man, and helped me a lot...'
But I don't have any apprentice...
He's still lying...
Looks like there's a lot of beetles and stag beetles collected here.
There you are, kids.
Hey!
That's not a toy, don't touch it!
Hang in there, mister!
Miyama... Stag Beetle...
On the next Conan: 'Chase the Miyama Stag Beetle'
Conan
Edogawa
Next Conan's Hint, Oh Yeah: Name!
Alright, I'm catching beetles!
Good luck!
Then am I the culprit?
Good luck.