[SIGN: Tsuchi'inishieka Station]
[SIGN: Namatame Ryūtarō (52)]
[SIGN: Roadside Station]
[SIGN: Yabe Kei (27)]
[SIGN: Ikeda Shūhei (50)]
[SIGN: Detective Motohashi (45)]
[SIGN: Officer Iwanaga (55)]
Yeah, yeah.
[SIGN: Miyama Stag Beetle]
Cool!
Come on, let me touch it too.
It's all prickly. It looks painful.
My dad bought it for me at the department store.
I've got a stag beetle at my house too!
There's no point in having it unless you catch it yourself!
But you do want a beetle, don't you?
Yeah.
A beetle?
So that's what you want. You really are kids.
You can catch as many beetles as you want.
R-Really?!
I won't forgive you if it's not true!
Well, I have an old friend in Yamanashi.
He says I can come and see him anytime I want.
You should be able to catch as many beetles as you want there.
And so, we ended up visiting the doc's old friend.
It's all the way in the middle of the mountains.
It looks like we're going to catch a lot of beetles and stag beetles here!
Absolutely!
There might even be a Hercules beetle too!
There's no way there'd be such a thing…
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Beetles, stag beetles, and even a Buddha statue?!
The Detective Boys' big search!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
He said he'd meet us here, but…
There isn't a single convenience store.
And no vending machines, either.
Agasa.
Ryūtarō, long time no see.
Have you been well?
Yeah, naturally.
Let me introduce you to him.
This is my friend, Ryūtarō Namatame.
Ryūtarō Namatame (52)
Nice of you to come, kids.
Welcome.
Thank you!
You said your house was at the foot of the mountain, but…
Is it far from here?
Oh, it's only about an hour by car.
Say, I'm so thirsty I could die.
Is there anything I can drink?
What a helpless kid.
Follow me.
I'll have a cola, please.
A big helping of soft ice cream for me!
What shall I have?
Hey, Kei!
If you're eating lunch here, that means you've been playing pachinko again, haven't you?!
N-No, I haven't!
Geez, how rude!
Kei Yabe (27)
I just brought some watermelon I grew to this market!
I doubt that.
Don't you get into debt and make your mother cry again.
I get it!
It's a beetle. It's big!
There's a Miyama Stag Beetle, too. It's so cool!
Hey!
Those aren't toys! Don't touch them!
Shūhei Ikeda (50)
Someone from a department store
in Tōkyō's coming to buy them.
If they're weakened then they can't be sold!
Shūhei, the children were just looking.
What's all the fuss about?
Ryūtarō, you know these folks?
Yeah. They're guests from Tōkyō.
Don't come onto my mountain just because you want beetles.
What a greeting after we just got here.
Oh, how pretty.
Sorry about that.
Ever since he was a child, Shūhei's been stingy and skeptical.
Also, we've had disputes over the borders of our land.
'Disputes over land…' Are you rich?
Don't be silly.
Well, since I live on a farm I don't have trouble getting something to eat, but…
I don't have any money.
But you're able to house all of us, right?
It's an old house, but it has a lot of
rooms, so don't worry about that.
Well, there's a lot of old junk too.
Someone from an antique shop who came by the other day
said that the Buddha statue that had fallen near the alcove
might be from the Kamakura Period.
Then I'll go with this one.
All right. Thank you very much.
This painting… it's kind of scary!
This is why children are helpless.
It might be by Maruyama Ōkyo.
That Buddha statue may have been made by Unkei.
Yeah, right…
Who cares about that? Let's hurry up and go!
That's right!
We're totally going to catch a stag beetle and brag to everyone in class!
Yeah!
Should we start around here?
They're here?
I don't know, but beetles and stag beetles like these kinds of oak and Japanese oak trees.
It reeks of liquor!
Why'd you put a good banana in liquor?
Never mind that. Open the stocking.
Yes, yes.
I was wondering why you told all of us to bring an old stocking, but it was for this.
My dad asked my if I was going to play robbers.
Are we really going to be able to catch one by doing this?
You're going to have to wait until tonight to see.
This ought to do it.
Let's put some more up.
I hope it gets dark quickly!
What are these tools for?
What would someone be doing at a place like this?
The key's still here, too.
Hey! What're you looking at?!
O-Oh, no, um…
The pachinko guy!
I said that I don't do such a thing!
What are you guys doing at a place like this?
We thought we'd catch some beetles.
Don't come near my car!
Now go!
We were just taking a look.
Just go already!
If you don't go, you'll be sorry!!
Let's go.
Yes, yes.
He didn't have to get that angry.
Do you think there might be something in there that he doesn't want others to see?
What'd you say?!
As usual, you're still making weird inventions.
'Weird' is uncalled for.
It's about time already.
That's right.
I think you'll be all right, but there are snakes around here, so take care of yourselves.
I'd be worried if the children went by themselves.
I'm going to go with them.
Ryūtarō, go ahead and go to bed.
Beetles! There's some beetles!
Amazing! Let me touch it.
We did it!
All right. Let's catch a bunch more!
There's a Giant Stag Beetle!
Look! It's a Nokogiri Stag Beetle!
Amazing! This is the first time I've seen so many!
How about this one?!
Mine's bigger!
Let's make them fight right after we get back.
I can't wait!
Geez. You can never let your guard down around that damn Ryūtarō.
Making me sneak around like this...
I won't let him get away with this!
That guy… from earlier today…
Someone from a department store
in Tōkyō's going to be coming to buy them.
If they're weakened then they can't be sold!
That's the man we met at the Roadside Station.
He said something about Ryūtarō.
Lots of fish, lots of fish!
That's a sailer, isn't it?
It looks like that guy is still awake.
That's strange. The sliding doors are open.
Mister! Hang in there!
What happened?!
Ryūtarō!
Mister!
Mister, I'm calling an ambulance now!
M-Miyama… Stag Beetle…
Did you say 'Miyama Stag Beetle?'
What do you mean?
Haibara! An ambulance!
Yes!
Oh?
What's wrong?
The Buddha statue that was here is gone!
Anyway, hurry up and call!
Right!
Out of service!
What...?
Either way, what did he mean by 'Miyama Stag Beetle…'
Namatame-san was transported to the hospital while unconscious.
And then, the police investigation began.
Detective Motohashi (45)
'Miyama Stag Beetle?'
Did he really say that?
Yeah.
We heard it too.
Detective Fuji'i (27)
It's not something you'd think someone would say before losing consciousness.
What do you think it means?
Who knows?
Um… There's one more thing that's bothering me.
What is it?
The Buddha statue that was over there when we left is missing.
Buddha statue?
Now that you mention it, a Buddha statue robbery case has been going on at temples throughout the prefecture lately.
When the victim caught them trying to steal the Buddha statue, the thief struck him with a nearby pot.
So it's settled.
Yeah.
Um…
This was on his clothes.
It's some kind of hair.
Just in case, run it through forensics.
Yes, sir!
Even so, why did Ryūtarō say 'Miyama Stag Beetle?'
There's no way a Miyama Stag Beetle could've done it.
Say, when we were coming back, we saw that man, right?
You can never let your guard down around that damn Ryūtarō.
That guy had a Miyama Stag Beetle at the Roadside Station!
Do you know his name?
Namatame-san called him Shūhei.
I think that's Shūhei Ikeda-san, who lives in this village.
Officer Iwanaga (55)
L-Let me go! Geez…
What'd I do?!
You've been having disputes with Namatame-san over the borders of your lands, haven't you?
Yeah. That's been my land for generations.
He tried to make a field out of it on his own.
But I didn't do it!
Where were you at around 12:00 last night?
12:00…
You were walking in the street, weren't you?
And very angrily you said 'You can never let your guard down around that damn Ryūtarō.'
That's…
Is it true?
When I went to patrol, the rice field's water had been stopped.
Ryūtarō's the only one who would do that,
so I thought I'd give him a good talking-to the next time I see him.
Didn't you 'give him a good talking-to' last night?
No… I would never do such a thing!
Believe me.
Mister, did you know there was a Buddha statue put up as an ornament in the alcove in the guest room?
Buddha statue? Oh yeah…
There was a terribly old and dirty thing there.
It seems that the one who attacked Namatame-san took that.
And it wasn't you?
Took the Buddha statue?
I see. A Buddha statue thief.
In that case, I have someone in mind.
Are you sure?!
It's Kei.
He had a coping saw and a grinder,
among other things, piled up in his truck.
I thought he was suspicious for going out night after night.
Those were definitely piled up.
Yeah. He got really angry when we saw them.
Really. It was scary.
Yeah. Now that you mention it, that guy was wearing a T-shirt with a picture of a Miyama Stag Beetle!
Who is it?
It's the police.
We have a few things we'd like to ask you.
Can you come with us?
W-What is it?!
What'd I do?!
Where were you at around 12:00 last night?
12:00…
Isn't it obvious that I was at home?!
Liar!
On my way back from my rice field patrol, I passed by the front of your house,
but your truck wasn't there.
You entered this house to steal the Buddha statue,
where you were found by Namatame-san,
so you struck his head and fled.
Am I wrong?
Just wait a second!
I wouldn't come here by car to steal.
Right? It's a short walk!
Then where were you at around 12:00 last night?
T-That's…
Anyway, I didn't attack Namatame. I mean it!
Did you find out what that hair is?
Yeah. That was a dog's hair.
A dog, huh…
What would someone be doing at a place like this?
The car key was left in.
Hey! What're you looking at?!
I knew it.
The one who attacked Namatame-san isn't either one of those two.
If so, who on Earth…
What are you looking at?
Oh, it's you, Haibara.
Don't 'it's you, Haibara' me.
What do you intend to do now?
It wasn't either of those two.
But both of them have a connection with Miyama Stag Beetles.
If it was one of those two, then Namatame-san should have said their name.
Then who is it?
I don't know.
But I can tell you at least that the person who attacked Namatame-san
did take that Buddha statue.
Is that dirty Buddha statue really that valuable?
Who knows?
He said it was made in the Kamakura Period, but…
Namatame-san said it may have been made by Unkei.
Well, there's still Unkei works left over from the Kamakura Period, but…
Could it be from the Heian Period?
No. I'm sure I heard it was from the Kamakura Period.
Now where did I hear that?
Well, there's a lot of old junk too.
Someone from an antique shop who came by the other day
said that the Buddha statue that had fallen near the alcove
might be from the Kamakura Period.
It was at that Roadside Station.
Haibara, let's go back to that Roadside Station!
We came here yesterday, but do you remember us?
I'm sorry. I don't remember.
If there's something that you noticed…
Miss, we came here yesterday, but do you remember us?
Yes. Weren't you some of the children with Namatame-san?
I remember.
Was there anyone else at that time?
Let's see…
Oh, how pretty.
Oh, there was a young married couple.
Do you remember anything about those people?
Even if you say that…
I only remember them buying a potted plant.
What kind of potted plant was it?
It was this.
Doesn't it have an interesting name?
Although it's not really to our taste.
This is…
What on Earth…
So that's how it was.
Say, that young married couple… weren't they...
Oh, how nice of you to know that. That's right.
Where did Conan-kun and Haibara-san go?
Along with the doc.
You don't think they're having lunch, do you?
Anyway, let's continue this conversation at the station.
But I said this has nothing to do with me!
Me neither!
Wait a second!
A-All of a sudden again…
Neither one of those two did it.
What'd you say?
Although, Kei-kun is guilty of being a Buddha statue thief.
D-Don't say stupid things!
I saw it underneath your car.
The Buddha statue was tied to the chassis.
Didn't you steal it from some temple last night?
How can you be so sure that neither one of these two attacked Namatame-san?!
The reason is simple.
Ryūtarō knows both of their names.
He wouldn't have said something like 'Miyama Stag Beetle.'
Since it was dark or something,
when he was suddenly attacked, wouldn't he not have been able to see the attacker's face?
When we got back, the lights in the guest room, the crime scene, were on.
Ryūtarō went to bed,
but he heard something, so he came to the guest room
and was attacked when he turned on the lights.
What if the attacker's face was hidden?
Even then, Ryūtarō would've probably known which of these two it was.
The truth is, we went to a Roadside Station on our way here yesterday.
There, Ryūtarō bragged that the now-stolen Buddha statue was from the Kamakura Period.
At the time, a married couple was there that seemed to be tourists.
That married couple bought a potted plant at the Roadside Station.
This is it.
This is...
.
Miyama
Stag
Beetle
This is...
That's right.
'Miyama Stag Beetle' wasn't an insect.
It was the name of this flower.
Ryūtarō saw the attacker, but he didn't know their name.
So he wanted to say that the culprit was the person who bought the potted Miyama Stag Beetle.
Is there…
Is there any proof?
According to the person who sold the potted plant,
that married couple was carrying a Maltese.
Maltese?
The thing that got onto Ryūtarō's clothes was also the hair of a dog.
If you do a DNA test, it should make it clear.
The culprit is without a doubt that married couple.
I leave the rest to you, detectives.
Afterwards, the police investigated
pet-friendly hotels and guest houses
and discovered the identity of the married couple.
The married couple that was arrested in Tōkyō
heard that the Buddha statue was from the Kamakura Period, thought they could sell it for a lot,
so followed the car that we got into,
and later entered the Namatame residence to steal it.
However, when they took the Buddha statue to an antique shop,
they were told that it wasn't an Unkei or anything special
and that its value was ¥5,000 at best.
Namatame-san was safely discharged
from the hospital a few days later.
What do you think?!
Aren't they cool, guys?!
We caught them ourselves!
They're Giant Stag… Beetles.
This flower's called 'Miyama Stag Beetle?'
That's right.
Are you really giving it to the class?
My mum said it's a rare flower so I should show everybody in class too.
Then let's set up a schedule for watering it!
That sounds nice! How do we pick?
It's too bad you can't brag about those.
Well, good work.
Cœur, how've you been?
What is it?
It looks like a map.
Is it a treasure map?
Maybe this map has no connection with a cat burglar but instead, it's about Kōzuki-san's case.
On the next Conan: 'The Great Dog Cœur's Triumph II'
Next Conan's hint: Cigarette butts!
Look forward to the next episode!
Today's Tanabata!
A botamochi off the rack!
tana
That's a godsend.
tanabota