Hiroshi Yagisawa (34)
Cœur
Good evening, Anella-chan.
H-Hey! That's not the way!
What's the matter, Cœur?
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Four marks on a picked-up map.
Is it a treasure or a case, Detective Boys?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Genta-kun, still sucking on candy?
This one's grape-flavoured.
Are you still going to be sucking on it when we go to school?
I started on it right when I left the house,
so I'll finish it up just as we get to school!
Don't blame me when you end up with cavities.
Hasn't he already got some anyway?
"Sakae-ya Cleaning"?
What's that?
Looks like a map.
A treasure map?
I don't think so.
The four X marks seem to all be homes.
You don't think... a cat burglar is targeting these homes?
Cat burglar?!
Look here.
Hasn't it been happening a lot in Beika Town recently?
Don't be silly. It's just something
scribbled on the back of a leafle—
That's gotta be it!
We've gotta tell them!
Are you guys listening?
Alright, let's go!
Right!
Hey, weren't we going to the library...?!
They've got more active imaginations
than a certain someone here.
Sheesh.
Then, there hasn't been a cat burglar here yet?
What a relief!
Ōga
Good, we're just in time, eh, Mitsuhiko-kun?
Yeah.
Norifumi Ōga (36)
But did a cat burglar really draw this?
I think there's a high possibility of it.
Have you seen any suspicious people
or strange things happening recently?
Not particularly...
Do you know these three houses?
Huh? I don't...
Misako Ōga (34)
How creepy. Why's our house got a X mark?
Hey! Don't go onto the lawn!
Didn't I tell you not to smoke in front of Tomoya?
S-Sorry.
Tomoya Ōga (6)
So, what do you do for a living?
I'm an architect.
Anyway, don't go bringing us weird things.
How about it?
Do you know anything about those three houses?
Nothing in particular.
I haven't been cat burgled,
Tamae Eguchi (32)
and I haven't seen anyone suspicious.
Nothing unusual's happened either.
Ma'am, do you live here by yourself?
That's right.
What do you do for a living?
I'm an illustrator.
Is that enough?
I'm busy young lady.
How about it? Do you know anything?
Fujiki
Nothing. I wonder who could have made this...
Shizuko Fujiki (61)
What's up, mother?
Ah, Kōichi...
These kids said they picked up this map.
A map?
See? Our place was marked with an X, right?
We figured maybe it was a cat burglar's map.
And if you saw anyone suspicious around lately...
Or someone doing something strange?
Kōichi Fujiki (33)
I don't think so...
Say, do you know any of the other three houses?
Nope.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a salaryman.
I'm starting to worry about this.
No, I don't think this has anything to do with a cat burglar.
But, mother, if you're worried,
I could take this map to a police substation.
When we've figured it out, we'll take it to one.
Here then.
Yeah.
Look, a patrol car's here.
Kōzuki. This is the place!
Maybe the cat burglar already got in?
Dammit! We're too late?
Good day. Did something happen in Kōzuki-san's house?
Kōzuki-san died.
Around 10 o'clock last night,
he had collapsed and was bleeding from his head
at the bottom of the stairs to the underground crossing
beneath Beika Highway just ahead.
The bottom of the stairs?
Falling to his death...
An accident? Or is it a case?
Well then, if anything comes to mind...
Sawako Kōzuki (35)
Thanks for the help.
Who's that?
She's Sawako-san, his only daughter.
So maybe this wasn't a cat burglar's map,
but has something to do with Kōzuki-san's case?
What do you mean?
The guy who drew this map,
he might still be targeting other people from these three houses!
So what do we do, Mitsuhiko?!
Detective, look at this map!
I'm busy right now.
If you want directions, ask at a police substation.
What's with him?!
That's the last he'll hear from me!
What do you think? About this case and the map...
I'd like to say they're not connected, but...
Anyway, we should take a look at the crime scene.
Hey, guys, wait for us at the park at the library.
W-Where're you going?!
What?
You're sure you smelt tobacco from the deceased's hand?
Without a doubt.
When I came running,
I could smell it faintly from his bloodied right hand.
But the deceased didn't smoke cigarettes, his daughter said.
And there weren't any cigarette butts at the crime scene.
How odd.
Cigarette...
Conan-kun's late...
And even as we're waiting here, the killer's doing more evil deeds...
Hey, we can take that guy all by our—
Wait until Edogawa-kun comes back.
Fine.
It's hot out though...
I want to eat ice cream.
Don't they have a vending machine in the library?
I'll go buy something and be right back!
How about you, Haibara-san?
I'm fine.
Ice cream, ice cream!
What are they doing?
Ah, Yagisawa-san!
Hello.
If it isn't Conan-kun! Long time no see.
You doing well, Cœur?
You know them?
Yeah. Some time ago thanks to Cœur, we solved a murder case.
Anyway, you guys—
The map went missing.
Maybe the culprit from Kōzuki-san's case made off with it!
You mean Kōzuki-san who died last night?
Did you know him, Yagisawa-san?
Actually, it was Cœur who found Kōzuki-san's corpse.
And that map you're looking for...
Was it one with Kōzuki-san's house
and 3 others with X marks?
How did you know about that?!
Because I drew that map.
The X marks were to mark houses
that my wife, who sometimes walks Cœur
instead of me, should be careful of.
She dropped that map when she was walking him.
At the first house, Ōga-san's wife is hot-tempered.
Once when Cœur just slightly stepped on their lawn,
she got really angry.
At the second house, Eguchi-san
sprays pesticides on her roses,
so I thought it would be best to stay away.
Eguchi-san uses organic fertiliser, and
liking the smell, dogs may want to stop by, right?
Yeah.
And at the third house, Fujiki-san's...
mother is an extreme neat-freak
and detests dogs peeing.
Right...
How did you know, Conan-kun?
That woman hadn't just sprayed
water in front of her own house
but also on the opposite house and
at the base of the telephone pole.
I see.
And Kōzuki-san also didn't like dog pee?
Yeah.
He was always sweeping outside his house.
Once when Cœur started to pee while we were on a walk,
he chased us away with a bamboo broom.
That reminds me, there were plastic bottles lined up there.
Those are to drive away cats.
Seeing them was what made me think about that.
Oh, that's what those were for.
Seems like that map wasn't connected to the case.
But, a new puzzle has appeared.
Why did someone steal a map
made for such a pointless reason?
The person who stole the map is
likely Kōzuki-san's murderer.
Huh?!
They didn't know who drew the map,
or for what reason, but
upon Mitsuhiko showing them a map connecting them with Kōzuki-san,
they thought it would be bad if it
were to be handed to the police.
Huh? That means...
In one of the three houses we visited
was Kōzuki-san's murderer.
That can't be!
The key is...
cigarettes.
Cigarettes?
That Eguchi woman was smoking a cigarette!
Ōga-san was stopped by his wife
when he went to smoke one too!
As for Fujiki-san...
His son smokes.
He intentionally hid the cigarettes he bought
in the pocket of his trousers.
His mother probably dislikes cigarettes.
Talking about cigarettes,
about 10 days ago,
at about 8 AM...
Damn it!
Who on earth keeps throwing away their cigarette butts here?!
If I recall,
the cigarette had two blue lines on it.
Two blue lines?
The same cigarettes that all three smoked.
Perhaps Kōzuki-san
met the person leaving cigarette butts at his house
at the underground crossing...
and started up trouble.
Then that's the killer?
Who is it, Conan-kun!
I don't know yet.
We don't have enough info.
If we check at Kōzuki-san's house,
we may find the butts he swept up.
No, they probably went in yesterday's
combustible rubbish collection.
Alright, we'll collect information!
Yeah! Let's!
Let's split up and ask around!
H-Hey...
Don't worry. I want to give them
a shock for stealing the map too.
Even you're at it...
Alright then.
But don't be reckless.
If you feel even slightly in danger, get away immediately.
Sure!
Understood!
Leave it to us!
Yagisawa-san, could you draw up the map again?
Sure.
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
As for the cigarette butts,
they really were in yesterday's combustible rubbish collection, they're gone now.
I see...
Ōga-san's design studio is right in front of Beika Station,
so he walks there everyday.
He leaves his house between 7:30 and 8:30,
but the times he gets back vary greatly,
and yesterday it was past 10.
It seems that Eguchi-san works four evenings a week
at a club in front of Beika Station.
Huh? Is that club a football club?
Last night she got back after 10:00.
It seems that Fujiki-san also commutes to Beika Station.
From the old woman opposite him,
he leaves every morning at exactly 7 AM,
and yesterday it was after 10:00 when she heard his door shutting.
All three commute to Beika Station.
And if they take this path, they pass by Kōzuki-san's house,
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
and the underground crossing.
Which means that all three of them
could have dropped their butts outside Kōzuki-san's house.
Before 8 AM and also late at night.
If not a football club, was it a baseball club?
When I asked the cleaners at the underground crossing,
they said they always found the same
brand of cigarette butts dropped there.
"Blue Line".
Around 10:00 last night, one of the three
dropped a butt at the underground crossing,
and Kōzuki-san, who found it, started arguing with them.
You're the one always dropping cigarettes outside my house, aren't you?!
That's why there wasn't a butt by the corpse.
But the question is which of the three did it...
Hey, what club was it?!
Ew! Genta-kun, you're disgusting!
Aw, I'd almost finished sucking it.
What a waste.
Finish sucking... Finish smoking...
Ah, could it be...?! But how can I prove it...
Hey, there's something I want to check on...
Let's go together! Cœur can come too!
As I thought, the river flows quickly...
Someone's there.
It's Eguchi-san.
She looks completely different wearing make-up though.
She smiled!
Suspicious.
Alright, let's follow her.
It's washed away... Was the cigarette
from the crime washed away too?
Finding proof will be difficult.
Ugh! Always this atrocious barking!
She's littering again.
That's not nice...
Good evening.
You're a good dog, but you shouldn't bark so much.
It depends on who it is.
Especially if they seem suspicious.
Hey, Haibara-san?
We'll lose Eguchi-san unless we...
Huh? That's...
Ōga-san.
What's going on?!
Interesting.
Again?
It's seems there's a woman who always litters here.
Always?
What is it, Cœur?
The recycling forgot to take those,
so I had to leave them there.
Could it be...?
I-It can't be!
That cigarette went in the river...
The one thrown in the river was a different butt.
Different?!
Yesterday, with the butt you took from Kōzuki-san in hand,
you headed for your own house, right, Fujiki-san?
On the way, you were suddenly barked at by a black dog, and dropped the butt, right?
Hurriedly surveying the surroundings
in the darkness, Fujiki-san
found and picked up a dropped butt.
It was the same brand, and even had a red mark on the filter.
He thought that it was the same one, and ran off again,
throwing it away on the bridge.
But what you picked up, Fujiki-san, was someone else's butt,
and what appeared to be blood was lipstick.
The butt that Fujiki-san dropped
went in the recycling containers left outside the house.
This way, Cœur!
Ōga-san was seeing Eguchi-san behind his wife's back.
Yeah.
That's why his expression changed when he saw the map.
When did you figure out who did it?
It's not like I was certain.
If I supposed the killer started smoking
when they left Beika Station...
Conv. Store
Matsumi
Bridge
Ôga
Eguchi
Fujiki
Underground
Crossing
Park
BEIKA
STATION
Mailbox
Kôzuki
PLAY-
GROUND
it's 400 meters to the underground crossing.
So I thought that was the distance
they took to finish one cigarette.
And when I looked at the distances
between Kōzuki's and the other houses...
So that's it.
Well then, a reward for a great detective's triumph.
It's fine, I don't need anything.
Uh...
Oh great detective, here's your reward, jerky!
She didn't mean me...?
Mister, over there!
That guy... I can't let him live!
That guy... he should just die!
Both of their initials are "K".
Katsutoshi Kusaka and Kiwako Kaitani.
One of those two did it!
On the next Conan: The Suspicious Initial K!
Next Conan's Hint: Ant!
Next time, pay attention to the initial "K"!
Me?
Wrong.
Then "Konan"?
Nope.