[Kaitani Kiwako (25)]
[Kusaka Katsutoshi (53)]
[Metropolitan Police Department - Beika Police Station]
[Caution! Stop driving without lights]
[Wear a helmet]
[First Interrogation Room]
[Second Interrogation Room]
[Prescription Service]
[South Jūō Pharmacy]
[Prescription]
[Kaitani Kiwako (25)]
[Kusaka Katsutoshi (53)]
[Ōoka Zenkichi (64)]
[Metropolitan Police Department - Beika Police Station]
[Caution! Stop driving without lights]
[Wear a helmet]
[Prescription Service]
[South Jūō Pharmacy]
[Prescription]
[Metropolitan Police Department - Beika Police Station]
[The Suspicious Initial K]
[Umbrella]
[Look forward to the next episode!]
Indeed.
I'm counting on you again next month.
Give me a break already. I'm at my limit!
Do you know how hard it was to get that money ready?!
Aren't you in charge of
accounting in your company?
Zenkichi Ōoka (64)
Security Guard
You have plenty of ways to make money…
Don't say stupid things!
There's no way I can do that.
I don't really care.
But what would happen if that were to be found out?
To your daughter's marriage.
W-W-Wait! Anything but that…
If it was to make your daughter happy,
you'd do anything, wouldn't you?
Please forgive me already.
With my salary, there's no way for me to continue paying you that much money!
I beg you.
If you're short on money then just get a night job.
I already have one! But, at this rate…
I don't mind if you run away.
But in exchange, this video will be leaked on the Internet.
If you don't want that to happen
then you know what to do, right?
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
The unusually conspicuous initial 'K'!
A suspicious dying message!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The Suspicious Initial K
That restaurant was rather good.
Yeah. Their fresh spring roll was something special.
Yeah.
Isn't that Officer Tateno?
You're right. I wonder if something happened.
Officer Sumio Tateno serves in a police substation in Beika Town, District 5.
He's earnest, kind, generous, and the people in the town also have deep trust in him.
Sumio Tateno (27)
Police Officer
Looks like it won't take long for his wish to come true:
to become a detective at Beika Station.
That's why I keep telling you!
Officer Tateno! Has something happened?
Oh, Mouri-san, it's nothing, really…
It is something!
Toshiko Hanazawa (49)
Housewife
Someone's been vandalising the garbage area,
so I've asked this officer to keep watch
all night and catch him for me.
That's why I've been thoroughly patrolling this area.
Are you all right?!
Hang in there.
Lady, is that blood?
A… person is dead in there!
What'd you say?!
Hang in there!
Are you all right?!
Is this the weapon?
A defensive wound on the body's arm…
The cushion...
Did the killer push the cushion against the victim so as to avoid getting hit by the victim's blood?
Mouri-san, please look after the crime scene.
I'm going to make sure that there are no suspicious people inside the house.
Headquarters! This is Tateno from Beika Town, District 5 PB.
Uncle, over there!
'K'… Is it a dying message?
His false tooth came out?
Did the killer break that?
There's no one in the house.
The kitchen door and the windows were all locked from the inside.
I see.
The victim is Zenkichi Ōoka-san, 64 years old.
He was living alone in this house and was a security guard at a supermarket in Haido City.
You discovered the body first, correct?
First, can you tell us your name?
Kiwako Kaitani (25)
I-I'm Kiwako Kaitani…
Her initials are 'K'…
You are?
I'm Hanazawa.
I saw the whole thing!
The whole thing?
Yes! I was talking with Nakajima-san,
a friend from District 4, out front.
And then, at a little past 6:00, Ōoka-san got home.
Right after that, a man came to Ōoka-san's house.
A man?
Yes. He looked like an office worker about 50 years old.
But after about 10 minutes, he left in a hurry.
And then?
About 20 minutes later, this girl came along and went into Ōoka-san's house.
Right after that, Tateno-san came along
just as Nakajima-san was leaving.
After we were talking for about five minutes, these people came and then this girl came out.
I'm sure the man who came before me murdered Ōoka-san…
I'm sure of it!
We need to find that man immediately.
Yes, sir!
What's the matter?
It's that man… The one who came to Ōoka-san's house before.
Look, he's amongst the onlookers.
The one in the hat?
Yes.
Wait!
You little!
Settle down!
Let me go!
What's your name?
Katsutoshi Kusaka (53)
I-I'm Katsutoshi Kusaka…
His initials are also 'K'…
Metropolitan Police Department - Beika Police Station
This is your kitchen knife, correct?
Interrogation Room I
T-That's certainly mine.
But I didn't do it!
Why did you visit Ōoka-san's house in the first place?
T-That's…
Actually, I was being blackmailed by Ōoka.
It's already been seven years.
I got involved in mahjong gambling.
The mahjong parlour was found out by the police, and I was arrested even though I was just a customer.
Ōoka was also a regular customer there.
Luckily for him, he escaped being arrested.
Even though I've given up gambling once and for all and have worked hard ever since,
I met him by chance at a supermarket I stopped by at in Haido City two years ago.
Since then, he's been…
…blackmailing you.
Yes. Month after month…
Six months ago, my daughter's marriage proposal was settled.
Since then, he started demanding more and more…
He even showed up at Shiomi Hotel where I was dining with the groom's family the other day.
He said something like he had a temporary guard job nearby.
At this rate, I thought my daughter's marriage would be ruined,
and whatever I were to do, I couldn't keep it in any longer.
Did you visit the victim's house today to give him money?
I always paid him after my payday at the end of the month,
but when he was going to go to an old friend's funeral,
he suddenly demanded money for the bullet train.
Instead of money, I brought a kitchen knife.
But while struggling, I cut his hand.
When I saw the blood that had spouted out, I suddenly got scared.
Throwing the knife, I got out of there!
That really is all!
Didn't that young woman come by after me?!
She probably did it!
Interrogation Room II
This was in your backpack.
It has a drug that is extremely hazardous to the human body.
You're a pharmacist, aren't you?
Did you steal it from the pharmacy that you work at?
It's… It's all his fault!
I graduated last year but I couldn't get a job,
so I became sort of neurotic and I started repeatedly shoplifting…
But he found me doing it,
and said he'd be quiet about it if I gave him money.
Since then, every month…
After I got a job, he demanded that I pay him twice as much.
He brought a prescription all the way to the pharmacy that I work at in Jūō City.
When I thought I'd be blackmailed
by him for the rest of my life, I…
That's why I hoped that he would just get a serious illness.
Did you visit the victim's house today to give him money?
It was always at the beginning of the month…
But he told me a friend from his hometown had died, and he was going to that friend's funeral,
and suddenly demanded I pay him for his hotel room.
But all I did was break his cell phone!
Since it had a video of me shoplifting.
It's the truth! The man who came by before me obviously did it!
So the victim was actually a blackmailer.
According to Kusaka-san, Ōoka-san was involved with a casino overseas.
A casino?
It seems that the reason he engaged in blackmail
was to earn back what he had lost.
Using money he'd gotten from blackmail
to absorb himself in a casino…
What a terrible guy!
Say, isn't this calendar from Ōoka-san's house?
Oh, you can't, Conan-kun.
There are weird things written all over it.
What is it?
Is it some kind of code?
It probably has some kind of
relationship with the blackmailing, but…
Hey! You're going to be a detective too next month.
So get used to this atmosphere while you can.
Y-Yes.
Hey, your hat's dirty.
There were no suspicious people in the house,
and the back door and windows were all locked from the inside, right?
Y-Yes! Roger that.
In other words, the only ones who could've entered or left the house were these two.
Katsutoshi Kusaka and Kiwako Kaitani.
The killer's one of them!
One of the two must be lying, right?
It doesn't quite add up.
The killer used a cushion to avoid getting hit by the victim's blood.
Can one of those two really commit such a crime so calmly?
Come to think of it…
Say, did you find the false tooth?
Kids should be quiet!
But it's bothering me!
It wasn't found at the crime scene.
If it fell out when the victim was struggling with the killer,
then there's also a possibility that it got onto the killer's clothes.
It was on neither of their clothes.
Kusaka-san, who left the crime
scene, could've thrown it away.
Takagi and Satō, continue questioning them.
Chiba, investigate the names listed in the victim's notebook.
Since there may be other blackmail victims.
Yes, sir.
'Circle… oka'?
So that's how it was!
If that's the case, then what on earth does the 'K' mean?
Ants? How come they're here?
I see. I get it!
Mouri-kun?!
Inspector, it's getting late so let's settle this here.
What?! Do you know who the killer is?
Yes.
I'm going to explain what happened now,
so can you bring the two suspects here?
Bring the two suspects?
You two were the only ones to enter and leave the crime scene after Ōoka-san got home.
I didn't do it!
Me either!
'K' was written using the victim's blood at the crime scene.
Based on the situation, it's hard to think
that one of you purposefully left the message in order to disrupt the investigation.
Certainly after seeing the dying message that the victim left behind.
But both of their initials are 'K'.
With just this, it could have been either of them…
Kusaka-san, you've been giving Ōoka-san money
on the 27th of every month, am I right?
Huh? Yeah.
On the 5th for Kaitani-san.
Yes. That's correct.
So Ōoka-san showed up at the
Shiomi Hotel on the 8th of this month?
That's right!
And he went to the pharmacy on the 17th?
H-How do you know?
It's all written on the calendar.
The calendar? You mean this code?
Inspector, take a look at the name tag on Ōoka-san's notebook.
'Circle… oka'?
That's read as 'Ōoka'.
Not 'circle,' but the letter 'O'.
Ōoka-san had a habit of turning the names of people and places into letters and numbers.
So the '9A' on the 27th and the '89 woman' on the 5th...
point towards Kusaka-san and Kaitani-san?
9A
The Chinese reading for Kusaka is kyū-ei.
yaku-zai-shi
Kaitani-san is a pharmacist.
If you turn 'yaku' into numbers, it becomes '89'.
Since she's female, he added a 'woman'.
I see. So '403' is really 'yon-ō-san,' or 'Shiomi'!
The '100' on the 17th is 'jū-ō'.
The pharmacy in Jūō City.
I see.
In that case, what's the 'K' that was left at the crime scene?
It was neither Katsutoshi Kusaka nor Kiwako Kaitani.
That was…
keikan
…the 'K' from 'police officer'.
Officer Tateno, the killer…
It was you!
Officer Tateno's the killer?
That can't be…
W-Wait a second!
Even if that was 'K' from 'keikan', why am I the killer?
When we discovered the body,
you said that you were going to make sure there were no suspicious people inside the house,
but you headed towards the kitchen first.
Isn't it strange?
Why didn't you start checking with the closest room to you, the one opposite?
T-That is…
At that time, you locked the back door.
The very back door that you came in and out of at the time of the crime.
Wasn't the usual garbage vandalising also your doing?
So even if you frequently visited that street in order to get information about Ōoka-san,
if you went there under the pretense of patrolling, nobody would suspect you.
And then today, you knew that Kusaka-san and Kaitani-san would be paying Ōoka-san a visit.
Using that knowledge, you came up
with a plan to murder Ōoka-san.
Y-You're wrong!
After Kusaka-san got out of there,
you sneaked into the house through the back door,
murdered Ōoka-san, and left through the same back door.
And then, with an innocent look,
you showed yourself in front of Hanazawa-san.
That's nonsense!
Do you have any proof?!
You had something on your hat, did you not?
Was that not sugar?
There are ants swarming around on the floor where you were standing.
He's right.
There was spilled sugar at the crime scene.
Didn't your hat slip off when you murdered Ōoka-san?
On top of that sugar.
As if…
One more thing.
In order to brush off the dirt,
you brushed it off by keeping the dirty part facing down.
I thought it was strange.
Would you by any chance have a reason why you couldn't turn it over?
That is…
If my deductions are correct,
Ōoka-san's false tooth that had disappeared from the crime scene is inside your hat!
Officer Tateno! Off with your hat.
Oh, no…
It's here!
Ōoka-san's false tooth probably fell
into your hat that had slipped off.
You noticed it when I told you to take your hat off,
and you were afraid it would fall out, so you couldn't turn your hat over.
Officer Tateno, why did you do it?
Answer me, Officer Tateno!
T-The truth is,
I was also a regular mahjong gambler at the same mahjong parlour as Kusaka-san when I was in school.
I was the same as Ōoka-san.
I also luckily escaped being arrested.
Since then, I had a change of heart,
studied hard, and became a police officer.
But six months ago at a supermarket that I went to to take care of a shoplifter,
I met Ōoka-san who was a security guard there.
But Ōoka-san's office is in Haido City…
He was a representative for the security guard who was on sick leave.
He remembered me.
And then, he started blackmailing money from me.
You gave him money on the 11th of every month.
The 水 (mizu) character that was written on the calendar was changed from a 'K' to deceive us.
That's right.
It's been six months from that day and every month…
Last month, there was an unofficial announcement that I was going to be assigned to the detective section.
Ōoka-san, who found out about that, started demanding more and more.
Officer Tateno…
When I investigated, I found out that
he had countless other victims.
At this rate, I couldn't let him get away with this.
That's what I thought…
That's right! I passed judgement!
In order to save the people that had been tormented by him!
In the name of justice!
This is the judgement of justice!
Don't you speak of justice!
No matter how many excuses you make,
what you did was murder!
It's no more than a begrimed crime!
And the foolish act that you committed
scarred the honour of every single one of the 290,000 police officers in this country!
You have no right to speak of justice!
Sumio Tateno.
I arrest you with the charge of murder.
Overwrite
I apologise for the discomforting feelings that I caused for both of you in this case.
O-Oh, no…
However, I shall charge Kusaka-san with bodily harm and Kaitani-san with theft.
Do you comply?
Yes.
I understand.
With a single mis-step, either of you could've made the same mistake as Tateno.
Take that to heart and properly make up for each of your wrongs.
Y-Yes…
I am truly sorry.
Mouri-san, you have to help me!
We have to hurry, her life is at stake!
She… was killed, wasn't she?
She's… not the victim?
She's the assailant.
On the next Conan: 'The Rainy Night Menace'
The Rainy Night Menace
Next Conan's Hint: Umbrella!
Look forward to the next episode!
A request from Detective Chiba?
For the great detective that the police can rely on?
Who?