Detective Conan ep 666
Translated by 1412
First Draft
(Timing: usotsuki)
Mio Ashida (23) Office Worker) (flip the name orders, please)
MONTAGE
(Murakami Takuya (20) College Applicant) (Rouninsei is a student who failed the entrance exam and is without a school, hence Ronin)
(Yoshizumi Karashima (28) Unemployed)
(Shirt: Pass the Exam) not sure if it's worth translating.
Somebody, help me!
ENDING SONG DAKARA BABY BABY
Man, what a lazy day.
Isn't anyone going to commit a crime?
Dad, don't wish for things like that!
Maybe I'll go out drinking.
But it doesn't look like the rain's going to let up.
Oh, it's Detective Chiba!
There we go! It's a case!
Mouri-san, you have to help me!
Welcome!
I need you to find her, quick!
Huh?
We have to hurry, her life is at stake!
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Detective Chiba has a job for the old man...
A peculiar incident on a dark and stormy night!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The thing is, I've been seeing this woman since we met in my favorite café.
A little while ago, she said she wanted to tell me something.
That she felt her life was in danger.
"Once I get out of jail, first thing I'm gonna do is find you."
He's been sending letters like this for the past year?
Yes... I was scared so I quit my job and moved.
Mio Ashida (23)
Office Worker
But even here, I feel like I'm being watched.
It might be just my imagination.
Either way, I told her to let me know right away if she saw him, or if anything escalated.
But...
When I left to use the toilet...
She was suddenly gone.
That woman suddenly paid the bill and left, sir.
She seemed rather shaken up.
Oh, no!
Wait...
That's her umbrella. She must have mistakenly picked up mine.
It didn't feel like negligence, it felt like he'd tried to kill me.
Had he seen the umbrella and mistaken me for her?
It was stupid of me not to have asked for her address...
I thought about pursuing this through the office, but there's no definite proof of anything.
And so I came here.
Doesn't sound like much of a case to me.
You don't know her personal info, so there's not much chance of finding her.
But if you've recently seen her more often at that coffee shop,
doesn't that mean she's moved closer to it?
I see!
Then we could go to the café, and search outwards from there.
You're right!
Hey, hey, I'm not taking a case like—
I'm going, I'm going.
This is one smart criminal...
Takuya Murakami (20)
Failed College Applicant
I wish that jerk upstairs would keep it down.
Aah, stop! Somebody, help me!
Is there a crime in progress?
What's wrong, Detective Chiba?
Yes. Yes, I understand!
A... young woman was involved in a homicide in a nearby flat.
That's the car from before.
What?
Are we too late?
Wait, Chiba!
Out of the way!
Chiba.
Wasn't today your day off?
She... was killed, wasn't she?
This man...
The hat and sunglasses I saw...
Back then...
Mio-san!
She's... not the victim?
She's the assailant.
Inspector.
Mouri-kun, what are you doing here?
Here's what happened.
I see.
So that's why you came here in search of her?
Yes.
The abandoned car was stolen, after all.
I see.
So what happened here?
Takagi, give us the rundown.
Yes, sir.
The incident took place 40 minutes ago, at 9:30 PM.
An unemployed student in the room below, Takuya Murakami-san,
heard a disturbance and a scream, and came to check it out.
He found the body and Mio Ashida-san standing next to it.
He used his cell phone to contact the police.
At the time of the incident, the front door appears to have been unlocked.
The victim is Yoshizumi Karashima-san, age 28.
Yoshizumi Karashima (28)
Unemployed
We've confirmed that he was just released three days ago from traffic jail.
Traffic jail? Was he incarcerated for traffic violations?
That's correct. One year ago, he was with someone who was driving under the influence.
They ended up breaking the guardrail and falling into a lake.
Two people were thrown from the vehicle,
one died at the scene, one had minor injuries.
The driver was at fault, but wasn't prosecuted, due to his death.
The passenger, who was also intoxicated,
was sentenced to one year as an accomplice.
That's Karashima-san, our victim here.
That's not true!
My brother swore he'd never drive again after his first drunk driving offense.
Her brother?
Karashima was the one driving!
Mio-san...
The deceased driver was her brother, a Toshiaki Ashida-san.
At the time, he was 28.
I couldn't believe it when Karashima testified that it had been my brother driving.
I filed several objections, but they were all overruled.
And then...
A year in prison?! You've gotta be kidding!
This is all because of those ridiculous allegations you all brought up!
I won't forget this!
You won't get away with this!
He was just trying to shift the blame!
He was bitter that he didn't get a suspended sentence.
Mio-san, show them the letters.
All right.
These were all sent while he was incarcerated?
They all say, "I'll come pay you a visit the second I'm out of here."
A veiled threat, perhaps, but clearly a threat.
So it would seem.
It's certainly hard to see how else one could interpret it.
"I want you to remember, and wait..."
What's this?
Hey, why's there a gap of almost half a year with no letters?
He probably cooled off a bit, then got worked up again once his release drew nearer.
Hey! Stupid kids should keep their traps shut!
I'm sorry.
Mio-san, you were afraid he was going to be released soon,
so you changed jobs and moved here, didn't you?
Yes.
I see.
You just moved here, so that's why most of your appliances and electronics are new.
Some don't even look like they've been used at all.
Now that you mention it, you're right.
They still have price stickers on them.
I would generally come home just to sleep.
I was just scared...
I can imagine.
Still, everything's a little too neat.
Guess she was watching TV...
though not using the remote.
Please describe how you found the victim after he forced the lock and entered the flat.
When I came home, the lights were on,
and the door was open.
I wasn't thinking, and didn't consider he could still be inside.
The moment I opened the door, suddenly...
Ashida-san fought back using the umbrella she was holding.
Their struggle took them into the living room.
So the fatal blow was to the back of the head...
Hmm?
Hey, there's a wound on the bridge of his nose.
Maybe he was hit during the struggle?
Look, on the edge of the TV stand.
It certainly looks like he struck here, but...
I think this is a pretty clear case of self-defense.
Seems corroborated by the fact that he tried to hit me
when I took her umbrella by mistake.
What's this?
The victim's shoes.
Ran-neechan, when did the rain start?
Let's see... It was just as the evening started, so maybe around seven?
Which means...
Well then, if we could get a more detailed statement from you back at the station, ma'am?
Of course.
It's okay, I'll walk you through it. Don't worry.
Thank you very much.
I already told you!
Pass the Exam!
Like I was telling the detective, I could hear that the TV was on the whole time.
Who are you, anyway?
I'm asking for the great detective upstairs, Kogorō Mouri.
So when did you first hear the TV turn on?
From around six o'clock, maybe?
Just as it turned off at 9:30, I heard the scream.
It's sort of a cheap flat, you can hear everything through these paper-thin walls.
Was there any sound other than the TV?
Now that you mention it...
I wish that jerk upstairs would keep it down.
Ah, stop!
So that's what it was!
Which means...
I knew it.
But that means this case is actually...
Now then,
Well, time to go home and have a nice cold beer—
What's that over there?
Mouri-san?
Dad?
Mouri-san, could it be—
Detective Takagi. I need you to check on something immediately.
Yes?
Inspector.
This case hasn't been cracked yet.
Yes. Yes. And when did that happen?
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Inspector, this isn't a case of self-defense.
It was premeditated murder.
Premeditated murder?
But... that's ridiculous!
Allow me to explain.
Please take a look at the umbrella stand.
It should have a puddle of rainwater at the bottom.
You're right.
The umbrellas we brought are lined up in the entryway,
to not contaminate the crime scene.
Which means there was only one umbrella in this room:
Detective Chiba's, which she accidentally took from the café.
That's true, but what does that mean?
It means that your umbrella was the one in the stand.
That contradicts her statement that she used it to fight off the victim,
who attacked her the moment she entered the flat.
Indeed. She wouldn't have had time to put the umbrella into the stand.
There's another contradiction as well.
Even though the victim drove here in the car parked in the empty lot,
none of his clothes were even damp.
It's because he must have had an umbrella.
But we just said there couldn't have been another umbrella.
Which means the victim must have arrived
before it started raining, before 7 PM.
That can't be! He almost ran me over just an hour ago!
That's right, his shoes...
The victim's shoes were wet!
Indeed his shoes are wet.
But why aren't his socks or pants?
Well...
Still, the victim's possessions include the hat and sunglasses I saw!
Can we be truly certain that those items actually belonged to the victim?
There's one more inconsistency:
the driver seat's setting in that car.
It was set to a position far too close for a person with a tall build.
Conan confirmed it for me.
That's all circumstantial evidence,
but it leads us to the same conclusion:
this wasn't self-defense, but a murder planned by Mio-san.
Mio-san...
Everything went according to Mio-san's plan.
Let me start from the beginning.
First, she picked the lock to her own front door.
Then, she called Karashima-san on the phone.
"I'll leave it unlocked, so come inside and wait."
Next, she went to the café and told Detective Chiba about the letters.
She made it seem like she was scared and being threatened.
She took Detective Chiba's umbrella on purpose, left the restaurant,
and attacked Detective Chiba who came after her with her car,
creating the impression that her life was in danger.
Karashima-san, who had entered the flat earlier,
was watching TV while awaiting her return.
He couldn't use the remote, so he turned it on manually.
At 9:30 PM, Mio-san came home.
Karashima-san turned off the TV.
He faced the TV and pressed the power button.
He was struck from behind with a heavy vase.
Falling forward, his nose hit the TV stand, and broke.
These are the sounds that Murakami-san heard from his room on the first floor.
She then placed the knife in Karashima-san's hand
and put the hat and sunglasses from her attack on Detective Chiba in the room.
And the scream that Murakami-san heard?
Entirely playacted by Mio-san for him to hear.
She likely moved here specifically for the thin walls.
Of course, he also heard the sounds of the actual murder.
Isn't that all purely conjecture, Mouri-san?!
At any rate, it's at least true that Karashima threatened her!
It's clear from the letters and what he said in the courtroom!
Is it really?
You're right about that day in the courtroom.
But what about the letters?
Especially those that were sent after the sudden gap in correspondence.
Along with phrases like "I'll come see you once I get out', we also see many instances of 'I want to meet you so I can tell you the truth."
What if he intended to confess to her that it really had been him driving on that rainy night one year ago?
That's impossible!
It certainly seems like a stretch.
Why not just plead guilty at trial or confess to the police?
Perhaps he thought he was running out of time?
Takagi, where have you been?
I was wondering why there'd been a pause in the letters he'd sent,
so I inquired at the traffic jail.
Just before the letters stopped,
Karashima-san had a medical exam at the prison infirmary.
He was diagnosed with a terminal illness and given six months to live.
What?!
However, once he was released, he never visited the hospital he was referred to.
He was most likely looking for Mio-san, who'd quit her job and moved.
Then he really was trying to confess his crimes...
You're wrong, I don't believe you!
Even if that were true, I wouldn't forgive him!
How could I forgive him?!
Mio-san...
After my brother's death, I broke off my engagement.
My father put off retirement, and overworked himself until he fell ill.
Both he and my mother passed away,
nobody would help us, and there was nothing I could do but watch.
No one believed my brother was innocent. That's why—
—you decided to take revenge?
Yes, that's right.
Are you... admitting you did it?
Yes.
Sorry to steal the show from the great detective, who only found circumstantial evidence.
But I don't regret what I did.
Not one bit.
Mio-san...
Then let me show you the truth that I found, rather than circumstantial evidence.
Perhaps once you see it, you'll realize that you've committed a meaningless murder.
Although I don't believe there is such a thing as a justifiable murder.
What do you mean?
Recreating the scene'll be easier than explaining it. Conan!
Coming!
Miss, you can be Karashima-san,
and Detective Chiba can play her.
Inspector Megure, can you turn on the TV?
Oh, sure.
Now Chiba, pretend to swing the murder weapon.
Like this?
Mio-san, from that position, please turn off the TV.
There's—
Karashima-san saw you standing behind him.
Yet, he didn't run.
What he'd wanted all along was to beg for
forgiveness, and put himself at your mercy.
Yes... he'd come to regret what he did,
from the bottom of his heart.
Knowing that, can you still have no regrets?
This case was the final chapter of an accident that happened one year ago.
But the lives that were lost will never return.
Nor will guilt be easily erased.
In the end, I couldn't help you.
I'm truly sorry.
Don't blame yourself.
I involved you to give the police a chance to redeem themselves for their mistake a year ago.
But if I had found you earlier, and given you the umbrella...
...perhaps I could have kept you from
committing a murder, at least for tonight.
Either way, I don't have the right
to let you hold an umbrella over me.
Mio-san...
I'm sorry...
Thank you.
I suppose now it's her turn to atone for her crimes.
I think at least Detective Chiba was able to express his feelings.
I'm sure you're right...
Well, even if you congratulate us...
Where are you, Hatsune?
She hired me...
...as a private eye.
I'm a detective.
A... detective?
On the next Conan: Wedding Eve (Part I)
Next Conan's Hint: Waiter!
Summer's all about going to the pool, and camping!
And beer, beer!
Dad...
And 24h TV!