Raita-kun! Hatsune-san!
Congratulations on your marriage!
Well, even if you congratulate us now,
the wedding's not until tomorrow,
so we're not really married yet.
Hatsune Kamon (37)
Bride
Raita Bamba (37)
Groom
It's fine, it's our wedding eve,
and straight after the wedding's over
we're flying off on our honeymoon.
I guess.
Hey, you two! I'm jealous!
Hi! It's been so long, Mouri.
Then, is he that great detective?
Yup, a bad friend from high school,
Kogorō Mouri.
Nice to meet you, I'm Hatsune.
Hello.
And so the two next to you are your...?
I'm his daughter, Ran.
And I'm Conan, a freeloader.
Because of some reasons,
we're looking after him.
I heard you fell in love at first sight, is that right?
Yeah, we felt it was fate from the moment we met.
As if we'd finally found each other.
In any case, our birthdays, blood types and histories are the same.
Sometimes, even if we're silent
we can tell what the other is thinking.
Thank you for waiting.
Hey!
S-Sorry!
Ugh! It's stuck to my trousers.
Oh... You're stepping on the cake.
I'm really sorry.
Today is my first day here.
Don't worry. Could you bring a cloth to wipe his trousers?
Sure! I'll go get one.
Hey, just because that waiter's hot
doesn't mean you should go ogling him.
Why, are you jealous?
It's not like that...
You haven't changed.
Still quick to get involved with women,
but jealous when they do the same.
What're you going on about?
Mouri, you're the one who used to
send anyone who courted Eri-chan flying.
W-What about it?!
Really?!
Geez...
I'll never understand why men
always want to monopolise women.
Oh? Where're you going?
The nail salon.
To get the nail tips for the wedding put on.
I told you, you don't have to do that.
It's pouring with rain.
No way, I've even got a reservation.
And the salon's staff are all
women, so you don't need to worry.
Like I told you,
I won't forgive you
if you go having an affair.
That's my line, "husband."
Well, I'll be back in 2 hours,
so look out for my fingertips!
Right.
She should do it just before the wedding.
She'll have to take them off before she goes to sleep tonight.
Oh, usually nail tips
go for 24 hours without being taken off.
Even when you have a bath?
Yup.
Hehe... being a woman sounds like it's tough.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
An unbelievable car explosion strikes a couple on their wedding eve!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
It's my last night as a bachelor
so be a bit kinder to me...
But Bamba-kun, won't your wife get angry?
Geez, he's still at it
even though he has a beautiful wife.
He really is just like a certain someone here.
Excuse me, mister.
Ugh, you again. What now?
Your phone's been ringing
for a while now.
Excuse me.
Oh, an e-mail from Hatsune.
"You won't pick up, so here's an MMS with my nails."
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
"In 30 minutes you can see them for yourself."
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
You won't pick up, so here's an
MMS with my nails. In 30 mins
you can see them for yourself.
Aww, you're already head-over-heels in love.
Oh, well, I guess.
Good for her.
Sorry, I've gotta go to the toilet.
See ya...
Hmm? A second phone?
He's scowling while talking with someone...
Huh? He hung up straight away.
Then went straight to the toilet...
Does that mean whoever phoned him is in there?
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did you see someone you know?
No, it's nothing.
Well, I can't do anything anyway.
Sanji Haruoka (48)
Customer
Don't tell me he's the one who phoned him?
Waiter!
Yes.
Thank you for waiting.
Bourbon, on the rocks.
Understood.
Be more careful, you moron!
S-Sorry...
Wait a sec, Bamba-kun. You're drunk.
I'm fine, don't worry.
Hey, waiter!
Yes?
Do you remember my order?
Yes, bourbon, on the rocks, wasn't it?
Okay, there's no mistake.
Well then.
Hey, Bamba-kun, what're you scowling at?
Huh? Nothing.
Hey...
This party's also Uncle Kogorō's class reunion, isn't it?
Yeah, seems like the bride's wedding party was on another day.
Though mum was busy with work and couldn't come.
Then that guy with the sunglasses is one of your classmates?
Huh? Hmm...
I don't remember him.
Anyway, it's been 20 years.
Hmm...
Hello. Yes, that's right...
Yes... yes, and?
Right. Yeah.
H-Hey! What're you doing?!
This customer suddenly threw a punch at me...
Are you all right?
Don't touch me!
Hey, Bamba.
You really are drunk, Bamba-kun!
Ah, your hand's bleeding...
It'll be fine.
It won't be fine!
You've gotta get it treated...
Bamba-kun, are you listening?
The only one I want to talk to now is Hatsune.
Oh, Hatsune. Where are you?
Huh? "Goodbye"?
What're you saying, Hatsune?
Hey, Hatsune! Hatsune, where are you?!
Hey, look!
It can't be... that car's Hatsune's...
- What?!
- Oh no!
Ran! Call a fire engine,
an ambulance and the police!
Right!
Hatsune... Hatsune...
Hatsune! Are you okay?! Hatsune?!
Hatsune!
The corpse is charred,
so we're having their teeth compared with medical records, but I think the deceased is probably the car's owner,
Hatsune Kamon-san.
Is it true that just before the car burst into flames,
there was a phone call from
Kamon-san implying it was suicide?
Yes.
Inspector.
There are two large travel suitcases in the car boot.
Those had probably been
prepared for their honeymoon.
The woman who died was going to be married to an old friend of mine tomorrow.
But why would someone so happy commit suicide?
Who knows. Could it have been something like marriage blues?
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Hey! You're in the way again...
What is it?
Isn't this a stick-on nail?
Huh? It is.
What's that doing here?
About two hours ago, Kamon-san said she
was going to a nail salon and left the party.
Huh?
It might be best not to conclude that this is suicide just yet.
Huh, it was murder?!
Not suicide?
Right.
On the end of the stick-on nail Conan-kun found, there were slight traces of skin.
Which means that what was on that stick-on nail
most likely is the skin of someone who attacked her next to her car.
W-Who was it?!
Who killed Hatsune?!
You are Raita Bamba-san, who was engaged to Kamon-san, correct?
Yeah, that's right.
How did you injure your hand?
This is from when I fell on broken shards of a glass earlier...
Well then, do you remember this hairbrush?
Ah, yeah, it's mine.
I thought it was in my travel suitcase though.
Yes, it was in your suitcase,
in the boot of the car that was set on fire.
Just to be sure, we had hair DNA
collected from this hairbrush analysed,
and compared with the skin DNA on her stick-on nail.
They're a rough match.
Huh?
What?!
W-What're you saying?
Are you trying to say that I did it?!
No, it's still not an exact match,
so we would like your consent
to do a proper check.
Stop joking around!
Calm down, Bamba.
You didn't do it, right?
O-Of course not!
Although, it would've be possible for him to have hit at me and gotten injured on purpose
in order to camouflage scratches from her resisting, wouldn't it?
W-What the hell did you just say?!
Hm, well said.
Couldn't you have killed the woman you loved
before she could become someone else's, waiter?
Huh?
H-Hold on, what do you mean?
If he won't say it himself then I will.
This guy is a lover of Hatsune's,
who's been secretly seeing her!
What?! Is that true?
How about it? Well?
I did meet her.
But that's because she hired me as a private eye...
Tōru Amuro (29)
Detective
I'm a detective.
A... detective?!
Don't you find it strange?!
How come the detective Hatsune hired just happens to be a waiter at our marriage party?!
It's not a coincidence.
I arranged for the party to be held at this restaurant, where I work part-time.
But why on earth?!
Of course, it was so I could watch your movements.
Watch me?!
Yes. I did so at Hatsune-san's request.
She asked me to investigate and keep watch on whether or not you, possessing flirtatious tendencies, were seeing anyone else.
That's why I purposefully stained your pants with cake,
so that you couldn't make advances on a woman.
Although Hatsune-san herself cannot testify that she asked me to do that
because she burned to death inside a car in this restaurant's parking lot,
it seems that the man in sunglasses there can testify that I received the request from her.
He happened to be there when I was reporting to her the progress of my background check on Bamba-san.
Who on earth are you?
No...
He's probably another detective.
D-Detective?!
His client is Bamba-san, the groom.
He thought she was seeing someone recently, so he asked the detective to find out.
The detective located their secret meeting place,
but the man she met was wearing a hat and a hood, so he couldn't identify him.
But the voice of the man he heard at that time resembled that of mine, a waiter,
so he called me to his table and ordered something.
After confirming that the voices were the same, he most likely sent a sign to Bamba-san that I was indeed the same man.
Right before that, he called Bamba-san and told him to come to the toilet
so that he could tell him that the man in question might be in the restaurant, and he intended to find out for sure.
Isn't that right?
Y-Yeah, that's right.
I didn't think you'd be a detective.
When I tried to tail you, you gave me the slip.
But, Bamba-san, you were trying to marry her even though you knew she was meeting a mysterious man?
Shouldn't you have asked her yourself?
The detective said he hadn't seen the man since that secret meeting.
Besides, I thought she'd hate me if she knew that I had hired a detective to investigate her.
We were in a relationship where we had confessed to each other that we were both adopted.
The "same history" that Bamba-san talked about...
If you'd have asked me, I would've found out right away that this nice guy's a detective.
How could I ask you?!
You're famous and have a well-known face.
And besides, I was planning on introducing you to her.
But still... If you'd have left it to me,
she wouldn't have committed suicide.
What caused her to set herself on fire
might've been the fact that this guy tattled to her that you were having a wild party.
I-I never made such a phone call.
Besides, I don't think she'd commit suicide
just from hearing on the phone that he was drunk and playing with women.
Speaking of phones...
Bamba-san, it seems that that you received a call that suggested suicide from her
right before the car went up in flames, but...
Y-Yeah... She said "goodbye" while crying.
I see.
I-If you don't believe me...
Look, tonight at 8:54!
It's in the call history.
If you'll allow me to have a look...
When did 110 receive the report?
Let's see... It was at 9:21.
There's a gap of about 30 minutes, isn't there...?
D-Don't ask me!
Um, about that...
I was the one who made the report.
I called an ambulance and a fire
engine first, and that took some time.
But by the time the ambulance and the fire engine arrived, it was too late.
The inside of the car was irrecoverably burnt.
But don't you find it strange?
The part of a car people ride in is usually made out of something that's hard to burn, so why did it burn so much?
You're right.
There were some explosions from time to time.
Oh, those were from spray cans.
There were a lot of spray cans, paper, and cardboard in the car.
That's what ignited.
Why were things like that in your car?
After the party was over tonight, we were planning to use pattern paper and spray paint to decorate the car.
We thought we'd surprise everyone by showing up at the wedding in the decorated car together.
If you don't believe me then look at the e-mail!
There's an e-mail from her saying she's got everything we needed!
Tonight at 8:18, there was an e-mail from her saying that she'd be back in 30 minutes, but...
Y-Yeah. She sent a picture message from the nail salon.
Which means you knew there was a large amount of flammable materials in the car
as well as the time she was coming back to this restaurant.
Is that correct?
H-Hey... What're you saying?
I'm saying that you could have secretly
slipped out of the restaurant,
ambushed her in the parking lot, knocked her unconscious, shoved her into the car,
set it on fire, and burnt her to death.
Hey, hey, hey...
On top of that, one of the stick-on nails that she had just put on tonight had fallen near the car.
A very small amount of skin was stuck on the tip of it.
W-Wait...
There's a high possibility that that skin got there when she was attacked by you, resisted, and then scratched you.
The skin DNA roughly matched the hair DNA on your hairbrush.
B-But, it's not like it was an exact match, right?
Hey! Say something too, Mouri!
I believe that "roughly" means that the skin left on that nail was contaminated
by rain, dirt, or the like, and that
complete data wasn't able to be taken.
When comparing the genome of people who aren't blood relatives,
a rough match of genetic information isn't possible.
Therefore, it's natural to think that the DNA is the DNA from the same person.
W-What the hell did you just say?!
P-Please stop with the violence.
Get a hold of him, Mouri-san!
What if he tries to hit me again?
There's no need for that.
Damn.
Hey, Bamba... Calm down...
It's not yet certain that the hair on that hairbrush is yours.
Isn't it better to just let them take your DNA and check it?
They're just going to take some saliva from your mouth with a cotton swab.
As I thought, this is...
Then how'd this person...
Now then, Bamba-san,
do you permit us to do a DNA test?
Y-Yeah.
Then this way, please.
But aren't DNA tests amazing?
You used to only be able to tell
someone's blood type from their saliva,
but now you can tell for sure if two
samples came from the same person.
Yeah. You're right.
Then people who change their appearance and deceive everyone can be found out in an instant.
Y-Yeah... Y-You're right.
If the results of the test come out then it'll be clear, but...
But if that person did do it, why is that still there?
Or was some kind of trick used?
If so, why not say something about that?
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
Kudō-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Inspector Megure.
There's a door in the back of the restaurant that leads to the parking lot,
but at the time of the incident it was raining hard
and there didn't seem to be anyone going outside, so the door was locked.
Then the only way to get out of the restaurant was by using the front entrance.
Yes. But in that case I think someone would remember.
And there are no other exits?
You can more or less get out through the window in the toilet,
but there's no pavement outside the window, and there's a big puddle,
so if you were to pass through there, footprints would've been left behind.
Also, it seems that the wind was
blowing at the time of the incident.
Since the umbrella that the deceased, Hatsune-san, was carrying had flown all the way to the end of the parking lot.
Wind?
Come to think of it, when we came to this restaurant, the wind was blowing rather hard.
So do you detectives have any clue?
I'm not sure.
When I told him that she was secretly meeting a man he was quite disturbed,
but recently he seemed more bothered by the fact that she's secretly been calling someone.
Well, she was probably talking with this guy anyway.
Oh, no... I contacted her by e-mail.
The only time I've met her in public was the one time you saw me with her.
But there was one thing that seemed to upset her.
Upset her?
Yes.
I'm a detective, so I thoroughly investigated Bamba-san.
And then, I learnt something.
Something?
He was saved from the same hotel fire as Hatsune-san,
and both of them, their identities unknown, grew up in the same church.
...which means that as we expected...
We can't help but think that you burnt her to death.
Why, you...
In that case, you're...
...not the killer!
And if my deduction's right...
An unwelcome sad truth will be exposed.
On the next Conan: Wedding Eve (Part II)
Next Conan's Hint: Cake!
There are three detectives,
san
so is it detective-san...?
I don't like old men...
That was terrible.