[ウェディングイブ（後編）][Wedding Eve (Part II)]
Ran and I were dragged along by old man Kogorō to celebrate the wedding eve of an old friend of his.
Amidst the festive atmosphere, the bride, Hatsune Kamon-san,
Hatsune Kamon (37)
Bride
headed to the nail salon in order to prepare for the wedding.
However, two hours later,
Hatsune-san, leaving behind the word 'goodbye',
together with an explosion from a car in the parking lot,
was found to have burnt to death.
Raita Bamba (37)
Groom
It was first thought to be suicide,
but found on a stick-on nail of Hatsune-san's that had fallen at the scene of the crime,
was DNA that roughly matched that
of the groom, Raita Bamba-san.
However, Bamba-san denied the offence
and accused a waiter, who had secretly met with Hatsune-san of being suspicious,
but it seems he was a detective Hatsune-san hired
Tōru Amuro (29)
Detective
to investigate Bamba-san's behaviour.
His testimony was supported by the detective Bamba-san hired,
Sanji Haruoka (48)
Detective
so Bamba-san ended up agreeing for
another DNA test to be conducted.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
The couple's past tells everything.
What can prove his innocence?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Inspector Megure.
There's a door in the back of the restaurant that leads to the parking lot,
but at the time of the incident it was raining hard and there didn't seem to be anyone going outside, so the door was locked.
Then the only way to get out of the restaurant was by using the front entrance.
Yes. But in that case I think someone would remember.
And there are no other exits?
You can more or less get out through the window in the toilet,
but there's no pavement outside the window, and there's a big puddle,
so if you were to pass through there,
footprints would've been left behind.
Also, it seems that the wind was
blowing at the time of the incident.
Since the umbrella that the deceased, Hatsune-san, was carrying had flown all the way to the end of the parking lot.
Wind?
Come to think of it, when we came to this restaurant, the wind was blowing rather hard.
So do you detectives have any clue?
I'm not sure.
When I told him that she was secretly meeting a man he was quite disturbed,
but recently he seemed more bothered by the fact that she's secretly been calling someone.
Well, she was probably talking with this guy anyway.
Oh, no... I contacted her by e-mail.
The only time I've met her in public was the one time you saw me with her.
But there was one thing that seemed to upset her.
Upset her?
Yes.
I'm a detective, so I thoroughly investigated Bamba-san.
And then, I learnt something.
Something?
He was saved from the same hotel fire as Hatsune-san,
and both of them, their identities unknown,
grew up in the same church.
Then, in that fire, each of their parents were...?
Yes.
It was a rather big fire, and there were many fatalities.
They were both infants.
Which means that they were childhood friends?
No.
While he was taken by foster parents right away,
she was raised in the church for quite a while.
But why was she upset by that?
I can't say. She said she'd investigate it herself from there.
Say, Ran-neechan...
Wasn't Hatsune-san shorter than you?
Y-Yeah.
And she was wearing rather high heels,
so she was much shorter than me, at about 150 centimetres.
But why do you want to know?
The average height of a Japanese woman
is around 159 centimetres, right?
Inspector Megure!
Did the results of the DNA test come out?
Oh, no. That hasn't come out yet, but...
According to the coroner's report, there was
one stick-on nail short from the body.
Like I said, we found that by the car...
No. Including that one, there's two short.
Then the one left came off inside the car and burnt up?
Or maybe...
Conan-kun?!
The place we found the umbrella?
What're you going to do if I tell you?
Uncle Kogorō told me to go and ask.
Here, on the car in the corner...
...it was caught like this, but...
H-Hey, kid!
If the missing stick-on nail landed in the fallen umbrella and was blown away with it, then...
There it is!
And it got sheltered from the rain by the tyre and the body of the car, so it didn't get dirty.
Is that some skin and blood on the end of the nail?
You know, there's a stick-on nail under this car.
It probably belongs to the lady who died,
so pick it up carefully.
Examine the stuff on the end of the nail closely.
O-Okay.
This likely will clear up who took her life.
And if my deduction's right...
An unwelcome sad truth will be exposed.
Damn! What on earth is happening?!
Damn it all!
Ow, ow, ow...
Hey, will you calm down already, Bamba?
You know you're in a risky position right now, right?
Hatsune-san burnt to death inside a car in the parking lot of this restaurant,
and skin thought to belong to the culprit was on the stick-on nail that had fallen by the car.
And the DNA of that skin roughly matched the DNA of the hair that was on your hairbrush.
Which means it's inevitable you're seen as the culprit.
So, did you let anyone use that hairbrush?
Let someone use it?
Like when a friend came to stay at your house or something.
I can't say. I don't remember anything like that.
Hatsune and I have been living together for six months now.
It could've been used by some detective Hatsune brought over while I was out.
I... I am a detective she hired,
but I've never been to your house.
That fact that you're claiming to be a detective is also suspicious.
Now that Hatsune's dead, there's nobody around to prove it anymore.
If you're so sharp that you could throw the detective I hired off the trail,
then you could've replaced the hair on my hairbrush with someone else's
to put the blame on me.
Oh, no...
I would never do such a spy-like thing...
Well, it's not true.
Just now, the results to the DNA test have come out,
and the hair on Bamba-san's hairbrush has been concluded to be Bamba-san's hair.
A-Are you serious?!
Yes.
Which means that as we expected...
You mistook me, a detective she hired, for her lover,
developed your jealousy from that into the intent to kill,
waited for her and ambushed her in the parking lot
when she returned to this restaurant,
shoved her into the car, and burnt her to death. There's no other explanation.
W-Why, you...
Then you'll voluntarily accompany us to the station, won't you?
W-Wait a second, will you?!
Do something, Mouri!
E-Even if you ask...
Mouri...
Now, then.
A-All right, all right.
The patrol car is parked some distance away, so without an umbrella, you might get wet.
It started raining again?
Yes. It's raining quite heavily.
I don't really care if I get wet.
It's really raining hard.
Is it really all right, Bamba?
I'm asking if it's all right for you to leave this restaurant.
Even if you say so, I can't do anything about it, right?
I've got no choice but to go to the station and convince them I'm innocent there.
Is that so?
In that case, you're...
...not the killer.
D-Dad?
Look, Mouri-kun,
even though he's going voluntarily for questioning,
isn't it going a bit far to say that he didn't do it from that?
Maybe he's taking the situation lightly,
and thinking that even when under investigation,
if he doesn't confess, he won't be caught.
T-That's not...
Then, think back to the time that Hatsune-san's car was set on fire.
The door leading to the parking lot was locked because it was raining,
and to go in and out through the toilet window
would be impossible without leaving footprints
around the big puddle beneath the window.
Which means the only option would be leaving the restaurant by the front door.
But if he, the host of this wedding party, left the restaurant...
Someone should remember seeing him, right?
It wasn't that nobody saw him, just that he wasn't noticed.
That is what I would deduce.
What do you mean?!
He disguised himself in the toilet.
Ahead of time, he hid the necessary clothes in the toilet.
For example, if he were to wear a knit cap and a tall windbreaker,
nobody would be able to identify him.
He introduced himself to everyone at the start of the party
so they would remember how he looked before disguising himself.
T-Then how do you explain the call I made to Hatsune,
just before her car went up in flames?!
She cried out 'goodbye' over the phone!
Was it really just before it went up in flames?
What?!
Didn't you really disguise yourself, then in order to ambush her in the parking lot,
call her just as she was exiting her car?
Using the opportunity made by her being distracted by the call to knock her unconscious...
And though she resisted slightly,
you somehow managed to stuff her into the car,
then after setting fire to the car, hurried back to the restaurant.
You changed back into your original clothes in the toilet,
then intentionally punched at me, a waiter, to injure yourself
and disguise the scratches she gave you.
Afterwards, you pretended to calmly call her,
making the customers nearby believe that she was saying something like a farewell,
then looked through the window,
so that the customers would notice the car on fire,
and you would become the tragic man who had
the woman he loves commit suicide in front of his eyes.
That the spray cans in the car exploded at the same moment was just luck.
T-That's nonsense!
She really did say 'goodbye' to me!
Check Hatsune's phone out! It should've been in the car!
There was a burnt phone there,
but even if the data could be recovered, there wouldn't be records of what sort of conversation you had...
But if that deduction is right, shouldn't his disguise have been found in the toilet?
It was cut up and flushed into the toi change to rest room}let.
A knit cap would go down easily, and if he used a thin nylon windbreaker,
it could be cut into small pieces.
What about the shoes?
You can't cut up shoes that easily.
He wouldn't have had to change his shoes.
Since if he kept walking, it wouldn't be possible to distinguish what shoes he was wearing.
The shoes he's wearing are sneakers that could be sold anywhere.
Then Bamba, take them off and look.
Look at the underside of your sneakers.
There you will find the proof that you aren't the killer.
There's something like cream in the tread on the bottom of the shoe.
What?
Ah, I think that's the chocolate cake.
Bamba-san stepped on a cake that fell off the table.
When did he step on that?
Before Hatsune-san left to go to the nail salon.
Ah, so that's it!
At the time of her death, it was raining heavily. So if he'd walked out in that,
then this cream should've been mostly washed off.
Especially if he hurried back here after murdering her!
Interesting.
In other words, he didn't leave the restaurant.
Yes...
The truth is, the first time I laid eyes on it,
I thought it was somehow faked by Bamba.
That somehow he changed his shoes,
and was showing me the cream beneath his shoes
to prove he hadn't left the restaurant.
But that cake was dropped by the young detective there, and was only stepped on by chance.
Bamba didn't say a word to me about
having cream stuck to his shoes.
And if he were to leave the restaurant now,
this precious evidence would be gone.
That's why I'm sure.
That that cream wasn't faked,
but is evidence that proves Bamba's innocence.
M-Mouri...
B-But the DNA...
There was DNA which roughly matched his
on the front of her stick-on nails, wasn't there?
Doesn't that prove he was with her?
Haven't you considered that the skin on her nails was her own?
What are you saying?
I just explained, it's impossible for two people who aren't blood relatives to have a rough match in genetic material.
In the current day, the probability of having the same DNA as someone else is 1 in 4.7 trillion!
To begin with, since women don't have the Y-chromosome that men have,
it would be found out right away.
The skin in question was contaminated by rain, dirt, or similar,
so couldn't it be possible that the reason it was a rough match was because the part identifying the gender couldn't be distinguished?
E-Even so, are you saying that such a couple just happened to meet,
just happened to fall in love, and tried to get married?!
Perhaps it was a coincidence that they met,
but I imagine it was inevitable for them to become attached to each other.
Since they were twins.
Twins?
Bamba, you two mentioned before...
That both of your birthdays and blood types are the same,
and that there are times when even if you're silent you can tell what the other is thinking.
Y-Yeah...
But deciding that we're twins from just that...
You may not have known, but when Hatsune-san and you were infants,
you both were saved from the same hotel fire, and your identities unknown, were raised in a church.
H-Hotel fire?!
I see. Both of their parents burned to death in that fire,
so they didn't know they were twins.
But if they're twins, wouldn't their DNA be the same?
That seems to be the case with identical twins,
but in that case, they should've both been either male or female twins...
It can rarely happen,
that if before splitting into two, the chromosomes of the fertilized egg are XY, male, then when polyembryony occurs,
for some reason, one side can lack the Y chromosome,
becoming XY and XO.
In other words, there is a chance
of identical twins being born of an opposite sex.
H-Hey, hey... You're joking, right? That Hatsune and I are twins...
Do you know how tall she was?
She said she was just under 150 centimetres.
She didn't like being short...
In that case, that is very possible...
The female out of identical twins of the opposite sex
is likely to turn out short due to Turner Syndrome.
B-But still...
What was Hatsune's skin doing on her own stick-on nails?
Do you not get it, Bamba?
If she was informed by this young detective
that you and herself were saved from the same fire
and said she'd investigate the rest on her own,
then you can't help but think that her investigation would be
a DNA test to clarify whether or not you two were twins.
Most likely, just as she was leaving her car after returning from the nail salon, she was called by the tester she commissioned
and told the results.
That you and Hatsune-san could not get married...
Since you two were twins related by blood.
That... That can't be...
That can't be...
The reason why her skin was on the stick-on nail
was probably that she was so shocked by the results,
that she scratched her own face hard enough that the stick-on nails came off while sobbing.
Another stick-on nail which fell off at that time
went into the umbrella she dropped and was blown away.
It's being examined right now,
so it should become clear when the results come out...
Yes, Megure speaking.
Is that so?
I understand.
D-Did the examination results of the other stick-on nail come out?
Yeah. On that nail,
as well as the blood that was on it, had mostly uncontaminated DNA
that exactly matched with that of Bamba-san's.
Except for the part that indicates the sex.
It also matched with the DNA that was managed to be retrieved from her corpse,
so the skin that was on the stick-on nail was concluded to be hers.
Then she really did commit suicide...
It can't be thought of in any other way,
but the tester really did call at the worst possible moment.
They probably heard that they were getting married tomorrow
and wanted to let her know before she did something she couldn't take back.
Hatsune...
Hatsune!
Bamba-san's scream echoed, piercing through the falling rain.
Nobody knows for sure why she chose to commit suicide by burning herself to death, but...
perhaps she wished to go back to start over again.
Back into those flames that led them to such a fate...
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Poirot
What? You want to be an apprentice?
To me, the great detective Kogorō Mouri?
Yes, of course!
I strongly realised my own inexperience when observing your great deduction the other day.
I want to start over again from the beginning.
That's why I want to work by your side
and accompany you in your cases...
But you see, I'm not the type to take apprentices...
I did intend to pay you...
...yen for case as a tuition fee.
S-Seriously?!
You're hired!
From now on, call me 'sensei', Amuro-kun!
Yes, Mouri-sensei!
Another annoying guy...
How about it, kids? You wanna go on an adventure?!
Yeah!
That's it, right?
We're gonna find you the treasure!
Yeah.
Ai-chan's gone!
We're coming now!
Stay here, Ayumi!
On the next Conan:
'The Dark Tower's Hidden Treasure (Part I)'
Next Conan's Hint: Mirror!
Look forward to the next episode!
'The Dark Tower' sounds thrilling!
Like it's out of some old mystery?
That's what your deductions are.