Say, have you heard of urban legends?
Yes... They're rumours that spread bit by bit through cities,
which may or may not be true, right?
Oh, I know!
Things like Kuchisake on'na and Jinmenken, right?
Slit-Mouthed Woman
Human Faced Dog
Yeah. And one of them is...
The Dark Tower.
A mysterious tower without doors or windows.
Yeah, it's supposed to be in the Kyōdō Garden!
And it's all black!
You're too loud.
Isn't Kyōdō supposed to be...
Ah, that reminds me, that lady said her name was Nanami Kyōdō.
Nanami Kyōdō (21)
Eldest daughter of the Kyōdō family
Yeah.
She's Ran-neechan's senior in the Karate club.
Kyōdō's a company that makes things like these.
Toy sellers?
A stationery shop?
No, no...
They manufacture optical goods like lenses and mirrors.
Look.
Don't play around with those.
Ah, sorry.
It's fine, it's fine!
I thought Conan-kun and his friends would enjoy them, so I brought them along as a gift.
Thanks, miss!
Ah, it's so pretty!
Wow, it's great!
Let me take a look too!
It's really amazing!
It keeps changing!
Come on, give it back.
Sempai...
What you mentioned last time sounds like trouble...
'There's treasure gleaming at the Kyōdō household.'
That's what you're thinking, right?
No... Well, sorta...
Even Momoe-san only came along lured in by the scent of treasure...
That's my current mum's name.
Though I think she'll break up with Dad before long...
'Living in a rich family is hard.' Isn't that what you're thinking?
Well, unfortunately we're not even rich anymore.
If only you could find that treasure...
Momoe-san's sure it exists.
You mean the treasure?
W-Where is it then?
Did this Kyōdō lady come to talk about where a treasure's hidden?
That's not it. She just wanted a shoulder to cry on.
Ah...
Sorry!
Well, it's true, so don't worry.
But I wonder...
Do you wanna go on a treasure hunt?!
We'll do it!
Wait, sempai! Don't get them excited for nothing...
I've nothing to lose.
If against all odds they do end up finding it, then Dad'll break up with Momoe-san, giving her the treasure as a divorce settlement.
In other words, it's to help my parents.
C-Come on...
So how about it? Wanna go on an adventure?!
Yeah!
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
On the edge of the city stands the Dark Tower...
With no doors or windows, what is its secret?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
It's almost like a public park.
This whole place is a garden?
That's the Kyōdō family for you.
It's that, right?
Yeah, it's the Dark Tower.
There's no doors or windows.
Sometimes laughter drifts down from the top floor of the tower.
It's been 40 years now since my
grandfather, Seitarō Kyōdō, built it.
He was obsessed with technology, and he filled the mansion with his tricks.
Seitarō Kyōdō
Previous head of the Kyōdō family
The Dark Tower was one of his creations...
But Dad plans to sell off the land, including the tower.
He'll sell the entire garden?
Yeah.
But if he does, there'll be no more treasure hunting, see?
So that's why your mum's impatient.
You can't!
How can you go selling treasure right in front of you?!
This is no time for selfishness!
It's the final chance to restore the Kyōdō name.
I can't keep going along with your dreams!
Momoe Kyōdō (38)
Nozomu's wife
It's not a dream... Tsutomu-san, you remember it, right?
That was just before Grandpa died.
Tsutomu Kyōdō (25)
Eldest son of the Kyōdō family
Nozomu Kyōdō (48)
Current head of the Kyōdō family
Don't ask me to remember something from so long ago.
But you heard about it, right?! You've heard of the treasure!
Well, I have certainly heard about it.
See? Even Tsutomu-san says it's there!
They're always like this.
Sorry you all had to see this.
Well, adults have their own worries.
It's the same in my family.
My mum's always snapping at my dad.
Somehow I'm relieved.
So let's go look at the tower first.
Yeah!
It's quite tall.
What's the top floor like?
There are no windows, so it must be pitch-dark inside.
Why did your grandfather build it, I wonder...
To hide the treasure!
That's what you'd think.
Then there must be an entrance!
Okay, let's look for it!
Yeah!
Didn't your father ever talk about the treasure?
Not at all.
Maybe it's because he was an adopted son-in-law.
I wonder if my dead mother knew about it?
There's also Nagase-san. He might know.
What's he like?
He was a technician too, and Grandpa's apprentice.
He's a live-in employee staying at a cottage here...
Kensaku Nagase (75)
Assistant of the previous head
I don't know about it.
Even a hint would be fine...
Can't you remember anything?
No matter how many times you ask, I don't know about the treasure.
If that's all you wanted to ask, then I'll excuse myself.
Nagase-san!
I'm sure he knows something.
He may not be too sociable, but he doesn't lie.
You should just give up on it.
Well, if there's no treasure, then I won't get a big divorce settlement, will I?
Then you don't mind if I take the divorce into the courts?
Momoe, you don't have to go that far...
Well then, I should be going too...
Tsutomu-san...
Everyone... thinks I'm dumb...
When I heard all about the treasure in the city...
Calm down. You can't just believe every rumour you hear.
And anyway...
Even if the tower doesn't have a door,
if there's a tunnel under here then you could go through the main building to get in, right?
That'd be an enormous construction job.
Grandpa may just've done it though.
For example...
See, there are lampposts here.
Right, now look at the tower through the arch.
M-My eyes...
S-Somehow I'm...
I-It's so weird!
A lens was put in the space of the arch.
Good job, boy! That's right.
When...?!
This is another trick Grandpa set up.
It wouldn't be odd for there to be a tunnel somewhere.
Why, Nanami-san, you look lively today.
Ah, Mum, this is my kōhai at high school, Ran Mouri-san.
This is my mum, Momoe-san.
Didn't I tell you to stop gossiping about boys?
Sorry my daughter troubled you.
Sorry for bringing so many people here.
You talked to my brother, right?
Did he remember anything useful?
He mentioned a blue button among other things...
But even he doesn't know what it means.
Who're these children?
We're the Detective Boys!
They came to help in the treasure hunt.
Good news for you, right, Mum?
Right. I'm counting on you.
Bye.
Children like that aren't going to help a bit.
She doesn't trust us.
Yeah...
She has strong perfume.
And she had really long false nails.
How far does this passage go?
It turns right just there, and leads to a free-standing warehouse.
Miso, shōyu, sake... Now it's just used for storage though.
Nagase... What's he doing in the warehouse?
That so? Treasure hunting sounds hard.
So, did you discover anything so far?
Yes, if there's treasure anywhere, it's gotta be in that tower!
A tower without doors or windows is just too suspicious.
Right. But if you can't get in, there's not much you can do.
How about when it was built?
It couldn't have been built without a way in or out, right?
Well, that's true, but...
If we search I'm sure we'll find a way in!
That's what these kids have decided.
So tell them the story, brother.
Okay.
When I was about seven, I had a cold and a temperature of almost 40°C.
My mother and grandfather came to see me.
They were talking beside my bed.
Taeko, you're the only one I want to leave my treasure to.
Before I realised, they'd both left.
I got lonely, and went to look for them...
I must've collapsed when I was searching,
as when I came to, my mother was holding me.
Tsutomu-chan... Did you try to follow us?
Did you catch the scent of treasure, huh?
Is that all?
All that you remember, I mean.
No, I just remembered something else recently.
Grandpa pointed at three buttons in different colours and said,
'If you push that button, that's the treasure.'
What colour was the button?
The one Grandpa pointed at was blue.
Thunder?
Hold on! I just remembered something else.
While chasing my mother, I vanished.
Right... There's no way to say it except that I vanished.
What do you mean?
I mean...
In other words...
No, I can't remember anymore.
But that was definitely at the entrance to the treasure.
There's more!
While I was crying and walking about, I got larger,
I got smaller, and then I multiplied!
Stop!
That's just because you were delirious from your fever!
Anyway, the treasure exists.
We just have to split up and look for it!
Will you help us too, brother?
Unfortunately, I'm not too interested.
Preparing blues is my favourite pastime.
That's how he is.
Under my brother, the Kyōdō business'll be ruined too.
It won't be!
Because we're gonna find the treasure!
Yeah.
I'm looking forward to it, miniature Detectives!
The tower's a lot closer.
I can't see the tower.
That... can't be!
How? I can see the tower from this window.
I get it... This isn't ordinary glass.
A 3D image's been put in it!
Begin investigation!
The weather outside's different in each window!
In this window it's sunny.
This one's cloudy.
Which one's the real weather?
It's the real one!
That was Mum's voice!
Mum! Mum!
Your brother's there!
Stay away, children!
Momoe! Momoe!
Call an ambulance, quick!
I've already called one!
What happened?
It almost looks like she fell from the top of the tower.
But this tower...
It doesn't have any entrance.
There's no way to climb it.
It was our time to shine.
He said 'Stay away, children!'
Even though we were involved.
Is it an accident, or is there a case?!
Oh, Mouri-kun. I guess the news spreads quickly.
No, actually...
I was wondering what to do about dinner, and heard about it when I called Ran.
She fell from the tower, even though there's no way in?
No, that's not the only possibility.
The corpse could've just been placed on the grass.
We heard her screaming.
Couldn't it have been recorded?
What? Recorded?
It's a simple trick.
The killer bashed her in the head somewhere else and carried her corpse here,
to make everyone think she fell from that tower.
But there's no way to get inside that Dark Tower.
Right! Therefore, the killer is somebody who didn't know that there are no entrances to that tower!
This is Mystery 101.
Everybody in the Kyōdō family knows there are no entrances to that tower.
Then we should suspect those who first came here today.
For example.
For example...
Me?
That's ridiculous!
But like Takagi-kun said,
an urban legend says that there's
a treasure inside, but no door to enter.
That's it!
The killer brought the corpse here and made it look like she fell from the tower.
This way, the police would inspect the tower
thoroughly and finally find the treasure.
I see. That's why the corpse was moved.
Then who's the killer?
In other words, every member of the Kyōdō family is a suspect.
Meaning we made no progress whatsoever.
Inspector...
There were some issues with the
company, as well as within the family...
And any one of them could have committed the murder.
Except this young lady.
But the father and the son denied the existence of the treasure.
Mouri-kun's deduction makes no sense...
No, wait... There was one person
who was sure about that treasure.
Exactly! So that person has to be the killer!
Unfortunately, said person was the victim.
Hey, Conan-kun, what do you think?
Was her death an accident?
It must've been murder!
Unfortunately, we can't be sure yet.
We met up with her in the garden.
So the killer wouldn't have had
enough time to move the body.
I can't argue with that.
It makes more sense to think that she fell from that tower.
So did the victim discover the entrance right after she left us?
How about this?
She was invited by the killer,
who knew how that tower worked.
Then the killer pushed her down.
The killer could still be in the tower.
But we have to find the entrance.
Exactly.
Even if we find the entrance, it's okay if we don't get in.
She was walking around near these garden lights.
So the entrance has to be around here somewhere.
Do you have any clue?
Old man Seitarō was a scientist.
I think he hid it with a mechanism like the glass windows and lenses we saw earlier.
Huh?
What is it?
That's strange.
I'm disappearing... No, I'm not.
This mark...
Is this the door?
We found the secret entrance!
All right...
It doesn't look like you can. It's too rusty.
If she really did go inside, there has to be a clear entrance.
Right.
Indeed.
Let's look somewhere else.
'I got larger, I got smaller.'
'And then I multiplied...'
'Disappeared, disappeared...'
Whoa, it's so pretty!
A-Amazing!
The entire floor's a planetarium!
We don't know what might happen, so stick together.
Hey, Ayumi!
Being alone's dangerous!
But...
Let's go together.
Okay.
Haibara too?
These are the toilets.
Oh, I see...
I'll be right out, so go ahead of me.
Okay.
'My appearance vanished...'
As if that could be true...
Wind?
Could it be...?
Ai-chan, aren't you done yet?
Ai-chan's gone!
What?!
Hey, Haibara!
Haibara-san!
Ai-chan!
Some wind's blowing through the gap...
Damn it, there has to be another entrance!
The next room's the winecellar.
Okay, let's have a look there!
Whoa, it stinks of alcohol!
I'm used to it, thanks to my dad.
There's a mirror!
What's it doing here?
It was put here to hide something.
It's put in tight.
She probably passed through here to get to the tower.
I vanished... There's no way to say it except that I vanished.
How did he vanish?
There's a mirror here, too...
This smell...
If you breathe too much of it, you'll get drunk.
It's not the alcohol smell, but the lady's perfume.
I can smell it around here.
What is it?!
We vanished.
Though we can still see the ceiling, we disappeared from the mirror?
The mirror was replaced by a screen!
That's projecting the picture.
Elastic tape?
We can get in!
It's the door leading to the treasure! Let's go!
But we'll be in trouble if the killer's in there!
H-Hey!
What do we do?
What do we do, Conan-kun?
Haibara?!
Ai-chan!
If even she's screaming like that...
I'm coming!
You stay here, Ayumi!
No! I want to help her too!
You can't!
Okay, let's go.
But make sure you don't let go of my hand.
Right.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
Edogawa
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
The brats disappeared?
Let's try to find them again.
If we ask Nagase-san, he might tell us about places even I don't know.
N-Nagase-san's...
Nagase-san's vanished!
This place is...?
Conan-kun...
On the next Conan: 'The Dark Tower's Hidden Treasure (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Circles and Triangles!
o-takara
Anyway, let's go find the treasure!
I don't wanna.
Eh? Why?
ottakara
Because somebody strange was here.