Invited by Nanami Kyōdō-san, Ran's senior in her karate club,
we, the Detective Boys, came to search for the Kyōdō family treasure.
The Kyōdō family mansion was built by the previous Kyōdō head, Seitarō Kyōdō,
Nanami Kyōdō (21)
Eldest daughter of the Kyōdō family
who meticulously included lots of tricks while building it.
Seitarō Kyōdō
Previous head of the Kyōdō family
One of them being the "Dark Tower".
A puzzling tower without any entrance or windows.
While Nanami-san guided us around the house,
we suddenly heard a woman screaming.
That was Mum's voice!
Mum! Mum!
Stay away, children!
Momoe! Momoe!
What happened?
It almost looks like she fell from the top of the tower.
But this tower...
It doesn't have any entrance.
There's no way to climb it.
We deduced that the killer could still be hiding in the tower,
so we started investigating to find the tower entrance,
but Haibara suddenly disappeared in the middle of the investigation.
Ai-chan's gone!
What?!
Hey, Haibara!
Haibara-san!
Ai-chan!
Some wind's blowing through the gap...
Damn it, there has to be another entrance!
The next room's the wine cellar.
Whoa, it stinks of alcohol!
I'm used to it, thanks to my dad.
There's a mirror!
Why'd someone lean a mirror against a barrel?
No, it just looks like it's leaning against it.
I vanished... There's no way to say it except that I vanished.
This smell...
If you breathe too much of it, you'll get drunk.
It's not the alcohol smell, but the lady's perfume.
I can smell it around here.
What is it?!
We vanished.
Though we can still see the ceiling,
we disappeared from the mirror?
The mirror was replaced by a screen!
Elastic tape?
We can get in!
It's the door leading to the treasure! Let's go!
But we'll be in trouble if the killer's in there!
H-Hey!
What do we do?
What do we do, Conan-kun?
Haibara?!
Ai-chan!
If even she's screaming like that...
I'm coming!
You stay here, Ayumi!
No! I want to help her too!
You can't!
Okay, let's go. But make sure you don't let go of my hand.
Right.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
While searching for treasure in a miraculous world,
the light of truth shines in a creepy tower!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the brain of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
It seems you were the first person to
discover the corpse, Tsutomu Kyōdō-san.
Tsutomu Kyōdō (25)
Eldest son of the Kyōdō family
Yes, it seems so.
What were you doing there?
Watercress.
I went to get some watercress for the meal I was cooking.
We cultivate some in the water of the stream below the tower.
I-I see.
The blue of the watercress stirs up my appetite.
How strange...
Did you find the Detective Boys?
Ah, Sempai!
I just tried calling Conan-kun, but...
Nobody's been seen leaving through the gate.
Don't tell me they went off looking for treasure on their own.
Dad!
Kensaku Nagase (75)
Assistant of the previous head
What's that sound?
A flood!
Don't worry. It's not real.
Close your eyes!
It's hot! It's hot!!
It's just an illusion! Just a hot wind blowing.
Pull yourself together, Ayumi!
Y-Yeah, I'll pull myself together.
Where were you when you heard your wife scream?
Near the rose garden.
I followed her to try and convince her one more time.
Nozomu Kyōdō
Current head of the Kyōdō family
How did you know where the scream came from straight away?
The corridor and the cellar would've both been closer, but you rushed straight to the tower.
That was probably because the scream sounded like it was coming from quite high up.
That tower was the only tall building in that direction.
That's why I thought Mome fell from the tower.
From a tower without any entrance?
It was so sudden, I didn't even consider that.
Say what?!
The brats disappeared?
Yeah.
We looked all over the mansion, but we couldn't find them.
They didn't go home early?
No, I called their home numbers, but they're not back yet.
Geez, what am I gonna do with those brats?
Let's try to find them again.
If we ask Nagase-san, he might know about some places that I don't.
You come too, dad.
I-It's an emergency!
N-Nagase-san's...
Nagase-san's vanished!
We've walked quite far, haven't we.
Yeah. Where do you think we are now?
Anyway, we won't stop until we find the treasure.
Yeah, you're right.
But...
Is that me?
Since when were you on a diet, Genta-kun?
Don't make fun of me!
Stop messing with me!
It's a door.
C-Could it be...?
...the door to the treasure?
Over there!
Damn! Even the doors are making fun of me.
I'll catch it!
Damn it!
I won't let you get away!
After it!
Huh?
It disappeared.
Did it get away...
Oh, there it is!
How does it open?
Be careful.
Ah, yeah...
Genta! Mitsuhiko!
Are you two all right?
Yeah, somehow.
W-What are you doing?
I'm looking for a switch.
Here it is!
I-It started to open!
All right!
Somebody's coming!
It's the killer!
Hurry, Conan!
Damn, is it broken? The door's closing again.
Mitsuhiko! You're slim enough to get through!
But if I let go now...
That's it! Just wait a sec!
A support!
Hurry! The killer's coming!
All right, let's make a run for it!
Right!
A child's room?
It can't be real...
But this doll's so cute.
Ah, it's stuck on.
This too.
And this too.
The books on the shelves are just drawn on.
But the sofa's real.
What's this room even for?
Don't be tricked! It's an illusion!
All that's turning are the walls!
You're in the way. Move.
And then I multiplied.
Was this what Tsutomu-san remembered?
Genta!
The killer...?!
A-A mirror?
Don't startle me like that.
Damn, where are they?!
Mitsuhiko!
This way?
I'm sure I just saw a shadow...
Is someone there?
Nobody's here, right?
Ouch...
Okay, now...
Ayumi?!
Where are you? Where are you all?!
I need to stay calm.
Panicking won't help me find them.
I should be thinking instead.
Just why were these tunnels built?
And then I should reassess my deductions...
Amongst the three of them, who
could have committed the murder?
From the scent of her perfume being left behind,
I can deduce that the victim entered the tower.
But whether it was Tsutomu-san who was just below
the tower, Nozomu Kyōdō-san who was in the garden,
or even Nagase-san who rushed over from the main building,
no one would've had enough time to push her from the roof and then come back.
These tools...
Wait...
Have I completely misthought this?
This tower was built 40 years ago...
And the underground passages...
They should be broken or have rusted by now...
Which means...!
So that's it!
What is this place?!
It was a dim place with a high ceiling.
I get it, this must be the treasure room.
Judging from the height, this must be the Dark Tower.
But it's supposed to be round,
while this is pyramid-shaped.
A mirror?
That means...
Could this place be a...
There still hasn't been any sign of Conan-kun or the other children anywhere in the house.
Of course, the same goes for Nagase-san.
Which means the only place left to look
is the Dark Tower.
Nagase knew that the previous head of the household hid the treasure in the tower.
I still can't believe that the treasure exists, I was sure it was just a dream...
That doesn't matter now!
Let's just hope the kids are safe...
There's not a second to lose.
I'd like your help looking for the tower entrance.
Conan-kun...
Going by what Tsutomu-san said, there
should be buttons around here somewhere.
There!
Are these the three-coloured buttons?
This is...?
It's the roof!
All right, now I can see them better.
That's..?!
One of Momoe-san's fake nails!
She must have put a lot of strength into pushing it...
So much that her nail ripped off.
Chief!
Yes, this is Megure.
Like I explained to you, we don't have any time to lose.
In order to thoroughly investigate the Dark Tower,
we should gather all the free officers and have them help investigate...
W-What?!
I don't think you need to gather them!
W-What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Just a sec!
The key to the main entrance is...
Red.
Hey, kid! Get back out here and explain yourself!
A-An earthquake?!
No, Mouri-kun!
The Dark Tower is rising!
So that's the entrance?
Welcome to the Dark Tower!
Hey, kid! Get down from there this instant!
Uncle, I've got something to show you.
Can you come up for a bit?
Like hell I'll go.
Maybe he found the treasure?
Maybe.
Did you say treasure? I'm coming already! I'm on my way!
Dad...
Wasn't he supposed to be scared of high places...?
Treasure, treasure!
Just wait for me, my dear treasure!
Where's the treasure?
Ah, look out!
All right.
I-I'm gonna fall!
He fell asleep all the way up here?!
He's got some talent.
Sorry for the fuss.
But I was just struck by the truth behind this case.
What?
The Kyōdō mistress's fall was not a murder, but an accident.
An accident?
Are you saying she slipped on the floor or something?
Of course, it's not that simple.
Finding the entrance to the tower, she came up here,
and discovered the three-coloured buttons.
Then she would've opened the door leading to the roof.
That way, she would get some light.
Conan, are you there?
I'm right here, uncle.
I've got it.
aoi
Then she pushed a button—the blue button.
Let me warn you that I haven't checked yet myself what will happen if this button is pushed.
But something was triggered and the victim fell from the roof due to it.
This is my deduction.
Conan, give it a try.
Yes.
The blue button, right?
What now? What's going to happen?
So cool!
So it's possible that the mistress who came here to find the treasure got scared and fell.
Holography... At the time, it must've been extremely advanced technology...
There was such a thing forty years ago?
The theory behind it was known even earlier,
but the use of lasers to produce
holograms was discovered in 1971.
Well, that's what they said on TV...
As unfortunate as it is, the Kyōdō mistress was so surprised by the holography
that she fell from the roof. I can only conclude that the case was just an unfortunate accident.
So Momoe was reckless to the very end.
Sorry to have caused you so much trouble.
But this is odd...
According to what my brother remembered, the treasure should have appeared when the blue button was pushed.
Uncle Kogorō told me that the
mistress pressed the wrong button.
The wrong button?
aoi
You pushed the blue button, right?
Didn't you call those green vegetables "blues" as well, mister?
Preparing blues is my favourite pastime.
You also called the watercress "blue", didn't you?
The blue of the watercress stirs up my appetite.
ao
That's wrong! When I said the blue button,
I meant the green button!
There are a lot of people who use 'ao' to say green.
But the victim took 'ao' literally, as "blue".
We can call this case a tragedy brought on by the ambiguity of Japanese.
But what would have happened if Mum pushed the green button?
That's exactly what Tsutomu-san's grandfather wanted to show him.
As I figured, you're all safe!
Yeah, we're fine!
Nagase-san saved us.
He helped me out of the broken lift.
He saved everyone a lot of trouble.
I apologise.
You were all scared because I was running behind with the repairs.
What's the meaning of all this, Nagase?!
Just why did you leave us all in the dark?!
Your late father said...
"If I tell Nozomu, he'll want to demolish it right away.
So I'm entrusting it to you, Nagase,
until the day Tsutomu walks my path."
But Tsutomu-san said he had no intention of inheriting the Kyōdō company.
He forgot the words he said as a child...
Everyone'll be so happy if we make the
amusement park in the tunnel a public attraction!
When I grow up, I'll show everybody a world of dreams too!
Since I wanted him to remember his words,
I went to the Dark Tower and renovated it.
You mean the last button, right...?
The green one...
Exactly.
The last treasure your grandfather concealed in the tower.
Can I push it?
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
Amazing!
A giant kaleidoscope!
So this is a kaleidoscope? It's huge!
Since it has oil running in it, millions, billions, trillions of different patterns can be made.
So this is the dream Grandpa built...
Pops!
W-What?
Do you want to destroy all this? It's the Kyōdō family's treasure!
Shut up!
You can't!
As the third Kyōdō head-to-be, I won't let you!
I promised Grandpa.
I'll make the name "Kyōdō" into a manafacturer of dreams.
If you think you can, then do it!
We received a simple-looking request via the Detective Agency's homepage.
But a man kept our client hostage and then committed suicide.
On the next Conan: The Detectives' Nocturne (The Case)!
Next Conan's Hint: A beat-up mobile phone!