A few days ago during the DNA case, we met a self-proclaimed detective, Tōru Amuro.
With plenty of evidence, he stated the killer was the old man's old friend, Raita Bamba-san.
Yet the old man proved him wrong, proving it was a suicide rather than a murder case.
He was so impressed with the old man's deduction
that he decided to learn how to be a detective from him while working part-time at Poirot, the coffee shop below the agency.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
We left the detective agency and came back.
In that momentary opening, the unbelievable happened!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
What you are seeing now is footage of the three-man bank robber group.
Furthermore, the three robbers are still eluding—
Geez... that's been all that's on the news since this morning.
It can't be helped.
It hasn't even been a week since the incident.
And one of the bank employees was shot and died.
If I remember right, while trying to be cool, he stood up to the robbers and got himself killed, right?
I don't think he stood up to them.
According to the customers that were at the bank during the incident...
...he seemed to be trying to calm them down by raising both hands in the air and saying: 'OK! Please stop already.'
Same thing, since instead he just made them mad and ended up getting shot.
But they won't get away with their crime.
Most of the 200 million yen that they stole were fresh banknotes that'd just been received from the head office,
so their serial numbers were all registered.
Yeah, they got a bunch of money they can't use.
So it's just a matter of time until the robbers get caught.
And what are you doing here?!
I brought sandwiches for your lunch, Mouri-sensei, as you're taking care of me.
It's my treat, of course.
Can we have some too?
Well, of course.
Thank you very much.
Not at all. It's the least I can do for Mouri-sensei.
He's quite the carefree guy...
And what kind of case will the client who's coming today be bringing?
How do you know about that?
Of course I know.
On days off, you're usually clenching a horse-racing newspaper in your hand and lazing about, Sensei.
But today you shaved your stubble and neatly tied your necktie:
the marks of someone who's waiting for a visit.
You're amazing, Amuro-san.
You don't look like you'd need to be Dad's apprentice.
That's not true, this is merely the result of Mouri-sensei's teachings.
You're doing great, Amuro-kun.
Thank you very much.
And to add another reason, Yōko Okino's live show is on-air right now.
Given that you're ignoring it and are still serious,
it must be a fairly important case, right?
Go! Go! Let's go! Let's go, Yōko!
Umm... What's...?
He delayed the meeting time with the client just so that he could watch this show live.
Go, Yōko!
The old man's pretty carefree too...
This time next week, a friendly football match—
Umm...
I was right about you waiting for a client, right?
Yeah.
But I don't know what kind of person is coming.
It's the first time I've had a client request via the Internet.
So you put your detective agency on the Internet?
As expected from Mouri-sensei!
You even have a website!
Kind of.
I figured I should try to get online and adapt to the globalised world.
Well, I'm the one who made the website.
So if I do this, then just enter the password...
You're amazing, Conan-kun!
The Doc showed me how to do it.
Well then, the live performance is over.
It's about time for the client to arrive.
An e-mail?
Let's see...
'This is Kei Kashitsuka, who arranged to see you today,'
'but given some circumstances, I'd like to move the meeting to the "Columbo" restaurant.'
'It should be quite close to you,'
'so I believe we can meet there at the arranged time.'
'I'm waiting to hear from you to know whether or not it's okay.'
Geez, what a pain.
Maybe I should say no.
You can't do that, Dad! This is a valuable customer!
Besides, Conan-kun and I haven't had lunch yet.
So we could just eat at Columbo.
Then what are we going to do about these sandwiches?
We can put them in the fridge for dinner.
Geez. Sandwiches for dinner?
Dad! Your cigarette ash's about to fall.
Hey Dad, be careful!
What if you start a fire?!
Though, since somebody doesn't want to work, our family finances are about to go down in flames.
That's funny.
Do you mind if I join you for the meeting with the client, Mouri-sensei?
My shift at Poirot ended at noon today.
Yeah, I don't really mind.
But if you want to join us, you have to pay the tuition fee.
Well, naturally.
Well then, Mouri-sensei.
You go on ahead.
I'll grab my jacket and meet you there.
So it's about a coin-operated locker key?
Yeah. His brother died a few days ago, and apparently that key came up among his belongings.
Since he doesn't know what locker the key is for,
he wanted me to find it.
He wants me to put it in his coffin and bury him with it if it happens to be something important.
But can you find it?
Keys typically have the name of the company that created them and serial numbers on them,
so if we just contact the company and ask them where they delivered the locker,
we'll get a general idea of where it is.
Sounds surprisingly easy.
I guess.
Is that all there is to the request?
Yeah! He said he'd give me ¥300,000 for it.
Rather sweet deal, huh?
I-Indeed.
If that's the case, don't call the client 'a pain'.
The client's not coming, is he?
Maybe there's another Columbo restaurant in the vicinity?
There isn't any.
You replied 'okay' to the e-mail asking to move the meeting here, right?
Yeah, right away.
And I also sent many e-mails saying 'I'm here waiting for you'.
But there's been no response.
I see.
The e-mail addresses the client used last night and today are different.
Maybe his phone's charging or something,
so he borrowed a friend's phone in a rush to send today's e-mail?
And maybe that friend turned off his phone.
Hey, the one I sent the 'OK' response to was today's address!
Then without knowing that you said 'OK', he might still be waiting, as originally agreed, back at the agency.
There's nobody here.
Indeed.
Just in case, I sent an e-mail to the first address saying 'I'll be right back'.
Then he'll probably reply soon, right?
Do you want some tea while you're waiting?
No, I'm good. I drank too much coffee at Columbo.
I need to use the toilet.
Ran-san, if you're making tea then I can help.
Thank you.
Then could you take some tea cups out?
With pleasure.
The client just replied.
He says: 'I just got to Columbo, please come.'
Then we should hurry up and go.
Then I'll come with you too, just wait a second.
I need to use the toilet first.
Another e-mail from the client.
He says: 'Hurry up and come all together.'
'All together'? Does he mean us?
Is there anyone else here?
Then let's go to Columbo all together again.
Come on, everyone, hurry up.
Come on! If we don't hurry up, the client will get tired of waiting and leave.
Geez. I'm not enough anymore?
Come on.
But he wants us to come all together, right?
Everybody, please keep quiet.
This is probably what's going on:
Somebody doesn't want the client to meet up with Mouri-sensei.
He drove him away using a fake e-mail moving the meeting,
and met up with the client at the empty agency acting as part of its staff.
As proof of that,
the keyhole has traces of having been picked open,
and there was a slightly wet tea cup in the cupboard in the kitchen.
Considering Ran-san's personality,
you wouldn't put a wet cup back in the cupboard as it is, right?
Right.
Not to mention, the cigarette ash that Uncle dropped before we left was completely wiped off.
That means someone wiped it while we were out, right?
So basically, this means someone invited the client in while Sensei was out,
wiped off the table, and welcomed him by serving tea.
And since he put the tea cup back on the cupboard without drying it properly,
it was still wet.
But why would someone do that?!
He just came here to ask you to find a coin-operated locker.
Maybe there's something really important in that locker?
Who knows?
Shall we...
...ask that person directly?
Ask the person directly?
Don't tell me...?!
The reply came just when you, Sensei, tried to go into the toilet, right?
And another one came when Conan-kun tried to go in too.
And there were some marks that look like something was dragged across the floor in front of the toilet.
That's right.
For some reason, that person dragged the client inside,
and is still hiding inside the toilet.
Don't tell me...?!
What?!
So, is this what happened?
Kei Kashitsuka-san, you came here to ask Mouri-kun to investigate a coin-operated locker's key,
but were met by a man claiming to be his assistant, and were knocked out with a stun gun.
When you regained consciousness, you were wrapped in duct tape and trapped in a toilet...
Yes...
To make sure I wouldn't run away, my boots were taken off, and even the laces were removed.
And then when Mouri-kun and the others came back,
this man panicked since they found he was confining you in the toilet,
inserted the gun into his own mouth and committed suicide by pulling the trigger, correct?
Yes...
But why on Earth would he want to trap you in a toilet?
He kept asking me the same question.
'What locker is this key for?
If you don't tell me, I'm gonna kill you!'
Inspector Megure.
According to the forensics, there was virtually no gunshot residue on Kashitsuka-san's body or clothing.
So he committed suicide.
And Kashitsuka-san's testimony is true.
Yes, probably.
All right! First, find the locker as well as what the man who committed suicide wanted.
Yes, sir!
Still, it doesn't add up.
Why would he bring Kashitsuka-san here?
He only wanted her to tell him what locker the key was for.
I know.
Despite threatening her with a gun and
interrogating her after forcing her to move,
he knocked her out with a stun gun and duct taped her, so it sounds like he was planning on shutting himself in here for a while.
To sum it up, it was suicide by gun.
Well, since I, Kogorō Mouri, came back earlier than he expected, he probably gave up knowing he couldn't get away.
But you weren't the one who realised that.
He looked very impatient.
He said that it'd be bad if he didn't find that locker quickly, or something like that.
But still, Kashitsuka-san.
Have you really never seen him before?
No. Never.
If his objective was the key in your brother's belongings,
then there's a good possibility that your brother knew him.
I never really met any of my brother's friends.
By the way, how did your brother pass away?
What did your brother die of?
What did your deceased brother die of?
Oh, yes... He died in an accident four days ago.
This is my brother.
You've made him your wallpaper.
This guy... Where'd I see him before...?
Speaking of mobile phones...
This mobile phone, belonging to the man who committed suicide, is strange.
Strange?
The e-mail he sent Mouri-kun while acting as Kashitsuka-san about wanting to move the meeting is in the sent history,
but there are no other e-mails whatsoever.
He sent the e-mails after that from my mobile.
But still, the fact that that's the only e-mail that was received or sent...
And the contact list is completely empty.
This doesn't look like that new a model.
Maybe he bought an old model for a cheap price?
It's in good condition.
Also, the change and wallet in his pocket with the mobile phone bother me.
Change and a wallet?
They were with the locker key that he stole from Kashitsuka-san,
along with the stun gun, cigarettes, and a lighter in his coat pocket,
but the change added up to around ¥5,000.
¥5,000?!
If he had that much, wouldn't they be heavy and rattle?
Right.
Furthermore, there were two ¥10,000 bills and five ¥5,000 bills in his wallet.
And there were forty-seven ¥1,000 bills.
Don't you find that strange?
Indeed...
Um... Excuse me.
If it's all right, could you show us the things that were in his pocket?
You wanna see them too, don't you, Uncle?
Oh... Yeah, that's right.
Well, I don't mind.
Sorry about this, Inspector.
Well, this is all of it.
He had this much stuff in his pockets...
Yeah...
The locker key's being examined by Takagi-kun right now, so it's not here.
Come to think of it, Kashitsuka-san.
Yes?
One of the two towels that fell by the body's feet in the toilet was damp on one side.
Do you know why?
I'm not sure. I was scared and had my head down the whole time.
Also, underneath those towels, there was a knot at the end of your boot laces
and they were caught on your boots.
Oh, that's a habit from when I was a child.
My brother always said when you wash fabric sneakers or the like, it's easier to hang them when the laces get like that.
Like you'd expect, I don't wash my boots, but the habit just stuck with me.
But... But... My brother isn't here anymore...
Inspector, would it be all right to leave it here for today?
It hasn't been that long since she lost her brother,
and a man she didn't know killed himself in front of her.
Then we'll be questioning you tomorrow,
so can you tell us your address and a way to contact you?
Oh, yes. I can write it on something, right?
If possible, if you have any kind of identification...
I've just finished university and am looking for a job, so I don't have a business card.
If I could go to my house, I could give you my insurance certificate.
Then please bring that tomorrow.
Understood.
Um... If you're going home, shall I drive you there?
I parked at a nearby parking lot.
There's a chance that an accomplice of his might ambush you near your home.
Sorry to trouble you.
Oh, please, there's no need to apologise.
By the way, what is he doing here?
Oh, actually, Amuro-kun's now my top apprentice.
Apprentice?!
Geez. So you have yet another detective around you.
'Another?'
Yeah. There's another one besides you.
A detective girl who's recently been showing up and wandering around crime scenes with Mouri-kun.
A detective girl, you say?
I'd love to meet her.
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
Kashitsuka-san, is this the right way to your home?
Yeah...
Come to think of it, this car's a different colour to Detective Satō's, right?
More importantly, why did you guys come along too?!
It's kind of cramped here.
S-Sorry.
This car isn't designed to have 3 passengers on the back seats.
Ah no, that's not your fault...
And why did you have to come along, Dad?!
Because I'm worried about Kei-san.
And I'm afraid to stay alone with Conan-kun in an office where someone just killed himself!
Then you could just go stay at Eri's house.
What's with you?!
You're coming along all carefree just because Kei-san's beautiful!
Don't be stupid!
Did that man really commit suicide?
But there was almost no gunshot residue in Kashitsuka-san's body, and she was with him.
Not to mention there was something strange about that guy's mobile phone.
Why were the contact list and send/receive history empty except for the e-mail sent to the old man?
And the coins in his pocket and the banknotes in his wallet...
Why did he need to carry so many with him?
Also, there is one more thing:
She's hiding something.
This smell...
Could it be...?
Anyway, did you like the fruit juice I recommended you?
Yeah, it's very tasty.
You're coming too, Sera-san?
Yeah.
On the next Conan: 'The Detectives' Nocturne (Abduction)'
Next Conan's Hint: Wiretap!
Gunfire in the toilet?!
And we were besieged before, too!
Is this detective agency cursed?!