We got an easy-looking request from the detective agency's new website.
But the client sent an e-mail requesting a change in the meeting venue,
so the old man went there along with me, Ran and his apprentice Amuro-san.
But the client never showed up.
Afterwards, we returned to the agency, at which time we got another e-mail from the client.
He tried to drive us out of the agency, but…
Everybody, please keep quiet.
This is probably what's going on:
Somebody doesn't want the client to meet up with Mouri-sensei.
He drove him away using a fake e-mail moving the meeting,
and met up with the client at the empty agency acting as part of its staff.
But why would someone do that?!
He just came here to ask you to find a coin-operated locker.
Maybe there's something really important in that locker?
Who knows?
Shall we…
…ask that person directly?
Ask the person directly?
Don't tell me…?!
The reply came just when you, Sensei, tried to go into the toilet, right?
And another one came when Conan-kun tried to go in too.
And there were some marks that look like something was dragged across the floor in front of the toilet.
That's right.
For some reason, that person dragged the client inside,
and is still hiding inside the toilet.
Don't tell me…?!
What?!
A woman called Kei Kashitsuka-san had been confined in the toilet.
She said she'd never met the man who committed suicide right beside her.
With him, the man had a mobile phone with no logs or data other than the e-mail he sent to the old man,
¥5,000 in coins, and a wallet full of banknotes.
Kashitsuka-san went through a brief questioning, after which she was allowed to go home.
Amuro offered to give her a ride home.
Kashitsuka-san, is this the right way to your home?
Yeah…
More importantly, why did you guys come along too?!
It's kind of cramped here.
S-Sorry.
This car isn't designed to have 3 passengers on the back seats.
Ah no, that's not your fault…
And why did you have to come along, Dad?!
Because I'm worried about Kei-san.
Did that man really commit suicide?
But there was almost no gunshot residue on Kashitsuka-san's body, and she was with him.
Not to mention there was something strange about that guy's mobile phone.
Why were the contact list and send/receive history empty except for the e-mail sent to the old man?
And the coins in his pocket and the banknotes in his wallet…
Why did he need to carry so many with him?
Also, there is one more thing:
She's hiding something.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
Something's odd at the client's deluxe flat, and something smells bad!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
This is a very nice block of flats.
The rent has to be pretty high.
Yeah, kind of.
But my brother and I've been living here thanks to our parents' money.
Well, you don't need to follow me anymore.
We've confirmed that nobody's trying to ambush me, after all.
T-That's right.
Then we'll be going now.
I forgot to go to toilet!
What do I do?! I'm about to burst!
Please let me use the toilet, miss! Please!
Please! I can't hold it anymore.
Okay. Just hold on a second.
This smell… Could it be…?
The toilet's the first door on the right past the entrance.
Okay, thanks!
Ummm, excuse me, I'm holding it in too.
Me too.
Then would you like to come in for a while?
Although I don't have anything other than tea to serve you…
My apologies, Kei-san.
You can't help it, so don't worry.
Necessity knows no law, right?
Dad!
What a mess…
Did you have a party or something last night?
Yes, I got together with several of my friends from university.
Sorry for the mess.
Nah, it's fine.
Let's see…
Oh, Kei-san, can I help you with anything?
Then please take care of the trash on the table.
Sure.
This afternoon at 4 PM…
In the Mouri Detective Agency's toilet in Beika City's fifth block, a shocking incident took place, where a man committed suicide.
No way! It's in the news already?
Looks like it.
Oh no! Mum must be worried, since I turned off my mobile phone.
Hello?
Why the hell did you turn off your mobile phone?!
I'm worried sick here!
Sera-san?
Sorry, sorry. There's a case, so it's a bit hectic here.
So are Con..-kun and Ko…rō-san all…ight?
Sorry, you're breaking up, it's hard to hear you.
Hello, Sera-san? Can you hear me?
Kei-san.
Yeah?
This room might be wiretapped.
But how do you know that?
It was Ran's phone call just now, right?
When there are wiretaps around, mobile phones get poor reception.
As expected from Mouri-sensei.
Kei-san, we'd like to search every room for wiretaps now.
You don't mind, right?
Ah, sorry.
Please wait 5 minutes. They're all messed up.
I'll tidy up my underwear and whatnot.
Where are you going?
Miss.
I'm out of tea leaves, so I'm going to buy some from a convenience store.
Then I'll come with you.
There's something I'd like to buy.
Should we call Ran-neechan too?
It's fine. Let's just go, the two of us.
It's already been 10 minutes, but Kei-san's not back yet…
I wonder if she went to the toilet?
Then let's start searching for wiretaps on our own.
Sorry for the bother, but…
Please stand in the middle of the room I'm searching through
while playing some sort of song from your mobile phone at full volume.
Using that song, we'll find the wiretaps and dispose of them.
So you have a driving licence, right, miss?
Yeah…
But driving licences can prove your identity, right?
Why didn't you show it to the inspector back then?
I didn't want to show it because I look ugly in the picture on the licence.
By the way, did you like it?
The fruit juice that I recommended and we bought from the vending machine on the way?
Yeah, it's yummy!
Amazing! It's the third one already!
There's one here, too.
Another one?
What's with this room?! It smells terrible!
What is that smell?
Apparently there's a wiretap in this room too.
By the way, I haven't seen Conan-kun and Kei-san for quite a while.
Let them be! Searching for the wiretaps is our first priority right now.
It looks like the wiretap's under the bed.
There's a huge suitcase under it.
Move aside a bit.
Okay.
Damn it! Why is it so heavy?!
The wiretap's in it, right?
The stench seems to be coming from there, too.
Anyway, let's open it up.
It looks like the wiretap's under the bed.
There's a huge suitcase under it.
Move aside a bit.
Okay.
Damn it! Why is it so heavy?!
The wiretap's in it, right?
The stench seems to be coming from there, too.
Anyway, let's open it up.
Why's there a body in the suitcase?!
And who's this guy?
He's a rather lean man.
He was beaten to death,
and I'm guessing it's been a little over a day since he died.
Like we thought, the wiretap was in here, but…
Anyway, let's tell Kei-san about this, since she owns the house.
But she might not even be here anymore.
Since her boots weren't there when I passed the front door a minute ago.
I wondered if they were on the shoe rack then,
but it's also plausible that she ran away because she was afraid that we'd find the body
while we checked the room searching for the wiretap.
Then you're saying Kei-san was the one who killed this guy?
I can't be sure about that yet,
but the fact that Conan-kun's shoes are also gone has me a little worried.
No way! Why?!
I can't say…
Perhaps he chased her when she escaped, or maybe she took him.
I'm going to try to call Conan-kun.
I just sent Kei-san an e-mail,
but if she ran away, I doubt she'll reply.
An… An e-mail!
From Kei-san?
Yeah.
'Seeing that I got an e-mail from you, I take it you found the body?
'Although I plan on giving the boy back when the day breaks,
if you try to report this to the police or get in my way of my escape,
then I can't guarantee his safety.'
Then Kei-san really did kill this guy?!
What if she was the one who actually killed the guy who supposedly committed suicide by shooting himself…
No way. That can't be…
But there was almost no gunshot residue on her.
Doesn't that mean that she didn't fire a gun?
We're only talking hypothetically here.
But we're really at a loss here.
To think that we found yet another body,
and the killer took Conan-kun, yet we can't make a move until the morning.
If only the brat would give us a hint of where they were…
That's right! Dr. Agasa might be able to figure it out.
Dr. Agasa?
Who might that be?
Oh, he knows Conan-kun.
Conan-kun always carries around a detective badge with a transmitter on it,
and Dr. Agasa made some glasses that can track it.
If there's something that convenient, then I'd definitely like to see it.
The number you are attempting to call is switched off or out of range so…
What? Conan-kun's been kidnapped?!
By a murderer?!
Yeah. That's why we want you track down Conan-kun's detective badge with the tracking glasses.
I… I got it.
I can track it with the spare glasses, but…
Oh, sorry. Got someone on the other line.
It might be Conan-kun.
If you figure out where he is, call us!
Hello? Conan-kun?
Why do ya keep hangin' up on me?!
Do ya hate me or something?!
S-Sera-san…
Sorry. There's a lot right now and we're all in panic.
Anyway, Conan-kun's in trouble!
Conan-kun?
But just how do you plan to track him down?
Isn't your Beetle in for repairs right now?
Y-Yeah… In this case, our only chance is to get a taxi to go after him…
Then will you go after him in my car?
I apologise.
I didn't mean to eavesdrop, but as I came to share some of my cream stew with you,
I heard you having a disturbing conversation at the door.
S-Subaru-kun…
Now, if you're going after him, then we must hurry.
B-But…
Then just give us the keys.
The Doctor and I'll go after him.
It's not that I mind or anything, but the car has some peculiarities, so I have to be the one driving it.
Then what if Subaru-kun and I go?
That would work.
That is, if this girl intends to stay here by herself and anxiously wait for a report on that boy's safety.
If it'd be all right, I advise for her to come with us.
But of course, I won't force you.
I see.
So a woman named Kei Kashitsuka was abducted by a guy who killed himself with a gun inside your detective agency's toilet,
and you took her back to her flat, but there, you found another man's body packed inside a suitcase.
By the time you realised it, she'd taken Conan-kun away,
and e-mailed you saying something like 'If you report this to the police, the boy dies,' right?
Yeah…
I don't know what's going on anymore.
Well, if what you told me about that guy's belongings
and the state of the crime scene is true,
then I think he knows everything.
'He?'
Anyway, I'm on my way over there now.
You're coming too?
Yeah.
I'd like to meet that detective you said was Kogorō-san's 'apprentice'.
The stench has mostly settled now that we opened the windows.
But what should we do…
Should we contact the police after all?
Maybe…
More importantly, this room is strange,
What do you mean, 'strange'?
There were only men's shoes in the shoe rack,
and the clothes in the laundry as well as in the closet are all men's clothes.
Then Kei-san's deceased brother was the only one living here?
Either way, you were able to investigate that much in this short amount of time?
I don't know about that yet,
but I can tell you that the occupant of this room paid quite a bit of attention
to an incident that took place a few days ago.
An incident?
Y-You're right.
News TV9
[i]
Network Today
Wide News
News Day
Evening Newspaper
Morning Day
Evening News
Satellite News
Wake-Up Flash
Best Morning Report
There's nothing but news and talk show recordings all in a row.
Moreover, the parts concerning the bank robbery case have been edited together.
This is an image of the 3-man robbery group as seen from the security cameras released this morning.
If I recall correctly, it was a 3-man group consisting of a short guy, a slender guy, and an athletic guy.
That's right. The athletic guy was shown firing a gun.
Although the person being shot at was out of frame and wasn't shown.
Additionally, the bank employee was shot to death after trying to calm the robbers down…
Ken'ya Shōno-san's wake was held yesterday evening.
The line of condolence callers who were touched by Shōno-san's brave actions continued after midnight.
Ken'ya Shōno-san
T-This guy!
He's Kei-san's brother! The one who was on her mobile phone's wallpaper!
But, why does he have a different surname?
And isn't it strange?
If the one living here was Kei-san's brother,
then there's no way she could've edited this morning's news!
Well, whoever was living here, seeing that they were taking the trouble to archive these news and talk shows,
isn't it natural to think that it'd be either a considerable crime enthusiast,
the victim's family planning to take revenge on the killer, or perhaps the robber himself?
I-Indeed.
Anyway, let's look around the room a little more.
Although, the only thing left is the PC in the bedroom.
Um…
Why are you my dad's apprentice when you're such a good detective?
You're obviously the better…
Mouri-sensei may pretend to be having trouble,
but he's actually already figured out the truth behind everything for the most part,
and is just testing me.
It was the same in the DNA case before.
And in the gun suicide earlier today,
my brash deduction led to a tragic result.
Sensei would've dealt with it a lot better.
I've still got a long way to go.
Sorry about this, Subaru-kun.
Don't mention it. So where are we off to first?
Wait a second…
First off, head towards Ōishi Highway.
I'll give you the details when we get there.
Understood.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
Edogawa
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Welcome.
Fill it up with regular, all right?
Certainly!
Um… Excuse me, but I'd like to use the toilet.
Certainly.
It's inside, in the back on your right.
Thanks.
They moved again.
It looks like that boy went with her on his own.
No. Perhaps…
Gunshot residue.
Who are you?!
Conan Edogawa…
Detective.
On the next Conan: 'The Detectives' Nocturne (Deduction)'
Next Conan's Hint: Change!
Hey, Conan-kun, are you all right?
Sleeping is my gimmick!