A mysterious case began following an easy request from the Detective Agency's website.
Don't tell me…?!
What?!
A man confined Kei Kashitsuka-san, who came to the Agency for a request, and committed suicide right in front of her.
After going through a brief questioning, she was sent home.
However, there were countless wiretaps in her house.
Furthermore, while searching for wiretaps, it turned out that under the bed was...
Meanwhile, I'd left the flat with Kei-san who claimed she was going shopping.
But when in the car, she put me to sleep by drugging my juice with sleeping pills.
After learning about it, Ran contacted Dr. Agasa and asked him to search for me with the tracking glasses.
However the Doc's Beetle was being repaired, so he had to use Subaru Okiya's car, as he happened to be there at the time.
Furthermore, when she heard about the incident,
Sera joined them as well, but…
Welcome.
Fill it up with regular, all right?
Certainly!
Umm… Excuse me, but I'd like to use the toilet.
Certainly.
It's inside, in the back on your right.
Thanks.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
Kimi no namida ni kon'na ni koishite'ru
(I love your tears so much)
(Natsu-Iro)
Conan Edogawa was abducted…
A detailed deduction shocks the culprit!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
© Gōshō Aoyama / Shōgakukan · Yomiuri TV · TMS 1996
(Deduction)
They're moving again.
They're now moving south on Ōishi Highway, in the direction of Toriya Town.
Roger. It doesn't look like we'll manage to catch up with them anytime soon.
But where is the kidnapper trying to go?
It looks like she's just wandering around…
She might really be wandering around.
Unable to find the blood-stained spot she's seeking.
Damn it!
The PC was locked.
You can't unlock it unless you know the password, right?
Geez…
Why'd they have to do something so annoying?
Then let's try playing with the name ‘Kei Kashitsuka’.
How do you two usually come up with passwords?
I use my birth date.
I'd use 5563 since it can be read ‘Ko-go-rō-san’.
N-No, that's not what I meant.
What if it's a really long password that you can't memorise.
I'd write it in my mobile phone's memo book.
I'd write it on a paper and hide it somewhere where nobody could see it…
I found it! I got the password!
Amazing, Dad!
As expected from you.
The number you are attempting to call is switched off or out of range, so it can't be reached.
Why?!
Why can't I reach any of those three?!
Do you want me to find her for you?
I mean the woman you are looking for, Miss.
Why are you awake, kid?
If you're talking about the juice drugged with sleeping pills that you bought for me, I didn't drink it.
I spilled half of it under the seat,
since I didn't hear the bottle pop when I opened it.
That's because you opened it before and put something inside it, right?
Anyway, if you want to find that person, then let's go meet them.
The three people you called just now are probably registered in an online address book, so we can find out where they live.
You want to kill that woman, right?
Serina Urakawa-san.
How do you know my name?!
The scratched-up mobile phone that you're holding right now told me everything.
Though it wouldn't have gotten that scratched if you hadn't treated it more carelessly than usual
and put it in the same pocket as something rough.
In the pockets of the coat you covered me with back there,
there was nothing but that phone, your wallet, and a sleeping pill case.
Your wallet and the case didn't have any scratches on them,
which means that the mobile phone actually belonged to the guy who died in the toilet,
and you switched it with the
mobile phone you brought, right?
That guy had a lot of change in his pockets,
and although the lighter and wallet in the same pocket were covered in scratches,
there weren't any on the mobile phone.
There was a stun gun in there as well, but it didn't have any scratches on it, so you must've brought that too, right?
D-Don't be silly. Didn't you see it too?
I was tied down with duct tape.
There's no way I could've switched mobile phones with a guy who was threatening me with a gun.
Tying yourself up with duct tape is easy.
After you pull the tape out, you hang the main part of the duct tape on the toilet's doorknob by the hole in the middle.
Since the tape is stretched out, you can tie yourself up just by turning around and around.
The duct tape was wound around your elbows and above, so you could use both hands.
After cutting the tape, you can remove the duct tape from the doorknob.
With your mouth, you should be able to tie up your wrists with duct tape too.
Then are you saying that I'm the one who shot the guy?
The light's green.
It might be too hard for you to understand, but on the arms and sleeves of a person who fires a gun…
Gunshot residue.
When you fire a gun, lead, tin, antimony, barium, zinc nitrate, and the like scatter
and get onto the body and clothes of the person who fired the gun.
You probably made the guy you knocked out with a stun gun hold a gun, and then made him sit on the toilet seat, right?
You made him hold the gun's muzzle in his mouth.
Then, with the untied bootlaces still connected to the boots,
you passed the laces through the gun's trigger from the outside of his hands,
took them out from under the toilet seat, and dropped them.
To make sure the gunshot residue didn't get on you, you covered your head with a towel.
You dampened the end of another towel and spread it beneath the gun's grip, to make sure it didn't slip.
Then with the laces you dropped from under the toilet seat covered by the towel, you were all set.
To finish it off, just after sending an e-mail to Detective Mouri as if trying to say ‘Don't come in the toilet’,
you pulled the lace while holding onto the boots with your knees in order to fire the bullet.
The guy was thrown back to the wall by the impact,
and by just pulling the lace and removing the towels before we came in after hearing the gunshot,
it looked like the guy that brought you into the toilet had been cornered and committed suicide with a gun.
As evidence, you couldn't answer right away when Amuro-san asked you how your brother died, right?
By the way, how did your brother pass away?
What did your brother die of?
Oh, yes…
That was because your right eardrum hurt, and you couldn't hear well when someone talked to you on that side.
When you fired the gun, though you could guard your left ear by sticking it firmly against the guy's knees,
you couldn't cover your right ear.
In other words, the Kei Kashitsuka-san that came to ask Detective Mouri to investigate a coin locker key was actually that guy,
and it was you who drove Uncle Kogorō away from the Detective Agency with an e-mail before he came,
and then met him at the Agency posing as someone who worked there.
Actually, you were only planning to take him somewhere else and interrogate him,
but he started doubting that you actually worked there,
so you had no choice but to knock him out with a stun gun.
But carrying him somewhere else was out of the question for you.
You could've snatched his mobile phone right there and killed him with the gun,
but if someone nearby were to hear the gunshot and come running to the scene, you'd have nowhere to go.
That's why you dragged him to the toilet, and played out the trick I just explained, right?
That way, you could get let off by the police
and you might be able to find the person you're looking for with the mobile phone you snatched from that guy.
What?!
Just who are you, kid?!
Conan Edogawa…
Detective.
What?!
Just who are you, kid?!
Conan Edogawa…
Detective.
D-Detective?!
Look ahead, Miss! The light's red!
Then you know my name from the cash card in my wallet?
No. I didn't know it was your card yet.
But when I checked the Internet, I learnt a lot.
To make us think that the mobile phone you snatched from the guy was your own,
you transferred a single photo to it to use as a wallpaper,
and the guy in the photo was a bank employee called Ken'ya Shōno-san who was recently shot to death by a bank robber.
You're probably looking around for those three robbers now.
The short guy who was hidden under the bed in the bedroom in Kashitsuka-san's flat,
and who you had no choice but to lead us to, was one of the bank robbers.
The second one was the athletic
guy called Kei Kashitsuka,
who died at the Detective Agency.
And then, with the phonebook of the mobile phone you snatched from him,
it looks like you were trying to find the third, slender guy,
but the names of the three people you repeatedly called were all those of women.
The fact that you know there was
a woman among the robbers
means that you were at the robbery scene.
You probably figured it out by seeing their body types or gestures from close by,
but the fact that there was a woman amongst the robbers hadn't been announced by the media yet.
Since you were at the scene, you should have also noticed…
Those words that Ken'ya-san said when he approached the robber, ‘OK! Please stop,’
were actually ‘Oi, Kei! Please stop.’
That's right. Ken'ya-san noticed that Kei Kashitsuka, a friend, was one of the robbers
and was silenced when he tried to stop him.
When I checked that mobile phone, Ken'ya-san's home phone number was in it, so those two must've been friends.
It looks like Ken'ya-san was a teller at the bank,
so I'm thinking that when he was drunk, he leaked information to Kei-san
that on that day, and at that time, 200 million yen would be brought in,
and that was used in the bank robbery plan.
And so, I called Ken'ya-san's house and asked.
‘Is Ken'ya-san's girlfriend still there by any chance?’
And then Ken'ya-san's family told me.
That Serina Urakawa-san didn't come to the funeral last night.
Wait a second! How come you're saying I'm his girlfriend?!
Didn't I say that I'm his younger sister?!
Since you were at the robbery scene, you're most likely also a bank employee.
To prevent corruption, relatives can't be assigned to the same bank branch.
That's how I knew.
That you're Ken'ya-san's girlfriend, Serina Urakawa-san,
who's trying to get revenge on the three robbers.
Hey, hey, hey!
Isn't this the plotter for that bank robbery?!
They had the nerve to include a photo of the three of them gathered together and holding guns.
Oh, no! Isn't the guy in the middle the one who committed suicide at the Detective Agency?!
The guy on the far right is the guy who was in the suitcase!
Then the lady on the far left must be the other robber.
Looks like that woman's contacted them.
Yeah. With an e-mail blatantly titled ‘Is the gun ready?’
An e-mail from the woman saying she's moving.
It has an address.
Let's go and see.
Yeah.
Well, I figured out right away that this Serina Urakawa-san
was a bank employee after checking your wallet.
Since whenever a bank employee gets transferred to another branch,
a new account is created for them with no transfer fee at the branch they are transferring to.
This next part is just supposition,
but first, relying on 'Kei,' the name that Ken'ya-san murmured, you found the address of Kei,
a friend of Ken'ya-san's, in his address book, and went over to his house, right?
Saying that you came to pick up something Ken'ya-san had forgotten, or something like that.
But Kei Kashitsuka wasn't home, and you were greeted by a short man who had been living with him.
Unfortunately for him, you found his gun, and thinking that you found out he was a bank robber,
he came at you to silence you, but you ended up beating him to death.
You were thinking about waiting there for Kei Kashitsuka's return,
but you saw that preparations for a party had been laid out in the living room.
You feared that many of his friends would be coming,
so you decided to hide the man's body in a suitcase and place a wiretap in it.
You figured that way, the body would eventually be discovered by the stench,
and you'd call the other partner out.
The reason you didn't go to Ken'ya-san's funeral
was because you were listening in on Kei Kashitsuka via the wiretap the whole time, right?
Probably from inside your car, parked in a nearby parking lot.
But even after the party was over, he didn't notice the body.
He suspected that the short guy became frightened and ran away, so he called his other partner
and proposed to her that they should take the rest of the money and skip town.
But even though they had the key to the locker that held the money,
they didn't know what locker the key was for.
Since nobody knew the location besides the short guy.
So then Kei Kashitsuka decided to have the great detective Kogorō Mouri find the location of the locker.
Of course, keeping the contents of the locker a secret.
Overhearing the exchange between the partners on the phone through the wiretap, you panicked.
If Kogorō Mouri discovered that he was a bank robber and he was arrested, you'd lose your chance at revenge.
That's why you ambushed Kei Kashitsuka at the Detective Agency
and tried to get information about the other partner out of him.
Is that about right?
Yeah, that's right.
I thought that I'd find out who that guy was talking with thanks to this phone's call history,
but he was careful and erased it all.
In that case, you have no choice but to go see those three women that you called.
Let's start with the closest one to us, Rinko Toyokita-san's flat.
Maybe the woman who took Conan-kun away is heading for that lady in order to avenge Shōno-san.
Yeah.
Got it, Miss? Do it how I said, all right?
A-All right…
What is it? So annoying…
I just moved here today.
Right, Mum?
Please accept this small token of my appreciation...
Oh, I see. My shift at the convenience store starts at midnight,
Rinko Toyokita (27)
so I'm usually asleep at this time.
Take care now…
Hey!
A nice smell!
Wow, it's an omelette!
Hey, brat!
Don't come back again!
They're on the move again.
At this speed, it looks like they're in a car again.
They're headed for Haido City this time.
But why'd they get out of the car for a while?
Did the culprit take Conan-kun out of the car and take him around somewhere?
No. Perhaps the one who's doing the taking around is Conan-kun.
Maybe she's not home?
My…
Do you have some business at my flat?
Sakae Furuya (31)
She's got nothing but designer bags.
Um… A welcome from moving in.
Oh, is that so?
But it's of no use to me.
I'm leaving here tomorrow.
How come?
I won the lottery!
That's why I went on a shopping spree today.
Oh, that reminds me.
Sorry, but could you take this out for me?
But, isn't the garbage pickup day around here the day after tomorrow?
.
Furuya
I'll be leaving here tomorrow.
Thanks for your help!
Nothing but leftovers from convenience store box lunches.
No way! I got an e-mail from Conan-kun.
‘I'm all right, so don't worry’, he says.
It looks like he went on his own accord.
That brat…
Acting like a detective again.
Well, the curiosity of a child entails the inquiring spirit of a detective and being mutually understood.
Yes, who is it?
We've just moved here today, so if you'd like, please take this.
.
Tegawa
Oh, forgive me.
Takayo Tegawa (29)
I'm not into taking such things.
Say, what do you do, lady?
I'm a writer.
It's right before a deadline now, so it's been tough.
She eats nothing but beef bowls.
Tegawa
Oh, that reminds me.
I'm sorry, but could you do me a favour?
You don't mean taking out the garbage, do you?
So we've seen them all now.
Have you figured something out?
Well?
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Koi ni Koishite
(Falling in love)
(Mai Kuraki)
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
.
Shin’
Shin’i
.
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
.
K
Shin’
.
Shin
Shin’ich
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
So, how about it?
Did you figure out who the robber is?
Yeah, of course! But I can't tell you, Miss.
W-What's that? This isn't what we agreed on!
Well, I can't let someone die.
I mean you, Urakawa-san.
Serina-san and I uncover the remaining robber.
The black shadow draws near…
Will Ran and the old man, along with Haibara and the others, make it?!
On the next Conan: 'The Detectives' Nocturne (Bourbon)'
(Bourbon)
Next Conan's Hint: ‘Left-handed’!
Long deductions are a little tough.
I'm always doing them!
I'll leave it to you!