We got an easy-looking request via the Detective Agency's new website.
But the client sent an e-mail requesting a change in the meeting venue,
so the old man went there along with me, Ran and his apprentice Amuro-san.
But the client never showed up.
Afterwards, we returned to the Agency, at which time we got another e-mail from the client.
Somebody tried to make us leave the Agency, but...
Don't tell me...?!
What?!
A man confined a woman,
who came to the Agency for a request
and was believed to have commited suicide by gun thinking he couldn't escape.
After going through a brief questioning,
the woman was sent home.
However, there were countless wiretaps in her house.
Furthermore, while searching for wiretaps, it turned out that under the bed was...
Meanwhile, I'd left the flat with the woman,
who claimed she was going shopping.
When in the car, she tried to make me drink juice drugged with sleeping pills.
However, I narrowly saw through it,
and instead determined her identity.
Her name was Serina Urakawa.
She was committing crimes in order to get revenge for her lover,
Ken'ya Shōno-san, who was murdered by
the three man bank robber group.
At the same time, old man Kogorō and the others closed in on the truth of the case with Amuro's help,
and went off to see the woman suspected to be the last bank robber.
Also, having been contacted by Ran, Dr. Agasa and Haibara began pursuing us in Okiya's car.
Sera also hurried to join up with
Ran and the others on her bike.
This next part is just supposition,
but first, relying on "Kei", the name that Ken'ya-san murmured, you found the address of Kei,
a friend of Ken'ya-san's, in his address book, and went over to his house, right?
Saying that you came to pick up something Ken'ya-san had forgotten, or something like that.
But Kei Kashitsuka wasn't home, and you were greeted by a short man who had been living with him.
Unfortunately for him, you found his gun, and thinking that you found out he was a bank robber,
he came at you to silence you, but you ended up beating him to death.
You were thinking about waiting there for Kei Kashitsuka's return,
but you saw that preparations for a party had been laid out in the living room.
You feared that many of his friends would be coming,
so you decided to hide the man's body in a suitcase and place a wiretap in it.
But even after the party was over, he didn't notice the body.
He suspected that the short guy became frightened and ran away,
so he called his other partner and proposed to her that they should take the rest of the money and skip town.
But even though they had the key to the locker that held the money, they didn't know what locker the key was for.
Since nobody knew the location besides the short guy.
So then Kei Kashitsuka decided to have the great detective Kogorō Mouri find the location of the locker.
That's why you tried to ambush
Kei Kashitsuka at the Detective Agency
and get information out of him
about the other partner.
Is that about right?
Yeah, that's right.
I thought that I'd find out who that guy was talking with thanks to this phone's call history, but he was careful and erased it all.
In that case, you have no choice but to go see those three women that you called.
Let's start with the closest one to us, Rinko Toyokita-san's flat.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
A case that began with a bank robbery, leads to Bourbon of the Organisation!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Got it, Miss? Do it how I said, all right?
A-All right...
What is it? So annoying...
I just moved here today.
Right, Mum?
Please accept this small token of my appreciation...
Rinko Toyokita (27)
Oh, I see. My shift at the convenience store starts at midnight,
so I'm usually asleep at this time.
Be careful now...
Hey!
It smells nice!
Wow, it's an omelette!
Hey, brat!
Don't come back again!
Maybe she's not home?
My...
Sakae Furuya (31)
Do you have some business at my flat?
Umm... A welcome present since I just moved in.
Oh, is that so?
But it's of no use to me.
I'm leaving here tomorrow.
How come?
I won the lottery!
That's why I went on a shopping spree today.
Oh, that reminds me.
Sorry, but could you take this out for me?
But, isn't the garbage pickup day around here the day after tomorrow?
I'll be leaving here tomorrow.
Thanks for your help!
Nothing but leftovers from convenience store box lunches.
Yes, who is it?
We've just moved here today, so if you'd like, please take this.
Takayo Tegawa (29)
Oh, forgive me.
I'm not into taking such things.
Say, what do you do, lady?
I'm a writer.
It's right before a deadline now, so it's been tough.
She eats nothing but beef bowls.
I'm sorry, but could you do me a favour?
You don't mean taking out the garbage, do you?
So, how about it?
Did you figure out who the robber is?
Yeah, of course! But I can't tell you, Miss.
W-What's that? This isn't what we agreed on!
Well, I can't let someone die.
I mean you, Urakawa-san.
Which way after that?
Turn left ahead.
They're about 5 km away in a straight line.
It seems like they're moving, but from the speed, they're walking.
I see. Then I think we'll catch up with them in about 10 minutes.
Even so, I wonder why they're wandering about on foot for...?
Who knows? But since it's Conan-kun,
he probably has some objective in mind.
Ran-san.
It might not give you a much but peace of mind, but...
I don't believe Conan-kun will be put in
any additional immediate danger.
There's the chance that we may ignore the warning in the e-mail from earlier and contact the police.
She'll have to keep her hostage alive in case she's stopped at a checkpoint.
But hey, if her goal is to murder the other robber, then if he ends up being involved...
Dad!
Right...
So he's still in a dangerous situation.
Let's hurry.
Dummy. What're you talking about, kid?
You don't want me to die?
You can't be thinking that after killing the remaining robber, I intend to commit suicide?
Yeah. Am I wrong?
Anyway, you're probably thinking that since I have a case of sleeping pills in my coat.
Those are pills I got since I haven't been able to sleep lately.
There's not many, not enough to kill someone.
I only used them when kidnapping you since they were there.
Although you caught on, and didn't fall asleep.
Your crimes have been too sloppy, see?
That with the sleeping pill was too, but, the first man you murdered...
It was good up until hiding him in the suitcase,
but putting a bug in with his corpse was bad.
You probably wanted to hear Kei Kashitsuka's surprised and terrified voice when he discovered the corpse,
but that's telling them that there are bugs planted around the flat.
It would've made him cautious instead.
It was also careless to put the gun you used to beat him to death
in the glovebox of your car, with blood still on the grip.
Along with another gun.
Adding in the gun used to shoot Kei Kashitsuka at the Detective Agency, the total is three.
You found the three guns used in the bank robbery in Kei Kashitsuka's flat and took them, didn't you?
You made another big mistake when you swapped your mobile with Kei Kashitsuka's after killing him.
It seems you deleted your phone's e-mails and phonebook, but
if the police contact the telephone company, they'll soon be able to find out who owns it.
Your actions were so makeshift,
it was like you had no plan at all.
For example, not caring about deleting precious e-mails, pictures, and close friends' phone numbers.
It gives the feeling that after you've got revenge on the three robbers who killed your lover, you don't care what happens.
That means you don't have any
attachments to this world, right?
That's why I went with you.
So I could hold onto you.
Though well, wanting to find out who the remaining robber is was another reason I came with you.
So if you'll do as I say,
I don't mind telling you who they are.
If you promise that if you agree with my deduction, you'll leave them to the police and give yourself up.
I-I understand.
I'll do as you say, so tell me.
The remaining slender robber was one of the three women we met earlier, right?
Yeah. You saw them too, didn't you?
The security footage taken of the three robbers.
Since they showed a characteristic of the slender robber, it was quite simple.
Characteristic?
In those pictures, the slender robber put her left foot first
when she tried to climb over the bank counter, right?
When you're trying to climb over something, the first foot you use is your dominant one,
and many people have the same dominant hand and foot.
She held the reel of packing tape with her right hand, and pulled the tape out with her left hand,
and when her friend fired a gun, the hand she brought to her mouth was also her left hand.
When people feel shaken up, they touch their faces to try and calm down,
and without thinking, they use their dominant hand.
Basically, though she tried to hide it by carrying the gun in her right hand...
she was actually left-handed.
Left-handed...
Then, could it be...
Basically, though she tried to hide it by carrying the gun in her right hand...
she was actually left-handed.
Left-handed...
Then, could it be...
Toyokita, who we visited first?!
She opened the door with her left hand.
Since those doors open that way, even right-handed people use their left hand to open them.
If you use your right hand, your arm comes in front of your body and gets in the way,
and visitors will only be able to see you in profile, right?
Anyway, she's right-handed.
The handle of the cup on the table was
facing to the right relative to the chair,
and the frying pan's handle was on the left and the spatula on the right,
so she cooks with her right hand.
If she hadn't used the butter knife with her right hand,
then butter wouldn't have been on the left side of the blade too.
Furuya-san, who we visited second, was also right-handed.
As the hand she used to unlock the door was her right.
Then Tegawa-san, who we visited third...
Yeah! The handle of the cup on the desk faced to the left,
and her memo pad was to the left of the phone
so she could take notes with her left hand while on the phone.
So that her left hand wouldn't cast shadows,
her desk lamp was on the right side of the table,
and her pens and sidetable were also on the left.
While she said she was a writer nearing her deadline to quickly drive us out,
no matter how many times you called her, her mobile wasn't switched on, was it?
Even though there was a landline at her place, a writer nearing a deadline would never turn off their mobile.
She did that because she heard on the news that a man had commited suicide by gun at Mouri Detective Agency,
and thought that Kei Kashitsuka must have commited suicide because Detective Mouri discovered he was a bank robber.
Tegawa-san, fearing that the police would call her, as she was in his phonebook, turned off her mobile.
Oh, and I forgot to mention,
the point that made me think Kei Kashitsuka was a bank robber most was the large amount of coins and notes he had.
Having ¥5,000 in change and forty-seven ¥10,000 notes is too much however you look at it.
He had that much change because the serial numbers of the stolen 200 million yen were known by the police,
so he was breaking up the problem ¥10,000 notes by buying small and compact things with them.
That's also why she ate lots of beef bowl takeaways.
Vending machines at beef bowl restaurants accept ¥10,000 notes,
and by getting takeaways, she doesn't have to stay at the restaurant,
so there's less danger of her face being remembered.
Unlike corner shops and brand shops, many restaurants don't use security cameras.
By choosing places like that, even if somebody discovers that one of the ¥10,000 notes was used at that restaurant,
there's no footage of it.
So? Do you agree to give yourself up?
Yeah, I do.
In deference to your deduction, I'll go to the police.
But there's one thing you got wrong.
I only took 2 guns from Kei Kashitsuka's flat.
The other one is a model gun that a gun fanatic
I know gave me that looks just like the real thing.
Though of course it doesn't fire bullets.
Then the other real gun...
If you know that much, then I can't just let you leave!!
So it was you after all...
Not far now.
At the next corner, turn right,
and they'll be just ahead.
Understood.
I'd better tell Ran-kun.
It would be best if you didn't yet.
We don't know what sort of situation Conan-kun is in.
While I doubt it, we can't rule out the possibility that we're too early to celebrate.
T-That's...
Anyway, hold off contacting them until we understand the current situation.
Okay.
Also, I'll say this now just to be sure.
Even if we find him or else the car he is in, we shouldn't act recklessly.
As we must not endanger his life.
I know that much!
I'm not a child.
Indeed...
Come on! Hurry up and start the car!
I'll guide you to a nice quiet empty place!
I never expected she'd follow us...
Damn it! I can't fire my tranquiliser gun since she's holding my left arm!
Hey! Stop stalling!
Hmm? That sounded like gunfire...
That car!
Edogawa-kun's in that car!
Well then, please convey this to Mouri-san.
Not the police?
They're the only ones who can explain the whole story to the police.
Tell them the car's model, colour and number so they can set up checkpoints to stop it.
B-But what if she uses her hostage as a shield and breaks through the checkpoint?
If that happens...
If that happens, we stop them by force.
What?!
The car the brat's in is headed north on Ōishi Highway?!
Aren't we on Ōishi Highway?
What sort of car is it?
A blue compact. What's the number?
A blue compact...
Hold on to something!
That jerk...
W-What?
What's this feeling...
Something...
Something's closing in!
Don't make that face.
I won't let them get away.
Doctor, take the wheel!
Wheel? Huh?!
S-Subaru-kun, what're you doing?!
Mouri-sensei, stay where you are and hold onto the right seatbelt.
Ran-san, take off your seatbelt and come this way.
Take it off?
Hey! What're you doing?!
W-What?! Who're you?!
Get outta here!
H-How violent...
I'm so glad to see you! Are you okay?!
What's she doing here?
Conan-kun!
Why are you here?
Really now...
Sorry...
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
Kudō-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
It seems you've gained their trust for now.
But you'll keep your promise to me, won't you?
Bourbon...
We're the only witnesses?!
A fierce marital spat at a barbecue!
From a misunderstanding comes a stabbing!
Detective Conan: Won't Forgive Even One Millimetre (Part I)!
Broadcasts at 6:00 PM on Saturday, November 10!
Next Conan's Hint: Barbecue!
Bourbon's one of those three!
Don't act reckless...
Right. I'll leave it to that guy next time.