[Beika General Hospital]
Today we're having barbecue...
Barbecue for lunch...
And for dinner even more barbecue... with curry.
Hey, hey, we were only invited for lunch.
But we're very lucky, aren't we?
Being invited to barbecue by a couple we met at a campsite and all.
All we did was share our rice with them since they forgot to bring some for themselves.
Well, it wouldn't have happened if someone hadn't gotten himself kidnapped, would it?
If our camping day hadn't been delayed because of that, we wouldn't have met that couple.
It's not my fault!
Sunday was the day after the case, so I had to go through exhaustive questioning.
Though, why'd you come too back then?
You could have left that kind of dangerous stuff to the Doc and Subaru-san.
Subaru-san himself asked me to come along.
Besides, I couldn't stay still and do nothing.
If I stayed home, I could've missed a chance to see you dying in agony.
Is that all.
But this is kind of unusual for you.
What is it?
Isn't this the first time you've called him ‘Subaru-san'?
Did you finally get used to him?
Don't make that face.
I won't let them get away.
Not really, no.
Hello?
Yo, Conan-kun, you doing all right?
Uh, yeah, I'm fine.
What's with the cold reaction?
I just saved you from an evil woman, right?
Get outta here!
I'm so glad to see you! Are you okay!?
Y-Yeah, you're right...
Thanks for back then.
Who's calling?
Ah, nobody.
That voice just now, was it that Haibara kid's?
Who're you talking to, Conan-kun?
If it's Ran-oneesan, let me talk to her, too!
Uh, which voice?
Well, never mind.
We got out of school early today, so we're heading over to the Detective Agency now.
If you want, bring her along with you.
Today we're gonna have a barbecue, so I'm not going there.
See ya.
H-Hey, what do you mean by barbecue?!
He hung up.
Come to think of it, Conan-kun and his friends said that they were invited to a barbecue for lunch.
You gotta tell me things like that earlier!
Sorry.
What?! You're going over to Ran's just because of that glasses brat?
Ah, well...
I do want to meet that Amuro guy,
this apprentice of Kogorō-san's too...
Ah, I see.
Back then it was pretty dark in the middle of the road.
And we went through the police questioning separately.
Shotacon.
By the way, have you ever met that Haibara kid?
Yeah. You mean Ai-chan, right?
I don't like her.
What kind of kid is she?
She's a bit weird, but she's very cute.
If I had to give an example, she feels like an unsociable
woman who was turned into a kid.
A woman?
Yeah. She says some very
mature stuff from time to time.
Right, sometimes she and the glasses brat make a nice pair.
Although it doesn't look like Ai-chan's a Holmes geek.
You might not know it yet since you just met Conan-kun, Sera-san,
but Conan-kun adores Holmes, just like Shin'ichi.
I've known it for a very long time.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
A passing marital spat that only we witness.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
That's strange.
We should be right on time.
Happy Halloween!
Halloween? That's already over.
Besides, usually the visiting children are the ones who dress up for Halloween.
Right...
Yeah...
See? I told you not to do it since it's inappropriate.
I thought the children would like it.
You always go overboard with everything.
Takushi Kon'no (34)
Husband
You dressed up as a reindeer for last year's Christmas party.
That's because you told me that dressing up as a miniskirt-wearing Santa would be too embarrassing!
Sumika Kon'no (32)
Wife
Act your age a little!
Well, sorry for being an old woman!
Hey, you two...
Yummy!
This meat's so yummy!
If you don't eat vegetables too, you won't have a balanced diet!
Okay!
That goes for you too, Doctor.
Please let me be.
Just like I thought, having a meal with children is so fun...
Excuse me, but don't you have any children?
No, we don't.
Even though we've been married for 10 years.
If we did have a child,
then maybe my husband would stop cheating on me...
Ah, well...
Ah, sorry.
This isn't something we should be talking about in front of the children, right?
Y-Yeah...
Hey, Sumika.
Have you seen my mobile phone?
No, I haven't.
Are you sure you didn't leave it in your coat pocket?
I couldn't find it there.
I was waiting for an e-mail from my boss in the company.
You didn't forget it at the cabaret club again, did you?!
I don't want to go there to get it again!
It wasn't my fault!
Back then, they called me at the office from the club.
I was at work, so...
Besides, you looked through my phone without permission and did something back then, right?!
Yeah, I sent e-mails saying ‘Die, adulterer!' to all the women who kept sending suspicious messages!
I wondered why everybody stopped
replying to my e-mails suddenly!
So it was your fault, after all!
What the?! It's your fault for
cheating on me in the first place!
What?!
When you have a super-jealous demon wife like you waiting at home,
it makes you want to cheat on her!
So you've been coming home lately because you were meeting with a woman somewhere, after all!
U-Umm...
Ah, sorry.
We're always like this.
Don't mind us.
I've had a very short temper recently...
Anyway, please help me find my mobile phone.
My supervisor gets angry if I don't reply to his e-mails immediately.
It is really a mail from your manager?
Yeah.
It's the mahjong invitations he always sends.
Try calling my phone from yours.
We can use the ringing to find it.
But I haven't been able to find my mobile since this morning, either.
I'm sure it's somewhere in the living room, but...
Are those two going to be okay?
Well, they say ‘fights are good for relationships.'
They also say ‘marital spats make even dogs lose their appetites.'
Genta-kun's still eating well, huh?
Yup! I'm not a dog!
You're leaving already?
Yeah.
But you came all the way here!
Why don't you come inside for a bit?
I remembered something I have to do.
And besides, it seems Kogorō-san's apprentice has the day off from his job today, too.
You aren't leaving just because the kid isn't here, are you?
No, no!
I really do have something I have to take care of.
Instead, next time I come, show me your photo albums and let's have a long chat about your boyfriend, okay?
You're really cheerful, though.
Really? Well, I used to know someone who would never smile.
When I was trying to make that person smile, I...
Hey!
What is it?! What happened?!
What's wrong?!
You suddenly ran off...
I thought I saw someone I know.
Someone you know?
There's no way he'd be here...
Ah, I'm full!
I can't eat anymore.
Are you recording Genta-kun?
Yeah. It'll be Kojima-kun's growth journal.
I'll document how he turns into someone like the Doctor.
Hey, hey.
He already is like the Doctor.
It's a mobile phone.
Isn't this the phone those two were just looking for?
Then I'll go give it to them.
Sure. They should still be in the living room.
Okay!
Mister! I found your phone...
Today is the day that I won't forgive you anymore.
I'll kill you!
H-Hey, Sumika...
C-Calm down, S-Sumika.
Die!
This is terrible!
Those two are fighting again!
Geez, again?
Let them be.
B-But she has a knife...
And said ‘I'll kill you!'!
What?!
Hurry! We have to stop her!
Miss! Miss!
Open your eyes, Miss!
Hang in there!
She's still breathing, but she's pale and has a weak pulse.
Her blood pressure's dropping due to the large amount of blood loss.
H-Hey, Conan.
Shouldn't we take that thing out of her?
Don't touch the knife!
If you take it out, her wound'll open up and she'll bleed to death!
Is the ambulance nearby yet, Haibara?!
It sounds like it'll be another ten minutes.
All right.
Do you have any cushions or blankets, Mister?
Well?! Go get some cushions or blankets!
Damn!
Doc, Ayumi, you guys find some cushions...
Mitsuhiko, go find a blanket and bring it here.
All right!
I'm on it!
She's only wearing an apron and a sweater.
She's dressed pretty lightly.
And she's wearing short Sabrina pants.
Hey, Conan, do you need water or anything?
No...
More importantly... Isn't that the kitchen?
Find a plastic bag and bring it here.
She might vomit.
G-Got it.
We brought some cushions!
Then put them underneath her legs to raise them up.
A-All right.
We'll decrease the blood flowing in her legs
and increase the amount of
blood circulating around her heart.
G-Got it.
What should I do with the blanket?
Cover her from where the knife is pierced in her chest down.
It should help stop her body temperature dropping from the shock.
All right.
Then for now, until the ambulance gets here,
I'd like to ask about her blood type and history of allergies, but...
with her husband in that state...
Hey, you!
I get that you're in shock from having unluckily stabbed your wife,
but at least tell us her blood type and allergies!
You're a couple who swore to love each other forever, aren't you?!
S-Sumika!
S-She has no allergies...
Her blood type is AB.
Although it's RH.
RH, type AB?!
There's only one in 2000 people with that!
Hurry up and tell the hospital, Haibara!
They probably don't have any blood in stock!
All right.
It's not like there's none at all.
As I'm also...
RH, type AB.
I've got a general idea, but could you tell me the details?
About why you stabbed your wife.
I just told the hospital staff as well, but it was my mobile phone that triggered it.
You remember that I was looking for my phone back then, right?
I found it under the sofa in the living room.
I hadn't received the e-mail from my manager inviting me to mahjong yet,
so I thought I'd give him a call and ask if we were doing it tonight,
but my wife took the phone away from me.
She said she wanted to find her own phone first, so she called it to make it ring.
We found that phone.
Right, Ayumi-chan?
Yeah. And then I tried to give it to you, Mister, but...
Is that why you ended up in a fight like that?
No.
The fight started after my wife rang her phone.
Who the hell is this woman?!
There's yet another woman's phone number!
‘Yet another...'
You're not going through my phone on your own, are you?!
Of course I am!
A wife has to control her husband!
I check it every night after you've gone to sleep!
Hey, hey, even if we're husband and wife, there's still something called ‘privacy'!
What a woman you are. I shouldn't have married you.
T-That's what I'd like to say!
And then, my wife took hold of a knife and came at me yelling ‘I'll kill you'.
While we were struggling, I thought she'd run out of strength, but the knife was stuck in her chest.
Is that how it happened, Ayumi?
Y-Yeah.
Although all I saw was when the lady was holding the knife and yelled ‘I won't forgive you'.
I see.
Well, I would think that it would be self-defence.
I'm impressed you two managed to stay married like that.
My wife changed.
When we met in front of the bloodmobile, she was a kind woman who laughed a lot.
We meet a lot, don't we?
I know. We both have precious blood.
But recently, she's been constantly angry.
Whenever I come home from the office, she says ‘I'm sluggish', ‘I'm tired', or ‘I'm sleepy'.
And she never has dinner ready.
When I occasionally cook dinner to cheer her up, it's like she really can't eat it, and she vomits.
When I suggested we go to the campsite that we used to go to together before we got married for a change of pace,
we got into a big fight because I forgot the rice.
Well, my wife's mood got a bit better thanks to you kids sharing the rice back there,
but to be honest, I can't take it any more.
But... But I like her!
She tried to make everybody happy by appearing in a Halloween costume.
And she prepared a barbecue while smiling.
I... I don't want her to die!
Don't make that face...
She will make it.
Don't make that face.
I won't let them get away.
I'll protect her with my own life.
Dai Moroboshi...
My sister's boyfriend who betrayed the Organisation...
But still, if she makes it, then wouldn't it be thanks to us for coming to the barbecue?
Y-Yeah... That's true.
If we hadn't found the phone back then, and if Ayumi-chan hadn't gone to give it to him,
we wouldn't have noticed those two fighting and it might've been too late.
What's this strange, uneasy feeling?
Things are going too well.
Something seems too contrived...
But what in the world is it...
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
It's been quite a while.
Don't worry. I'm sure she'll survive.
Yeah.
Ah, an e-mail arrived.
That's the wife's mobile phone we found before, right?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
You can't! Don't look at other people's e-mails without their permission!
‘I think you should go see a doctor about the health issue we talked about before.'
A heart mark at the end of the message?
Putting a heart mark in an e-mail about a health issue.
Why?
Hey, Conan-kun!
You're even going to check the sent e-mails?
T-This is...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
That wife said she sent e-mails saying: ‘Die, adulterer!'
to the women who kept sending suspicious e-mails to her husband, right?
Yeah. But these messages are completely different.
But it looks like she has a short temper because of her health issue.
I see. So that's why there was a glass there.
A health issue means you have trouble with your health, right?
It looked like that woman was about to take some medicine.
Because there was a glass full of water in the kitchen.
A glass of water?
Then was there any medicine beside it?
Nope. There was only a container of sugar next to it.
I thought of taking that glass of water to her, but...
Are you okay, Genta-kun?!
It looks like Genta-kun's the one who needs medicine.
Did you catch a cold?
That's not it.
My nose itches, that's all.
It won't stop...
Then how about you try pressing down under your nose with your index finger, and cover your nostrils?
Like this?
If that doesn't work either, hold your nose.
Woah! It stopped!
It's a home-made remedy of sorts.
Remedy...
C-Could it be...?!
Did he take advantage of that to kill his wife?
Next Episode Preview
We, the Detective Boys, encountered a stabbing during the barbecue we were invited to.
We thought it was an accident at first, but that was the culprit's ingenious trick.
On the next Conan: ‘Won't Forgive Even One Millimetre (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: A glass of water.
A marital spat is horrible, isn't it?
You mean that bad dog food?
The one that makes dogs lose their appetite.