We, the Detective Boys, were invited along with Dr. Agasa
to a barbecue at the house of a couple we met at a campsite.
The couple greeted us happily, and when everyone was eating the barbecue,
the husband couldn't find his mobile, and the couple went into the house.
But, Ayumi found the mobile under a garden bench, and when she went to give it to him...
Today's the day... I won't forgive you anymore.
Sumika Kon'no (32)
Wife
Takushi Kon'no (34)
Husband
I'll kill you!
H-Hey, Sumika!
C-Calm down, S-Sumika.
Die!
This is terrible!
Those two are fighting again!
Geez, again? Let them be.
But she has a knife, and she said ‘I'll kill you’!
What?!
Hurry! We have to stop her!
To begin with, it seemed that it was an accident,
with the knife being accidentally stabbed through the wife's chest while the couple were struggling, but...
But still, if she makes it, then wouldn't it be thanks to us for coming to the barbecue?
Y-Yeah, that's true.
If we hadn't found the phone back then, and if Ayumi-chan hadn't gone to give it to him,
we wouldn't have noticed those two fighting, and it might've been too late.
What's this strange, uneasy feeling?
Things are going too well.
Something seems too contrived…
Ah, an e-mail arrived.
That's the wife's mobile phone we found before, right?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
You can't! Don't look at other people's e-mails without their permission!
T-This is...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
That wife said she sent e-mails saying: ‘Die, adulterer!’
to the women who kept sending suspicious e-mails to her husband, right?
Yeah. But these messages are completely different.
But it looks like she has a short temper because of her health issue.
I see. So that's why there was a glass there.
A health issue means you have trouble with your health, right?
It looked like that woman was about to take some medicine.
Because there was a glass full of water in the kitchen.
A glass of water?
Then was there any medicine beside it?
Nope. There was only a sugar container next to it.
I thought of taking that glass of water to her, but...
Are you okay, Genta-kun?!
It looks like Genta-kun's the one who needs medicine.
Did you catch a cold?
That's not it.
My nose itches, that's all.
It won't stop...
Then how about you try pressing down under your nose with your index finger, and cover your nostrils?
Like this?
If that doesn't work either, hold your nose.
Woah! It stopped!
It's a home-made remedy of sorts.
Remedy...
C-Could it be...?!
Did he take advantage of that to kill his wife?
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
A marital spat causes a case?
Did the couple's feelings for each other miss their mark?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Remedy...
C-Could it be...?!
Did he take advantage of that to kill his wife?
But right now, there's no proof.
The only thing I can rely on is the wife's testimony, but she's...
Hey...
Something's shining.
What?
I happened to be recording when Yoshida-san found the wife's mobile, and went to give it to her...
This is terrible!
Those two are fighting again!
Geez, again? Let them be.
After this.
But she has a knife, and she said ‘I'll kill you’!
Here.
The light on the phone Yoshida-san's holding is on, right? Look.
Could it be an answering machine service?!
He said she called her mobile from his,
so it may be here...
A portion of the trick that led
to his wife's stabbing, that is...
This is the answering machine service.
You have one new message.
Today's the day... I won't forgive you anymore!
I'll kill you!
H-Hey, Sumika!
C-Calm down, S-Sumika.
Die!
Did they stop?
If you wish to hear this message agai—
W-What was that last sentence?
It was the wife talking, wasn't it?
I thought I heard her saying ‘Did they stop?’, but that's...
It's as I thought.
It wasn't self-defence.
He took advantage of his wife's
personality to try to murder her!
Don't tell me, he didn't know that by doing so,
two lives would be coming to their end.
The light went out!
They must've finished operating!
S-Sumika!
S-So?
How was the operation?!
Don't worry.
Her pulmonary artery was slightly injured,
but she was saved thanks to the appropriate first aid that was administered immediately after the stabbing.
She'll likely be discharged in a few weeks.
All right!
Thank you very much.
It's no problem.
Really, thank you.
However, I had to tell the police about the unfortunate accident
at the end of your marital spat.
Ah, sure.
Please explain what happened to the policeman that's coming over here about it too.
As even though it was an accident, it was a serious wound.
I-I understand.
Well, when she recovers, I think they'll question your wife about it too, so keep your marital spats to a minimum.
R-Right. Thank you very much.
Take care.
Relief, guilt, then fear.
Which means the next actions he'll take are...
To either tell the truth to the police, or attempt to run away.
Or perhaps...
Huh?!
You were at the crime scene when the wife was stabbed too?
Yeah! Though we didn't see her get stabbed.
Ayumi-chan saw them just before she was stabbed.
Right. I found the phone he was looking for,
so I went to the room they were both in to give it to him, but she was holding a knife, and said...
Today's the day... I won't forgive you anymore!
I'll kill you!
Ah, I see.
We heard about it from Ayumi-kun,
and ran over to see, but instead, it was her who'd been stabbed and collapsed.
I see, I see...
So the husband ended up stabbing her in their struggle, right?
And where is he now?
Huh? He was just here...
Now you mention it, Conan-kun
and Haibara-san are gone too.
They are. I wonder where they went?
Maybe to the toilet?
Running away?
I'm asking if you plan to run off to the afterlife, leaving your wife in that state.
What are you talking about?
I just came up here to get some fresh air and breathe a sigh of relief since I found out my wife was safe.
Come on, don't be silly, go back to the others.
After chasing us away by saying that, you're gonna jump, aren't you?
As if your wife recovers and is questioned by the police, they'll find out.
That from the very start, you were trying to kill your wife.
That expression shows it.
You had the same expression when the doctor mentioned your wife undergoing police questioning earlier.
When you heard your wife's operation was successful,  your face welled up with tears, showing your relief.
Upon hearing again that your wife had been severely injured,
you looked down to avoid his gaze, from guilt that you'd done something bad, but...
After that, when you realised your wife would reveal the truth of what happened,
you twisted your mouth up and opened your eyes wide, which shows you were hiding fear.
If you'd unluckily stabbed your wife in self-defence, you wouldn't have made that face.
As for faces... Didn't your friend see my wife's, kid?
She was waving around a piece of cutlery and slashing at me, saying she'd kill me...
It was the only way I could save myself.
I couldn't help it!
Your wife wasn't trying to kill you.
She was only trying to scare you.
S-Scare me? W-Why would she...
Because they wouldn't stop.
Your hiccups, that is!
You think that to stop my hiccups...
S-She'd really go waving around a knife, and slash at me saying she'd kill me?
No way.
You know your wife's personality too, don't you?
Last year, on Christmas, you stopped her from dressing up as a miniskirt-wearing Santa,
so she dressed up in a reindeer costume.
And she tried to make us happy by greeting us in a Halloween costume, even though it's already over.
She's the type that if she thinks something will go well,
she'll dash into it without considering the consequences.
For someone like that, it wouldn't be a stretch to think that if she saw you troubled by hiccups that wouldn't stop,
she'd get carried away trying to stop them.
Even more so if you'd left a fruit knife out in the kitchen, and were about to phone your boss while hiccuping.
Although, there was a glass with water and
a sugar container left out in the kitchen too,
so it seems she also considered other methods to stop hiccups.
Sugar?
Shoving a spoonful of sugar down someone's throat is an unusual method that's said to stop hiccups.
The two most common methods in Japan are to drink water or to get a sudden scare.
Basically, the trick you set up went like this.
First, in front of us who you'd invited to a barbecue, you'd mention that you couldn't find your mobile.
You deliberately created an argument with your wife by giving responses that would irritate her.
Then, you invited your wife into the living room so that she could help search for your mobile,
then pretended to find your mobile which you'd hidden beneath the sofa.
After saying that since his e-mail hadn't arrived, you'd better phone your supervisor and check,
you pretended to hiccup to make your wife fall into your trap,
by lamenting that you had to phone your
supervisor, but your hiccups wouldn't stop.
Then, you just had to make sure that your wife picked up the knife as you expected,
and then called your wife's mobile, which you'd hidden under the seating for the barbecue beforehand.
One of us would come to the living room to give it to you,
and with someone witnessing your wife attacking you with a knife in hand,
then even if you took the knife from her and stabbed her,
your wife had been angry at you and tried to kill you, so it'd look like you had to stab her in self-defence.
Ironically, your wife's phone, which you rang to create a witness recorded the proof on her answering machine.
You have one new message.
Today's the day... I won't forgive you anymore!
I'll kill you!
H-Hey, Sumika!
C-Calm down, Sumika.
Die!
Did they stop?
Anyway, even without the answering machine,
once your wife recovered, she'd be able to testify.
I told you, didn't I?
My wife pushed me to my limits.
I could bear it until a while ago.
Even her getting carried away had its charm.
But recently, she really has been constantly angry...
That she said she was sluggish, tired and sleepy, she was neglecting the housework,
and that she brought up my cooking were all true.
But really... I wasn't sure what to do.
Whether to use this murder trick or not.
At least, until she said that.
Yeah, I sent e-mails saying ‘Die, adulterer!’ to all the women who kept sending suspicious messages!
I'd thought it was odd.
I completely stopped hearing from good friends who'd always invited me to the seas and mountains...
A girl working under me at the company who said she had something to discuss with me about
suddenly quit the company without saying a thing.
I... I was fed up with her!
She never thought about anyone but herself!
But I really was dumb.
She's my wife, so even though I stabbed her, I was praying that she wouldn't die.
Even though her being saved meant my doom.
Yeah, you are dumb.
Look.
These are the real e-mails that your wife sent to your female friends.
T-The real e-mails?
Thank you very much for always inviting my husband to the seas and mountains.
However, my husband's blood is RH-, type AB,
so I'd like to ask you to please be careful
to make sure he doesn't get any serious injuries.
Thank you for always taking care of my husband.
Once your discussion with my husband is over, how would you feel about visiting our house?
I don't know if I can be of much help, but as an older woman, I may be able to offer you some advice.
S-Sumika...
Your friends stopped inviting you to seas and mountains because they were worried about your health.
The reason your subordinate didn't talk with you...
was because she had some ulterior motive, wasn't it?
Anything a woman could want to talk to you about without your wife knowing wouldn't be anything good anyway.
And also, aren't you misunderstanding something?
M-Misunderstanding?
Being irritable, getting worn out easily, tiring quickly, being sluggish, vomiting.
They're all early symptoms of pregnancy.
It's probably the reason your wife was lightly dressed too.
When pregnant, some people feel feverish due to the increase in female hormones.
Though it doesn't seem she's realised it yet.
By the way, the reason I watched your
expressions after your wife's operation
was so that I could see if you really were relieved she was saved,
and whether you really did regret stabbing her.
Well, personally, no matter how much relief and regret you showed...
...I won't forgive you even one millimetre.
As I wouldn't want a baby who's about to be born
to be the child of a criminal who'd try to kill his wife over a misunderstanding.
Anyway, I'll make something up for the police today,
so when your wife recovers, apologise from the bottom of your heart,
and discuss with her what you intend to do from now on.
Several Days Later
Well then, on the day of the incident,
as your husband and Conan-kun have said,
you waved the knife around trying to scare your husband to try and stop his hiccups.
Your husband took it seriously and a struggle began, and you ended up being stabbed instead. Is that correct?
Yes... I guess my acting was a bit too realistic...
S-Sorry for causing you all this trouble...
Don't be. Well then, this time I'll leave you with just a stern warning.
Please keep your marital spats to a minimum too.
Thank you very much.
Well then, excuse me.
Make sure you keep your promises to me, okay?!
Y-Yeah...
No affairs! Dinner will be eaten at home!
I understand.
And... If you ever try something like this again,
I won't hesitate to kill you, so you better be prepared!
Right, ‘daddy’?
Right!
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
Edogawa
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
What a surprise that wife was though!
Yeah! For her to be trying to stop hiccups!
But she went overboard.
That's right!
Speak of the devil, isn't that him?
He's bought lots of toys.
Does he even know if it's going to be be a boy or a girl?
What a silly dad.
I still won't forgive him even a millimetre though.
Now, now...
Dragged along by the old man,
Ran and I set out to go surfing.
But there's a woman's corpse!
And around the corpse there isn't a single footprint, but a mirror-smooth beach!
On the next Conan: ‘The Footprintless Beach’!
Next Conan's Hint: Surfboard!
I wanted to eat a bit more meat...
You can't.
We won't forgive you having even one milligram more.