Ōhama Beach
We've arrived at Ōhama Beach, which is two hours by car from Beika Town.
Old man Kogoro suddenly decided he wanted to go surfing, and thinking that trying to stop him would be hard,
Ran and I ended up reluctantly tagging along.
Hold the wetsuit tightly, and put your feet in as if you were stepping forward.
I-It's tight!
Right. If it was loose, water'd get in!
The one who started it all was this woman that he recently met, who invited him here.
Nagisa Imaoka (25)
Put more strength into it!
To make sure you don't lose track of your surfboard, attach it to your ankle with the leash.
Its length is slightly longer than the surfboard itself:
about 2 meters for adults, and 1.5 meters for children.
Can't it get cut off?
Well, very rarely.
But if a big wave comes and tosses you about, there's no telling what will happen.
Though that's what's fun about surfing.
Well then, let's go ride the waves!
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
A single figure laying on a sandy beach with no footprints in sight!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
So you're Mouri-san?
I do apologize.
I was out buying stock, so I'm late to introduce myself.
I've been looking forward to having the great detective Kogoro Mouri-san here
ever since Nagisa told me you were coming. I'm Kaishirō Imaoka.
Kaishirō Imaoka (60)
Thanks for taking care of us.
Well, even though it's my first
time surfing, it was really fun!
I'm the type of guy who likes to ride the waves, so I'm a great surfer!
More like the type who likes to ride on your ego.
Even now, we're wasting time here!
I'm itching to go surfing again!
Hey mister, is this a tide calendar?
Hmm? Ah, that's right, kid.
Looking at this, it'll be spring tide tonight.
Yeah. Ōhama Beach here is famous due to the big variances between high tide and low tide.
At high tide at night, the coastline'll be about 100 meters closer than it is now.
And when the morning comes, the waves recede as if running away.
A wide, empty beach washed blank by the waves extends for more than a kilometer.
It's fun to wake up early and run around leaving footprints.
Right, I know just how you feel!
Like finding a place nobody's stepped on when it's snowing, and going psssst—
Dad!
Hey, are these trophies yours?
Yeah, that's right.
She was quite a surfer in the amateur world.
No surprise to me. Ah, I'm jealous that you have such a wonderful daughter.
Ah, no...
I'm a bit embarrased to say it, but she's not my daughter.
Don't tell me she's actually your son? She's a man?!
Ah, no, she's my wife. My bride.
Wh... B-Bride?!
You mean you're married to him?!
There's 35 years between our ages.
Don't sink into the sea in depression, old man...
Come on, Dad, let's keep surfing!
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Ah, I don't care anymore...
I'm so tired all of a sudden... So she was married, huh...
Then it's just us, Nagisa-san.
Okay, shall we get going?
Stop!
I heard in the car that there's a high-pressure front coming in.
Look at the waves. They're starting to have whitecaps!
I heard that surfing was more fun when there were some waves though...
Some people think so, but not me.
Anyway, you two are beginners, aren't you?
Many people lose their lives getting snatched up by high waves.
You must never take the sea lightly.
You'll never enjoy surfing if you keep being such a wimp!
You'll be fine, I'll be with you.
Don't be full of yourself!
What can you do to stop high waves!
I've had enough of your arrogance!
Ah, sorry...
I didn't realize I was shouting, I do apologize.
Don't worry...
The high-pressure front'll probably be gone by morning. At least wait until then.
Really... Doesn't he have a challenger's spirit?
He's turned into an old geezer who lives for plastic models!
He's no fun at all!
I can hear it.
The sea's calling "come and get me"!
In here, the restless blood of a surfing maiden is burning!
You know?!
Not really...
I see what kind of marriage this is.
If we can't go surfing, how about we go back to the boarding house?
I guess...
Left, left... No, no, right!
Urgh... There! Ahhh...
Ah, so Nagisa-san was a customer at that shop.
Hmm? Yeah, from what the owner of the boarding house said,
she came here frequently to conquer the waves here.
Agh... And then three years ago they conquered her instead.
Yes? Come in.
I apologize.
Imaoka-san, what's wrong?
What? Your wife's gone missing?
Yes, while I was in the kitchen preparing for tomorrow, she disappeared.
So I thought she might have gone to visit you...
No, she hasn't been here...
Don't tell me she went out in the sea?
What about her surfboard?
It's in the shop.
Could she have taken one of the boards from the stock?
Yeah, she could have.
When looking at rough seas like today's, her eyes narrow.
Like a shark chasing its prey.
Mister, something's shining in your breast pocket.
Isn't it the new message light on a mobile?
It's from Nagisa.
"Sorry for not saying anything.
At karaoke. Might stay all night."
Ah, I'm relieved.
Good thing she didn't go to the sea, huh?
Even if she's a shark, she can't
do any surfing at a karaoke bar.
Right. But leaving without saying a word...
I don't get what she's thinking at all.
The troubles of keeping a younger wife?
"This shouldn't have happened" has become a catchphrase between us lately.
The high-pressure front went away at dawn, and the tide's all the way out at sea.
Isn't the beach nice and clean, Conan-kun?
Yeah, you're right...
Uncle, what's that?
Driftwood?
No...?!
Isn't it someone wearing a wetsuit?!
It can't be!
I-It's...
Nagisa-san!
Too late, she's dead.
Oh no...
That's...
Anyway, Ran, contact the police.
Kid, bring Imaoka-san out here!
And just to be careful, bring some cardboard or something to spread around the corpse.
Got it!
Couldn't you manage to control your surfing maiden blood...?
This is most likely a murder case.
But the only footprints around the corpse are ours, from running over to it.
Just how did the killer do it...?
Nagisa... Nagisa...
Nagisa...
What?
Sand?
Why would it be there...?
Nagisa...
Hmm? This guy's Kogoro Mouri-san?
Yeah, he appears on TV a lot.
Let's get his autograph later.
Right.
So, Mouri-san.
Have you figured anything out?
Hmm... To be frank, this was an unfortunate accident.
Ah, so it was an accident.
Yes. Seeing the rough seas brought by a high-pressure front, she probably couldn't bear it.
So she sent a fake e-mail saying she'd gone to karaoke to her husband, Imaoka-san,
secretly put on one of the suits her workplace had in stock,
and with a board from the stock in hand,
went out to the sea via the back door.
But I wonder why Nagisa-san didn't wear her own wetsuit which is hanging there?
You're right...
She probably thought I'd spot her from the kitchen.
Knowing that if I did, I would've stopped her.
Nagisa... really loved surfing.
I know how you feel.
Then when she was enjoying surfing, she got tossed about by the high waves,
and the momentum wound Nagisa-san's leash around her neck.
Then the waves pulled the board away, and as a result, her neck was strangled.
But the marks from the cord on her neck are inside her wetsuit.
What about it?!
She was facing stormy seas!
The cord could've got inside!
But the suits are meant to be skin-tight so that water doesn't get in, right?
You're so noisy, geez!
Go away, you brat!
And then, with her board missing, Nagisa-san was returned to this beach, to the place of her lover, Imaoka-san.
So perceptive! That's a sharp mind at work.
Huh? Look at Nagisa-san's toenails.
You're right... maybe she went out to sea while she was putting on a pedicure?
Where have I seen that...
Imaoka-san! It's Nagisa-san! Nagisa-san's on the beach!
Imaoka-san!
Those bags!
This really was a murder case.
And the killer is...
Huh? Footprints left by someone over 100 kg?
Right. Like, if someone weighing 60 kg carried someone weighing 50 kg on their back, they'd leave deep footprints, right?
I don't know what this is about, but anyway, when we came, the beach was clean, with nothing like that.
Guess you're right. Thanks.
You're welcome.
Damn it! He has to be the killer, so how did he carry the corpse out to the beach?
If I can't figure that out...
What? Was it crushed by something?
Crushed... by something...?
If I'm right...!
There!
I see. So that's what happened.
Embraced by the waves, Nagisa...
Yes, she began her journey.
That's what I think!
Dad?
Oh! This is...!
...is what I'd like to say, but this was a murder case made to look like an accident.
M-Murder case?!
That's right.
Look at the toenails on Nagisa-san's left foot.
She was applying a pedicure, see?
Don't you think it odd she would go to the sea while painting her nails?
I-It is.
I thought it was odd too when Conan-kun mentioned it earlier.
As for why she did, it was because she had to stop halfway.
Basically, while applying her pedicure...
...she was murdered.
And at your hand, Imaoka-san.
M-Mouri-san, what is this all of a sudden?
Look at the rope mark on Nagisa-san's neck.
Part of it goes inside the wetsuit, see?
That is because in order to make it look like an accident, after murdering her with the leash, you put a wetsuit on her.
W-Wait a sec, Mouri-san.
You know too, don't you?
You need strength to put on a wetsuit.
If Nagisa was dead, even if it's a bad example, she'd be like jelly and not be able to stand up, right?
How're you saying I got Nagisa into a wetsuit?!
Then shall we try an experiment?
Sakata, you're dead. Don't move.
Right!
There!
Oh! You're right, his foot came through without needing much strength.
And the other one!
Putting plastic bags on her feet reduces the friction.
Look at the bin Ran brought.
There are traces of a pedicure in the plastic bags.
They should match with Nagisa-san's feet.
I see, I see.
So he put a wetsuit on the corpse, then went offshore on a rubber boat to dump her.
Then in the morning, the corpse would have washed up.
That's what you mean, right?
Please wait!
When am I supposed to have taken a rubber boat out?
Yesterday evening, or at night.
A high-pressure front had come and the seas were very rough.
A rubber boat would've been capsized.
Then this morning, when the high pressure front had left and the waves had calmed.
Give me a break!
A boat would be heavy with Nagisa in it!
Are there marks anywhere on the beach from a boat being dragged?
Well...
Nagisa went surfing on stormy seas
yesterday evening and died doing so.
And this morning she washed ashore on the beach here.
Certainly, when we discovered Nagisa-san, there were no footprints or anything on this wide beach.
So it seemed that she'd been washed ashore.
But, Imaoka-san, you looked at the plastic model on that shelf
and thought up the trick to this crime.
Plastic model?
Ah, this one?
A crane. By extending the boom,
fastening the rope to the deceased,
then swinging it left and right like the pendulum in a clock,
and letting go when the reaction is large enou—
Sorry.
Anyway, the deceased flew through the sky and landed in the sea, leaving no footprints on the beach. How's that, Mouri-san?
Wrong!
Imaoka-san, after murdering Nagisa-san,
you buried her in the sand to hide her.
The karaoke e-mail was also your doing.
Then, this morning, you dug up Nagisa-san and carried her on your back.
B-But that'd be the weight of two people.
There'd be footprints...
You used a certain thing so that footprints would not be left.
Taking a hint from the machine's crawler.
Imaoka-san, you put these together to make a loop, didn't you?
I-I see!
With Nagisa-san on your back, you went inside and moved along the beach, left Nagisa-san behind and then returned.
How was that? Did I miss anything?
It happened yesterday, after Mouri-san's group had left.
Nagisa... She said this...
Tomorrow morning, I'm meeting
someone under the lone pine tree.
If it works out, I'm sending you a divorce notice.
Won't you reconsider?
In the end, the world is ruled by looks and money.
Give it up.
Nagisa had married me for my money... Just for my money!
Damn it!
Now, the last 100 meter straight!
Tawāru Gītaka's Anjō-no-Yamagawa's being followed by...
Go! Go!
Go!
Run! Run! Run!
Come on, run!
Haha... I guess someone who can't ride the waves can't go riding money on horses either.
How'd this happen?!
Morons, I've had enough!
Did we travel through time?
Serial murders shake Nagasaki of the Bakumatsu.
What is the true identity of the girl who holds the key?
A masterful deduction by Sakamoto Ryōma!
On the next Conan: The Nagasaki Mystery Theater (Bakumatsu Case).
Next Conan's Hint: Font.
You can't ride money on a winning horse, and can't ride the waves.
bōto
botto
Then should I just sit still on a boat?
Yeah.