Nagasaki Station
DETECTIVE
CONAN
Murderer!
To think something like this would happen...
It's no use, Mr. Glover.
I have one of these too.
With that, the magistrate's office'll happily arrest you for it.
If that happens, the business and the Satchō Alliance'll be over.
Don't worry! I, Sakamoto Ryōma, shall clear any doubts on me!
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
A Bakumatsu period drama set in Nagasaki.
Where is the missing scriptwriter?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Did we travel back in time?
Nah.
As usual, Ran drew first prize in the shopping district's lottery,
so today, we've come to Nagasaki.
Nagasaki Station
Nagasaki Confucius Shrine · Historical Museum of China
Ōura Church
Glover Garden
This is Glover Garden, where Thomas Blake Glover,
an English merchant who supported Shishi like Sakamoto Ryōma in the Bakumatsu period once lived.
It's the most famous place in Nagasaki.
What's she looking for?
The heart stones.
Heart stones?
Two of the paving stones in the Garden are shaped like hearts.
There's all sorts of legends about them,
such as 'if a couple finds them they'll be married', and 'if you touch them your love will come true'.
Found it!
It's so cute!
Now where's the other one?
Never mind that, I want to try Nagasaki's famous Champon and Sara Udon—
Murderer!
W-What was that just now?!
I'm sure they said 'Murderer!'...
This way!
Out the way!
Nobody move!
You can leave the rest to the great detective Kogorō Mouri...
What's with this victim?
He came back to life!
Who exactly are yo—
Cut!
So I didn't make it...
We're sorry.
Anyone'd get misled.
What was going on here was filming a 2-hour TV mystery drama based in the Nagasaki of the Bakumatsu period.
A murder occurs in the Glover Residence.
Sakamoto Ryōma, who was hiding in the Residence, takes on a detective role,
aided by the young female doctor of Western Medicine, Ine.
He sets out to solve the case to clear the doubts people have of him.
How about it, Ine?
Was a pistol used after all?
Kyōnosuke Sasahara (33)
As Sakamoto Ryōma
To think something like this would happen in our mansion...
Benichiyo Yamashita (42)
As Tsuru
It's unfortunate for sure.
Andrew Hatta (50)
As Glover
There's no mistake. He was killed by a pistol.
Futaba Nanao (23)
As Karasuma Ine
Cut! Okay!
Hey, was that really okay?
A temporary doctor shouldn't show that much emotion.
It's fine.
Keisuke Sakakibara (45)
TV Drama director
Ine's a novice doctor, so it makes sense for her to be emotional.
O-Chiyo-san's acting was great as always too.
Akikazu Nakane (48)
Cameraman
T-That's right, Benichiyo-san.
Ryūhei Kishimura (30)
Assistant Director
Is that right? Then it'll do.
Umm... next up is the scene where the victim's
merchant friend, Soneya Chūbee, first appears.
Sazanami-san, go ahead.
Okay!
Treat me well, Bara-chan.
Chōjirō Sazanami (45)
As Soneya Chūbee
Sure. I'm counting on you, Chō-san!
Where are Soneya's props?
Here.
Kazuomi Sakota (35)
Prop Master
They're all here.
Isn't this a bit over-the-top?
No...
Can't you do something about this comb too?
But... but those are from 'Madame Butterfly'...
An opera lover as always, Sakota.
But is this really okay, Bara-chan?
Can we really start filming without even
knowing the end, or should I say, the culprit?
Well, even if it's a bit late, it'll be a masterpiece. This is Tatsumi we're talking about here.
She's quite a beauty, that girl playing the doctor.
Isn't that Futaba Nanao-san?
She's a new actress thought to be getting her break soon.
Don't give me that! I can't just ignore it!
Like I said, it'll be really bad, so make sure you cover it up...
I heard from Sonoko that Sasahara-san's a handsome bachelor who's a regular among most-wanted boyfriend rankings.
I wonder what's happened.
(Gesture referring to love in Japan)
Hmph. Maybe it's trouble related to this?
No way!
We're in trouble!!
Taizō Ōki (52)
Drama Production Company Producer
T-T-Tatsumi's run off on us!
Well, I knew he'd been stuck lately, but still...
Even though his old friends are all here for the first time in ages...
Wait a bit longer and see.
Argh! I'm at my limit!
Your limit, huh?
Then...
Of course!
Actually...
What'd you say?
Sleeping Kogorō?
Yes?
I beg you!
Great detective Sleeping Kogorō, please deduce who the culprit is in this mystery drama!
Sure...
Hey, hey...
Kōsaku Tatsumi (45)
Scriptwriter
This mystery drama's scriptwriter, Kōsaku Tatsumi-san, is a veteran whose scripts have won various prizes.
This drama isn't an adaptation, but an original work by Tatsumi-san,
and the writing's taking too long, causing the filming to begin with an unfinished script.
So the upcoming developments, not to mention the culprit of the case in the drama, are unknown to all but Tatsumi-san.
If this drama goes belly up, it'll wreck our company!
If you can at least spot the culprit, Mouri-san, I'll manage the rest somehow.
We're counting on you!
Just as I thought, it's impossible...
The script's not even half-finished, so no matter how much they ask, to spot a culprit from this is just too much...
But you took the job anyway, didn't you?
Saying there's no riddle that Sleeping Kogorō can't solve.
About that...
True, there aren't enough clues...
Hmm?
These are?!
Serial Art Theft Case
Illegally Sold
Among Fans
A Large-Scale Smuggling Organisation
What're these?
Why are they here?
A group of art thieves.
That's it! So there was a real case it was based on.
You mean the culprit is the group of thieves?
But they don't appear up in the current script at all.
That's because it he hadn't put them in yet.
I wonder...
If so, they wouldn't be hidden by being stuck up here.
Yes, right. I'm leaving now.
That's why you've gotta do something about it!
How'd this happen...
Ah, I'm worn out!
In the end, we didn't find many clues at all.
I told you, the culprit's the group of thieves.
Hey, Mouri-san.
Ah, I'm Andrew Hatta, the actor playing Glover.
Doesn't my real face look just like
the Glover statue in Glover Garden?
Ah, no...
Though when Glover was working with Ryōma, he was only 30 years old...
Detective Boy!
You were thinking that the actor's much older than the real Glover was, weren't you?
Ah, no...
The management are going through trouble at Ōki-san's production company.
That's why, thanks to Ōki-san and Sakakibara-san's connections,
most of the actors this time are
working for lower pay than usual.
Don't tell me that you are too, Andrew-san?
Yes. We go back a long way.
The director said that old friends had gathered for the first time in ages.
Yeah...
Sakakibara-san, Ōki-san, O-Chiyo-san, and Sazanami-san and I've worked together since the days before we became popular.
Tatsumi-san too, of course.
Really?
They hadn't cast anyone for the role of Glover but me,
so they decided that we'd be a middle-aged couple, with me already married to Tsuru.
Maybe Tatsumi-san didn't agree with that.
He was someone who liked to respect reality.
So is that why he abandoned the script and vanished?
I don't know...
Dutch Slope
Higashiyamate No.13
Uncle Kogorō told me to ask you just in case.
Well, I don't know. How about you, Bara-chan?
Me neither. Finding bits of info was a secret hobby of Tatsumi's.
Hey, what're you doing?! It's only a matter of time now.
Hey, kid.
You're the kid who was with Mouri-san, aren't you?
Nagasaki Museum of History and Culture
In 1582,
the Tenshō embassy to Europe
left Nagasaki
Dad, Futaba-san says she was born in Nagasaki.
And since my parts in the current script are all done filming,
I thought I could help you by being a guide...
Oh, that's a big help.
Visiting famous places with a beautiful actress tour guide!
Running your mouth off again, I see.
We visited the places related to the notes and photos
Site of Kameyama Shachū
that Tatsumi-san made when creating this drama.
This pistol's the one Kid...
Yeah.
Kazagashira Park - Statue of Sakamoto Ryōma
'The dawn of Japan is close!'
Nagasaki 'Flag' Archive
In Nagasaki, we call kites 'flags'.
Spectacles Bridge
Ah, that's Spectacles Bridge.
Conan-kun, gimme yours.
Ah, how interesting!
Ran-neechan, give them back!
Just a bit more.
Geez...
Man, I'm so hungry...
That's...
It can't be! It's Sleeping Kogorō!
Shikairō
This is the shop that invented Champon.
I'm looking forward to eating it!
Their Sara Udon's pretty tasty, too.
That thing's cute.
Ah, this?
I bought it at a shop by Glover Garden.
Oh, I've been waiting for this!
It looks tasty!
Delicious! It's the best!
It's really tasty, right, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Aren't you going to eat?
Well, actually, a few days ago, Tatsumi-sensei was almost hit by a car.
What'd you say?!
He said that he thought someone pushed him.
Really?!
Why didn't you mention it earlier?!
W-Well...
Anyway, Tatsumi-sensei might've disappeared because he thought his life was in danger.
In the end, we didn't find any usable clues.
Tatsumi-sensei!
Futaba-san!
Is that Tatsumi-san?!
We lost him...
Why was she running so desperately?
Hello?
Ah, Ōki-san.
What?! Tatsumi-san sent part two of the script in an e-mail?!
And is the culprit's name in it?
What? It's still not finished?
Dejima
Look out!
A-Are you okay?!
S-Somehow...
It's strange, they were fixed in place...
Please, be careful.
Even so, that was amazing, young lady. Was that karate?
Though she may not look it, she won the Kantō Tournament. She's the Champion!
Trading Post Chief's House
The second part of script that was e-mailed was also unfinished.
And in it, a second murder was depicted.
The crime scene was the Dejima Trading Post Chief's house.
The victim was a spy employed by the Nagasaki magistrate's office,
and he left the kanji numeral nine as a dying message.
So what'd he say?
For further information, ask the daughter of the Miura shipping agency, O-Tei.
Cut! Okay!
Though we've ended up with no holes in the schedule, the problem is what to do now...
Which means?
Without any foreshadowing, a new character's suddenly appeared.
The character has lots of puzzling lines, and I think it's an important role, but...
We don't have any actor to play the character, nor time or money to bring someone from Tōkyō.
That's a disaster!
Yes, a disast—
You, how old are you?!
I'm seventeen.
That's it! That's what we can do!
Don't tell me...
We're borrowing this!
You're kidding! I can't do this! It's too much...
I won't! I won't do it!
Help me, Dad, Conan-kun!
Go for it.
Go for it!
No! It's the wrong way up!
Amateurs are so useless!
S-Sorry...
Ah, that was my fault.
Hey, will this really work?
This isn't some school's art festival.
Don't worry. Relax.
If you can at least say your lines, we'll take care of the rest somehow.
Ah, r-r-r-right...
Then, try practising your lines.
You can start off by looking at the script.
Ah! Wait a moment!
Okay, start!
S-S-Sakamoto-sama, I-I am the daughter of the Miura family, O-Tei.
W-What may I do for you?
Well, isn't that a 'dress', like a Western girl would wear?
The daughter of the Miura family is famous throughout town for wearing exotic clothes!
By the way, the man in the Trading Post Chief's House.
He left behind the number nine.
Do you know anything about it?
Nine?
Numbers are important.
Numbers will solve everything.
Right?
Ah, yes, Miss.
Why me too?
Cut! Okay!
Take a break!
What a weird line.
'Numbers will solve everything.'
That reminds me, a lot of the actors in the production have numbers in their names.
Andrew Hatta-san who plays Glover has one, right?
Playing his wife, Tsuru, is Benichiyo Yamashita-san.
Right. Futaba-san's surname is Nanao too.
There's some in the staff too.
Ōki-san's name is Taizō.
Sakota-san's is Kazuomi.
Sakamoto-sama, did you know?
There's a demon living here in Nakashima River.
What?
But you need not worry.
The demon's weak point is the second tooth from the left in its lower jaw.
Cut! Okay!
The demon's weak point...
Yet another puzzling line.
What's this?
The font changes just for this line.
Could this mean...?!
Could these lines be a message from Tatsumi-san?
And if O-Tei of the Miura family is a character created to convey that message...
Then it must be about the reason for his disappearance!
Then that means...
Serial Art Theft Case
Illegally Sold
Among Fans
A Large-Scale Smuggling Organisation
That is all that I know.
Now, next I'll guide you to the first ever Western-style restaurant.
I've had enough! Let me out of this!
He was probably punched. And with bare hands.
Hold on! Sakota!
Where's the ambulance?!
I've called it! It'll be here soon!
Damn it! Who got you?!
Huh? Me?
What?!
Ran?!
I-It can't be!
The karate champion?
It can't be... I...
H-Hey, Sakota! Hold on!
Sakota!
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
Edogawa
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Where are you now?
I'm just about to leave.
At the viewing platform... I was suddenly attacked by someone.
That's it! I've got it!
The meaning of the dying message is...
The person who attacked Sakota-san and Sazanami-san...
it was you, Ran!
On the next Conan: 'The Nagasaki Mystery Theatre (Present Day Case)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Kanji Stroke Order!
Look forward to the next episode!
Dad, when did I—?!
Sleeping Ran, huh?
I'll save you for sure.