A mystery drama where Sakamoto Ryōma takes on a detective role in Nagasaki of the Bakumatsu period.
The scriptwriter writing the scenario,
Kōsaku Tatsumi-san, suddenly vanished,
Kōsaku Tatsumi (45)
Scriptwriter
and with the scenario not even half finished, the old man was asked to deduce the drama's culprit.
When we took a look at Tatsumi-san's place, we found articles about art thieves pinned up in the closet, as if to hide them.
Serial Art Theft Case
.
It seems there's something else going on here.
Then, while still on the run, Tatsumi-san continued the scenario in an e-mail.
In it, a second murder occurs, and an unscheduled character, O-Tei of the Miura family appears,
and Ran ended up being dragged in to play O-Tei.
And because of that, I ended up like this.
Also, O-Tei has many curious lines, and for just those lines, a different font is used in the script.
Could these lines be a message from Tatsumi-san?
Then, an incident occurred.
The Prop Master, Sakota-san, was attacked by someone.
What?!
Ran?!
Ran's the culprit?!
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
Can the Bakumatsu Drama be finished?!
The suspicious staff hide secrets upon secrets.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
'Detective Conan'
Serialised in Shōgakukan's 'Weekly Shōnen Sunday'
Original Comics by
Gōshō Aoyama
© Gōshō Aoyama / Shōgakukan · Yomiuri TV · TMS 1996
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(       )
Opening Theme
'Kimi no namida ni kon'na ni Koishite'ru'
Performed by:
Lyrics:
Music:
Arrangement:
Natsu-Iro
Nayu Okuno
Aika Ōno
Takeshi Hayama
(D-GO)
Planning Assistance
Hiroshi Torimitsu
Kazumasa Ogura
Masakazu Hakuya
Producers
Shūichi Kitada
Takeshi Yamakawa
Associate Producer
Mitomu Asai
(      )
(TMS/V1 Studio)
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
Kei'ichi Ishiyama
(      )
(TMS/V1 Studio)
The Nagasaki Mystery Theatre
(Present Day Case)
The wounds on Sakota-san's face were found to be from being punched by bare hands,
Kazuomi Sakota (35)
Prop Master
so the Nagasaki Police are questioning Ran, a black belt in karate, as a suspect.
I don't know.
I was learning my lines alone then.
Can anyone verify that?
I don't really know...
Ah! Something yellow went past me...
What was it?
No good, I can't remember.
It was around here that Ran was learning her lines...
The only yellow things here are the flowers...
So it was a witness!
I've no choice but to look for someone who saw Ran there when it happened.
This is...
Puccini Statue
Puccini, the composer of the opera 'Madame Butterfly'.
chōchō
And the opera singer who played the heroine Madame Butterfly, Tamaki Miura...
Tamaki Miura Statue
Miura?
Is there some connection to Ran's role, O-Tei of the Miura family?
Sakota-san was an opera lover too...
Just like Tamaki Miura-san, Teiko Kiwa-san is famous for playing Madame Butterfly.
Tamaki Miura and Teiko Kiwa...
O-Tei of the Miura family!
Shōkichi Shimizu (68)
Nagasaki Saruku Guide
Well then, let's move on to the next exhibit.
Yellow?
Hey, mister!
Have you seen this girl?
Yeah, I remember her.
I saw her engrossed reading something on a bench.
Thanks to the testimony of the guide, Shimizu-san, the suspicion on Ran was lifted.
But then why had Sakota-san pointed at Ran?
Well, here I am.
I just heard from the detectives that a man who looks like Tatsumi was seen in the area.
Oh no...
Is that true?
Apparently after hearing screams from the parking lot, he ran off...
Taizō Ōki (52)
Drama Production Company Producer
That's a lie!
Futaba Nanao (23)
As Karasuma Ine
Ryūhei Kishimura (30)
Assistant Director
Tatsumi-sensei wouldn't...
It's gotta be a lie!
Do you know something we don't?
Ah, no...
I mean that, well, Tatsumi-san writes such brilliant scripts that I'm sure he wouldn't do something like that...
Let's leave the case to the police.
Keisuke Sakakibara (45)
TV Drama Director
Akikazu Nakane (48)
Cameraman
And Mouri-san, the culprit in the drama...
Well, about that...
Hey, I wonder why Sakota-san was in this parking lot?
Wasn't it too early for him to be going home?
The script had been continued, so you had to keep filming, so it's like he tried to sneak off.
Sneak off...?
That's it!
Sakota-san read through the script, and realising he was in danger, he tried to run off!
In other words, Tatsumi predicted that Sakota would be attacked,
and left him a message in the script!
It's likely contained in the dying message, 'nine'!
Then what does the nine mean?
It's pointing at you!
Futaba Nanao-san!
It can't be!
But why?
Simple addition.
If you add the the two of Futaba and the seven of Nanao, you get nine!
Basically, it was a message saying that Futaba-san was targeting him, so he should be careful.
That can't be!
Then why did you volunteer to be our guide?
Was it not to find Tatsumi-san quickly so you could silence him just like Sakota-san?!
Y-You're wrong!
I was just worried about Tatsumi-sensei...
This seems like a bit of a stretch,
Benichiyo Yamashita (42)
As Tsuru
2 + 7 = 9...
The day's already over, so I'll be leaving for today.
Ah, not yet...
Oh well. Let's stop filming for today then.
Hm? What's wrong, Ōki-chan?
Hey, Bara-chan, I just remembered,
in her prime, O-Chiyo-san was quite a famous actress for action stuff.
Is that true?!
That's right, she did some Chinese martial arts.
Though even Chō-san played a boxer once...
Gimme a break, that was over twenty years ago!
Chōjirō Sazanami (45)
As Soneya Chūbee
Kyōnosuke Sasahara (33)
As Sakamoto Ryōma
What a mess...
More suspects keep popping up, and they're all actors...
Hey, last night Andrew-san said Tatsumi-san may've been upset
since Glover and Tsuru being married
wasn't historically accurate.
Was he?
No, he wasn't.
Tatsumi's the one who suggested that.
Andrew Hatta (50)
As Glover
Is that true?
Yeah, though it's unusual for him.
Where are you now?
I'm just about to leave.
Yes, that's right...
Yeah... But do something about it, I'm begging you!
Nagasaki Ropeway
It's wonderful...
Should we take a look?
Mt. Inasa Viewing Platform
Sazanami-san was attacked?!
The police just told me...
It was at the Mt. Inasa Viewing Platform.
What was he doing there?
I thought I'd take a look at the world-
renowned night view of Nagasaki.
And then I was suddenly attacked by someone...
I probably tore that off them in the struggle.
It seems Tatsumi's fingerprints were on that strap.
What sort of strap was it?
It was shaped like a silver heart.
A silver heart...
No way!
Teramachi Street
Okay, quiet.
Don't look at the cameras, okay?
Right!
Why me too...?
Conan-kun's so cute!
I told you, I know that already!
He's always doing that...
Ready! Action!
Cut!
Hey, the stroke order's wrong.
I'll rewind it.
That's not the first stroke, the sweeping stroke is!
That one was the same!
Ah, as for that, see, a picture was attached to the script.
He said to make it just like this.
Like I thought...
'Ask O-Tei of the Miura family'...
'Numbers are important. Numbers will solve everything'...
Tamaki Miura and Teiko Kiwa, who played Madame Butterfly...
Nine written in the wrong order...
Madame Butterfly...
Chōchō...
That's it! I've got it!
The meaning of the dying message is...
"A demon lives here in Nakashima River."...
"Its weak point is the second tooth from the left in its lower jaw."...
Ah! Sorr—
Conan-kun, do that thing!
With your glasses!
Huh? This?
Yeah! That's it!
So that's it!
Got it.
A letter arrived from Tatsumi-san!
It says he'll give us the rest of the script if we go to O-Shirasu.
O-Shirasu?
Nagasaki Museum of History and Culture
Did you really get a letter from Tatsumi-san?!
Yes, saying he'd give us the rest of the script here.
O-Shirasu Theatre
This is...?
A theatre where plays are performed.
Are your wounds okay?
Yeah, they're not too bad.
Tatsumi's not here yet?!
So all the actors are here.
Before Tatsumi-san comes...
I, Kogorō Mouri, will reveal the culprit to the real life case of who attacked Sakota-san and Sazanami-san!
Are you saying it wasn't Tatsumi-san?
But Tatsumi's fingerprints were on that strap.
That strap was a trap set by the culprit!
The true culprit... is you!
Kyōnosuke Sasahara-san!
What? Me?!
Among the staff and cast, many people have numbers in their names.
And you do too, Sasahara-san!
Where in my name?
The kyō in Kyōnosuke Sasahara is a numerical unit if read as kei!
So what?
The dying message in the script was also a number!
So what about it?!
Well... I mean...
Haven't you always been making phone calls to someone?
And having arguments with them!
T-That's...
Was it not Tatsumi-san
that you were arguing with?
No! It's...
Okay, I'll tell you the truth!
I was arguing with my agency.
The truth is...
I have... a wife and child...
Oh, this is the first I've heard.
Even though you're a regular in
most-wanted boyfriend rankings?!
A weekly magazine found out, and I was being advertised as single, so I told my agency to stop them...
See!
.
Ah, so that's what was going on...
Then, Benichiyo-san!
Didn't you go out the night Sazanami-san was attacked?
Huh? Now I'm your suspect?
Where to?!
D-Do I really have to say?
O-Chiyo-san, don't tell me...!
Didn't you go eat Turkish rice?
Nagasaki
Specialty!
Turkish Rice
Correct.
I'm supposed to be on a diet for my next job.
But I couldn't resist the Nagasaki specialty, Turkish rice!
T-Then the culprit—
Spinning around again...
I apologise for that. Now for the real thing.
Oh! This is the famous Sleeping Kogorō!
Bring the camera!
Right.
I wrote the letter that arrived from Tatsumi-san this morning.
What?!
So I could formally reveal the person who attacked Sakota-san and Sazanami-san.
The culprit was...
...you, Ran!
What?!
Oh no...
It was her...?
H-Hold on a sec, Dad!
Calm down and listen, Ran.
In the script, what was the dying message at the second murder?
What?
It was the kanji numeral nine.
Yes.
However, the stroke order was wrong.
You can see by looking at the marks left in the dirt.
Basically, the dying message was not the number nine,
but the hiragana te.
Te?
In other words, Ran, it was pointing to your role, O-Tei of the Miura family.
Of course, that's for the case in the drama.
However, I thought that Tatsumi-san's script was intended to reveal something about a real case at the same time.
A real case?!
Look closely at the script.
The font is different on specific lines.
If they're a message from Tatsumi-san...
First, O-Tei's lines.
Numbers are important. Numbers will solve everything.
With this line and the dying message, Tatsumi-san
was pointing to a letter connected with
the number in a certain person's name.
That is...
Chōjirō Sazanami-san's chō!
That's...
It can't be!
Sazanami-san?
What're you saying, Mouri-san?!
I'm saying that the culprit in a series of cases is you.
Wait!
For chō, shouldn't chi have been left instead of te?
That's right!
In the old Japanese kana orthography,
'butterfly' was written tefutefu.
Where'd you get butterfly from all of a sudden!
Tatsumi-san's messages were closely connected with Madame Butterfly.
For further information, ask the daughter of the Miura shipping agency, O-Tei.
This font was different for this line too.
If 'O-Tei of the Miura family'
was named after the opera singers who played Madame Butterfly,
Tamaki Miura-san and Teiko Kiwa-san, then O-Tei is connected with Madame Butterfly.
Basically, the dying message was the te of tefutefu.
So that's it!
Y-You're twisting facts!
One theory is that the model for Madame Butterfly was Glover's wife, Tsuru.
The reason Tatsumi-san even went against historical fact to include Tsuru in the drama was to prepare for this message.
In other words, Tatsumi meant to reveal Chō-san in his script from the very start?
Probably.
But the case hadn't happened until after that.
What Tatsumi-san was revealing was another case.
Another case?!
The only one who realised it was the opera lover, Sakota-san.
And when trying to escape by himself before I could solve the mystery, he was attacked by you.
The reason Sakota-san pointed at Ran was because O-Tei was a character created to reveal Sazanami-san.
Wait a sec!
Then they're both accomplices in something?!
Conan!
Here!
These were at Tatsumi's place...
Don't tell me it's about this?!
Gimme a break!
I was attacked by Tatsumi after that!
That was your own performance.
In order to incriminate Tatsumi-san.
What?!
That's awful...
T-That's bull!
I guess I have no choice.
Let me show you some conclusive proof.
Do you remember O-Tei's line, 'A demon lives here in Nakashima River'?
Conan!
This is the demon.
Demon? Isn't that Spectacles Bridge?
But you know, if you do this...
See? It looks like a demon, right?
You're right.
So the demon's weak point being the second tooth from the left in its lower jaw meant this stepping stone.
Uncle Kogorō told me to check it, and last night I found this there.
This Micro SD card.
Mister, will you show us what's on it?
S-Sure...
They're not gonna use these props anymore, so let's put them in here.
Plenty more easy money.
T-This is...?!
As you saw, the stolen works of art were hidden in the props used for filming,
and when they arrived on location, were secretly sold to collectors or rich people.
This video proves it.
Tatsumi-san tried to reveal this in the script for the drama, but hid as he felt he was in danger.
But he found out Mouri-san had arrived, and tried to sneak clues in when continuing the script, right?
Sleeping Kogorō, solve this puzzle!
That's just like him.
So where is Tatsumi-sensei?
Sazanami-san knows where he is.
I-I don't know...
Why should I...
Tell me!
Where's Sensei... Where is Kōsaku-san?!
You can't talk your way out of this, Sazanami-san.
After all, you're the one who had the strap with Tatsumi-san's fingerprints on it.
Futaba-chan, don't tell me you...
...and Tatsumi are...
Yes. The reason she offered to help me was because she wanted to save her beloved, Tatsumi-san.
Is that true?
But my agency bans relationships, so I had to keep it a secret.
I'm sorry!
But if he had this much evidence, why didn't Tatsumi-san go to the police?
I'm sure he wanted him to give himself in.
In this drama with all his old friends in,
he wanted to force Sazanami to repent.
Kōsaku-san!
Futaba!
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Koi ni Koishite
(Falling in love)
(Mai Kuraki)
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
.
Shin’
Shin’i
.
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
.
K
Shin’
.
Shin
Shin’ich
.
Shin’ichi Kudō
In the ICU, Sakota-san regained consciousness, and supported the case with his testimony.
The art theft ring they were part of will likely be unmasked someday.
The drama's filming resumed.
Of course, as well as removing scenes including Sazanami-san, Ran and me, Tatsumi-san rapidly fixed up a new script.
I heard the agency's supported their relationship!
That's good for them!
And did you know?
If you write Nagasaki in rōmaji,
ai
it ends in love.
Just like for those two...
Is this the cactus we heard about?
Mister!
Bro, then you really did...
No! I didn't do it!
I see. So that's what happened.
Then the killer is...
With that alarm, I figured everything out.
What?
Cactus Capriccio
On the next Conan: 'Cactus Capriccio'!
Next Conan's Hint: Heater!
Dad's so cool when he's asleep!
Look forward to the next episode!
But Ran-neechan has a horn
that makes her look like a cactus!