Is this the cactus we heard about?
It's called a Golden Barrel Cactus,
and takes 50 years until its flowers bloom.
50 years?
Yeah.
I've raised it myself
since it was this small.
Zenzō Sunada (66)
Wealthy Person
Before I noticed, it'd already grown this big
and started blooming.
Then you've been raising it since
you were Ran-neechan's age?
That's right, kid.
Sonoko-chan came here with her father to see it once.
Really? Did that actually happen?
Of course you won't remember it.
You were just a toddler back then.
Really?
Anyway, where're these important flowers?
They're blooming up there.
Surrounded by spines, the yellow blooms look like a crown of feathers.
They do! How cute!
They seem kinda odd...
Indeed.
Vivid summer memories surpass their season to solve mysteries!
Rare cacti and painful spines in a
greenhouse with flawless security.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
You really do have lots of cacti though.
But some of them are valuable, aren't they?
Don't thieves try and get in?
Actually, I've got a custom alarm system.
When night comes, I'm the only one that can turn it off with this card.
It looks like some smartcard from a train station.
B-But why's it in your breast pocket?
I feel most at ease when I keep important things here.
Dad!
What is it, you two?
Yasuyuki Sunada (36)
Pro Golfer
Naoki Sunada (33)
Import Car Dealer
We heard from the lawyer.
You changed your will?!
Be quiet! There are guests here.
Shut up! Just answer!
Don't argue with me! Get out!
Your words'll rot the cacti!
It's no use, Bro... Let's come back later.
We'll get a proper answer out of you later!
Damn.
Honestly... and when the Golden Barrel's finally in bloom.
Yashiro!
Yashiro, you here?!
Yes, I just arrived.
Misa Yashiro (27)
Housekeeper
How may I please you, master?
What exactly are those?!
I told you not to use bisque flowerpots!
Put them away now!
My apologies.
He's scary...
Excuse me.
Seems like we've come at quite a time.
Apparently he used to be known as 'Demon Zenzō' and was quite a shrewd person.
Ah, how embarrassing. Though
I yelled at her, Yashiro does her job well.
Her cooking's superb.
R-Really...?
Completely different from my useless sons.
Well then, I'll go back to the mansion for a while, so please, look round at your own pace.
Sure!
What're you doing?
D-Dad...
I asked you, what are you doing?!
I-Isn't it obvious?!
Unfortunately, what you're looking for is in here.
WILL
Is it true that you're not leaving us an inheritance?
Together with the cacti, I'm donating it to a botanical garden.
W-What'd you say?!
You sound disappointed.
So you'd give your money to your cacti instead of your own sons?!
Of course! What sort of job's a pro golfer?
I won't give money to sons who're all grown up and are still nipping at their father's heels!
What?!
Still, we came all the way out here to see them and they're only some tiny little flowers.
Don't say that.
We should be thankful that we were allowed to see some extremely rare flowers.
Hey, what do you think that is?
Isn't it a hot-water radiator?
It's probably maintaining the temperature in the greenhouse.
Yeah, I know!
I think this is the heat contro—
Hot!
Hey, Sonoko, are you okay?!
Then how can I get you to change your will back?!
Hmph! As long as you don't intend to inherit my work, I'll never change it!
You're telling me to stop golfing?!
You're a third-rate golfer who'll always get beaten in the preliminaries anyway!
Now you've gone and said it, that's just what I'm gonna do!
That's my line!
Fine, I get it! I'll just do what I want too then!
Hmm? What're you up to?
Ah, well...
You just came here to extort money out of him anyway.
You've been sneaking around too, Bro.
What?!
Please stop!
You're in front of the master's room!
Think I care?!
You're too loud!
You come back for the first time in ages, and the only thing you can talk about is money?!
You're wrong... I'm concerned about you, Dad...
Liar.
I've heard the import car dealership you
only just set up's already out of money!
What sort of concern is that?
And don't bother sucking up to him.
The only thing he can even think about is cacti.
Don't go picking fights, Bro...
Calm down for now and let's try and persuade him again tonight.
We're back!
Ah, looking at all that made me hungry somehow.
Geez, it's like the phrase 'dumplings over flowers' was made for you.
Conan-kun!
Ow ow...
You okay?!
What're you doing!
Sorry...
Geez.
I'm so sorry.
Um... this.
Oh, thanks.
Ah, Yashiro-san.
Yes?
Bring my dinner to my room.
Understood.
Yasuyuki-san seems different.
He gives me a bad feeling.
Ah, I'm full!
My stomach's bursting.
Sonoko, you ate too much.
You kept asking for more.
I can't help it.
When food's tasty, a girl wants to eat.
Yashiro-san!
Yes?
I'm going to go and practise golf outside.
I'll go and look at the cars in the garage.
See you later.
Yashiro-san, thanks for the meal.
It was really tasty.
Would you tell me the recipe for your gravy sauce?
Hmm? Who do you want to make eat it?
Could it be your husband?
No! Honestly, Sonoko...
I am honoured to have pleased you.
Would you like some after-dinner coffee?
We should be going about now.
Is your master still in the greenhouse?
Yes. He tends to his cacti every night from 8 to 9 PM, without fail.
Then we'll go say goodbye.
Oh, but the master instructed me that
he was not to be disturbed until 8:30.
Would you wait a while longer?
Then I'll have an after-dinner nap!
I wonder if I'll get fat.
Oh, Sonoko, really...
You're worrying about that now?
Yasuyuki-san?!
No! It wasn't me!
What happened?!
T-That...!
Isn't that his will?!
I-I...
Oh no!
Mister?!
Mister!
The cause of death was cerebral contusion  from being hit from behind by a shovel.
The estimated time of death is 8 to 8:30 PM.
And the first on the scene was...
Geez...The brats I always see at crime scenes...
Hey, tell me what happened when you found the corpse.
Umm...
After dinner, we were talking in the living room, and at about 8:30, the greenhouse's alarm bell rang.
So we ran over along with the housekeeper, Yashiro-san, and Yasuyuki-san was in front of the greenhouse.
Yasuyuki-san?
Yasuyuki-san was holding Zenzō-san's will!
His will?
It seems that Mr. Zenzō changed his will lately.
Right after that, Yashiro-san ran into the greenhouse with us following behind her,
and Zenzō-san had been...
Hey, go hear the others' stories.
Right.
I told you, when the alarm bell rang,
I rushed in and Dad had collapsed!
Why were you at the greenhouse when you went to practise golf?
T-That's because Dad sent me this e-mail.
Look.
Come to the
greenhouse at
8:30.
- Zenzō
I see...
Received at 8:20...
And on the victim's phone?
Also sent at 8:20 to Yasuyuki-san.
Which means the vic was alive till then.
And the will?
Weren't you standing outside the greenhouse holding the will?
W-Well...
From my Dad's breast pocket, I...
Bro, then you really did...?
No! I didn't do it! Believe me!
This had been dropped beside the corpse, do you recognise it?
A golf ball marker!
T-That's Yasuyuki-san's...
Bro!
I-I don't know how it got there...
Believe me! I didn't do it!
I didn't kill my Dad! Believe me!
Receiving an e-mail from the victim, you headed to the greenhouse under the pretense of golf practice.
Having been invited in by the victim, you began arguing about the will,
and enraged, picked up a nearby shovel and beat Zenzō-san to death!
So you'd get the inheritance, you stole his will and fled.
Then you triggered the alarm system and the alarm rang!
Am I wrong?
W-Well...
Hey, Inspector Yokomizo.
The card to turn off the alarm should've been in Zenzō-san's breast pocket too.
So why wouldn't he take that too?
If he had, the alarm wouldn't have rung.
The deactivation card was in the victim's breast pocket...
Having hit his dad, he'd obviously be panicking, right?
And another thing.
What now?!
A potted pillar cactus was knocked down next to Zenzō-san.
But when we first looked around in here, it wasn't knocked down.
That's because either the killer or the victim knocked it over when struggling!
Then isn't it odd?
What?!
The earth that spilt out of the pot is all dry.
Would it really dry out that much in just an hour?
And also, cactus spines are stuck in Zenzō-san's chest area.
That's enough! I'm tired of having brats sticking their noses into every single investigation!
Go away!
Okay.
They've withered?
Could it be...?!
This...?!
I see. So that's what happened.
Which means the killer...
...must be that person!
Why?!
Why do you have to take me in?!
I'll hear what you have to say at the station.
So stop complaining and get in.
I told you, I didn't do it! Honest!
What is it? Did something happen?
No, not really...
But the alarm's ringing!
Sonoko?!
W-What?
H-Hey...
With that alarm, I figured everything out.
What?
It was an alibi trick using the alarm system.
The incident took place before Yasuyuki-san entered the greenhouse.
First, when Mr. Zenzō entered the greenhouse at around 8 PM,
the killer secretly crept in... and committed the crime.
Then, in order to frame Yasuyuki-san for it, they left at the scene a golf ball marker that only Yasuyuki-san should have.
Afterwards, using one of the fingers from the victim's corpse, the killer tapped out an e-mail calling Yasuyuki-san over,
and to conclusively prove their own alibi, scheduled it to be sent at 8:20.
If you check with the phone company, they should confirm it.
Also, the killer used the card to turn off the alarm which was in the victim's breast pocket and left the greenhouse,
then stealthily returned to the mansion by the back door, which can't be seen from the living room.
And then...
Straight after running over to the crime scene, the killer returned the card to the corpse's breast pocket.
That's why when Yasuyuki-san stole the will, he didn't notice the card.
As of course, the killer had it at the time.
Which means...
When the alarm rang, the greenhouse was empty.
Then why did the alarm ring?
That was a key to their trick, a trap set by the killer using an unexpected property of the alarm system.
Look on top of that radiator.
Two bisque flowerpots have been placed on it.
The greenhouse's alarm system checks for the small amount of far infrared rays the human body gives off and rings the bell.
When the pottery of bisque flowerpots is heated, they too give off the same far infrared rays as humans.
The killer used that.
Will that really ring the alarm?
I just conducted an experiment.
Sonoko-neechan told me to put those flowerpots on there.
I see. That's why the alarm rang just now...
The situation was the same as when Yasuyuki-san entered the crime scene.
The bell did its task, and rang.
And there's only one person who could've commited this crime.
Misa Yashiro-san...
Only you could've done it!
Yashiro-san...
That was an interesting tale.
But that's simply a theory.
Do you have any proof that I'm the killer, I wonder?
When the killer beat the victim to death, he happened to knock over a cactus.
But the killer had to move the cactus from the corpse.
In order to steal the card to turn off the alarm.
When doing so, cactus spines got stuck into their hands.
In other words, whoever has those wounds is the killer.
Misa-san, if you say you aren't the killer, then by all means, show me your hands.
I've lost.
Just like you said, I'm the killer.
T-These're...
But how did you know?
The cacti told me.
When I arrived at the crime scene, the earth spilt from the cactus's pot had already begun to dry out.
And the flowers that were blooming this afternoon had for some reason withered.
Then I had a flash of insight.
I figured it was connected to the temperature in the greenhouse.
Another key to solving the trick was the flowerpots.
The flowerpots which you had been scolded about and should have been tidied away
somehow remained at the crime scene after the murder.
So I was certain.
The killer could only be Misa-san.
After all, you were the only one who'd
know where you'd put the flowerpots.
I...
I despised Zenzō Sunada...
When he was working, his management led other companies to go bankrupt one after another,
driving many managers to commit suicide.
One of them was my father, who'd raised me without any help...
When Sunada retired, and advertised for a housekeeper,
I decided that I'd get revenge with my own hands.
And seeing those perfect examples of prodigal sons who only had eyes for their father's fortune...
I thought, why not frame one of them?
Yashiro-san...
When I heard you were coming so suddenly, I did have second thoughts.
But it was now or never!
Today, the family who spent all their time apart were all assembled...
Let's hear the rest at the station.
Okay...
Misa-san...
It's not that I don't understand your hate for Mr. Zenzō.
You lost your dear father because of him.
But even so...
Taking someone's life in revenge is never right!
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
Edogawa
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
I'm so tired for some reason.
You were really cool though, Sonoko.
Solving a hard case like that.
That so?
Even the hardest case is no match for the
Super Detective Deduction Queen, Sonoko-sama!
Honestly... All you did was sleep.
sabotten
Don't go slackin' off!
saboten
Only with a cactus.
In front of the Police HQ, a man gave
the Detective Boys a tablet computer.
Shown on it is a video of Detective Takagi in big trouble.
On the next Conan: 'The Life-threatening Broadcast of Love (Begin Broadcasting)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Date!