Happy New Year!
Did you have a fun New Year's Day?
Did you get lots of New Year's money?
Did you eat too much New Year's food and get a tummy ache?
Thanks to all of you supporting us,
Detective Conan has reached its 18th year.
This year too, we'll keep solving more and more cases, so...
the Detective Boys hope you'll enjoy Detective Conan!
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
Our 18th year opens with those two detectives' love story?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
Just a sec, Mr. Detective.
Yumi-san!
Going to a stakeout?
Nah.
I got let off early today.
There's somewhere I've gotta go now.
Well, I'll stay there tonight and be back first thing in the morning.
Now what could that be?
An overnight date with Miwako at a hot spring?
No...
It's not a date.
No way! You don't know where Takagi-kun went either, Miwako?
No.
Inspector Megure said he had to go and report to a certain someone.
Could that someone be your parents, Satō-san?
To say "Give me your daughter!" or something.
Now see here.
If so, then why wouldn't he tell me?
And my mother lives in Tōkyō, so he wouldn't need to stay overnight...
Wait, who are you?
I'm Naeko Mi'ike, I transferred here from the Haido Police!
A-Ah, I see...
Wouldn't Inspector Megure know
who this "certain someone" is?
It seems like he really didn't say.
He just said he'd say once he got back and settled in.
It sounds suspicious.
Doesn't it?
Well, I don't think it's a love affair.
He said straight out that it wasn't a date.
Geez.
I wonder if he's forgotten the anniversary of Date-san's death?
That's right, it's been almost a year...
And he's the one who suggested we visit his grave together...
Who?
The detective who tutored Takagi-kun.
He was such a tough guy who wouldn't die even if he was killed, and then so easily, in a traffic accident, he...
Then could he have gone to say something to that detective's parents...?
No, both of Date-san's parents live in Tōkyō.
Which means it really is connected with some woman...
Now I think about it, Takagi-san's
popular at the Traffic Department.
Well, not quite as much as Miwako.
Damn you, Takagi!
Oh no... I wonder if I caught a cold.
Luna Airlines' Flight 299 to Tottori leaving at 19:35 has now begun check-in.
Passengers for this flight, please head to Gate 18.
Satō-san, I...
I seem to have lost confidence in my ability to make you happy...
The Detective Boys've finally done it!
We're gonna be models for pamphlets in a crime-prevention project for children!
Yeah! It's because we've solved lots of cases!
What're we gonna do? We're gonna get famous!
I wonder if the Doctor's alright...
He said he'd come straight over after parking his car, but...
He was really coughing a lot.
Did he catch a cold?
And Detective Takagi's late too.
He said to phone him when we got to Police HQ for him to guide us around the PR department that's running it,
but he's not answering at all.
Maybe he's gone off flirting again?
Kissing just like before!
I don't think even Detective Takagi'd do that on duty...
That's right!
Hmm?
Are you acquainted with Detective Wataru Takagi?
Yes, we are, but why...?
That's a stroke of good luck.
I've got a gift from him, see?
I want you to give this to the senior detective he's in love with.
Oh, you mean Detective Satō, who we were just talking about?
Hmm? You're acquainted with that female detective too?
Yes.
Though she's scary and as strong as an ox.
Now, now...
But she's really really pretty!
Yeah!
Aren't they getting married soon or something?
Right?
They're totally in love!
Then here's a message from him for that happy female detective.
'That is perishable, so open it quickly.
If you delay, tomorrow and the next day it'll be no good.'
Hey!
Ah, Conan-kun!
Then I'll leave it in your hands.
What did that guy want?
It seems he's an acquaintance of Detective Takagi.
Never mind that, where's the Doc and Haibara?
Seems like the Doc really did catch a cold.
He went back home with Haibara.
Well, he's just faking it.
We couldn't let Haibara have her picture put on pamphlets, after all.
Then Haibara-san'll miss out, how disappointing...
It's disappointing for me too.
I thought I'd get to meet this "Dr. Agasa"
that I'd heard rumors about.
A-Amuro-san?!
I heard from Mouri-sensei that you Detective Boys
were going in Dr. Agasa's car today to have your pictures taken at Police HQ for a pamphlet.
As I told him I had to go to Police HQ too.
Though that's already finished.
Why were you called here?
It was about that case where I crashed my car into the car your kidnapper was driving to stop it.
They asked me back in for questioning in deciding whether I'd gone too far.
That reminds me, Sera said she was called back to Police HQ too.
Though what she did was going 100% too far...
Well, I did have another reason for coming here too.
Another reason?
Oh, don't worry about it.
That reason doesn't matter anymore.
Hey, Conan.
Who was that guy?
A detective. He's old man Kogorō's apprentice.
He's a detective?!
He's really handsome!
Anyway, hasn't Detective Takagi come?
It seems like he forgot.
He's not answering his phone.
Well then, let's try phoning Detective Chiba.
In that case...
Let's call Detective Satō!
Since this is perishable!
What?!
Takagi-kun was looking at a sticker from
a photo booth in his notebook and crying?!
Yeah...
At a glance, it looked like a cute sticker, but when I asked if it was of you...
Don't be so stupid!
...he got really angry...
S-Stupid?!
He said he'd explain why himself, so I shouldn't say anything...
Hey! Where's Takagi-kun?!
I don't know... I haven't seen him yet today.
Hello?
Huh? Conan-kun?
A-A gift for me from Takagi-kun?
That's what the guy you didn't recognize said?
Yeah!
Here it is!
What's with him... He didn't even come in to work.
Detective Takagi hasn't arrived yet?
He said it's perishable, so make sure to eat it tomorrow or the next day!
But...
This doesn't look edible.
A tablet PC?
Then maybe it's a video letter?
He was probably too embarrassed to tell you directly.
Detective Takagi is shy, after all.
Geez, if you wanna tell me something, then come right out and say it.
T-Takagi-kun!
There's a rope tied around his neck!
So that he can't get out.
But if he's just knocked out and tied up, then...
It changed!
Yeah! This camera's on a different angle!
H-Hold on!
If he rolls over and falls...?!
He'll end up being hanged!
Wake up, Takagi-kun!
Wake up and realize what's going on!
T-Takagi-kun!
Let's see...
Where am I?!
Calm down... Calm down...
I've gotta think... Remember what happened...
I remember meeting that guy last night,
he said there was a landscape he wanted me to see, so he brought me here...
Then from behind, he suddenly drugged me...
But why...?
Ah! He can't possibly think I...?!
Which means the footage from these cameras is going to the Police HQ?!
What?!
Someone kidnapped Takagi-kun?!
Right! This is video of it!
T-Takagi-kun!
The camera changed.
There are likely three cameras.
Video from three angles: straight-on, horizontal and from below, seem to be being broadcast at random.
Can we tell where the video's coming from?
Yes, if we leave it to the Anti-Cybercrime Division.
I don't think you'll be able to straight away.
C-Conan-kun!
The only thing usable on that tablet PC is the button on the front to turn the video on and off.
Other than that, the touch panel, the power button, and even the connector to charge it have been made unusable.
But Conan-kun, if the tablet's taken apart, it can be charged directly from inside.
And if we pull the data off the hard disc, we can tell where it's receiving from...
And what happens if we can't watch Detective Takagi anymore because it's been taken apart?
We're up against someone who's modified the buttons and wrote a program to disable all input from the touch panel.
It'd be wise to assume that they also set it up so that if it's taken apart, the video'll be disabled and not work anymore.
Well, we could ask the tablet's network provider to trace it without needing to take that risk,
but criminals like this usually use overseas servers, so I don't think you'll be able to find the source in a short time.
That's what Shin'ichi-niichan said when
I told him about it on the phone earlier.
But even if it takes quite some time, if there's a chance we can find out...
The time limit's tomorrow or the next day, though.
T-Tomorrow or the next day?!
The guy who gave the tablet to Genta and the others said
"That is perishable, so open it quickly.
It'll be no good by tomorrow or the next day."
W-What does that mean?
Probably, if he's left tied up like that...
Without drinking or eating, he'll reach his limit in three days.
Basically, we have until the day after tomorrow.
B-But how did Takagi-kun end up like this...
He's not the type to be resented much...
Detectives must expect to be resented.
You never know who will come to resent you.
S-Superintendent Matsumoto!
Megure, is it true that Takagi said he was staying overnight somewhere to meet someone?
Yes.
He was concerned about the monorail timetable, so he was probably headed for Haneda Airport.
Then contact Haneda Airport and ask if Wataru Takagi was on any passenger list last night!
Understood!
Shiratori, go to Takagi's house and check his post and the e-mails on his computer to find out who he was going to meet!
Right!
Chiba, you watch the tablet's video!
R-Right!
Don't leave it on constantly.
If we can't charge it, then we can't view the video for more than ten hours.
Turn it on for only ten minutes each hour,
and record the video while you're watching it.
So we can try and find something to identify where he is!
U-Understood! I'll get ready now.
S-Superintendent!
What do I...
Satō, you go question the children who're waiting in another room.
Right!
After all, they're precious witnesses who've met the suspect.
Find out what he looked like, and also anything else helpful, like habits or speech patterns!
Right!
Everyone else, investigate everyone connected with Takagi's prior investigations!
Everyone, be they suspects or victims!
Right!
Detective Satō, let's go.
I'll... I'll save you for sure...
Wait for me, Takagi-kun!
I see! So that's it!
That's why he brought me here!
Then even though it's scary...
I've gotta do it!
Then, going over it one more time,
a guy who looked like this gave you the tablet, right?
Yeah.
He started by asking if we were acquaintances of Detective Wataru Takagi,
and I said we were...
He said to give it to Detective Takagi's detective girlfriend.
Then he might hold a grudge against me too.
I don't think that's the case.
He knew Detective Takagi by his full name, yet only knew you as "his detective girlfriend", Detective Satō.
Then did he have any special habits or speech patterns?
There wasn't anything unusual, right?
Yeah...
Big trouble, Satō-san!
T-Takagi-san's...
S-Satō-san!
Takagi-kun... Takagi-kun!
W-What's going on here?!
Why's he about to fall?!
I just turned it on to record the third video today, and he was like this.
But why?!
He's been tied up there for several hours already.
It wouldn't be strange if he'd given up, and...
G-Get it together! Takagi—
His police notebook...
Hey, if anyone picks that up and reports it, we'll know Detective Takagi's location!
Don't worry. It looks like Detective Takagi's thinking clearly.
Y-Yeah...
Hey! What's going on!
Wataru Takagi's name wasn't on the passenger list for any flight leaving Haneda last night,
there's no clues at all at his house, and there's nobody of note in cases involving Takagi?!
Umm...
What?!
Actually, last week I saw Takagi
coming out of the Record Office.
What?!
He was crying, so I wondered what records he'd been looking at...
Okay!
Bring every single one of those records here!
Right!
The records that Detective Takagi looked at that day
were all about women who committed suicide by hanging themselves about a year ago?
Yeah.
Three cases in all.
They all had no signs of foul play,
so they were out of our jurisdiction.
What were the three cases like?
I think the first woman was called Yūko Tokugi-san, a sixth-year student at the Tohto University Faculty of Medicine.
She killed herself in the living room of her flat.
It didn't seem like a very feminine room, but it was meticulously clean, and from the suicide note left at her feet,
several days ago she'd hurt someone in a hit-and-run, and her conscience couldn't bear it any longer.
The second woman was a lecturer at an English conversation school,
Natalie Kuruma-san, whose mother was American.
From what was written on the calendar at her place,
she'd been having dates with her boyfriend almost every day, but fell to despair when he dumped her.
It seemed she had a date planned for the day she commited suicide too.
How do you know that?
Her mobile.
The rapid-response team that were first on the scene said she'd written that in English in an e-mail to her mother.
The third woman was the most popular hostess at a bar in Roppongi, Kyōka Hiko'ue-san.
Even though she earnt quite a lot, she lived in an old flat full of empty beer cans.
From her diary, she realized that the boyfriend she'd been supporting was just a fraudster wanting to marry her for money,
and in a fit of emotion, hung herself.
Was that fraudster caught?
Yes. But the charge wasn't fraud, but murder.
He'd been shouldering quite large debts, and having trouble with a loan shark, he went and stabbed someone.
I think it was Date-san that caught him.
Date-san?
Oh, right, you never met him, Conan-kun.
Straight after catching that fraudster, Date-san died in a traffic accident.
He'd dropped his notebook, and when he went to pick it up he was hit by a driver who'd fallen asleep at the wheel,
according to Takagi-kun.
According to Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
Takagi-kun happened to be there when it happened.
It seems that they were on an all-night stakeout, and when they were both heading home in the morning,
he was trying to show Takagi-kun something in his notebook when he got hit.
You know, the black notebook Takagi-kun's always using.
He inherited it from Date-san.
He works hard trying to fill it completely black, as he wants to quickly become as good a detective as Date-san was.
So Detective Takagi was good friends with that detective?
Yeah.
Date-san was Takagi-kun's tutor, so he even said that the two of them were the "Wataru Brothers".
Why "Brothers"?
Well, Date-san's name is Wataru Date...
His name was Wataru, just like Takagi-kun's.
Well, even though they're both "Wataru", unlike Takagi-kun, who doesn't really notice women, Date-san was a real Casanova.
And though he only had a year on me, Date-san had the face of an old man.
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me the reason Detective Takagi was kidnapped is...
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
Kudō-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
T-This is an earthquake!
H-He's abroad?!
Come on...
I've got to get out of this somehow...!
And I have to tell that person!
Among the three suicide cases, was there anyone connected to that place?
As that day, he was hit by a car and died!
On the next Conan: The Life-Threatening Broadcast of Love (Crisis State)!
Next Conan's Hint: Crow!
Uh... What's going to happen to me?
You'll be fine! It's hardly the first time...
Yeah... Wait, that's kinda bad.