Detective Takagi went somewhere, without telling anyone where he was headed.
The next day, the Detective Boys were waiting outside Police HQ for Detective Takagi, but he wasn't showing up.
And then...
Are you acquainted with Detective Wataru Takagi?
Yes, we are, but why...?
That's a stroke of good luck.
I've got a gift from him, see?
I want you to give this to the senior detective he's in love with.
Oh, you mean Detective Sato, who we were just talking about?
Hmm? You're acquainted with that female detective too?
Yes.
Aren't they getting married soon or something?
Right?
They're totally in love!
Then here's a message from him for that happy female detective.
'That is perishable, so open it quickly.
If you delay, tomorrow and the next day it'll be no good.'
When we opened the parcel, there was a tablet PC inside.
When it was turned on, the screen showed...
Takagi-kun!
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
Unable to move, Detective Takagi's fatigue leaves him in a desperate state!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
Hey, how is he?
Is Takagi alright?
Y-Yes!
He's been lying face-down for the last three hours.
He just seems to be quite exhausted...
The police notebook Takagi dropped earlier!
Has anyone reported finding it?
No.
We haven't heard anything yet.
Have you been able to contact the families from the three suicide cases that Takagi inspected in the Record Office last week?
Well...
The family of the first woman, the medical student Yūko Tokugi-san, lived in Kōchi,
but they moved half a year ago, and we haven't been able to locate them yet.
The second woman, the English teacher Natalie Kuruma-san, was born in Hokkaidō, but her only blood relatives were her parents,
and when they were on their way to pick up their daughter's corpse, they got caught up in a traffic accident and both died.
And it seems that the hostess, Kyōka Hiko'ue-san, lied about her birthplace when working, so her background is unknown.
But from what a friend at her workplace said,
she'd sometimes slip into the Hakata dialect.
Shikoku, Hokkaidō and Kyūshū...
They're all far enough away to need to stay overnight.
All three suicides happened on the same day, right?
Yeah.
It'll be a year the day after tomorrow.
What happened?
T-The picture suddenly started shaking!
What?!
T-This is an earthquake!
Contact the Japanese Meteorological Agency and find out the epicenter!
If this is live footage, we can narrow down the location!
R-Right!
H-He's shaking quite a lot...
Don't fall, Takagi!
Hey, Shiratori! Haven't you found out yet?!
W-Well...
Yesterday and today up until now,
there have been no earthquakes in any of Japan's 47 prefectures.
W-What?!
D-Don't tell me...
H-He's abroad?!
It looks like the shaking stopped.
T-There's a crow!
What does that mean?
Most likely, a crow landed on the pole or whatever the camera is fixed to, and the picture shook from that impact.
I-I see.
Anyway, there's an extremely high chance that this is the act of someone connected to the suicide cases who bears a grudge.
Contact the local jurisdictions keeping detailed
investigation records, and check for the suspect!
Right!
Sorry about keeping you so late today, kids.
I bet you're tired from all the questioning.
We're fine.
Shouldn't you be more worried about him?
Takagi'll get sleepy when it gets dark.
That's right!
What if he rolls over in his sleep...?
D-Don't worry, Takagi-kun's usually a peaceful sleeper.
You sleep together?!
You really are close!
Uhh, it's just that when we're on
stakeouts, we take naps in the car.
Perhaps the kidnapper has a grudge against
Detective Takagi from one of the suicide cases.
If it was actually a murder then since Detective Takagi decided it was suicide...
I don't think that's it.
If that was the case, he should hold grudges against the other detectives and forensic officers who came to the scene,
and it doesn't seem that anyone asked for any of the three cases to be re-investigated.
Right.
All three cases happened the day after Date-san died in a traffic accident,
and Takagi-kun was in a daze at the scenes, so since I'm an Assistant Inspector, I'm the one who decided they were suicide.
If he has any grudge, it should be against me.
What about if it was that woman going to medical school?
Maybe she hit that Date detective then commited suicide.
The person who hit Date-san was arrested at the scene.
Tokugi-san had caused a different accident.
How about the English teacher?
Maybe she was dating Detective Takagi!
No way.
The calendar at Natalie-san's place had "date" written all over it in English, but no detective could go on dates every day like that.
Then isn't it the hostess?
Maybe she killed herself because her boyfriend was caught by that Detective Date?
And that detective was good friends with Detective Takagi!
It was Date-san who caught Hiko'ue-san's boyfriend, but she hung herself in a fit of emotion
when the papers the day after Date-san died said that her boyfriend was a marriage fraudster.
There's no reason to hold a grudge against the police.
Hey, I think it'd be a good idea to find out more about Detective Date from other people.
Hmm? Why's that?
I can't help but wonder...
About Detective Date's given name being "Wataru", just like Detective Takagi.
It's already night...
It's so cold here that I'm freezing...
Maybe I am gonna die here...
It's my fault for getting into this...
Maybe this is my punishment...
Takagi...
I'm...
...leaving it in your hands...
D-Date-san!
I-It's up to you now...
No! Come on...
I've got to get out of this somehow...
...and tell that person!
Tell them the truth for Date-san...
I-It's no use, Superintendent!
We contacted the network provider, but it seems that an overseas server is being used.
We've requested the co-operation of the local investigation authority, but...
You mean that it'll take some time?
And even if we did find out the source, it could be routed through many more countries...
An investigation would take much longer, and by the time we find out, Takagi'll have frozen to death.
How's Takagi doing?
He seems very weak.
He's been moving about all night long.
Even if he's trying to warm himself up, he's just wasting his strength...
Huh? "It's not a date"?
Detective Takagi really said that before he left, two days ago?
Yeah.
Yumi made a joke asking if Takagi-kun was going on an overnight date at a hot spring, but he just said with a scowl on his face...
"It's not a date!"...
But anyway, you said on the phone that you realized something...
The way the guy who handed us the tablet talked was a bit odd!
He said "If you delay, tomorrow and the next day it'll be no good."
That is strange.
If he said "Tomorrow, or if you delay, the day after tomorrow..." I could understand, but...
Maybe he's a foreigner proficient in Japanese?
But he really looked Japanese, right?
Yeah...
Say, among the three suicide cases,
was there anyone connected to Hokkaidō?
Yeah.
The English conversation teacher, Natalie Kuruma-san
was born in Hokkaidō.
Then someone connected with her may well be Detective Takagi's kidnapper.
Why's that?
asatte
ashita-asatte
In the Hokkaidō dialect, "the day after tomorrow" is said as "tomorrow and the next day".
But why?
She was probably Detective Date's girlfriend.
Date-san's girlfriend?!
What she had written in English on her calendar almost every day was not "date".
"Date" is spelt "D-A-T-E".
If you read that as romaji, it's the name Date.
It was probably a symbol that Detective Date was staying over.
Just like Detective Takagi said, "it was not a 'date'!"
I see.
I assumed D-A-T-E meant the English word "date" because she was an English teacher.
And you said she had planned to go out on a date on the day she commited suicide, right?
Yeah.
If that meant that he'd promised to take her somewhere...
Maybe she waited for him without knowing about Detective Date's traffic accident,
and took her own life out of despair, thinking she'd been dumped?
T-That's...
Detective Takagi probably finally realized that a year later, and wanted to tell the truth to her family.
That reminds me, Takagi-kun was apparently looking at a photo booth sticker in his notebook and crying.
It's possible that he'd just confirmed it was Natalie-san in that photo booth sticker from the case records last week.
But wait a sec!
Isn't that about Detective Date?
It's nothing to do with Takagi!
And how about if she told her parents not that her boyfriend's name was Date, which could be confused with the English "date",
but that he was Detective Wataru-san from Police HQ?
And if Detective Takagi contacted Natalie-san's family saying "I want to meet with you to report something about her"...
They thought that the "Detective Wataru from Police HQ" who'd abandoned her and drove her to suicide
had finally turned up without any worries a year later, and Takagi-kun ended up like that...
But, when Natalie-san's parents were going to pick up her corpse, they had an accident, and...
Then who picked up her corpse?
I think it was an elderly teacher from the same English conversation class.
He also picked up her belongings.
That reminds me, the agency involved reported a while ago that that teacher collapsed into tears when they gave him her corpse.
They came from the same town, and she was like a daughter to him.
Then it's got to true.
He's the one who kidnapped Detective Takagi!
Looking at the e-mails on her phone, he convinced himself that it was Detective Takagi who dumped her and made her commit suicide!
The suspect has been confirmed!
His full name is Ryūsaku Fuemoto.
Last month, he left the English conversation class due to an illness, and is thought to have returned to his hometown in Hokkaidō.
His residence in Hokkaidō is unknown,
but based on the knowledge that he has yet to vacate the flat he previously lived in within the city limits,
there's a chance that he might still be hiding there.
Hurry there and capture him as soon as you find him!
Make him spit out Takagi's location!
Yes, sir!
Fuemoto
Go ahead, the door's open.
So you've finally, finally managed to find me.
I thought I might end up dozing off and pushing the bomb's trigger while I was waiting.
So? Is this him?
Yeah!
There's no mistake!
That's the old man!
Now, tell me where Takagi-kun is.
Is it you then?
The senior detective that Wataru Takagi's in love with, I mean.
I see.
Just like he said, you're quite a beauty.
But even so, he shouldn't have left Natalie—
Now listen up before I end up hitting you!
The man you kidnapped was Wataru Takagi, but Natalie's lover was Wataru Date!
And he didn't dump her!
B-But she said in an e-mail that
'Wataru won't come anymore'...
Of course he wouldn't!
As that day, he was hit by a car and died!
T-That can't be!
So hurry up and tell me where Takagi-kun is!
Don't tell me... Don't tell me the wine was poisoned?!
Call an ambulance! Quickly!
R-Right!
Hold on!
H-He's...
Where? Where is he?!
Hurry up and tell me!
Where is he?!
Hey, Sato! What happened?
What's going on? Did you capture the suspect?!
What happened? Say something, Sato!
Sato!
Superintendent, unfortunately...
The death of the suspect, Ryūsaku Fuemoto was just confirmed.
It seems that the wine he was drinking at the time we entered had poison in it.
The suspect's dead?!
Was he poisoned by someone?!
No, the bottle of poison had been placed next to his wine bottle.
It seems that he decided to end his own life when the police arrived to start with.
Seeing that he possessed a bomb, he likely
intended to blow himself up if forcibly secured.
And if he had time to talk, then he'd
drink the poison and watch us despair.
As it seems that the suspect held a grudge against the police.
Did you tell him it was a misunderstanding?
Yes, I told him that he kidnapped Wataru Takagi because he mistook him for Wataru Date, also from Police HQ,
and that the motive for Natalie-san's suicide was not that he dumped him, but because he died in a traffic accident.
But by the time I could tell him, he'd already drunk the poison, and before he could tell me Sergeant Takagi's location, he...
Have any clues been found at the suspect's residence?
No...
We're searching now, but not yet...
The only thing we found was Takagi-kun's mobile, which was probably taken from him when he was kidnapped.
In the inbox are several e-mails from the suspect,
and among them, there's one saying that while the suspect did intend to come and meet Takagi-kun directly,
he felt unwell, so he would send Takagi an airline ticket he bought for himself, and asked Takagi to use it to visit him...
There's also an unsent e-mail addressed to me, which we believe was written by the culprit,
saying "A present from Detective Takagi was left in the shrubbery in front of the Police HQ".
So he probably originally intended to hand over the tablet by doing so.
But then he happened to meet children who knew Takagi, and entrusted the tablet to them...
Right. That way, there's no chance of it being taken by someone else.
Are there any other e-mails that hint at where Takagi is?
No.
Just "I'll meet you when you get to the airport".
Then I'll leave you in charge of continuing to search the flat!
Understood!
It's unlikely they'll find anything.
Yeah.
After all, we're up against someone who only gave us a tablet on which we can see video of Takagi-kun.
Most of the functions have been disabled, all the markings on the back have been scraped off,
and the video is sent through an overseas server, so we can't tell its source.
If he planned to commit suicide in front of the police to begin with,
then I don't think he would've left behind
anything which could pinpoint the location.
Normally, we'd assume it to be the
suspect's birthplace, Hokkaidō, but...
Just in case, we're checking with local construction contractors, but...
There haven't been any reports of Takagi being spotted at a four-story building site as shown in the video yet...
The only clue left is the video of Takagi.
If it started raining or snowing, we could
narrow down the location, but it hasn't...
The only thing that showed up was a crow.
A crow showed up?
Y-Yeah.
If you recorded it, then let us see it too!
Children know all sorts of things about animals that adults don't.
Yeah!
It's just an ordinary crow...
That's right.
But look, its neck is gray, right?
T-That's a Western Jackdaw!
But I thought they were...
Sato, reporting in!
So? Did you learn anything?
No...
All the data on his computer had been deleted, and we're trying to find out how he obtained the bomb, but nothing yet.
I see.
So? How's Takagi-kun?
Don't worry. He's still alive.
Although he seems quite weak.
All right!
W-What happened?!
Takagi-san's been moving around since yesterday.
I thought he was moving because he was cold,
but he was actually using the edge of the plank to try and cut the rope on his legs.
And just now, he cut them!
I see! If he puts his legs on either side of the plank,
it's less likely he'll fall.
All right!
But what's that?
He's doing something with his legs.
Isn't he trying to pull the sheet on the plank closer?
If he covers himself with it, he could stop his body temperature dropping a bit.
It can't be! He dropped it!
W-Why...?
Does he want someone to notice the sound of the sheet falling?
Takagi-kun, what are you trying to do?
S-Someone... Please, notice it...
T-That's...?!
Wait a sec!
What's that?
Shin'ichi Kudo
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudo
Kudo-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
Kudo-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudo
T-That's...?!
Wait a sec! What's that?
A bomb?!
What?!
And if it's set on a timer to explode at that time...?
Have you checked the blurred footage, I wonder?
The Sun Pillar phenomenon.
Where are you, Takagi-kun...
It couldn't be...?!
Date-san...
Sato!
Takagi!
On the next Conan: The Life-Threatening Broadcast of Love (Rush to the Scene)!
Next Conan's Hint: "Meteorological Phenomena"!
I'm at my limit too.
What're you saying?
No wonder people just walk over you...
Scary...