Detective Takagi went somewhere, without telling anyone where he was headed.
Are you acquainted with Detective Wataru Takagi?
Yes, we are, but why...?
That's a stroke of good luck.
I've got a gift from him, see?
I want you to give this to the senior detective he's in love with.
'That is perishable, so open it quickly.
If you delay, tomorrow and the next day it'll be no good.'
When we opened the parcel, there was a tablet PC inside.
When it was turned on, the screen showed...
T-Takagi-kun!
While investigating to try and discover the location Detective Takagi was being held at,
three connected people were discovered.
And through them, the person thought to be the kidnapper was determined.
Then when the police rushed to ambush him...
So you've finally, finally managed to find me.
I thought I might end up dozing off and pushing the bomb's trigger while I was waiting.
Now, tell me where Takagi-kun is.
I see. Just like he said, you're quite a beauty.
But even so, he shouldn't have left Natalie—
Now listen up before I end up hitting you!
The man you kidnapped was Wataru Takagi, but Natalie's lover was Wataru Date!
And he didn't dump her!
B-But she said in an e-mail that
'Wataru won't come anymore'...
Of course he wouldn't!
As that day, he was hit by a car and died!
T-That can't be!
So hurry up and tell me where Takagi-kun is!
Don't tell me... Don't tell me the wine was poisoned?!
Hold on!
H-He's...
Where? Where is he?!
Hurry up and tell me!
Where is he?!
Around the same time, Detective Takagi finally managed to cut the rope tied around his legs,
and dropped the sheet that was near his feet.
And then...
T-That's...?!
Wait a sec! What's that?
A bomb?!
What?!
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
Detective Takagi's in all sorts of danger!
From exhaustion, a bomb and a time limit!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
I see something like a timer too.
Is it a time bomb?
Hey, Shiratori!
Do you know the time that Natalie-san committed suicide?
I-I think the estimated time of death was 10 AM...
H-Hey, tomorrow'll be exactly a year since then.
What if it's set on a timer to explode at that time...?
So no matter what we do here, Takagi'll be blown to bits in less than 18 hours?
No way...
W-Wait a minute!
The packet tape securing the bomb came unstuck, and it's about to fall!
Damn it!
T-Takagi-kun!
Don't worry!
Takagi-san realized it too, and he's trying to make it drop off with his feet.
Go, Takagi!
Just a bit more!
Drop it off!
H-He put it on top of the plank.
What're you doing, Takagi!
There's somebody there.
Detective Takagi heard someone's voice from below, so he didn't want it to drop.
That tablet doesn't carry audio, right?
Yet Detective Takagi's mouth is still covered with packet tape.
Which means that he's in a place where people could pass close enough to hear him.
Then in order to protect whoever's there, Takagi-kun...
T-Takagi...
Who's gonna be the best tomorrow?
It's gonna be our dad, of course!
Dad's the strongest, after all!
S-Strongest...?
You really are the strongest, Date-san!
You captured a huge suspect so quickly!
I heard you got the best grades in the whole police academy too.
That info's fake, you dope.
I was always second.
I never beat him in brains or brawn.
"Him"?
He was a kind, tall and thin man, a bit like you.
I wonder what he's been up to...?
Maybe he recklessly overestimated himself and is lying dead somewhere.
You be careful too.
Even detectives only have one life.
Don't screw up by overestimating yourself.
Date-san...
W-We should limit our search for Takagi-kun to Hokkaidō?
Why's that, Conan-kun?
The crow that showed up with Detective Takagi is probably a Western Jackdaw.
Western Jackdaws are usually found in Europe, and have only been found in Japan twice.
Both times have been in Hokkaidō.
But to decide on Hokkaidō from just that is a bit much...
Hey...
What's that light?
No idea...
What's that?
This here, a thin pillar of light in the sky behind Takagi-san.
The sun pillar phenomenon.
At sunrise and sunset, if sunlight reflects off diamond dust in the atmosphere, it can be seen as a shining pillar.
According to the Internet, you can only see it in cold places, like Hokkaidō.
Hey! Takagi's somewhere that cold?
Then we have to hurry and save him!
He'll freeze to death!
Hey! Do you know the temperature at which diamond dust forms?
I-I think it was 20 degrees below freezing...
Minus 20°C?!
It looks to be quite far away,
so we can't say for sure that Takagi-kun really is somewhere that cold...
But he's certainly near somewhere that is.
S-Superintendent...
It's Hokkaidō! Takagi has been determined to be in Hokkaidō!
Ask the Hokkaidō Police for help in the search, and contact every construction and demolition contractor in the prefecture!
Demand that they check again!
Yes, sir!
Let's go.
Megure! You fly to Hokkaidō with Sato!
The suspect mentioned friends in his e-mails, so there's a chance that accomplices may be lurking at the scene.
Don't forget to carry your handguns!
Yes, sir!
Wait for us, Takagi...
Just be patient a bit longer...!
Go ahead!
But it's strange...
They said they were checking all four-story building sites in Hokkaidō, so why haven't they found him yet?
It'd be different if he had lots of friends, and they made the building site themselves...
Otherwise, since they asked the contractors, he should've been found when four-story building sites were checked...
Detective Takagi dropping the sheet bothers me too...
It's true that he may've been trying to get someone passing nearby to notice the sound of it falling,
but if the sheet covered the police notebook he dropped yesterday, it'd be all for nothing...
Maybe...
Maybe he had a different reason for doing that...
Hey! Mitsuhiko!
You recorded some of the footage of Detective Takagi, right?
Oh, yeah... Some of it.
Let me see!
Is it possible that where Detective Takagi is, there's a...!
Could it be...?!
Hey, Megure! Haven't you found Takagi yet?
No... We're having helicopters from Hokkaidō Police HQ help search,
but if we don't narrow down the location...
Have you received any reports on your end?
No...
As soon as dawn broke, we had them check again,
but it seems they still couldn't find Takagi at any four-story building site as shown in the video.
I-Is Takagi okay?!
Yeah... Though he looks like he could die any minute.
By now we have to start considering places other than Hokkaidō...
What is it? What happened?!
S-Snow! It just started snowing!
Superintendent, what about over there?
Is there snow in the video of Takagi-kun?
T-There's snow here too!
Check with the Meteorological Agency! Hurry!
Right!
S-Superintendent.
There's less than an hour before the expected time of explosion.
I know that!
Superintendent! It's only snowing in Hokkaidō!
It seems it started snowing almost everywhere in Hokkaidō at once.
Then Takagi really is in Hokkaidō?!
But how?
Every four-story building site in the prefecture's been checked, so why hasn't he been found?!
Because it's not four stories high.
What?
The kidnapper used a trick to make it seem like a four-story site.
Conan-kun said he figured something out from yesterday's footage, so I brought them in.
I analyzed the footage all night at my house, and finally found proof.
But us police have watched through all of the footage, and we didn't see anything...
Did you check the blurred footage?
B-Blurred footage?
This footage, from when the crow landed on the pole or whatever the camera is fixed to.
When shaking, the angle of the camera shifted oddly, so if you look at it frame-by-frame...
See!
Look closely at this image.
Next to Detective Takagi's left shoulder.
Something's there, right?
What looks like a hook.
T-There is...
But what...?
It's the hook at the end of the string on a police notebook.
Then that's the police notebook Takagi dropped?
But isn't it in an odd place?
Y-Yeah... It's almost like it's floating...
It's not floating. It's just sitting...
...on top of the mirror!
M-Mirror?!
That's why Detective Takagi dropped his police notebook.
He wanted you to realize the mirror trick.
Though unfortunately, it fell under the plank.
He dropped the sheet that was on the plank for the same reason.
In other words, the lower half of the straight-on footage is a reflection, and it's actually only about two stories high?
Yeah. What proves it is that Detective Takagi's still alive.
Being alive is proof?
Didn't you know?
The sun pillar phenomenon only occurs below -20°C.
In places so intensely cold that you can see one,
a man abandoned wearing just a business suit would freeze to death before the day is out.
T-Then, why is Takagi-san still...
A heating element was laid beneath the mirror.
So that if snow fell, the heat'd melt it so it wouldn't pile up.
Right, Doc?
Huh? Right...
If snow piled up, it'd be obvious that there was a mirror.
I guess the heat raised the temperature a bit, which was a blessing for Detective Takagi.
Okay!
The search target is now a two-story building site!
If it's two stories, it's likely a detached house!
Inform the Hokkaidō Police HQ to include renovation contractors in the search too!
Yes, sir!
Megure! The location is likely a detached house with the roof removed!
It'll be easier to find from the skies!
There's likely 40 minutes left before the bomb explodes.
So find him before then any way you can!
Understood!
Where...
Where are you, Takagi-kun...?
Superintendent!
Takagi-san caught the edge of the packet tape covering his mouth on the pole next to him...
Did he pull it off?!
Now he can call for help!
Hey, what's wrong, Takagi?!
Why isn't he calling out?!
He probably can't.
He's so exhausted that he can't speak.
It's been over two days since he drank anything, so his throat'll be bone dry.
No way...
Takagi...!
Wait a sec!
Those things in the sky behind Detective Takagi, aren't they kites?!
And it's not just one or two of them!
I-It's a kite-flying contest!
Shiratori! Find out where it is!
R-Right...
Today, kite-flying contests are being held at three places in Hokkaidō: Ikeguchi Town, Komamae Town and Hibai City.
Then quickly inform the Hokkaidō Police HQ!
Right!
But can't we get it down to one place?! There's less than five minutes until the bomb explodes!
Superintendent!
H-His mouth... Takagi-san's moving his mouth to try and say something.
What?!
But it's not straight-on footage, and with snow blocking the view, it's hard to read his lips...
Komamae!
The only consonants that can't be said without closing your mouth are "m", "b" and "p"!
If he's trying to tell us where he is,
then out of those three places,
the only place with two of those letters in it is Komamae!
Megure! Komamae Town!
Hurry to Komamae Town! Takagi's there!
I-If it's Komamae Town, we're above it now!
There he is!
Right of the helicopter! Straight below!
Takagi-kun...
Takagi spotted!
The location is near Komamae Town's third district!
No accomplices visible!
Hurry! There's less than two minutes!
Oh, no! If we get any closer, Takagi'll get blown away by the helicopter's downdraft!
Inspector!
Evacuate the neighborhood and any passers-by with the megaphone!
H-Hey, Sato!
S-Sato! What're...?
Sato!
Sato-san...
Somehow I imagined that Sato-san just floated down from the sky with her underwear exposed...
Maybe I am done for...
Takagi!
Move your head left, and keep still!
Sato!
Takagi!
You're alive, Wataru?
Ah, yeah... Somehow...
I'm so happy!
Wait, we should get out of here!
W-What happened to Takagi?!
T-The video cut off.
Don't die!
Takagi!
S-Sato-san, you're on-duty...
It's okay. Nobody can see us, anyway!
He seems fine...
Takagi...
He should've just died...
By the way, from the information that just came in from the Hokkaidō Police HQ,
the illness that the suspect, Fuemoto, had was terminal cancer,
and the house used in the kidnapping had been bought under a fictitious company name.
Renovation contractors had been called in to install a skylight to give the entrance an open ceiling,
but it seems they were ordered to stop working for three days.
And nobody's listening.
Shiratori, I'll leave the rest to you.
Ah, right.
Megure, they're both fine.
You go meet up with Hokkaidō Police HQ.
Ah, the battery died.
We've ended up visiting Date-san's grave a month late now.
Well, you were in pretty bad shape from frostbite and whatnot, Takagi-kun.
I couldn't help it.
If I'd just told that woman on the day that Date-san had died in a traffic accident, this wouldn't have happened...
Don't be silly.
Natalie-san knew that Date-san had died.
Date-san's parents remembered her.
They said that when they went to the hospital to identify his corpse,
there was a half-Japanese woman standing outside the room with her eyes full of tears.
It seems that that night, Date-san had planned to go to Hokkaidō to meet her parents.
He intended to bring his parents along and introduce her to them too.
Really?
So it's not your fault, Takagi-kun.
Still...
He wanted to give her this ring, after all.
I'm sure that's what Date-san's final words meant.
I'm...
...leaving it in your hands...
A toothpick...
Why's there one here?
Now you mention it, Date-san was always chewing on a toothpick.
Yeah...
Someone who visited his grave before us must've left it as an appropriate offering.
But who could it be?
Rest in peace...
My friend...
I'm always telling myself,
"I didn't fall, I didn't fall..."
He fell!
Let's go check out the scene!
Come on, hurry!
I took the photo.
I wrote the article.
And I ended up being the editor.
"Ended up"?
On the next Conan: Froth, Steam and Smoke (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Beer, coffee and cigarettes!
You did it, Detective Takagi! A Live Broadcast of your Love!
Everyone was watching.