If you want to kill me,
then come and do it. I'll
be waiting with the door
open. I'll kill YOU instead.
- Daisaku Katsumoto
If you want to kill me,
then come and do it. I'll
be waiting with the door
open. I'll kill YOU instead.
- Daisaku Katsumoto
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
A mass e-mail sent just before a fatal fall... Was it a trick to hide a murderer?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Sorry, Conan-kun, but it seems Dad won't be able to drive you.
He was up drinking until past 5 AM, so he's still sleeping.
I apologise, but could you and Ai-chan take the train?
Okay, got it.
Be careful!
Sure.
Now I think about it, the old man wasn't in bed when I got up...
Looks like the Kogorō-san rental car plan failed.
Crap, and it's already seven...
Even if we go back to the bus stop now, the ski bus with the doc and the kids are on will have left.
That's why I said that since I forgot something, I should've come back and got it by myself.
Idiot! I came with you as a child wandering about alone is just asking to be kidnapped.
Though I'm not a child...
You still look like one...
So, what should we do?
We could go by train, but we'd have to wait ages switching trains,
and it'll be evening by the time we got there.
Can't help it...
It's not we have any other choice.
Don't we?
We could have Subaru-san drive us.
B-But is that okay?
Why not? He always seems to have tons of time to spare.
I meant is it okay with you.
Didn't you hate him or something?
I can't always be so choosy.
Like I said, I'm not a child.
But you look like—
Though I guess that doesn't matter here...
And perhaps he is...
Okay, okay...
Stop being so noisy first thing!
Daisaku Katsumoto (58)
Publishing Company President
Oh, it's you... So you actually turned up.
Well, come in, I may as well hear you out.
Though I doubt you've anything of interest to say...
Oh, so you're all going skiing?
That sounds good!
As I happen to be going, I may as well try some skiing too.
I feel like my body's a bit out of shape.
Why, is there some reason you need to stay fit?
Well, I would like to impress the ladies.
Detective Takagi!
Conan-kun!
Were you on a stakeout?
Yeah.
Chiba just took over for me.
I'm glad to see you're back to work so soon though.
Yeah... Though I still dream about it sometimes...
I always wake up the moment I fall off the plank though.
I'm always telling myself, 'you're okay, you didn't fall, you didn't fall...'
He fell!
Someone fell!
Get an ambulance!
Was that from the other side of this block?
Get in, Detective Takagi!
Let's take a look at the scene!
Come on, hurry!
Right.
I... couldn't help but look...
Unbelievable...
Excuse me!
I'm with the police. What happened?
T-This is...
I happened to pass by here when I was jogging, and suddenly this man fell from above.
I saw it as well.
This street's on my dogwalking course...
So he fell from this block of flats?
Does anyone know who this man is?
He has a mobile phone in his shirt pocket.
Ah, you're right.
- Daisaku Katsumoto
kill YOU instead.
then come and do it. I'll
If you want to kill me,
Looks like he sent an odd e-mail just before falling.
And also, it was transmitted simultaneously to a number of people.
Then why don't we try resending it?
Hey, hold on!
It seems it was sent to those three.
Which means you all must know the man that fell, right?
Why didn't you say anything earlier?
Well... I'd only just rushed out of my flat after hearing some screams, and I hadn't been able to see his face yet...
Keisuke Ogino (34)
Cameraman
Kaori Tsukihara (28)
Magazine Editor
M-Me neither.
Someone yelled so loud that I spilt the coffee I was drinking.
Kazutomo Sodesaki (31)
Writer
I also came here since I heard someone cry out.
But if the man who fell was the one sent the e-mail earlier, then...
it must be President Katsumoto that fell?
No way!
Seriously?!
Umm...
He was a company president?
Yeah...
He was Daisaku Katsumoto, the president and editor-in-chief of Katsumoto Publishing.
You must've heard of 'Weekly Great', the magazine that's been selling more and more copies lately.
Yeah... I've heard it's full of things like celebrity gossip.
Oh?
The company president lives in the same building as his employees?
It's just a coincidence, it's because the company building's nearby.
I've been intending to move for a while.
I'm a freelancer, not an employee.
Well, the three of us live on the third floor,
and the president on the twenty-sixth floor.
I see...
Well then, could you accompany me to the station?
There's various things we'll need to ask you about...
Hey, wait a second!
Are you suspecting us?!
We just said we were all in our own flats until it happened!
But is there anyone who can prove that?
I guess not... All three of us live by ourselves...
Then let's take a look at their flats now.
It's been less than four minutes since we heard someone shouting 'He fell!'.
We may be able to figure something out, right?
I wonder what they hope to figure out by seeing their flats...
Considering the injuries on the corpse,
it seems he fell from quite a high floor.
If this was a murder, the killer probably pushed the victim from inside his flat,
then rushed here straight away.
If there's any trace that they were just in their flats, they'll be cleared.
They're only able to see their flats straight away
as Detective Takagi happened to be close to the scene.
Since this situation would be impossible for the killer to predict, they wouldn't have had any need to return to their flat after the crime,
and orchestrate that they were in there until just before.
You certainly seem to know a lot about murders.
Of course! I'm a Sherlockian.
But what interests me is not the murders, but their solutions.
That so?
So, Tsukihara-san and Sodesaki-san, could you both wait by the entrance with the door open?
Sure.
What's that bag?
It's an attendance gift I got when leaving a funeral recently.
So, do you have any way to prove you were here until not long ago?
L-Look, the TV's still on!
Uh, well...
That's not quite good evidence...
Ah, this is good, right?
There's still all this froth left on my beer.
I'd been watching TV while drinking it until just before.
I see...
Something that could prove I was here until recently...
Do I have anything...
You went to the same funeral as Ogino-san?
Yeah, all three of us went.
Though the president didn't come.
Umm... About this coffee...
Oh, that's the coffee I was drinking just before I left the flat.
I can't get going in the mornings until I've had my daily coffee.
Then this could potentially be evidence, couldn't it? There's still steam faintly coming from it.
Hurry up, Detective!
Hurry up and look!
Come on, please calm down.
When I heard about the steam from Tsukihara-san's coffee, I remembered!
Oh no, it's already out...
I left a cigarette I'd just started smoking in the ashtray right before leaving,
so I thought it'd still be lit...
Look!
See, there's still smoke rising from it!
This is proof I was here not long ago.
I-Indeed...
So none of you three went to the president's flat, right?
Yeah.
Of course!
That's what we've been telling you.
So the elements proving their alibis are froth, steam and smoke...
Froth, steam and smoke?
Their alibis are based on such unreliable things?
Yes. Let me explain everything step by step.
At around 7:30 AM, on my way back to the station after finishing my shift at a stakeout,
I heard people screaming that someone had fallen down, and rushed to the front of this block.
I found a man dressed in a gown and pyjamas lying on the pavement.
From speaking to witnesses, I found out he had fallen from one of the topmost floors.
There was a mobile phone inside the breast pocket of his pyjamas,
and when I checked it, I found he'd sent a mass e-mail at 7:25 AM, just before falling.
- Daisaku Katsumoto
kill YOU instead.
then come and do it. I'll
If you want to kill me,
So I attempted sending the same e-mail again...
I see...
So these three received that inflammatory e-mail designed to encourage the killer to act, right?
Yes.
The man who fell was the president of a publishing company
that those three work for, Daisaku Katsumoto-san.
The content of the e-mail being what it was, I thought about having them come to the police station to question them,
but realised that if I went into their flats straight away,
there may be some evidence proving they were in there until just before.
So you went into their flats,
and froth on beer, steam from a cup of coffee,
and a cigarette's smoke were what they showed you.
Yes.
If one of the three had pushed Katsumoto off and then hid among the crowd,
he or she would have had to come straight here without taking any detours.
As the sooner they were seen here, the more believable a claim they'd rushed here after hearing the commotion would be during questioning.
But you're the only one who saw the froth, steam and smoke, right?
I made sure to take some pictures!
Though they're with my mobile phone camera.
C-Conan-kun?!
I came across him and his friends in their car when I heard the 'He fell!' shouts.
So you're telling me you took Conan-kun with you into the flat of somebody who might be a murderer?!
Uh, yeah...
Actually, it was Conan-kun's idea to visit the flats right away...
Really...
Hey, take a look!
This is Ogino-san's beer's froth,
this is Tsukihara-san's steaming coffee,
which I recorded a video of since it'd be hard to see in a photo,
and this is Sodesaki-san's cigarette smoke.
I asked each of them to hold their evidence when I took the picture so you could tell which was from which room.
Where were the other two suspects while you were taking these photos?
I asked them to wait outside each flat with the door left open,
so none of them had time to sneak into their respective flats to make up their alibi.
So, president Katsumoto was pushed off his balcony on the 26th floor.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Both the front door and the window to the balcony were left open.
It seems that right after sending the e-mail, the president called an interior construction company.
An interior construction company?
Yes.
They remodelled his flat last night,
but it appears the carpet put in was not the one he had ordered.
While on the phone, the president actually measured the length of the carpet's pile and complained about it.
While he was on the phone, the doorbell rang, so he said he'd call them back and hung up.
So president Katsumoto was in his own flat right until he was pushed off the balcony.
And it's safe to assume it was his killer who rang the doorbell.
By the way, how long does it take to go from the suspects' flats to the president's?
All three of them reside on the third floor, and the president's flat is twenty-three floors above that,
so a round trip should take about seven minutes.
I tried timing myself using the stairs, so I have no doubts about that.
The stairs?
Why didn't you use the lifts instead?
The lifts are fitted with surveillance cameras.
I had the control room show me the footage from them,
and none of the suspects appeared in the footage around 7:30 AM, when president Katsumoto fell.
If one of them was the killer, they'd have had to take the stairs, which don't have surveillance cameras.
I see...
Ringing the president's doorbell...
Pushing him off after having been invited into his flat...
And then leaving to rush down to the ground floor...
Then by the time you entered their flats after the incident,
if one of them was the killer, their room would've been left unoccupied for more than ten minutes.
Yes, and I think ten minutes is enough time for any froth, steam or smoke to have disappeared.
I see...
But why did the president send that e-mail to you?
Because of the lawsuit.
The three of us were planning to sue him.
At the beginning of next month, you see.
Sue him?
Haven't you heard?
Last week, a famous actress committed suicide.
Oh... If I recall, she killed herself because she made the news kissing her lover, a dangerous man.
I took the photo of that kiss.
I was the one who wrote the article.
And I apparently edited it and published it in Weekly Great.
Huh? Apparently?
Yeah, the photo and the articles were complete lies!
The photo was taken as they were about to hug.
They weren't kissing at all.
The background he was given in the article was also faked.
He was a stuntman, and the facial injuries he had were resulting from shooting that day.
But that woman was engaged to a young actor, right?
Still, if they were hugging each other, then I guess it wasn't completely made-up...
That's a wrong assumption as well.
He was her younger half-brother, and they hugged because she told him she was engaged!
Then, why did...?
We learnt the story was false before it was published, so it was scrapped.
But president Katsumoto rewrote the whole thing and put it back in without anybody's permission!
With a headline of 'Popular actress caught in a late-night dangerous affair before her wedding'!
The magazine was released the day before the press conference for their wedding,
so it sold like hotcakes...
One of her rabid fans
attacked her brother.
Even now, he's still in hospital, unconscious.
Of course, the marriage was cancelled. And in her despair, she chose to commit suicide.
But if she had revealed the truth straight away, wouldn't everyone realise the article was faked...?
She couldn't say anything!
Her brother was born out of an affair her father had!
Well, we're sure the president faked the article knowing she couldn't say anything.
But we can't forgive him for releasing that article with our names on it!
That's why, last night, we sent him an e-mail signed by all three of us!
Saying we had proof he'd fabricated the article, so he'd better prepare himself!
And that we'd sue him until he had nothing left!
I see...
So, upon reading the e-mail you sent him this morning, he sent that inflammatory response to you.
Then those funeral bags in each of your flats, could they be...
Those were gifts for attending that actress's funeral.
Though we had to give fake names and say we were some of her agency's employees.
If the motive for the murder was that article, shouldn't we consider her relatives to be suspects as well?
But the murder happened almost immediately after the president sent the e-mail.
So we can't exactly remove these three from our suspect list...
That much is true...
The timing is too good to be a coincidence,
but that froth, steam and smoke prove those three couldn't have committed the crime.
I thought we could find something by going into each of their flats right away,
not giving them enough time to fabricate an alibi...
Or is there really something?
Is there a way to forge evidence in an instant?
Hello?
Oh, Conan-kun!
When're you going to get here?
We've already started skiing!
Give us a call once you're here, okay?
We'll be waiting!
Sorry, but we ended up involved in a case, so I don't think we can come.
No way!
Conan-kun's saying he can't come because of a case!
So Haibara-san won't be coming, either?!
Probably not.
Forget that case and come!
It's great out here, you can even see your breath!
Yeah, it's great!
See your breath...?!
Sorry, I'll call you back later!
Conan-kun?
He hung up...
Hey, Inspector Megure!
Since you're here and all, how about an experiment?
An experiment?
Yup.
An experiment with froth, steam and smoke.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
kimi ni zenzen kyōmi nai uso you are my perfect guy
tokimeki wa kakusenai honto wa ki ni natte shikatanai
koi ni bukiyō son’na style kimi no mae da to betsujin mitai
dare ni mo ienai himitsu no mama
soredemo I’m alright koi no yukue nante
mada it isn’t the last chance for me
iron’na love story o egaite’ru mune no naka
demo risō ni wa hodo tooi
watashi-tte wagamama sore kurai no koto wakatte’ru
dakedo nani ka ikenai no?
Edogawa
kimi to no koi ni koi o shite’ru dake de tsutaetakute mo mada
himitsu ni shite’ru hō ga shiawase dakara ima wa watashi dake no secret love
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Well then...
What do you think his plans are...?
What?
I mean about the skiing.
Dr. Agasa and the children are waiting for you, right?
Oh... We probably have to cancel.
The call he just received was probably from the kids.
He probably said we got ourselves involved in a case and couldn't make it.
As usual.
I see... What a shame.
So you can go back home now, as we no longer need to be taken anywhere.
No, it's fine. I'm interested in the result of the case, anyway.
Besides, I can't just leave a frail lady on her own. Especially when a killer could still be on the prowl.
You're not exactly a reliable guardian knight, you know.
That's a harsh thing to say.
I'll protect you with my own life...
Princess.
A trick hides among the uncertain alibis of the three suspects.
On the next Conan: 'Froth, Steam and Smoke (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Tools of the trade!
Should I call Mouri-san for the experiment?
Mouri-kun'd drink the beer, so of course not!
Right.