To catch up with the rest of the Detective Boys,
who'd taken a bus early to go skiing,
Haibara and I were having Subaru-san take us in his car.
On the way, we met Detective Takagi, and while we were talking...
He fell!
Someone fell down!
Let's take a look at the scene!
Come on, hurry!
When we reached the scene, there was a corpse of someone who'd fallen from a flat on a high floor.
Since three acquaintances of the victim were near the scene,
we headed to their flats to question them, when...
Ah, this is good, right?
There's still all this froth left on my beer. I'd been watching TV while drinking it until just before.
I see...
Umm... About this coffee...
Oh, that's the coffee I was drinking just before I left the flat.
I can't get going in the mornings until I've had my daily coffee.
Then this could potentially be evidence, couldn't it?
There's still steam faintly coming from it.
Hurry up and look!
Come on, please calm down.
When I heard about the steam from Tsukihara-san's coffee, I remembered!
Oh no, it's already out...
I left a cigarette I'd just started smoking in the ashtray right before leaving,
so I thought it'd still be lit...
Ah, look! See, there's still smoke rising from it!
This is proof I was here not long ago.
So the elements proving their alibis are froth, steam and smoke...
Hey, Inspector Megure!
Since you're here and all, how about an experiment?
An experiment?
Yup.
An experiment with froth, steam and smoke.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
A marvelous trick used to hide every trace...
Break the alibi by testing the evidence!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Well, as Conan-kun said,
I thought steam would last longer in low temperatures, but...
The temperature set for this room is 27°C.
When I entered this room with you, Detective,
Kaori Tsukihara (28)
Magazine Editor
I didn't tamper with the AC remote, right?
Indeed, you didn't.
Looks like no matter how many times we measure it,
the coffee's steam always disappears in eight minutes.
Well then, did you notice anything when you left your flat after hearing the commotion?
Like spotting a suspicious person or hearing a strange noise.
I wonder... It seemed like some people upstairs were trying to take the lift down too, and it was taking ages to come...
So I took the stairs to the ground floor,
but I didn't see any suspicious people there.
Then how about sounds?
Let's see...
Right before I left my flat, a bell was ringing in my neighbour, Ogino-san's flat.
Oh, that bell was the alarm clock I keep by my bed over there.
When I'm not already working and waiting for a photo, I always wake up at 7:30 AM.
But I woke up in the middle of the night yesterday,
so I was watching some live football matches from abroad.
Keisuke Ogino (34)
Photographer
So, how's the beer froth?
I've tested several glasses, but it seems the froth always disappears around six minutes.
By the way, when you left your flat,
did you see or hear anything?
Now that you mention it,
when I was walking down the stairs,
I heard Sodesaki descending below me.
He always has a bunch of keys swinging from his waist, so they jingle when he runs.
Yeah, I carry keys with me.
See my keyring?
You do have quite a few...
Kazutomo Sodesaki (31)
Writer
These keys are for my house, car, office, bicycle, and safe.
So cigarettes completely burn out in just under nine minutes.
The cigarette you showed me was just about to burn out, wasn't it?
Y-Yeah.
Which means that for around nine minutes, your flat was empty, right?
Of course!
We didn't get to my flat with the detective until after he checked the others.
Then, when you left your flat, did you notice anything that stuck in your mind?
Like a sound or a person...
For a sound...
When I got to the scene, I could hear the ringtone from Tsukihara-san's mobile phone from the crowd.
Who was calling her?
Oh, it seems like it was the chief photographer.
Apparently he called to say he'd scooped a photo.
I see...
What should we do with those three, Inspector?
They have more than enough motive to have done it, so I guess we'll keep them in for questioning a bit longer.
An alarm clock, a bunch of keys and a ringtone...
That's what those three said?
Huh? Yeah.
They're being questioned separately right now.
So how did the experiment go?
Froth on beer lasts around six minutes,
steam lasts eight minutes,
and cigarette smoke just under nine minutes.
So it wasn't connected with the room temperature...?
You look tired, Detective Takagi...
Well, yeah.
I was at a stakeout all night, so I couldn't get any sleep.
If I could use some of the eyedrops Chiba always has, I could at least pretend to freshen up.
But he's still at the stakeout...
Pretend?
That reminds me of something the old man said...
Well? Surprised?
It's something I did a lot back when I was a broke student.
I see, so that's it!
So that person was the killer after all!
Though are you okay, Conan-kun?
It's about time you should be going home.
How about I drive you?
I'm fine, there's a car waiting for me outside.
And once you've heard what I have to say, you may end up going back one more time.
To that block of flats.
Isn't this the first time that the two of us are alone?
Well, now that you mention it, I think it is.
Since I parked on the street in front of Police HQ,
if we are to wait for him, shouldn't we go to a nearby parking lot and wait inside the car?
If that's what you want to do, why don't you force me in?
I'd never do something so inelegant.
I did promise her, after all...
Then I apologise, but could you two stay there and wait for me?
I think it'll all be over in 30 minutes.
Good grief... He should just leave that to the police.
Umm...
Are you sure you don't want to wait inside the car?
kaze
You'll catch a cold.
I'm fine.
kaze no ko
Children belong outdoors.
Hey, hey! It's already past 7 PM!
No matter how many times you do this, it's just a waste of time!
Didn't you already try this several times before we were taken for questioning?
Why'd you come back to time things again?
I don't have any more cigarettes left!
Just after the incident, when I went back into my flat with the detective,
there was still froth on the beer I'd been drinking, right?
There was still steam on my coffee too.
My cigarette was still smoking too, right?
Doesn't that prove that we were all in our flats until just before the crime?
And why are you doing these experiments in my flat?
I was wondering that too, but Takagi-kun...
Because being here will tell us...
...who the killer is.
C-Conan-kun?!
Well, the first ones to enter the three flats were Detective Takagi and I, so only we noticed that, right?
That true?
Umm, well...
Even if you say you noticed something...
C-Conan-kun.
The one who noticed the truth was actually Shin'ichi Kudō-kun and not us, right?
That's why if we do what Shin'ichi-niichan said in his e-mail, it'll be fine.
'When the time comes, the consequences that the criminal failed to erase will emerge.'
That's what Shin'ichi-niichan wrote in his e-mail.
C-Conan-kun.
The one who noticed the truth was actually Shin'ichi Kudō-kun and not us, right?
That's why if we do what Shin'ichi-niichan said in his e-mail, it'll be fine.
'When the time comes, the consequences that the criminal failed to erase will emerge.'
That's what Shin'ichi-niichan wrote in his e-mail.
Then he should've just called Inspector Megure and explained the truth himself...
Hey!
I don't know what you're planning to do.
but you said by being here you'd figure out who the killer is...
You couldn't be thinking I killed President Katsumoto, could you?
No...
The killer used the stairs to avoid the cameras in the lifts, right?
If I had pushed President Katsumoto out of his 26th floor flat,
there's no way I could've got to the front of the block of flats before those guys, right?
I was the first one to show up, right?
Yeah.
When I got there, Tsukihara-san was already among the crowd.
Then why did she get there before you, Sodesaki-san?
You heard the commotion about someone falling and came running too, didn't you?
Why?
I was in the middle of writing an article, and couldn't pull myself away.
But I must've got there only a minute or two later.
Then why did you get there even later than Sodesaki-san, Ogino-san?
There was an unmissable scene,
so when I went to leave, I couldn't.
I was watching football on TV, right?
And what was that unmissable scene?
I-I forgot...
There's exquisite passes, corner kicks, all sorts of things...
Then you were intently watching a football match, right?
Yeah, that's right.
So much so the commotion outside took second place.
Then...
wasn't it annoying?
T-The alarm clock's bell?
Now that you mention it, I also heard it before hearing the commotion and leaving the flat.
That ringing is from the alarm clock in your flat, right?
Yeah, probably.
It's now 7:30 PM.
You said you set the alarm to ring at 7:30 every morning, so why is it ringing now?
That's because the bell rang without being stopped, and stopped naturally after enough time had elapsed.
In other words, it proves that you weren't inside your flat at the time.
You wouldn't be able to calmly watch a football match in a room
where a bell is ringing loudly enough that it can be heard in the flat next door.
Well, it'd be understandable if you ignored the bell ringing to rush out of your flat when you heard the commotion outside,
but if so, you should have got to the scene before Sodesaki-san at the least.
How about that?
That's right!
I remember it now!
The toilet, the toilet!
I had to go to the toilet just then.
I did hear the alarm ringing, but I couldn't stop it.
I heard the commotion about someone falling just before going to the toilet, and it was on my mind, but I just couldn't hold it.
So when you left the toilet the bell had already stopped, and then you headed to the scene?
Y-Yeah, after watching a bit more football...
Damn, that does sound reasonable...
And didn't you already explain it?
If I was the killer, and used the stairs to go up 23 floors to the president's flat, push him off
and then run down to the ground floor, my flat would've been empty for over ten minutes when you got there.
If ten minutes had passed, the froth would've vanished, just like with those.
But when you got to my flat,
my beer still had plenty of froth, didn't it?
Or what?
Are you saying I did some sort of
magic trick to create more froth?
Abracadabra! Alakazam!
And ta-dah, there's all this froth!
T-The froth should be long gone! So how?!
I found salt in the kitchen and sprinkled some in.
So if you pour salt in beer, froth appears?
It seems anything granular that sinks into beer, like sugar or sand, would've worked too.
The moment a granular substance is poured into beer, the surface area in contact with air increases,
so carbon dioxide gathers more easily, and the beer frothes.
So, look, if I pour salt into another glass where the froth has gone...
It's true.
Amazing!
Still, Conan-kun, how did you know something like that?
I heard it from Uncle Kogorō.
Well? Surprised?
It's something I did a lot back when I was a broke student.
He was a poor, broke university student,
so he used to add salt so people wouldn't notice that he was drinking his beer slowly.
Incidentally, this method is also used when photographing beer.
Because having more froth makes it look more appetising.
Something a photographer like you is likely to know.
B-But I didn't have any salt then...
But Ogino-san, when you entered your flat, didn't you knock down a bag by the entrance?
That was a funeral attendance gift, right?
Which means that a certain something would be inside.
Purification salt.
I see. So he used that salt.
Yeah, probably.
As he put the tea that had fallen out of the bag from the impact back in.
At that time, he surreptitiously took the purification salt,
put it in his pocket, ripped the sachet open, and put some salt in his hand.
Just before showing me his glass of beer, he sprinkled some salt in it to show me that his beer had froth.
Well, since that was a trick thought up on the spur of the moment,
even if he managed to get rid of the sachet somewhere,
there should still be some grains of salt left inside his pocket.
And if he pushed someone off a balcony alone, they probably struggled,
and since the circumstances called for him to leave the president's flat as soon as possible,
I'm sure that if we were to check the carpet President Katsumoto had had changed the night before, then we'd find
some trace proving you were in the president's flat between last night and this morning.
B-But, I can't believe Ogino-san was the one
who murdered President Katsumoto.
Right! Even the solicitors said that if it went to court, we had a good chance of winning!
You told me that the president's fingerprints were on the memory card with that photo sequence to begin with, right?
And that proves that the presdent deliberately chose that picture out of them!
He wouldn't have any reason to kill the president when he would win the trial...
But it vanished...
It vanished?!
This morning, the e-mail I received from the president made me feel strangely uneasy, so I checked
and the memory card was gone from my camera bag.
I could immediately tell who did it.
So I went to the president's flat to question him, and as I thought...
How persistent... If you want that memory card,
then try asking the assistant of yours that just quit.
Though he's come into money, so he's probably playing around in another country somewhere.
Even if you call him, I doubt you can reach him.
I knew it! You stole that memory card with your money?!
It was your assistant who told me you lot were planning to sue me.
Just in case you wouldn't drop the charges, I had some ideas of my own.
I can use that photo sequence for quite an exclusive scoop.
Such as 'Famous actress set up by former classmate: A despicable photographer!'
Y-You were classmates?!
With that actress?!
Yeah, back in middle school.
That's how I knew the man was her half-brother.
And those photos weren't taken without them knowing.
I was with them, and I took them to send them copies.
My assistant misunderstood and took them to the president, and that's how the article came to be.
So when I thought she might've killed herself because she thought
I put those photos of her in that article, I couldn't forgive him...
When I snapped out of it, the president was on the ground far beneath, crushed like a frog.
But... Even though I hadn't planned on the crime,
I thought I'd been able to fool you with the beer's froth.
To think that trick made me suspicious instead, and even became evidence against me...
Oh, I suspected you as soon as I heard you were a photographer.
Seriously?
As when you rushed to the scene, all you were holding was your mobile phone.
So I had my eyes on you from the start.
But it's not unusual to rush over
empty-handed if you hear a commotion...
No...
There's one thing a news photographer would never forget to bring to a scene that could bring in a job...
Our tool of the trade: the camera.
Shin’ichi Kudō
Shin’i
Shin’
Kudō
Kudō-sempai
udō-sempai
ō-sempai
-sempai
Kudō-sempai
K
Shin’
Shin
Shin’ich
Shin’ichi Kudō
kimi ni zenzen kyōmi nai uso you are my perfect guy
tokimeki wa kakusenai honto wa ki ni natte shikatanai
koi ni bukiyō son’na style kimi no mae da to betsujin mitai
dare ni mo ienai himitsu no mama
soredemo I’m alright koi no yukue nante
mada it isn’t the last chance for me
iron’na love story o egaite’ru mune no naka
demo risō ni wa hodo tōi
watashi-tte wagamama sore kurai no koto wakatte’ru
dakedo nani ka ikenai no?
Edogawa
kimi to no koi ni koi o shite’ru dake de tsutaetakute mo mada
himitsu ni shite’ru hō ga shiawase dakara ima wa watashi dake no secret love
To Conan
Edogawa-kun
Really, well done, Takagi-kun!
Even you can do deductions if you try!
Right?
It's not that big a deal...
I just said what Kudō-kun told me to in the e-mail...
It seems the case's been solv—
From here on is my area.
Not your territory.
Adults feel the cold. We don't belong outdoors.
What's wrong, you two?
You left the door open.
Nothing.
Let's go home.
Let's. It's started to get cold.
We, the Detective Boys, find ourselves involved
in a serial bombing case while looking for a puppy.
On the next Conan: 'The Car Carrying a Time Bomb'!
Next Conan's Hint: Puppy!
The exploits of Kogorō-san, huh?
I'm no ordinary alcoholic, see!
Yes, you are.