Wait, Candy!
Mao Misawa (5)
Wait!
Candy...
2:30 PM
90 minutes to explosion
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
A delivery van carrying a bomb.
The Detective Boys plan a rescue against the clock!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
When does the Beika Library close?
Will we make it in time?
Ayumi-oneechan!
Candy's in trouble!
Mao-chan! What's wrong?
Hey, who's that?
I think she's a girl who lives near Ayumi-chan.
Huh?! Candy got into a delivery van and was carried away?
Onee-chan, I don't know what to do...
It's all right.
We, the Detective Boys, will definitely find her!
So don't worry about her.
Let's go, Mao-chan.
Onee-chan...
Hey, hey! That's not a job for the Detective Boys—
It's something.
Candy!
Isn't it that van?
Mao-chan?
Yeah! It's got a fox mark on it.
That's Fox Delivery!
Candy!
Candy-chan!
Candy-chan? Are you there?
Candy!
W-What?
Hey, you lot!
Huh? It's Detective Chiba.
Conan-kun.
She's not here.
This must be a different van.
Candy...
It's okay. We'll find her soon.
The Detective Boys are here to help.
Right?
Leave it to us!
Hey, Detective Chiba...
Did some case come up?
Ah, well...
Hey, Chiba!
It wasn't in my van. How about yours?
Huh? Conan-kun!
Hey, is there some case?
Uh, nothing special...
Anyway, it's dangerous for you kids, so hurry off home.
Another van's been stopped near the third district. Let's go.
Right.
Well then, take care!
Goodbye!
Looks like something's going on.
Yeah.
You guys, wait here for a bit.
Hey, Conan-kun!
You too, Haibara-san?
Oh, geez...
Hello?
Ah, hello, Ran-neechan?
What is it, Conan-kun?
What's Uncle Kogorō doing right now?
I'll go check now, hold on.
Please... One more drink...
Geez, Dad, for crying out loud...
Figures.
Ah, don't worry then, it's nothing. Bye!
Megure speaking.
Inspector, it's Mouri.
Oh, it's you. I'm a bit busy right now.
On the Delivery Service case?
What?! How'd you know that?
I happened to see Detectives Takagi and Chiba investigating.
I see...
So, what kind of case is it?
Well, uh...
If I can help, leave it to me!
Inspector!
Truth be told, Mouri-kun, there have been two successive bombings earlier this afternoon.
What?!
Kōzō Tonomura (58)
District Court Judge
The first victim was Kōzō Tonomura, a district court judge.
Kazuhiko Saeki (45)
District Prosecutor
The second was Kazuhiko Saeki, a district prosecutor.
Though their injuries were severe, they were fortunately not life-threatening.
Both of the bombs were time-bombs delivered by a delivery service.
Then, using fingerprints found in the wreckage from the first bomb,
they arrested a man named Utsugi, who had been in jail up until last month
Masato Utsugi (35)
after being charged for violating the Explosive Substances Act.
His motive was revenge, from resentment towards the people who put him in jail.
Also, according to Utsugi's testimony, he'd sent a third bomb as well, to the former detective who arrested him.
Shigekichi Kaneko (65)
Former Police Detective
I see...
So you're looking for a delivery van.
Yeah.
But it's not going well...
Inspector Megure!
We've confirmed that ex-detective Kaneko is safe.
The bomb doesn't appear to have arrived yet.
Okay.
If we believe Utsugi's testimony, the remaining bomb is set to explode at 4:00 PM.
So there's an hour and a half left...
Inspector, we received a reply from Fox Delivery.
According to the reciept for the package,
it was specified to be delivered between 3 and 4 PM.
So where's the bomb now?
The company said they'll try to contact the van carrying it.
The bomb squad has also been readied.
As soon as it's found, they'll mobilize.
Is that so? Looks like we'll make it somehow.
Yes, hello?
What did you say, the delivery van was stolen?!
What?!
Yes, this is van 4.
Huh? A bo—
Gimme the key!
Kingo Ebisawa, 28.
Ginji Kaniyama, 25.
They both have criminal records from committing robberies and other offenses together.
Just before noon, they broke into the Beika branch of Marugane Loans and made off with a million yen.
The description given by the driver of the delivery van
matches with the surveillance camera footage of them.
Isn't "Marugane Loans"...
Yes. It's a loan shark company.
But why would they steal a delivery van?
It seems their getaway car had stalled, and wouldn't start.
It was found abandoned nearby.
Perhaps they chose it to intercept police radio?
A radio receiver was also found in the abandoned car.
I see... So they probably chose the delivery van because of its radio.
Yeah, and without knowing it was carrying a bomb.
What a turn of events...
We're doing everything we can, but we've been unable to find the delivery van with the bomb.
I see...
By the way, where was the van stolen?
Oh, Beika's third district.
Is that so...
Well then, I'll let you know if I learn anything.
I'm counting on you.
Excuse me.
Don't tell me she's in that delivery van?
Yeah.
She might be.
Hey, Conan! How long are you gonna just stay here?!
Come on... Don't you want to look for Candy?
Please, you two!
Ah, of course we'll look for her.
Hey, Mao-chan, where did Candy get into the delivery van?
Huh?
This is a message from the Police HQ to all units.
Continue searching for the bank robbers centering on the location where their getaway car was discovered.
We did it, Bro! Now we'll be able to avoid the cops and escape!
Yeah!
We're lucky you're good with machinery.
Wha—
What are you?!
H-Hey!
Heh, ain't you cute.
2:50 PM
70 minutes to explosion
Here! This is where Candy got into the fox van!
Then it turned round that corner and you lost sight of it, right?
Yeah.
There's not much we can do here by now though, right?
It's probably already somewhere completely different...
Well, we know what direction it headed at least.
Really?
Yeah.
On the right is the exit of a one-way,
and the left is blocked off due to construction.
And none of the side streets are wide enough for a delivery van!
Which means...
They had to go keep going straight, right?
Exactly.
All right! Hurry, hurry!
Yay!
Nothing's moving, there's a traffic jam!
We might be able to catch up with it now.
But which way did it go?
Right? Left? Which way should we go?
Criminals fleeing a crime scene would probably not risk cutting through to get to the other side...
This way!
Wait, Haibara-san!
Let's hurry, hurry!
That's right, Haibara! Now, just in case...
Hello? Doc?
Damn it! Isn't there any way out of this?!
Show me!
Hey, Bro, if you see a shop, let's stop there.
Both of us are starving here.
What's wrong with this thing?! Damn it, damn it!
Never expected them to even deliver puppies...
You don't even have a recipient on you.
So where you headed? Nah, just joking.
Oh, shut up! Stop messing around with that puppy, go do something about this GPS!
Hey, did you know, bro?
GPSes can apparently be used
in reverse to find us as well.
W-What?!
I think I saw that in some drama on TV.
So I broke it when I got in.
I-I see... Good job.
There it is! 300 meters ahead!
We did it!
You ain't getting away!
Candy...
No way!
It can't be!
Not after we've come this far...
Candy...!
3:10 PM
50 minutes to explosion
I don't see it.
Damn!
And we were so close.
Candy...
Are you okay, Mao-chan?
Sorry for the wait.
Doc!
Good timing!
Hurry, Doc!
I know.
Well then... Which way?
It's gone...
Where'd it go?
Maybe they turned again.
Now how can we find it?
What should we do? It'll blow up at 4, right?
There's only 40 minutes left!
Explode?!
Doc...
They didn't know?!
What's going on?!
Now you have no choice but to tell them.
Well, the truth is...
A time bomb'll explode at 4 PM?!
Candy... What'll happen to Candy?
Geez, what're the police doing?!
If they know the number, why haven't they set up checkpoints and started searching for it?!
What about the radio? Couldn't they contact the van directly?
They can tell them there's a bomb aboard!
Of course they're searching for it, but pinpointing a specific Fox Delivery van out of all the vans in the city is quite difficult.
And the culprits have been eavesdropping police radio from the very start.
If they were to erect checkpoints or call out to them on the radio,
they might abandon the van somewhere. And that would hardly be ideal...
What can we do then?
Candy! Candy!
Hey, doggy! Sorry for the wait!
Wow, how cute!
Can I hold it?
So cute!
Wanna go, doggy?
Hey, Ginji, let's go already!
It won't take long, what's the problem?
Sheesh...
3:30 PM
30 minutes to explosion
All right, that's what we can do!
Wait inside the car, guys.
Doc, you stand by so the car's ready to go anytime.
Okay, got it.
Hey, Conan-kun!
Hey, Conan!
What're you doing?
Megure speaking.
It's Mouri.
Inspector, you said they were
intercepting the police radio, right?
Yes, that's how we've been looking at it.
Then please follow these commands.
R-Right... Right...
W-What?!
But that's...!
All right, understood.
Contact the communications command center right away!
Contact Takagi and Chiba as well!
Roger.
Hey, do you really work for Fox Delivery?
Why aren't you wearing your uniforms?
The one with the fox mark.
Genji, let's go.
This is bad!
What if those kids tell the cops?!
Bro...
If you go too fast, what'll happen if we get pulled over for speeding?
R-Right... I guess you're right.
This is a message from the Police HQ to all units.
Checkpoints have been established at the following locations. Passage through each will be prevented.
The intersection of the metropolitan ring road and Kurinishi's third district...
Bro!
Get the map, the map!
This is bad, Bro!
If we go straight, we'll hit a checkpoint!
What? Damn it!
And if we go this way, we'll hit another checkpoint!
Tell me which way, quick!
Turn right here!
Now left... Now right!
Turn right again... No, wait, left!
Get a hold of yourself!
Uh, next... next... Turn left again!
Got it!
We did it, we got away!
We've escaped all the checkpoint! We're home free!
Yahoo!
There it is!
Candy!
Way to go!
Good job, Conan-kun. How did you do it?
I asked old man Kogorō to have Inspector Megure broadcast information about false checkpoints.
I see.
So you left them with just one escape route to lure them here.
That's right.
You in the Fox Delivery van, stop the vehicle!
Eat this!
Watch out!
Bye!
3:45 PM
15 minutes to explosion
Not this one.
Or this one.
Or this one!
The bomb's still in the delivery van!
Candy!
Doc, open the boot!
Hurry, there's just twelve minutes left!
Not this one...
Or this one.
Hey! Are you Candy?
H-Hey! What're you doing, kid?
Here it is!
Damn, there's no time left!
I can't throw the box out in a place like this!
Hey, you two.
Go to some wide open place!
This is a bomb!
B-Bomb?!
You must be joking!
Chuck him out, Ginji.
Okay, Bro!
It's true! Two were already delivered and injured people!
This is the last one, and it's going to explode any minute!
Kid! Hold on tight!
Ginji, get the map!
Got it, Bro!
No, no... There's nowhere open nearby...
Let me see!
Two minutes left!
I know!
Where is it?! Where is it?!
Oh, there it is!
Go there!
Damn! Where is it?! Where is it?!
Only a minute left! There's no time left!
Don't give up!
20 seconds left!
Where is it?!
10 seconds left!
There it is!
3, 2, 1...
I-It can't be...
We were too slow...
Amazing!
That was close...
Stop it!
I know!
Candy...
Candy, that tickles!
A great victory for the Detective Boys!
Shin'ichi Kudō
Shin'i
Shin'
Kudō
Kudō-senpai
udō-senpai
ō-senpai
-senpai
Kudō-senpai
K
Shin'
Shin
Shin'ich
Shin'ichi Kudō
Good job, Mouri-kun! That was amazing!
Yeah! I can't drink anymore!
Huh?
Hmph! Come on, get up, Dad!
A locked room murder at an ice hotel.
How did the killer do it?
On the next Conan: The Unsolvable Ice Trap!
Next Conan's Hint: Will-o'-the-wisp!
A great success for the Detective Boys!
Here's some candy for a reward!
No, you're Candy...