Conan-kun!
Haibara-san!
Doc!
Over here!
Wow, cool!
Isn't that Gomera?
It's beautiful!
Pretty stunning, isn't it?
Yeah, they're really pulling out all the stops.
But of course!
It's been a while, Agasa-san!
Mika Itakura (27)
Ice Festival Executive Committee Chairman
Mika-kun!
This is the woman who invited you guys, Mika Itakura-kun.
She's this festival's Executive Committee chairman.
Welcome to the Ice Festival!
You all enjoying yourselves?
Yeah!
Oh, but those two don't seem to be enjoying themselves that much...
Don't mind me.
It isn't like that!
Ai-chan's a bit of a tsundere, right?
And Conan's kinda cheeky.
Those two aren't very child-like, really.
Oh, I see...
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
A frozen bed in an ice hotel, and the trick behind a locked room murder!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Mika-kun's father was an old friend of mine.
He used to be the village's mayor.
Really?
I was sorry to hear about him...
Yeah...
You mean Mika-san's father...
He passed away in a car accident last year, when the brakes of the car he was driving failed.
W-Who's that man?
Ah, it's Shiota-san!
Wow, so cool!
Shiota-san's so skilled at making ice sculptures that he could even win the world championship!
Incredible!
Tetsuya Shiota (43)
Ice Sculptor
Thank you — I really appreciate such honest words of encouragement.
Most of the statues you see here were made by Shiota-san.
I could only become a sculptor due to Mika-chan's father supporting me.
I'm just trying to return the favour...
Shiota-san...
Besides, I didn't do all of this by myself — all the villagers worked on it together.
Indeed, it looks like everybody teamed up for this.
Yeah, we all love this festival.
This is the last year they'll get to enjoy it, though.
Mayor Yamaguchi!
What do you mean 'this is the last year'?
Tarō Yamaguchi (61)
Mayor
I mean that this year I'll be putting an end to this foolish festival.
Did you decide that on your own?!
Please don't tarnish the mayor's reputation.
Kazuyuki Ogi (34)
Secretary
This course of action was properly
determined by a communal meeting.
Do you know how much debt the village got into from holding this festival each year?
For this village to survive, we were left with no choice but to have Tohto Resort set up a hotel here.
And all went well thanks to this man's hard work with the ice hotel.
Yeah, the festival piqued the interest of the representatives from Tohto Resort.
Well, this is going to be the festival's last hurrah, eh?
We'll be signing the contract with Tohto Resort tomorrow.
The village'll finally be saved from financial ruin.
Which is something the previous mayor never accomplished, did he?
To be honest, I'm actually glad he passed away.
How can you say that?!
Aren't you the one responsible for his death?!
You've got some nerve!
That story again?
Even the police agreed it was an accident!
But didn't my father go out to meet you just then?
There's no way he could have an accident like that on the village outskirts!
I told you I didn't see anything!
The main gate...
That's it, the festival's over!
There's no way it can go on with the main gate in this state.
Did you have a hand in this?
Did you arrange this in order to cancel the festival?
Cut it out!
The festival will be ending this year anyway, so why would I even bother?
Now start cleaning up this mess!
The festival's over!
No, it isn't over yet.
Everything will be fixed by tomorrow morning.
Hold your complaints until then.
Mika-chan, please lend me a hand.
Sure!
Let's do this!
Agasa-san, please leave the rest to us.
You all could use some rest.
No, I...
She's right.
Besides, I'd like to let the children stay at the ice hotel.
hoteru
Ice hotel?
hotaru
Ice firefly?
He said 'hotel', right?
That's right, the ice hotel was built to liven up the festival.
Shiota-san helped build it.
However, it seems it ended up backfiring...
What do you mean by that?
Financially, the village's going through some rough times, so the mayor attempted to attract Tohto Resort to the village.
Since the village doesn't really have any attractions, the others couldn't come up with a better alternative.
Back then, the ice hotel we built caught the mayor's attention, and everyone agreed it'd be good to use to attract potential investors.
We built the ice hotel for the festival's sake, but in the end it ended up becoming the final nail in the coffin.
I should've known better.
Don't be so hard on yourself!
Everybody's really proud of it!
Hey, everyone, please look over there!
It's incredible.
It's beautiful!
Did you build all that out of ice?
That's right!
Won't we end up frozen if we sleep in there...?
There're fur pelts laidover the beds, so you'll be fine if you sleep in a sleeping bag on top of them.
Do you really think these estimates are right?
Are you ever going to learn how to do your job right?!
You're useless!
M-My sincerest apologies!
Make sure you get everything fixed up by tomorrow morning!
What does that damn geezer think he's doing?
Is the mayor going to sleep in here as well?
Yeah, he wants to check out the quality of the ice hotel before Tohto Resort come to sign the contract.
So, this is the dome where you'll be staying tonight.
Amazing!
Here I go!
Ah, it's all nice and fluffy!
It kind of looks like a coffin...
Yeah, I guess you could use one of these to bury someone.
Hey, hey!
Well...
Good night, everyone!
Thanks!
It's cold!
I wonder if the gate has been repaired by now...
It's probably done by now, since
everyone was working on it together.
I'm sure it'll look great!
I can't wait to see it...
What's the matter, Mitsuhiko-kun?
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko? Are you hungry?
A-Actually...
Mayor, please hang on! Mayor!
What's going on?
T-The mayor's...
These are...
Burn marks?
There are some rope-like marks...
But there's something weird about this bed...
Edogawa-kun?
Call the police!
The mayor has passed away.
The cause of death was strangulation, and the estimated time of death is around 2 AM.
Akira Haraguchi (31)
Niigata Prefectural Police Inspector
Because there are no marks of strangulation on the back of the victim's neck,
it seems the killer approached him in his sleep
and killed him by applying pressure from the top of the sleeping bag by means of a thin, string-like weapon.
What puzzles me are the burn marks on the sleeping bag which are right where the victim's neck would be...
Are you implying I did this?
It's true that I suspected the mayor to be behind my father's death.
But I...
Really?
I heard you two were arguing quite a bit regarding this year's festival.
That's—
Hmm? What happened to your hand?
Oh, last night while I was working, my hand
grazed one of the bonfire drums, so I got burnt.
Oh, so you got burnt?
As a matter of fact, there are burn
marks on the mayor's sleeping bag.
What are you trying to say?
She was working with us all night to repair the gate.
There's no way she had enough time to go and kill the mayor!
Can you back that up?
I had to go fetch some tools twice.
But there are plenty of other witnesses.
I see.
By the way, Shiota-san, could you tell me
an estimate of when you went to get the tools?
First around midnight, and then around 4 o'clock.
Both trips took about ten minutes each.
Hey, Detective...
It looks like the entrance to the room was locked, so how did the killer manage to get inside?
There must be a duplicate key at least.
Only the mayor's secretary, Ogi-san, has one.
Since the keys are custom-made, only one
duplicate was ordered besides the master key.
And why do you have the duplicate?
It's my job to wake the mayor up first thing in the morning, so...
So, that means that you were the only person who was able to enter and exit the dome after the mayor had locked it.
Is that right?
Hold on!
Where were you last night at around 2 AM?
I was in my office, doing paperwork.
Were there any witnesses?
I was alone...
But I didn't do it! Honestly!
Ogi-san had the only spare key, and he lacks an alibi...
But would he have committed the crime under such precarious circumstances?
What's with this hole?
Now that I think about it, that bed still seems odd to me...
Did you find anything?
Y-Yeah, there's this strange hole...
Hey! There you are going off on your own again!
We want to help with the investi—
Hey, are you all right?
Hey, running on ice is dangerous!
Still, I wonder why the ice is so slippery...
It wasn't the ice's fault that you slipped, it was the water's.
The water's?
You see, when pressure is applied to ice, it melts into water.
I
C
E
Your feet have your body weight pressing down through them, right?
Do you mean I can melt the ice by doing this?
That's right.
When you do that, the resulting water coat lowers the friction between the ice and your feet, making the surface slippery.
But there doesn't seem to be any water there.
That's because when the pressure's removed, it naturally turns into—
Wait a second... Could that hole be...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, what's wrong?
You don't look good.
Actually, I saw it...
What did you see?
The mayor's ghost!
It happened around 4 o'clock, when
I was coming back from the toilet...
It's cold!
I saw a spirit flying inside the mayor's dome!
Eh, really?
That can't be!
I see. So that's what happened!
I tell you I didn't do it! Please believe me!
We'll hear the whole story once we get to the station.
Please hold on!
I've finally realised the truth behind this case.
The only certainty is that Ogi-san was the only one who was able to get into the dome.
Actually, entering the dome wasn't necessary...
The weapon was able to strangle the mayor's neck without anyone going inside.
Hey!
Conan-kun!
Here are the things you asked for!
Okay!
What're you going to do with something like that?
You're going to describe the trick for us, right?
Oh, yeah... Allow me to describe the trick that was used.
Let's suppose that block of ice is the dome where the mayor was found dead.
And the murder weapon is represented by the plastic bottles and string.
Please pay attention, okay?
The string...!
It's slipping inside the ice block!
The pressure applied by the rope melts the ice.
It's true... The string moves down with ease...
But would something like this really work?
You'd be able to see where the ice melted...
You don't have to worry about that.
Take a good look at the melted part.
It's true, it froze again!
H-How?
I get it, it's because of regelation!
Ah, umm...
When pressure isn't applied anymore, the ice reforms.
The killer estimated the time the mayor would fall asleep, and set up this trick outside the dome.
This way, it was possible to kill the mayor while being elsewhere.
Then suspicion falls right back onto...
Wait a minute!
She didn't have the time to dispose of the murder weapon!
Would it take a long time?
What're you talking about?
Mika-chan's a woman!
It'd take quite a while for someone like her to carry such a heavy weight!
What if she didn't have to carry anything at all?
Hey, Conan!
Is this it?
Yeah!
These are the weights the killer used.
T-This is glass, isn't it?
Something like this would be undistinguishable from ice,
so it could be left in place without looking conspicuous.
All that's left is to pull the string that got stuck inside the dome and...
It won't come out!
Of course. That's because the ice has frozen back in place again.
But that means the trick can't be completed!
That's why the killer had to use this.
I see! By setting the string on fire it could be burnt away.
And it's the reason why the mayor's
sleeping bag ended up getting charred.
But would the part that's inside the ice really burn up so easily?
Actually, it will.
Will this do, kid?
Yeah, thanks!
It could be done with a magnesium ribbon like this one, right?
Oh, that's right.
Magnesium is highly flammable, so even if it's inside ice it'll keep burning.
So that's the spirit I saw!
And this is also why the sleeping bag got charred.
That's...!
As the magnesium burns, it creates a compound: magnesium oxide.
If you check inside the dome, you should find the same compound.
Forensics!
Yes, sir!
You'd only need five minutes to get rid of the murder weapon this way, right?
But... I...
That's right, Mika-kun didn't do it.
But you just said...
To make sure this trick works, you'd have to know
exactly where the mayor was sleeping.
And you can't tell where the bed is placed from outside.
That's certainly true...
However—
Only one person had that knowledge...
The one who designed this ice hotel, Tetsuya Shiota-san!
It can only be you!
That can't be...
H-Hold on!
Though I designed the place, there'd be no way for me to know exactly where the mayor's neck would be while sleeping!
The bed in the VIP dome was a perfect fit for the mayor.
I found it strange, how, despite the dome being really
spacious, the bed was actually quite small in comparison.
That's because the bed was made to
perfectly match the mayor's short height.
Do you...
Do you have any evidence to prove that?
The proof is the white powder on Shiota-san's sleeve.
That's magnesium oxide, which caught on your sleeve when you burnt the murder weapon, isn't it?
S-Shiota-san... Please say something!
That's enough, Mika-chan.
And I thought it'd work out fine...
Shiota-san...
Shiota-san, what reasons did you have for killing the mayor?
I'd overheard...
What those two were saying!
One time, when I went into the city hall on an errand, I overheard them...
We have to make them sign the contract!
Yes, sir!
Otherwise, we won't be able to continue tricking the village out of its money.
We don't want anyone else to realise what's going on, like Itakura did.
Don't worry about that.
If anyone else notices, I'll cut their brakes, just like Itakura's.
T-That can't be!
Yamaguchi had been embezzling the village festival's
funds, and one day Itakura-san found out! So they—
I-It wasn't like that!
If you have something to add to your story, now's the time.
As even if you don't tell us, we'll know soon enough!
So, to cover their schemes my father was...
And the ice hotel we all looked forward to ended
up being a murderous tool devised by Shiota-san!
He probably did this to give you an airtight alibi, Mika-kun.
Me?
Yeah.
If the mayor was murdered, you were
highly likely to become the prime suspect,
so he did all this to craft a perfect alibi for you.
Shiota-san...
Most likely, the one behind the main
gate's collapse was Shiota-san as well.
I just wanted to protect you...
Itakura-san's beloved Mika-chan...
I did it for your sake.
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
Ultimately, the festival had to be cancelled.
After what happened, it's not like there was much of a choice.
But I'll make sure to bring it back next year.
For this village's sake.
When that happens, can we make some ice sculptures too?
You're gonna make one?
Yeah, I did make one!
What's that?
It's the one thing Genta-kun loves the most, right?
Yeah.
Don't tell me...
It's an eel lunch box!
Are the eels supposed to be inside it?
One morning while off-duty, Detective Takagi found a bag on a street corner.
And, inside that bag, there was...
On the next Conan: 'Detective Takagi Finds 30 Million Yen'!
Next Conan's Hint: Plaster cast!
Genta-kun, did you even put any eel in it?
Of course, it'll make a great souvenir!