It's still early in the morning
but I already ate too much.
Let's run a bit and get back home.
Morning!
Good morning!
Good morning, you're up early.
I'm not a suspicious person!
A lost item?
Looks like it.
I'm not going to keep it for myself!
It's exactly 30 million yen!
It wasn't reported lost?
No.
But it's a good thing you're the one who found it, Takagi-san.
So you're a police detective. Sorry for doubting you.
So Sasamoto-san, do you run this course every day?
Yes. I just hope whoever lost it gets it back sometime soon.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
30 million yen lying in a lost bag.
What is its owner planning?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Have I seen anyone carring a brown bag?
Yes. The person who dropped it might not have been from this area though.
I'll ask my neighbors as well.
Thank you.
You did it, Detective Takagi!
I heard you found a lot of money!
How do you guys know that?
We call ourselves the Detective Boys for a reason.
Hey, if the bag's owner doesn't claim it within six months, then it'll belong to you, right?
You'll be a billionaire!
No way.
It's a policeman's job to return lost items.
Oh? So you won't treat me to some eel bowls?
Told you so.
We'll help you find whoever lost it, right?
We don't have school, so we have some free time.
You found it today early in the morning, correct?
Yeah, around 6 AM.
Today was my day off so I slept at a friend's place nearby last night.
Then, while I was jogging with a woman named
Sasamoto-san, I just ran into it right here.
In the middle of the road?
Yes.
What a moron.
Dropping a bag full of money...
Let's work together on this, Takagi.
If a normal citizen such as myself had found the bag...
Hello...
Yes, it is.
Eh? The bag's owner showed up?
Well, if you need any help later, call me.
What did he come for?
Toshiyuki Hiranuma (45)
Manager of an Organic Food Shop
Toshiyuki Hiranuma-san, you're the one who lost this bag, correct?
Yes.
His wife died from an illness recently.
The 30 million yen is from life insurance.
I see.
But Hiranuma-san, why did you drop that money?
Well, it's an embarrasing story.
My friend was in Beika Town,
so I thought I'd show it to him.
So you were carrying 30 million yen just to brag?!
Well, yeah. I was in such a good mood that I went for some drinks.
But when I woke up this morning, I paled when I noticed I didn't have the bag with me.
So you dropped it last night, not this morning?
R-Right.
Got it.
Though since it's such a large amount, I can't exactly give it back to you right away.
I see.
Oh, is this paint?
Oh, sorry? Where did I get that from?
Well then, we'll call you as soon as we can give you the bag.
Fine. I'm not in a hurry anyway.
We found the owner right away.
The Detective Boys didn't even get to do anything.
That was boring.
Oh, Detective!
I was just about to go to the police station.
Oh, you're the lady from this morning!
It wasn't there?
Yeah. I passed through there delivering newspapers at about 5 AM, and there wasn't anything there then.
Then maybe Hiranuma-san dropped it later?
It looks so creepy!
Did you find anything, Conan-kun?
I'm not sure yet...
Look! Could these be Hiranuma-san's footprints?
Well, Hiranuma-san's shoes were dirty.
And look at the paint flaking off here.
It's the same as the paint on his shoulder.
So, Conan-kun, are you saying that
Hiranuma-san came here this morning?
Yeah, and he put the bag here just before you arrived.
"Put"?
Even that early in the morning, it's hard
to believe that nobody'd pass here
for the entire hour that went by between
the newspaper delivery guy and you.
I see.
If it was dropped here just before I came, then
I should have been able to spot Hiranuma-san.
Yes.
In other words, Hiranuma-san put the bag in the middle of the street with the right timing so somebody would pick it up.
He was observing the situation from this warehouse.
A lost item?
Looks like it...
But why did he want Detective Takagi to pick it up?
I see! It was for Sasamoto-san!
I just happened to be here, but Sasamoto-san said she jogs through this place every morning.
So, he tried to make Sasamoto-san pick up the 30 million yen?
But it's still very strange! It's a lot of money!
Yeah.
Hideko Sasamoto (47)
Part-timer
So, we can give the bag back to its rightful owner, right?
I'm glad.
His name's Toshiyuki Hiranuma-san.
Do you know him, Sasamoto-san?
Hiranuma-san? I don't think so.
Who is he?
Who is this guy?
I heard he's from the police.
Police?
She didn't look like she was lying...
Excuse me...
Detective!
What is it?
Kunitarō Ōba (50)
Hideko's Boss
Did you find the culprit?
Culprit?
So it's not the same case.
My name's Ōba. I'm the floor supervisor at this supermarket.
And so what is this case about Sasamoto-san's husband?
Sasamoto-san's husband was murdered.
Last month, on the 30th, fifteen years have
passed and the killer still hasn't been found.
And the statute of limitations used to be fifteen years, didn't it...
Yeah.
Hideko's quite cheerful now,
but she couldn't smile at the time.
She was always looking down.
Actually, Hideko-san and I are going to get married.
She refused to marry me when I asked her at first.
Out of respect for her late husband, she didn't allow herself to become happy.
But that's not a good enough reason, is it?
Recently, she finally started thinking about her own happiness.
A few days ago, we both went to her husband's grave, to ask him to release his wife.
But it's complicated.
If the killer shows up again, I think she'll never stop hating him.
Supervisor!
Oh, sorry! I'm coming!
Fifteen years passed, but it's still unsolved.
Are this case and the 30 million yen bag related?
No way.
How could they be related?
I don't know yet.
Gotcha. I'm going to look into this case.
The case happened in a fourth-floor office at night at night, 15 years ago.
The killer didn't want to get caught on the surveillance camera,
so he climbed up the pipes in the gap between it and the next building up to the 4th floor.
He then sneaked into the office from the balcony.
He killed Akio Sasamoto-san, who was doing overtime by himself, and left after stealing 5 million yen in cash.
But since some footprints were left behind by the killer's tennis shoes,
a list of all the people who bought these shoes was established,
and a thorough investigation was started.
Hiranuma-san's name was also on that list.
I see. So, that's why...
What do you mean?
To redeem himself for the murder, he tried to give the 30 million yen to the widow, Sasamoto-san.
Once Sasamoto-san had picked it up, if he didn't show himself in six months, the money would go to her.
So, Hiranuma-san was the killer?
No.
I thought the same thing at first.
But Hiranuma-san can't be the killer, Conan-kun.
It was literally impossible for him to commit the crime.
How so?
When a police officer questioned him, he had a broken leg.
When we checked the hospital he went to, we learnt he got
the plaster cast for this leg three days before the crime.
He couldn't have climbed up to the 4th floor with a broken leg!
And he can't wear tennis shoes with a cast, either!
Right.
So, the case from fifteen years ago and
Hiranuma-san's 30 million yen aren't connected.
And the idea that he tried to make somebody pick it up is probably just us overthinking it.
All right...
Oh, a phone call! It's from Uncle.
Hello?
Hey, Uncle. What is it?
Uncle Kogorō seems to be interested in this 30 million yen case.
When I told him what we learnt, he told me to
ask Detective Takagi to investigate something.
Whether or not anyone Hiranuma-san knew also had a broken leg at the time.
If Mouri-san's asking, I guess I can check...
He wondered if he could get the help of the Detective Boys, too!
He said that whatever kind of information we can get is okay, as long as it's related to Hiranuma-san.
We're assisting a Great Detective?
All right! Time to investigate!
Okay, see you later!
I apologise, but the organic food shop Hiranuma is now closed.
—Hiranuma
The shop closed a month ago.
That was when his sick wife died.
Hiranuma-san seems to be a very honest man.
But something strange happened recently.
Though he said he was going for a trip for a while,
he happened to come back the same day!
It happened a week ago.
A week ago?
Oh, that? It was at the end of last month, on the 30th.
Though now I think about it, Hiranuma-san said
something peculiar the previous evening.
You nursed your wife a lot.
But you should relax now.
Your late wife would agree.
I wish I could, but...
There was something I decided to do a long time ago...
But when the time came...
I got scared.
What are you talking about?
I'm...
really...
such a pathetic man!
Then he kept saying it wasn't something which could be compensated for with money.
Then, the next morning...
Oh, Hiranuma-san!
You're carrying a bag. Are you going to a hot spring?
No, I'm leaving for a while.
Morita-san, please take care of yourself.
It was as if he was saying his last goodbye.
Still, he came back the same day during the evening, saying he'd been unable to go on his trip.
What do you think, Conan-kun?
It's Detective Takagi.
Hello.
Hey, Kan-chan! Already having beer at noon?
Today is my day off.
Good afternoon.
Welcome!
One kakesoba, please!
One kakesoba, coming up!
Is that so?
Yeah, I missed a step, and then my right leg...
Back then, Kanzaki-san, you didn't have
your own health insurance card, right?
Who are you?
And just what are you saying?
That day, Hiranuma-san knew that...
That's why he could...
So, what does the famous detective Kogorō Mouri-san want with us?
I don't know, either...
But first, the introductions.
This is Hideko Sasamoto-san. She found the bag with me.
Hey, Takagi! Why did you call me here all of a sudden?
I'm busy, you know!
Huh? But you're the one who—
What did I—
Not again!
Here it is!
He fell asleep!
A detective of my skill can decipher an entire case by simply listening to gossip.
Hiranuma-san...
What is it?
I'm here to speak about the murder-robbery you commited fifteen years ago, of course.
You can't be serious.
But I am.
But that's impossible, Mouri-san!
Hiranuma-san broke his leg three days prior to the murder.
Just because the X-rays were tagged with Hiranuma-san's
name doesn't mean they're necessarily his!
You mean Kanzaki-san borrowed his health insurance card?
And the cast?
He did it himself with plaster after the crime.
But...
I don't have any proof.
But Takagi, if you think Hiranuma-san is innocent,
can you tell me why he's not objecting?
I thought about it when Kanzaki broke his leg.
My leg hurts!
I'm sure it's broken!
Geez, at least get yourself some health insurance, you moron!
Here, I'll lend you mine.
Won't I be caught?
How could you? It doesn't even have a picture on it.
Yes, it was me.
I did it.
My deepest apologies.
At that time I was an irresponsible coward.
A worthless delinquent.
But...
I met a woman who changed my life.
I married her and worked honestly.
Then, I got my own shop, even if it was a small one.
But the happier we became, the more I regretted my past mistakes.
I thought many times about turning myself in.
But I just couldn't.
My wife got seriously ill.
Nobody would have watched over her if I wasn't around.
And then she died last month and I received the 30 million yen.
So then you really didn't drop it —
you put it there on purpose...
Yes.
But why did you go though all this trouble?
He's right!
If you really felt guilty, you would just have to meet her and give it to her directly!
I was a coward.
I was afraid of getting caught by the police.
That's not right, is it, Hiranuma-san?
You came here a week ago, right?
You planned to give Sasamoto-san the 30 million
yen, and then turn yourself in to the police.
But you weren't able to.
When I came here, I heard them.
Sasamoto-san, I proposed to Hideko-san.
But she then told me that it would be too
disrespectful to you if she's happy without you.
I understand her feelings.
But it's been fifteen years now.
Well? Could you release her from being just a victim's relative?
I won't forget you, but I want to bury that case
in the depths of my heart and forget about it.
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
Yes.
I couldn't come out.
Since his widow was trying to forget the case.
In the end, you failed to give her the
money, apologise, or turn yourself in.
If a killer who escaped the police
for fifteen years turned himself in...
Reporters would've swamped the victim's relatives.
Despite her finally trying to start her new life.
But Hiranuma-san, no matter how much you try to convince yourself, you cannot erase the past.
But this case is special.
You can't erase it, but you can conclude it.
If you serve your sentence, and Sasamoto-san accepts it...
If you finally put an end to it, nobody will have to bear the burden of it anymore.
You'll be able to have a fresh new start.
Both of you!
Right, Takagi?
Toshiyuki Hiranuma-san.
As a suspect to a robbery and a murder,
please follow me to the police station.
Yes.
Could you accept the 30 million yen?
Please use it yourself, when the
time comes for you to start afresh.
Bye!
See you tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
Yeah!
Oh, crap! I forgot about him...
Where am I?
Sorry, old man.
We were heading to the place of
someone who'd identify a killer for us, but...
On the next Conan: The Client's Message!
Next Conan's Hint: Fox!
Mouri-san got left behind?!
Give me 10% of that 30 million yen!
He'll be fine.