Then that woman who hired you to investigate
whether or not her boyfriend was cheating...
Yeah, she's dead.
She fell down a stone staircase.
Kaoru Sasamori (24)
Deceased
Tsuge! How dare you come here?!
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb!
Takashi Sasamori (28)
Kaoru's Elder Brother / Photographer
You were just using her, weren't you?!
Then when your marriage drew near, Kaoru became
a nuisance, so you pushed her down a stone staircase!
Hikari Tsuge (33)
Kaoru's Ex-boyfriend / Sculptor
Talk about nonsense.
I saw it!
You were at the top of the staircase Kaoru fell from!
P-Please, stop!
Mariko Noguchi (30)
Tsuge's Manager
The police investigation already determined that to be a simple misunderstanding!
Shut up!
You might have fooled the police, but not me!
Stop it!
You two, please cut it out.
Kazumi Ishikura (25)
Kaoru's friend / Ballerina
Don't argue in front of Kaoru.
Please let her rest in peace.
She's right. Remember, this is a funeral.
No matter how much you might hate me, I didn't do it.
If you excuse me.
Hey, Tsuge-san.
That was three months ago.
Then this morning, Tsuge-san contacted
you and said he'd reveal who killed her?
Yeah.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
What is the real meaning behind an artist's unusual piece of art?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Is something wrong?
Well, there was a landslide up ahead, so this road's blocked.
Really?
We were trying to get to that house.
Ah, you too?
It's on that road, so you should be fine.
Thanks.
Damn, I can barely see what's in front of me.
Can you drive all right? Be careful, Dad.
Hey, who else is coming?
He said he called the three who'd
been arguing at the funeral, too.
Looks like someone else got here first.
Mouri-san, did Tsuge call you here too?
Yeah.
Ah, it's raining cats and dogs.
Anyway, let's go in.
Umm, whose car is this?
Oh, it's Tsuge's.
These past three months he's secluded himself in this atelier while working on a piece.
Oh no, he forgot to lock the door.
Tsuge-san! It's me, Noguchi!
Here.
Sorry, I forgot to bring an umbrella.
Thanks.
No problem.
Anyway, you should hurry and dry off your clothes.
Tsuge-san?!
It's too late.
Ran, call the police!
Right!
The crime scene must be preserved.
Everybody, please leave the room.
Umm...
Please make sure they don't touch that piece of art.
Huh? That's art?
It looks like a pile of junk.
Is there really any point in something like that?
H-How rude!
Are you making fun of Tsuge's work?
No, no.
Anyway, I'll make sure to tell the police, so could you leave the room for now?
Are you sure you will? I'm trusting you here!
Yeah, I've got it, understood!
What's this?
There's no dust on top of the tape,
so there was something there recently.
Is that a screen?
"Demurrer"...
If I recall correctly, that means something like "a declaration of objection".
Hey!
Don't go wandering about!
Sorry!
Just what was there?
And who moved it?
There's nothing anywhere in the house that'd look like it'd fit, so the killer probably took it out.
The victim is Hikari Tsuge.
Real name, Ritsu Hikage, 33 years old.
He worked as a sculptor.
By the way, it seems "Hikari Tsuge" was an anagram of his real name, "Ritsu Hikage".
An "anagram" is when you rearrange the order of letters in a word to create another one, right?
Yeah.
The cause of death was intercranial injury from a blow to the back of the head.
A hammer that we believe to be the weapon was found lying nearby, but any possible fingerprints had been wiped off it.
So, just to confirm...
Everyone here was invited by the victim, who was to reveal who was behind a previous incident?
That's right, Inspector.
By the time we arrived, he was no longer
breathing and the killer had already escaped.
About that, Mouri-kun.
According to the police officer at the checkpoint, absolutely nobody came down from the road that leads to this atelier.
So, that means whoever did it is still around here?
We must consider that possibility.
No, to begin with, there were only four cars that
came this way instead of turning around, he said.
Only four cars, huh?
So me, Kazumi-san, Sasamori-san,
and Mouri-san and company.
So, the killer's right here?
I see. There's only one direct road leading here,
and there's a checkpoint right before it.
Escaping down the slope in this rain and total darkness would be impossible.
Which means this area's truly a closed circle.
No, that can't be.
After all, we were the first ones to arrive and everyone else followed.
That's right. I was the first one who arrived after you.
I came behind him, and Noguchi-san got here last.
Then, we entered the atelier
together and discovered the body.
I see.
But, you know...
When we told him we were coming to this
atelier, the officer said "you too", didn't he?
Which means there was another car that came to the atelier before us, right?
We'd be able to find out the killer if we ask that officer about that car's model or driver, right?
Well, although he remembered there were four cars,
he said he couldn't remember any of the drivers' faces nor their cars' models.
There's no way I could tell with all this rain!
Come on, I was counting on you.
So, to summarize all of this.
To begin with, there was a single car at the atelier, which belonged to the deceased Tsuge-san.
Then, Mouri-kun and company arrived here.
He was followed by three more cars, making it a group of four.
However, according to what the officer said, another car passed him before Mouri-kun's.
Which means...
The first car to arrive was the killer's, who killed Tsuge-san, then left the atelier and hid somewhere.
And, when everybody showed up, joined them as if nothing had happened.
That's what must've happened.
So, what was the motive of the crime?
To silence him, of course!
Hearing that Tsuge-san would reveal who had killed Kaoru Sasamori-san three months ago,
the killer rushed to the atelier as soon as they could and murdered him.
In other words, the person behind this
murder is also Kaoru Sasamori-san's killer.
And that person is...
One of you three!
That's it!
Thank you, Captain Obvious.
The problem is which of the three did it.
Hold on a sec.
If we assume the killer's among us three, and Tsuge
knew it, then why would he call that person?
Maybe he was trying to play detective?
He did act childish at times.
Yeah, so does that mean he summoned us all the way to this
atelier because he wanted to proclaim the killer was one of us?
Oh, well...
Anyway, I'm not the killer.
That day, I'd promised to have dinner with my sister.
But I got pushed into holding a photo shoot,
so I was a little late, and when I went to meet her...
Kaoru?! Are you okay, Kaoru?!
Somebody... from behind me...
Someone pushed you?
I'm sure I saw him back then.
I caught a glimpse of Tsuge atop the stone staircase.
So I was convinced Tsuge was the one behind it.
But it wasn't like that...
Tsuge-san was a witness, right?
Therefore, I can't be the killer.
However, there's nobody who could prove that, is there?
Are you calling me a liar?!
Kaoru was my sister!
But you didn't get along all that well, did you?
She told me that you were disputing how your parents' inheritance would be split with her.
She told you that?!
So you got fed up...
and pushed Kaoru down the staircase, didn't you?
What'd you say?!
Please hold on, Kazumi-san.
You might look like you were really close friends with her...
But didn't you have a motive for killing Kaoru-san too?
What do you mean?
You see, Tsuge was with another woman besides Kaoru-san.
What?!
And Mouri-san was hired to find exactly who.
That's right.
Then, that other woman you mentioned...
Yeah, it was Kazumi Ishikura-san.
I didn't know he was going out with Kaoru either.
What's this?
Tsuge-san just proposed to me!
What should I do?
What the hell is this?!
Tsuge-san, what does this mean?!
I'm talking about work right now. Wait until I'm done.
How long have you been dating Kaoru?
It isn't like that.
Don't play dumb with me!
Break up! Break up with her!
Even so, it's not like you didn't have a motive to kill her.
My sister once told me...
Kaoru-san, take this.
What is it?
There's one million yen inside.
I want you to split up with Tsuge.
No way...
Ever since you two started dating,
Tsuge's barely worked at all.
So, take this and split up.
I'm leaving!
I heard that since Tsuge was barely working,
your clients started looking for different artists.
If that happened, you'd have to pay a huge amount of money for breach of contract.
Are you saying I killed Kaoru-san over that?
It's true that ever since Kaoru-san died, Tsuge started devoting himself to his work like he was possessed.
But that had nothing to do with me!
Hey, Inspector Takagi.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Uncle Kogorō wanted me to ask you
to check if there's any possible hiding places for
a car between the police checkpoint and here.
Ah, sure.
Maybe around here?
I'll just take a quick look!
Ah, Conan-kun!
Over here, that cabin'd be in the way, so you wouldn't be seen by cars coming up the hill.
Which means...
Is this it?
The object that was taken from the crime scene.
In which case, it's just like I thought.
Then, everyone...
I'd like all of you to accompany me to the
station so we can hear your stories one by one.
Dad?
It's time for Sleeping Kogorō!
There's no need to go to the police station.
Inspector, I'll settle this here and now.
What?
When I found Tsuge-san's body here in the atelier,
I spotted traces of an object having been taken away.
An object?
Taking the situation into account, the perpetrator
most likely took it away after the murder.
Takagi, bring it here.
Y-Yes!
Why did Tsuge-san let three months pass before
stating he'd reveal Kaoru Sasamori-san's killer?
He could've revealed the killer on the day of Kaoru-san's
funeral, when he got into an argument with Sasamori-san.
That's true.
Tsuge-san probably wanted to identify the killer in his own way, and three months were necessary to do so.
You couldn't mean...
Correct. The time he took producing the objet d'art you see before you.
This piece of art is titled "Demurrer".
It means "a declaration of objection".
Mouri-san, I've brought it here.
If you please, place it at the back of the
room, aligned with the sellotape marks.
Right.
Remember this. His artistic name, Hikari Tsuge,
was an anagram of his real name, Ritsu Hikage.
"Hikari Tsuge" and "Ritsu Hikage"...
hikari
hikage
Truly an artist of light and shadow.
So if you take the title of this piece of art, "Demurrer", to be an anagram...
From the original title, a new one emerges...
"Murderer".
An alternate title, hidden in the shadow.
It has an alternate title of "murderer"?
The preparations are done.
Ran, lower the projector screen that's above the door and turn off the room lights.
Okay.
Takagi, turn on the lamp.
Understood.
What about this is related to a murderer?
Takagi, turn the sculpture's base around slowly.
Okay.
That's...
Shadow art.
It's impossible to tell what the piece is on a first glance,
but when light shines on it from a certain
angle, an artistic shadow emerges.
Tsuge-san was trying to identify the killer through his work.
Ran, turn the lights back on.
Kazumi Ishikura-san...
You're the one behind the deaths of Kaoru Sasamori-san and Hikari Tsuge-san!
Hold on a second, Mouri-kun!
It's a bit of a stretch to identify her as the
murderer just with a shadow of a ballerina.
As you say, that shadow alone isn't strong enough evidence.
However, the lamp was removed from the scene
out of fear that the shadow would be seen.
And that action itself is irrefutable
evidence pointing towards the killer.
Think back.
To reach the lamp's position you would have to step over Tsuge-san's body.
However, there was a pool of blood on the other side,
so the killer couldn't step over it,
as footprints would be left behind.
In other words, just like Conan did
back when we discovered the body,
the killer crawled underneath the workbench
to fetch the lamp from the other side.
Sorry if I sound rude, but Sasamori-san and Noguchi-san's physiques
prevent them from crawling underneath the workbench.
The only one who could've passed through there was the ballerina, Ishikura-san.
And there's one last thing...
When you got out of your car, you didn't have an umbrella, and were soaking wet.
But Conan told me that the driver's seat in your car was also drenched.
In other words, you were already drenched before leaving your car.
That's because you went out in the rain in order to throw away the lamp.
We were supposed to get married.
At least, that's what I believed.
So when I heard he called all of you here, I thought he intended to announce our engagement, so I rushed here straight away.
But instead, Tsuge showed me the shadow art and identified me as a murderer.
What are you talking about? Weren't we
going to announce our engagement today?!
You told me you'd marry me if Kaoru was gone, didn't you?!
That woman was getting so annoying, she even hired
a detective to sniff about, so I just said that out of frustration.
I never thought you'd take me seriously
and actually go kill her.
She was your best friend!
Kaoru?! Are you okay, Kaoru?!
Talk about betraying a friendship.
I won't say anything bad if you surrender youself.
I called a detective named Kogorō Mouri here, too.
That guy should be able to take you to the police.
If you want, I can introduce you to a good lawyer—
Then...
Then why didn't you break the sculpture?
That way, you wouldn't have had to conceal the lamp.
It was more than that she didn't break it...
She couldn't break it.
Yes, I couldn't break it.
I was happy.
As even if he made it just to accuse me,
it meant that he was thinking about me for the
whole three months he worked on this piece of art.
So, I couldn't break it.
Hey, Dad!
You're drinking too much beer!
Besides, why are the lights off?
Shut up! Just you watch!
This is my shadow art, y'see.
Seriously?!
Amazing, it's Mom's profile!
S-S-S-So it seems...
I guess you do have artistic talent, right, Dad?
I... I guess so...
From now on, call me "Art Kogorō"!
More like "Argh" Kogorō Mouri, right?
What?
Ran and two of her friends discover
an odd corpse on the way to school.
And next to it, there is...
On the next Conan: Yūsaku Kudō's Cold Case (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Candy!
tō-san
Dad's cold case, huh?
Who do you mean by "dad"?
I meant Saitō-san, Saitō-san!