Huh? We should stop?!
You mean we should drop the case?!
Well, yeah...
As the police, we should arrest the killer ourselves without relying on some novelist, Assistant Inspector Megure!
The media's in quite an uproar about this case, after all.
They think the "death" character written in the deceased's blood could mark the beginning of a series of bizarre murders.
Yeah...
It's fine.
Because this wasn't a murder.
B-But this "death" character...
I guarantee it.
On my name as Yūsaku Kudō.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
What's the mystery behind Dad's unsolved case from ten years ago?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
So Shin'ichi Kudō-kun's dad is the famous mystery writer, Yūsaku Kudō?
Yeah. Though it seems he's not in Japan at the moment, but writing abroad.
When I was younger, I used to read his books a lot.
Like the Night Baron series.
Well, it's thanks to those books
that his son ended up as a mystery nut.
But it must be a relief for you. With
a best-selling author for a father-in-law,
you'll be living the good life when you're married.
Married...?!
Anyway, is what you said earlier true?
You said you knew about an odd case where even Yūsaku Kudō threw in the towel.
Yeah, back when Shin'ichi's dad was still in Japan, he used to help with investigations.
But in that one case, he gave up halfway.
Shin'ichi was really mad because of that.
And? What kind of case was it?
Hmm... I think there was some bloody character written near the body...
Hey, are you okay?!
Hang in there, Takaichi!
Takaichi-san!
Hey, Takaichi!
What happened?
Well, he didn't come to work today, so we went looking for him and found him lying here.
There's blood dripping from his mouth, too...
I called an ambulance just in case.
He doesn't need an ambulance.
He's already been dead for nine hours, it seems.
Did he happen to be an alcoholic?
Uhh, yeah.
Even though he said his doctor told him to stop.
But how did you know that?
The whites of his eyes have turned yellow, and despite being thin, his belly is bulging out.
That's ascites, which proves he had a bad liver.
Also, a can of beer was left untouched in the delivery bin of the vending machine.
Judging from the situation, it's probably what he was trying to buy just before he died.
People with bad livers usually avoid alcohol,
as it makes their symptoms worse.
I theorized that if he wanted to drink
despite that, he could have been an alcoholic.
Amazing...
Having drunk alcohol, his cirrhosis caused him
to vomit blood from variceal ruptures,
and at that time, nobody was around to help him, so he ended up dying...
That's what you'd normally think.
But he didn't die from illness...
...but due to a maliciously perpetrated crime.
The proof of that is right in front of him.
Look.
The character for "death" was written in blood.
Wait a second!
This "death" character...
It's just like the one found at the crime scene ten years ago!
Huh?! Could that mean...!
You mean the one you said Shin'ichi-kun's dad gave up on?
Yeah. Back then, Shin'ichi showed me a photo from the scene, so I'm sure of it!
Huh? Got an e-mail on the Shin'ichi phone?
Oh, it's from Ran.
"Today, on our way to school, we came across a murder scene."
"Shockingly, there was a character written in blood just like the one you showed me ten years ago."
"Since Sera-san and Sonoko want to see that photo too, after school we'll go to your house to look for it. I think I know where it was,
"so that's okay, right?"
A character written in blood ten years ago... Does she mean the case Dad ran out on?
Hey, wait a second!
She said they're going to look for it, so does that mean Sera and Sonoko are going to my house too?!
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
Now that you mention it, he's not here.
That brat, did he run off on us?
He said he had something urgent to do, so he had to leave early.
He said he'd make amends someday.
Make amends?
If he's making us something, I hope it's got lots of eel in it.
An eel assortment, you say...
Ah, I got a reply from Shin'ichi.
"I don't really want you turning my house upside down without me there,"
"so I told Conan-kun where the photo is and I'm having him pick it up, and bring it to the Detective Agency for you."
"Sorry about that."
Then just tell me where it is...
I get it! Could it be that there's
porn hidden close to it?
But, you know... We're already here.
KUDŌ
Isn't this Shin'ichi Kudō-kun's house?
Yeah...
Since we're here, we might as well go in.
I heard there's somebody called Subaru living here too.
I'd like to meet him!
Sorry for intruding!
Oh, those are Conan-kun's shoes.
So he's already here, huh?
That brat sure is fast!
But you know, there's something I've been wondering about Subaru-san for a while.
Huh? What?
You know, he always wears clothes that cover his neck!
Huh? Really?
Yeah, that's why I think he has an embarrassing tattoo
or something on his neck that he wants to hide.
Well, now that you mention it...
So when he lets his guard down sometime, let's leap in and tear off his clothes!
How about it?
"How about it?" Are you sure you don't just want to see him naked?
Well, I guess there's that too.
Conan-kun...
So you were in here!
Oh, Subaru-san. Umm...
We heard Conan-kun was coming.
Do you mean that he's in the library?
Okay then, we'll go check.
Sonoko!
Looks like he doesn't have any tattoo on his neck...
Sera-san, let's go.
Yeah, I'm coming.
Hey, Conan-kun?
Do you need some help finding it?
It's fine. I think I've almost got it.
Why don't you go have some tea in the kitchen?
I'll bring it to you once I find it.
Really?
Then we'll wait for you, okay? Let's go.
Yeah. See you later, Conan-kun.
Okay.
For crying out loud, I told her not to come in the e-mail!
I knew it. Shin'ichi-kun's hiding something, isn't he?
Hiding something? Like what?
P-o-r-n!
No way...
I mean, he has you clean the place up every month.
Isn't it odd that that photo's the one thing he doesn't want you to look for?
But...
No. Maybe what he was hiding was the presence of a woman.
A woman?!
Take a look at this.
It's a hairband.
I found it left on a shelf over here.
It's the sort of thing a woman could leave behind by mistake, right?
Ah, I'm sure it belongs to Shin'ichi's mum. Right?
Now that you mention it, she does tie up her hair a lot.
But in among the unwashed dishes, there's a glass
someone wiped a lipstick mark off with their thumb.
And in the sink's drain, there's a long strand of hair.
Though it looks like it's a hair from a wig.
D-Don't tell me Shin'ichi's having an affair and brought some other woman here?!
If you think so, then take a photo of this and stick it in your diary to preserve it.
If you carefully chronicle where and when you found this piece of evidence, and how you felt at the time, it'll be useful in the trial.
T-Trial?!
For a camera, use an instant one, as digital photos can be altered.
With the diary, use a ballpoint pen or
something that can't be amended later,
and if you write down today's news and
weather too, you'll increase its credibility.
W-Weather and news...
So that's how you'd beat that eloquent mystery nut, master?!
W-Well...
Anyway, hasn't Kudō-kun been away from the house for a while?
Wouldn't you normally think that it's that Subaru guy from earlier who brought the woman in?
I guess you're right...
Hey, I brought the photo. What were you talking about?
Eh, it's okay, it's okay. You don't need to know about it.
It was grown-up chit-chat.
It's true, the bloody "death" characters really are alike.
Then, could that mean the killer from ten years ago struck again?!
That means it's a serial killer!
Yeah, I checked on the Internet, and no photos of the bloody character from ten years ago have been made public,
so I don't think it's wrong to assume both crimes were committed by the same person.
They're certainly identical...
But ten years ago, Dad...
I guarantee it.
On my name as Yūsaku Kudō.
The murderer that wrote this "death" character will not appear in all of eternity.
What happened...?
Didn't he mean that they'd never appear again?
Dad...
Huh, really?!
Yūsaku Kudō really said that?
Yeah.
He said a killer leaving "death" characters near the victims wouldn't appear again.
Shin'ichi-niichan said he heard his father say that, ten years ago.
I remember Shin'ichi saying that when he showed me the photo too.
"Moreover, there was blood on that man's palm and fingers, but not on his fingertips."
"So if the man didn't write it himself, how is this not a murder?", he said in frustration.
Even if it isn't a murder...
There's no doubt that there was someone close to the corpse before the blood dried.
Besides, we were at a scene with an identical bloody character just this morning.
But wasn't that case ten years ago actually an accidental death?
Yeah, I think so.
An accidental death?
It looks like there's more info in the papers that were in with the photo.
Let's see...
The deceased, Takefumi Kōriyama-san, head of a nursery, died due to shock after sustaining damage to his heart.
Shards of a fishbowl that were stabbed into his chest pierced his heart, and he died.
In order to clean the nursery's aquarium,
he was supposed to transfer the goldfish into a fishbowl temporarily,
but the principal forgot the fishbowl at his house, and went back to get it.
While headed to the nursery with the fishbowl,
he took a shortcut through the park,
where it seems he unluckily tripped on the uneven stone paving, and fell and died while holding the fishbowl.
The first person to find the body was a boy who went to that nursery,
Ryōsuke Nishimura-kun, age 5, the only son of a nearby temple's head priest.
When the other nursery staff were talking about the principal not having returned,
they heard him say that on his way to the nursery, he had seen the principal lying down.
When they rushed to the park, they discovered the body.
At first, the boy was scared and wouldn't say anything, but when he started to eat the sweets he had with him, he finally began to talk.
He said that he and the other nursery children were secretly looking after a puppy in that park,
and he'd gone to check on it on the way to the nursery.
Then when the principal didn't answer, he thought he was dead, and picked some of the park flowers as an offering.
It's true.
There are some flowers in the photo, above the bloody character.
They look like they've been scattered rather than offered though.
The killer probably kicked them about.
But if someone killed the principal,
they could've pushed him from behind while he was holding the fishbowl, causing fatal wounds,
and written the character with the principal's blood...
But when the boy offered the flowers,
he didn't see the bloody character, it seems.
Which means that, after killing the principal, the perpetrator had to quickly hide from the kid when he approached.
After waiting for a while for the boy to leave, the killer approached the corpse again and left behind the bloody character.
W-What if that boy did it?!
Writing that bloody character, I mean!
He probably wrote it when he offered the flowers!
You know, he was a temple child, so it could've been to mourn the deceased!
But wasn't he just five?
He wouldn't have known the kanji for "death", right?
I'm sure this brat could write it, and he's not much older...
Hey, when you three came across the dead man this morning, what did you see?
If there's any similarity to the case from ten years ago,
couldn't that be a hint to help catch the killer?
I don't think there was anything similar but the bloody character...
Beside the body there was a cigarette, not flowers.
I see. So that thing in the photo is a cigarette?
Yeah.
It was all bloodied though.
That man's estimated time of death was probably around 11 PM last night.
The corpse was leaning against a vending machine, and it had a new can of beer left in the delivery bin.
So I think that something happened to cause his death straight after he bought the beer, and he stayed there like that until dawn.
Vending machines stop selling alcohol at 11 PM, right?
But the "death" character beside him, that was written in blood, right?
Was he stabbed or anything like that?
The blood had come from his mouth.
Because he was an alcoholic, the first thing I thought was that the blood was due to his varices rupturing and that he vomited blood...
until I spotted the bloody character which had been written by someone facing the body.
In other words, the only common elements between the two cases are bloody "death" characters written in similar styles,
and that neither appeared to be a murder to begin with, right?
Y-Yeah...
And...
According to some newspaper clippings which were in the envelope,
"The nursery staff, who rushed to the park, only noticed the "death" character after moving the corpse to attempt to wake him."
Which means this photo was likely taken after the corpse had been moved slightly, so when the boy found him,
the bloody character could've already been written, but he couldn't see it due to the body covering it.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sorry for butting in...
Oh, Subaru-san's a Holmes fan, and he really likes making deductions.
That reminds me, when we found the corpse this morning, his coworkers were shaking him.
Yeah. Maybe that corpse had been moved a bit too.
Then, why don't we ask the police?
Detective Takagi came running when Ran-neechan reported it, right?
He might be able to tell us more.
Ah, the corpse this morning?
I think it was a man named Isao Takaichi-san, who lived close to the scene.
I don't know what happened to the corpse afterwards though.
Since it was a theft case, the investigation was handed over to Division Three.
T-Theft? Wasn't it a murder case?
Hey, quit fooling around! How is this a theft case?!
A-And you are...?
I'm Sera, I was at the scene along with Ran-kun!
That female high-school detective?
Didn't you see that bloody "death" character too?!
Y-Yeah, I thought the same thing.
"Perhaps this is some bizarre murder."
But Inspector Megure, who passed you girls as you headed off to school,
said "This must've been theft..."
the moment he saw that bloody character...
It turned out that we couldn't find a wallet on the corpse either.
But he bought a can of beer, didn't he?
If he lived nearby, couldn't he have carried just enough money to buy it?
Y-Yeah, I thought the same thing.
Oh, by the way, the cause of death was just like you said to begin with,
vein bursting caused by cirrhosis of the liver.
Hey, Takagi-kun, let's go interrogate the witnesses.
Uhh... Yes, sir.
Well, sorry but I gotta go!
H-Hey!
I hadn't finished talking yet!
Hey!
Damn it...
Not a murder case, but a theft?
Isn't it strange?
I'm sure Inspector Megure was the lead
investigator for the case ten years ago too.
It wouldn't be odd for him to think it was the work of a serial killer.
She has a point...
Ten years ago, Inspector Megure had his eyes fixated on that bloody character, so why?
And back then, didn't Dad say something to the kid who was the first to discover the body?
And he did it with a smile...
How?
How did he decide it wasn't a murder?
How?!
What is the mystery behind the bloody "death" characters written next to the corpses?
On the next Conan: Yūsaku Kudō's Cold Case (Part II)
Next Conan's Hint: Pocket Change!
Ran's more concerned about an affair than the case!
So I can win the trial!
Hey, hey!