Ran, Sonoko and Sera came across a corpse while headed to school.
What happened?
Well, he didn't come to work today, so we went looking for him and found him lying here.
There's blood dripping from his mouth, too...
I called an ambulance just in case.
He doesn't need an ambulance.
He's already been dead for nine hours, it seems.
Did he happen to be an alcoholic?
Uhh, yeah.
Even though he said his doctor told him to stop.
But how did you know that?
The whites of his eyes have turned yellow, and despite being thin, his belly is bulging out.
That's ascites, which proves he had a bad liver.
Also, a can of beer was left untouched in the delivery bin of the vending machine.
Judging from the situation, it's probably what he was trying to buy just before he died.
Having drunk alcohol, his cirrhosis caused him to vomit blood from variceal ruptures,
and at that time, nobody was around to help him, so he ended up dying...
That's what you'd normally think.
However, he didn't die from illness...
...but due to a maliciously perpetrated crime.
The proof of that is right in front of him.
Look.
The character for 'death' was written in blood.
A bloody character proclaiming 'death' was found beside the corpse.
It resembled one from ten years ago, in the one case where my father, Yūsaku Kudō, never revealed the perpetrator.
To look for similarities between the two cases, we called Detective Takagi, who led the investigation.
Ah, the corpse this morning?
I don't know what happened to the corpse afterwards though.
Since it was a theft case, the investigation was handed over to Division Three.
T-Theft? Wasn't it a murder case?
Hey, quit fooling around! How is it a theft case?!
Didn't you see that bloody 'death' character too?!
Y-Yeah, I thought the same thing.
'Perhaps this is some bizarre murder.'
But Inspector Megure, who passed you girls as you headed off to school,
said 'This must've been theft...'
the moment he saw that bloody character...
Not a murder case, but a theft?
Isn't it strange?
I'm sure Inspector Megure was the lead
investigator for the case ten years ago too.
It wouldn't be odd for him to think it was the work of a serial killer.
She has a point...
Ten years ago, Inspector Megure had his eyes fixated on that bloody character, so why?
And back then, didn't Dad say something to the kid who was the first to discover the body?
And he did it with a smile...
How?
How did he decide it wasn't a murder?
How?!
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, cases, today, or tomorrow!
The mystery behind the character connected with Dad's cold case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Perhaps he knew who the killer was, but the police forced him to stay silent?
N-No way!
You couldn't mean that the son of some police bigshot
or important businessman did it,
and even though they hate the thought,
the police can't lay a hand on him, like you see all the time in movies and dramas?!
Look who's talking. You're a child of the Suzuki Financial Group yourself...
I don't think Shin'ichi's dad would back off from
a case just because of something like that though.
Y-Yeah, that's true...
Then why don't we try asking him?
You can ask Kin'ichi-kun, that
deduction-loving classmate of yours.
Kin'ichi...?
I guess you're right.
Huh? What're you talking about?
If we're gonna ask anyone about the case, it should be Shin'ichi Kudō-kun, right?
Because he's a high-school detective and your boyfriend.
Though I guess he's not living here at the
moment because he's off chasing some case.
Oh... So this house belongs to that high-school detective?
Don't tell me you've been living here
without even knowing that...?
Right. Ran-san said that the Shin'ichi-kun living here was just an ordinary high-school student.
Also, there are rumours around saying that the high-school detective Shin'ichi Kudō lost his life investigating a case,
and vanished from the world of mystery-solving.
P-People are really spreading rumours like that?!
Yeah. That's why I thought the Shin'ichi-kun you kept talking of was somebody else.
But he isn't dead, right?
I've worked on the same case as him twice.
Though both times it was just over the phone.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Uh, yeah... That's right...
Then who is Kin'ichi...?
Ah, well...
Shin'ichi told me not to tell you too much about him, so I improvised...
I'm sorry...
But why are there rumours about Shin'ichi-kun being dead?
That's probably because he always insists that everyone involved in cases with him should keep his involvement hidden.
Almost as if he doesn't want to alarm the culprit of the case he's on...
What, is he some sort of ninja
infiltrating the enemy fortress?
A ninja...?
Then why don't we call him right now?
I'd like to hear him figure it out too.
B-But I already sent him an e-mail outlining the case earlier in the evening.
You haven't told him that the police are calling it a theft case yet though, have you?
Well, I guess...
Also, he should hear Ran's voice once in a while.
While she's at it, Ran can respond to Shin'ichi-kun's confession too!
I-I gotta go to the toilet!
Really? This is bad!
Come on, hurry!
Oh, if you're going to call him, could I put in a word?
Ah, Shin'ichi?
It's me, Ran.
Can you talk now?
Y-Yeah, what is it?
Oh, if it's about the case you came across this morning,
that four-eyed kid just sent me an e-mail about it.
He said the police are treating it as a theft case.
Right...
And there's s-something else I have to say too...
S-Something else?
Tell him you love him!
W-What do you mean by something else?
A-Ah, w-well...
'I like you, I like you, I like you... I love ya!'
L...
L-L-L...
Look, Subaru-san...!
Wha—?
S-Subaru-san left a message.
He said you're just like the shinobi, Kirigakure Saizō.
He wanted me to tell you.
Kirigakure Saizō...?
Oh, because he's in hiding?
Yeah, probably...
B-But why say that now...?
Wasn't Kirigakure Saizō one of the Sanada Ten Braves?
I think he was a fictional Iga ninja
said to have served Sanada Yukimura.
Hold on... Sanada Yukimura...
The Sanada-maru...
sanadahimo
Braided cotton...
Sanada...
Sanada?!
So that's it! I figured out the truth behind the case!
Go to the scene from this morning right away!
Hey, Shin'ichi...!
If my deduction's right, they should fit perfectly!
I see... So that's it...
Hey, Shin'ichi...!
What do you mean?
Shin'ichi! Shin'ichi!
I can't believe it. He hung up.
Huh? And Ran didn't even respond to his confession!
So, what did Kudō-kun say?
'I've figured out the truth behind the case,'
'so head to the scene from this morning right away!'
He said that if his deduction was right, it should fit perfectly.
Then maybe he also figured out the truth of the case his father, Yūsaku Kudō, threw in the towel on ten years ago.
He didn't throw in the towel!
Shin'ichi-niichan said he knew what happened but he couldn't tell everyone.
C-Conan-kun!
You spoke with Shin'ichi?
Even though I was just on the phone to him?
Ah, well, he e-mailed me after the call, it was just a moment ago, really!
Then he should've just said that to Ran...
Huh? W-Well he...
Conan-kun, you stuck a bowtie on your smartphone?
Oh no! I forgot to take off the voice-changer!
Ah, t-this is...
popular at school right now...
Anyway, if you want to find out whether his deduction is right or wrong, you must go to the scene.{[with your own
Isn't that right?
High school detective, Shin'ichi Kudō-kun...
...said that, didn't he?
That's right. Let's go check it out, Ran.
Yeah!
Hey, come with us, Conan-kun.
You've got the e-mail with Kudō-kun's deduction, right?
Yeah.
Just like we thought, there's not even a single policeman here.
I guess they really are sure it's a theft case,
so they withdrew everyone from the scene...
But usually, if you found a corpse, and in front of it was a bloody character saying 'death'
that the victim obviously didn't write, you would at least suspect it could be a murder case...
Hey, Ran-neechan, have you got your purse?
Huh? Yeah.
H-Hey, you don't want to buy some beer even though you're just a brat, do you?
That's not it!
Shin'ichi-niichan wrote in his e-mail that if we line up
some pocket change with the bloody character...
Look! They fit perfectly.
No way! But how?!
This wasn't a character that someone wrote on purpose,
but just a coincidence caused by blood falling onto coins that were scattered about like this.
B-But...
What about that long, straight gap, then?
Did the blood just happen to avoid flowing there?
No, the cigarette was probably lying there.
It did have blood on it.
And if the wallet that had the change in fell surrounding it, then the bloody 'death' character is complete.
Basically, the man whose corpse we found this morning came here to buy a beer last night,
and crouched down when he started vomiting blood due to variceal ruptures caused by his cirrhosis.
When doing so, he dropped his wallet, change and a cigarette, and the blood dripping from his mouth landed on them.
Then, after the man died, someone who passed by stole the change and the wallet,
so all that remained was the bloody character...
But if someone took his money, couldn't they have killed him as well?
I don't think so.
If the blood hadn't dried when
the wallet and change were taken,
then this bloody character wouldn't have been so clearly defined.
Then it actually was a theft case.
Yeah.
Though I'm surprised you figured it out, Conan-kun!
I-It wasn't me who figured it out, but Shin'ichi-niichan.
What Subaru-san said gave him a flash of insight, he said.
Oh, you mean the message he asked me to tell Shin'ichi,
'You're just like the shinobi, Kirigakure Saizō'?
Then do ninjas use bloody characters like this one a lot?
That's not it. Kirigakure Saizō was one of the Sanada Ten Braves.
The war banner of the Sanada clan
had six mon coins on it, right?
That's how I figured it out!
This bloody character wasn't made by being written, but instead a shape created from six round coins.
Huh...?
Ah... O-Of course, that's what Shin'ichi-niichan said.
But the case ten years ago was an accidental death, right?
The nursery principal stumbled on the stone paving in the park and fell,
breaking the fishbowl he was carrying, which pierced his heart and ended up killing him.
C-Could that have been a theft case too?
But in the photo of the scene from ten years ago,
there were the flowers offered by the kid who discovered the corpse, but nothing like a cigarette.
And Shin'ichi never said that his wallet had been stolen either.
Then was that case really a murder?
No, that case was about the six mon too.
Remember, the boy who discovered the body, Ryōsuke Nishimura, found the principal collapsed in the park, not moving.
He thought that he was dead, so by the corpse, he left some flowers as an offering...
and the six mon-toll needed to cross the Sanzu River.
T-The Sanzu River?
Wasn't he just five years old and at nursery?
But he was a child from a temple, wasn't he?
There's a chance that he could've heard about it from his parents, right?
Yeah...
If someone dies without having six mon, then at the shore of the Sanzu River,
Datsueba takes their clothes instead, and they fall into Hell.
That boy had likely heard about that story, so he left an offering of six mon coins beside the principal's corpse.
Then to prevent them from being stolen, he hid them by surrounding them with flowers.
B-But even if he lived at a temple, would he really be carrying around six old mon coins?
He didn't have them, so he used something else that looks similar instead.
Something else?
You know, what that kid was carrying in one of the photos.
Ah! The ring-shaped candy!
Right! Instead of the six mon coins, he left six candies by the corpse's left hand, and hit them with flowers.
But the blood flowing from the corpse got in through the gap formed by his thumb,
and just by coincidence happened to create such a sinister bloody character.
That's why nobody noticed the bloody 'death' character until the corpse was moved.
Before the corpse was moved, the bloody character was seen as an extension of his left hand.
That's why there wasn't any blood under his left hand in the photo,
even though there was said to be some on his palm and fingers.
So that's it! That long, straight gap wasn't made by a cigarette, but by the corpse's thumb!
There weren't any candies anywhere in the photo though...
The dog that boy'd been looking after in the park probably took them and ate them, disturbing the flowers.
That dog didn't have a collar in the photo, and there were three of those candies in his bowl too.
Then why didn't Shin'ichi-kun's dad announce what really happened publicly?
That's because there was quite an uproar about that bloody character sparking a chain of bizarre murders.
Depending on how it was interpreted, it could have been misunderstood as the kid playing an imprudent prank,
and if that was reported in the news, he could end up being ostracised.
Couldn't that be the reason why he kept it quiet?
Well, judging by how quickly Inspector Megure figured out that there were round coins in the bloody character in this case,
he probably told the Inspector what happened at least.
It wasn't just the Inspector.
Back then, Dad spoke with that kid with a smile on his face.
So Dad probably said to him...
It looks like the principal could go to heaven thanks to you.
Really?
Next time you leave someone an offering though, you should talk about it with your parents first.
Okay, got it!
Also, keep what happened today a secret to everybody.
If the Datsueba finds out it was you who gave her the candies that made her teeth rot, you'll be in trouble, right?
...he probably said something fitting just like that...
Well, I'm relieved to know that Dad didn't run off on that case...
Conan-kun...
...right?
A-Ah, I was just reading from Shin'ichi-niichan's e-mail...
Oh come on, don't scare me like that!
Your face even looks like his...
I'm sorry...
What a shame.
Even though the case is finally solved, we still don't know who the thief was...
Maybe this bloody ¥10 coin I found under the vending machine could be a clue.
If it's got blood on it, that means...
Yeah. When the thief took the coins, they probably dropped this one and it went under the vending machine.
But if the fingerprints on this match any from previous offences...
They sure do!
Assault...
ABH...
Blackmail...
Altogether, that's three previous offences.
Oh wait... Theft makes that four.
So won't you give that back to us?
You can spare ¥10, right?
Then after that, the three of us'll show you our 'love' all at once.
Okay...
Take it!
Hey!
Damn! What'd ya do that for!
Damn it!
You brat!
You bastards... Gimme a break!
Case closed!
That ball... Was that you, Conan-kun?
Huh? Uh, y-yeah...
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
Huh? You're not going to the police station?
Yeah. Sorry about that. Could you do the questioning without me?
There's something that I have to do, so I've gotta be going.
O-Okay...
Hey, Conan-kun!
You grazed your elbow, didn't you?
Oh, when I fell earlier...
Come on... You've gotta be more careful.
It'd be bad if it got infected.
Ah, right... I'm sorry.
I guess... I really am a bad girl.
A serial robber demands that a ransom be delivered by old man Mouri.
On the next Conan: 'The Evening Cherry Blossom Viewing Route on Sumida River (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Surveillance cameras!
You might beat me, Sera-san!
You're stronger than me!
...I really don't wanna fight either of you.