M spotted.
His mobile's ringing.
Hello, this is Mouri.
Yeah. Nihon Bridge Post Office, right?
Got it.
The man on the phone told me to pick up a package held at a post office.
And in under five minutes.
Let me through, quick!
M is heading south down Main Street.
I'm here to pick up a parcel being held.
Sure. Do you have any ID?
This case began five days ago...
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, deductions, today, or tomorrow!
The culprit chose the old man?!
A surprising case aboard a cherry blossom viewing boat!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Several employees of 'New Image', an company
specialising in importing and selling American cars,
were attacked and severely injured in quick succession.
Then, New Image's president received
a threatening call from the one responsible.
2.4 million yen?! You must be joking!
I see.
So, the case fits exactly 2.4 million yen.
Hey, Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
I was going to a department store with Ran-neechan when I spotted Uncle Kogorō running about.
Mouri-san's in the middle of a job, so don't disturb him, okay?
Sure.
Oh, Miwako! Were you waiting? Sorry!
'Were you waiting'? Sheesh...
Then, today's on you, right, Wataru?
It always is, isn't it?
What did you just say?
Ah, nothing!
Well then, we should get going.
Right.
'Put the money in this briefcase.'
'Get rid of your mobile. I'll contact
you through this transceiver.'
'Get on the 17:45 flower viewing
cruise departing from Nihon Bridge.'
'Get rid of the microphone you're
using to contact the police.''
M is heading north, still on Main Street.
Roger.
Huh?
Conan-kun!
Here, it's a note Uncle discarded.
I think it's part of his job.
Thanks. Take care on your way home, okay?
Sure!
These are the culprit's instructions!
Inspector Megure!
According to a note from the criminal,
future contact will be through a transceiver,
and he told M to board a cruise departing from Nihon Bridge.
My bad! Sorry for making you wait!
Are you Ishida-san?
Ah, yes!
We thought you weren't going to show up.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry, everyone.
I've kept you all waiting.
Well, then, now that everyone's here...
Let's depart!
The boat M boarded just departed.
Hey, mister!
The boat that just left, that was
the flower-viewing cruise, right?
Where does it go?
It is. It goes out of the Sumida River and into Ōyoko River.
Would you like a pamphlet?
Thank you.
But, Inspector...
I wonder why I was chosen to deliver the money?
We aren't entirely sure.
Don't you have any ideas yourself?
No, not at all.
He also said that he'd take a life if the police didn't
stay out of this, or if his demands weren't met.
I've prepared the 2.4 million yen that guy demanded.
I'm leaving this case in your hands.
Our employees' lives can't be replaced.
Understood!
You can count on Kogorō Mouri!
In about 10 minutes, we'll be leaving the Sumida River,
so be careful not to fall off when the waves get rough.
Hey, look over there.
Wow, it's like in the movies!
Seein' Tōkyō by boat's great, ain't it?
It says here that the Sendaibori River ahead is called the Sendaibori because it was built by the old Sendai Domain.
Oh, is that so?
The cruise M is on just passed Minato Bridge.
The suspect will pick up the money somewhere along the river.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Roger.
A transceiver has a range of 100 metres at best.
The criminal must be somewhere within that range!
Satō, where are you right now?
We're on standby just past Eitai Bridge.
We've contacted the cruise company, and the boat's scheduled to enter Ōyoko River from Sumida River.
Get ahead of it and wait for it at Ōyoko River.
Roger!
Ah, amazing!
It's beautiful!
It's about time to get started.
The boat is about to pass the Ōshima River flood gates, and head into Ōyoko River.
When it does, place the briefcase on the boat's roof.
Put it right in the middle so it doesn't fall off.
Once that's done, sit down and await further instructions.
Wow, the boat's not shaking at all now!
That's because the Ōyoko River is actually a canal.
The region's daimyō built it under orders of the shogunate.
That brat...
Don't get in the way, brat!
Lower your head!
That was a shock.
At high tide, the water level rises so much that
even this boat has trouble getting under bridges.
I see.
Well, when you usually don't lower your head, it's a good experience to bow right down to someone once in a while.
What'd you say?!
The briefcase is on the boat's roof.
He wouldn't be able to pull it up onto the
bridge when there's so many people about.
Even more so...
When there's surveillence cameras dotted about.
Were you waiting?
That was close!
M has entered the Heikyū River.
The briefcase's on the boat's roof!
What?! Don't take your eyes off that boat!
Roger!
I'll go get the car.
The briefcase is gone!
Conan-kun, why're you here?
What?!
Oh, no! We've gotta tell the Inspector!
Damn it!
Uncle!
Uncle, bad news!
Hmm?
Hush, you! Don't get in the way!
The briefcase's not on the roof!
What?!
It's gone, gone, gone, gone, gone,
gone, gone, gone, gone, gone!
Please be careful! That's dangerous!
The briefcase vanished!
Mouri-san!
What happened?
How did the criminal get the briefcase
from all the way over there?
So you received orders through a transceiver, right?
'When you reach Ōyoko River,
put the briefcase on the roof.'
Ye...
Y-Yes.
Was that the only contact you had?
Yes.
And before you knew it, the briefcase was gone.
Yes, they ordered me to sit down
and wait for the next order.
How humiliating.
So, Conan-kun, where did you last see the briefcase?
Umm...
Here! At Tōtomi Bridge!
We last saw it here, at Shiomi Bridge.
And you realised the briefcase was gone
when you were here, at Hamazono Bridge.
So, the culprit must've taken it somewhere
between Heikyū Bridge and Hanazono Bridge.
Mouri-kun, did you notice anything special?
Sorry... I think I caught a cold.
We can see that.
That's it! Back then, I heard a sound
like something hitting against metal.
Hitting against metal?
I think it was somewhere around here.
It was an ordinary, small bridge.
There were two rowboats moored under the bridge.
Were there any people on them?
No, not one.
The boatman turned to the right to avoid those rowboats.
Then, when we passed under the bridge...
Hmm? What was that?
Did you hit the bridge?
No way.
If I did, the boat'd be shaking more.
I see.
That was probably Shigure Bridge.
When we looked over from Shiomi Bridge, we could see
Heikyū Bridge, and there weren't any rowboats there.
And Ishihama Bridge, beyond Shigure
Bridge, has flood gates right behind it.
It isn't what you'd think of as 'an ordinary, small bridge'.
I see.
Hamazono Bridge is straight after that, so I think
that metal sound must've been at Shigure Bridge.
But is that metal sound really connected with the case?
Inspector Megure!
This was found floating in the river near Heikyū Bridge.
That's...
Mouri-san, this is definitely the briefcase, right?
There's no mistake! This is it!
Let's open it up and check inside.
Can I watch too?
Hey, Uncle.
The cloth in the lid of this case is ripped!
What?!
Yes, as Conan-kun said, forensics reported
that the lining in the lid had been torn out,
and there were traces that something
had been planted inside the lid.
What?!
Then the culprit took the case
using whatever they put in there?
No, they couldn't tell that much.
Mouri-san?
Dad?
Inspector, this is a clue to how the briefcase was taken.
Mouri-kun?
Y-Your voice is back to normal.
Whoops!
My flash of insight cleared out my nose.
Is that so...?
Anyway, Inspector.
The culprit used a powerful magnet.
Magnet?
One characteristic of Ōyoko River is that the water
level changes greatly with the tide's ebb and flow,
greatly decreasing the space under the bridges.
The perpetrator probably checked what time the water level rises beforehand,
and concealed a powerful magnet in the briefcase's lid.
Then, when the cruise boat passes just under a bridge...
Hold on. There are so many bridges, the criminal wouldn't be able to tell which one it stuck to...
Yes. That's why they used an electromagnet that would only magnetise when they needed it to.
An electromagnet created by wrapping a coil around a conductor
is only magnetic when electric current flows through the coil.
The culprit likely put magnetic cores with coils
wrapped around them and a battery into the lid.
And to allow it to be activated remotely, they connected a remote switch.
Then, when nobody was around, they
turned off the power, and retrieved it.
All right. Based on your deduction, Mouri-kun, we'll
recheck the area around Ōyoko River and Heikyū River.
Yes, sir!
Oh, Dad.
If you sleep here, you'll just make your cold worse.
I wonder why the culprit chose Uncle.
Yeah.
You keep documents about the cases Uncle investigates, right?
Yeah, I think they're filed away over here.
Maybe we could find out something
if we looked through them?
You don't think the culprit is someone
who holds a grudge against Dad?
It's possible.
Something wrong, Ran-neechan?
No, it's nothing.
I was just thinking that if Shin'ichi
were here, he'd solve it in an instant.
Don't worry. I'll solve it for you.
Well, you are part of the Detective Boys.
Then we'll solve the case together instead of Dad!
Yeah!
The key is New Image, right?
There must be some connection between Uncle and New Image.
asahi ga noboru ryōsen
The morning sun rises on the mountains
ikusuji mono hikari no hashira
Casting uncountable pillars of light
doremo ga kimi no kokoro e
Each one leading to your heart
jū-nen ga ni-jū-nen ni natte
Even if ten years turns into twenty
ima no sekai kawaranakutemo
and the world still hasn't changed
futari wa ayumi tomenai
We will never stop walking
kagayaku tobira akete massugu yuku
Open the shining door and go straight through
me no mae ni wa michi no mystery...
In front of you lay yet unknown mysteries...
futari no shisen awasete mezasu wa ginga no mystery...
When our eyes meet, we seek the galaxy's mystery...
futari no shisen awasete tsutamu wa uchū no mystery...
When our eyes meet, we grasp the universe's mystery...
I've got it!
Couldn't this be it?
Look at this!
Satoshi Nishizawa, 32 years old.
Mechanic and engineer for the
import car company, New Image.
A client, Kaori Yoda, asked the old man to find
out the identity of the stalker following her.
Through the investigation, the
stalker was found to be Nishizawa.
He received a court order to stay away from the client, and was dismissed from his job.
This case was two months ago, right?
What's his address?
Fukagawa, Kōtō district.
That's right near Ōyoko River!
Yeah.
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
This way.
That's the flat, right?
Yeah.
Nishizawa-san, are you there?
Nishizawa-san!
Looks like he's out.
It's open.
Nishizawa-san, are you here?
Nishizawa-san?
Ah, stop, Conan-kun.
Oh, Conan-kun, you can't just
walk into someone else's house.
While trying to find out what happened to the ransom,
Next Episode Preview
the suspect was found dead.
On the next Conan: 'The Evening Cherry Blossom Viewing Route on Sumida River (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Flower-viewing boat!
Dad, are you okay?
hana
He ran to look at flowers, and caught a runny nose.