One after another, employees of a company called 'New Image' have been victims of assaults,
and the company president has been subject to threatening calls demanding money.
And surprisingly, the criminal demanded that old man Mouri be the one to deliver the ransom.
M is heading south down Main Street.
The cruise with M on just passed Minato Bridge.
The suspect will pick up the money somewhere along the river.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Roger.
A transceiver has a range of 100 metres at best.
The criminal must be somewhere within that range!
It's about time to get started.
The boat is about to pass the Ōshima River flood gates, and head into Ōyoko River.
When it does, place the briefcase on the boat's roof.
Put it right in the middle so it doesn't fall off.
Once that's done, sit down and await further instructions.
That brat...
M has entered the Heikyū River.
The briefcase is on the boat's roof!
The briefcase is gone!
The criminal fit the briefcase with electromagnets which were used to stick the briefcase to a steel bridge
and artfully steal away the 24 million yen.
We thought it suspicious that the criminal had requested the old man specifically, so we investigated,
and found one person who stood out:
Satoshi Nishizawa, a man who worked as a mechanic engineer for New Image.
The old man had identified him as a stalker as part of a job,
which got him fired from New Image.
Nishizawa-san, are you there?
Nishizawa-san?
Looks like he's out.
It's open.
Nishizawa-san, are you here?
Nishizawa-san!
Ah, stop, Conan-kun.
Oh, Conan-kun, you can't just
walk into someone else's house.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, deductions, today, or tomorrow!
Can the case be solved with the suspect dead?!
Where's the stolen money, and how will the case turn out?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Not knowing exactly what you're searching for
living in the moment in your reckless way
If you don't brighten up a bit soon
you'll get crushed by your own anxiety
Surely you have dreams too?
I want to fulfill them, I want to cry... but I'll still chase them
Aren't you just quietly giving up?
Can't you see now the reality you've distanced yourself from?
Take me to the high, we never cry on
To a tomorrow we've never seen
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Not everything is bad, we're dreamers after all
Try again Try again Try again Always
Try again Try again Try again
Speak out the truth!
Nishizawa-san!
Wait, Ran-neechan!
Take a look.
Even though the bath's full to the brim, there's no sign of any water that spilt out of it.
It probably already dried up.
In other words, Nishizawa-san was placed in the bath quite some time ago.
Probably at least five or six hours have passed since then.
It can't be.
Anyway, Ran-neechan, call the police.
Got it.
An empty bottle of sleeping pills?
A flower petal?
What kind of flower could it be?
It's shaped like a cherry blossom, but the colour's wrong.
Hey, Ran-chan!
What are you doing here?!
Detective Satō! In the bathroom, Nishizawa-san...!
Nishizawa-san?!
He's already dead.
C-Conan-kun!
Takagi-kun, contact headquarters.
R-Right!
Hey, Detective Satō, why are you here?
A stolen motorboat was found in Heikyū River.
We found fingerprints belonging to Satoshi Nishizawa on it.
Well, now that you know, leave it up to us. Out, out!
Right!
Well then, let's get out of here, so we don't get
in the way of their investigation, Conan-kun.
Hey!
Hey, Conan-kun, you can't do that!
These are...?!
Nishizawa committed suicide.
His fingerprints were found on a boat that we suspect was used to commit the crime.
Also, this will was found on Nishizawa's PC.
The estimated time of death is around 1 AM today.
He drowned after taking a large amount of sleeping pills.
There's no doubt this was a suicide.
'My goal was never the money.'
'Kogorō Mouri, you took my pure love to be simply the
actions of a stalker, and turned me over to the police.'
'On top of that, I was fired by President Ishida.'
'My goals were to disgrace you, Great Detective,'
'and punish President Ishida, who could
not protect even one of his employees..'
'I desire to continue this disgraced life no longer.'
'I no longer have a reason to live.'
Well, we can't be sure without more evidence.
That's all we know for now.
Inspector...
Has the stolen money turned up yet?
No, not yet.
I see.
See you later, Mouri-kun.
It's not over yet!
You think you can call the case closed
when the money still hasn't been found?
This case has yet to be solved!
I don't know anything about what happened to Nishizawa-san.
I heard you were on good terms with him.
Just tell me what you know.
Even if it's something you may rather not know?
Atsushi Tanaka (28)
New Image Engineer
I don't mind! Lemme hear it!
Nishizawa-san held a grudge against you.
Yeah, seems like it.
So, did he mention anything about his plans for the crime?
Nothing.
I see.
By the way...
Do you have an alibi for 1 AM this morning?
Me?
Why do I need an alibi?
Wasn't it a suicide?
That hasn't been settled yet.
Well, if we ask President Ishida's human relations
department, the truth is bound to come out.
If that's the case, then you should
be doubting the president, not me!
Nishizawa-san was extorting money from President Ishida.
That's extortion, you know?!
Isn't it the president's job to look after his employees?
How can you suggest that when you go hurting the company's image?
If you're going to fire me, give me some proper compensation!
Now you're talking nonsense.
I'll tell everyone! I know you've been embezzling the company's money!
I don't care if this company gets shut down!
Don't lose your temper. Let's talk it over nice and slowly.
The president had more than enough motive
for murdering Nishizawa-san, I'd expect.
So you're not going to tell me your alibi?
I was at home talking with my girlfriend on the phone at 1 AM last night.
That's not an alibi if it was a mobile, you know.
It was a home phone!
If you doubt me, go check the call records or whatever you want!
There's no need to investigate, is there?
Wasn't it a suicide?
Don't you want to get the 24 million yen back?
I don't care about such paltry sums.
Gen Ishida (42)
New Image President
I can get it back just by selling a few cars.
Thanks for your work. Now, please forget about it.
It must've been tough for you,
being chosen by Nishizawa and all.
Go on, take it.
What is your alibi for 1 AM?
Me? I was asleep.
I live alone, so there's nobody who can verify that.
I'll take my leave.
Aren't you going to take it?
Put it toward Nishizawa's funeral or something.
You should be doubting his subordinate, Tanaka.
He was close to Nishizawa, liked to gamble,
and racked up quite large debts while doing so.
He once came to me for help, but I refused, because he wanted more than I could reasonably advance him.
A surveillance camera?
That was close!
That's right, that road didn't have any surveillance cameras!
There aren't any cameras here, either.
Whoops! Can't go straight ahead here.
It's the Toyosu Canal!
There aren't any cameras on the route I just took, so if
someone came this way, they wouldn't have been recorded.
So, they kept a boat moored here,
which they used to retrieve the briefcase left in Ōyoko River.
Mister!
And this side canal here goes to the Sendai Canal area.
Watch your head!
It seems narrow, but should be wide enough
for a motorboat to fit through, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Aren't the cherry blossoms in full bloom great?
Stop over there!
As I thought, this is where Nishizawa-san lives.
But I can't see any yellow flowers.
Did you find anything?
Nope.
Hey, do you know a yellow flower that looks like a cherry blossom?
Oh, that must be a turmeric cherry blossom.
Turmeric cherry blossom?
Around here, you only see them in Tsukuda.
They usually don't bloom until after the Somei Yoshino do,
but for some reason they're already in bloom this year.
Let me see them!
What?! You've figured out the true culprit?
I know who it is for sure, Inspector Megure.
Didn't Nishizawa commit the crime, then kill himself?
That's a wrong assumption!
Who is the true culprit?
I'm keeping that a surprise for later.
Tell the president, Ishida-san, and the engineer,
Tanaka-san to go to the president's office at 5 PM today.
Well, I can do that, but...
Are you sure it's going to be okay, Mouri-kun?
Have faith in the one and only Kogorō Mouri!
Dad!
I told you not to go overworking yourself.
Settle down and have some rest!
Understood, we'll be there right away!
Inspector, a large amount of ¥10,000 notes were reported
to be floating in Sumida River, in the vicinity of Tsukuda.
This must the money from yesterday's case.
They said they'd only found the empty briefcase, so the contents must've drifted away.
It's strange.
The empty briefcase was found here.
But we're over here.
Why isn't there any money floating in the river between the two places?
You can't keep going with this fever, Dad!
I've gotta perform the Great Detective
Kogorō Mouri's deduction show at five.
You really think a cold can keep me down?!
Sheesh...
What's going on?
Tell him to stop, Conan-kun!
Dad's insisting he performs a deduction show and won't listen to me.
Did you figure out the culprit?
You'll have to wait and find out at five.
Now that you mention it, some of the
stolen money was found in Sumida River.
What did you say?!
It looks like it had just been thrown away.
This man...
This is bad. If the money's already been
found, then my reasoning falls apart.
Ah, my fever's taking over.
That's why I told you not to overwork yourself.
How about I do the performance instead?
We have a video camera, right?
So, it'd be fine if I record Uncle's deduction
and have everyone watch it, right?
Uncle Kogorō couldn't come because of his cold,
so he told me to have you watch this recording.
It's fine, just make it quick.
I'm a busy man.
Sure!
People all around the world know me as a Great Detective.
That's right! I—
...am Kogorō Mouri.
There are two keys to solving this case:
A grudge held against New Image,
and someone who held a grudge towards me, Kogorō Mouri.
There are three suspects:
Satoshi Nishizawa-san, who died and left a will behind.
His subordinate, Atsushi Tanaka-san.
And the president of New Image, Gen Ishida-san.
Satoshi Nishizawa-san harboured resentment towards both
the Great Detective Kogorō Mouri and President Ishida.
Furthermore, he was blackmailing President Ishida.
N-Nonsense!
If you're gonna say Nishizawa was extorting me, then show me some evidence at least!
President Ishida has no alibi for the time the money was taken at Ōyoko River,
or for the time of Nishizawa-san's death.
So he would be the most likely suspect if Nishizawa-san was murdered. However...
Even so, that doesn't mean I'm the criminal!
Tanaka-san had neither a grudge against
New Image, nor a reason to kill Nishizawa-san.
Furthermore, he does have an alibi for Nishizawa-san's estimated time of death.
I'm glad he understood.
However, because of Tanaka-san's penchant for gambling, he had racked up huge debts.
As such, he could've had a reason to commit the crime...
But in the end, Tanaka-san's innocent.
H-How come?!
Taking into account the will left
behind in Nishizawa-san's home,
he must've fitted electromagnets inside the briefcase,
stolen a motorboat and moored it in advance,
and used them to steal the money at Ōyoko River.
Afterwards, he threw the case and the money in the river,
returned home, took sleeping pills, and drowned in the bathtub.
Therefore, Nishizawa-san committed suicide—
W-What're you trying to say, Detective Mouri?!
Now, I'll finish Detective Mouri's deduction by reading this!
Are you all right with that, Conan-kun?
Yup!
Detective Mouri says that the true culprit is...
Tanaka-san, it's you!
What's he saying?! I had an alibi, didn't I?
You had debts of roughly 20 million yen
you owed to banks from your gambling.
You committed the crime in order to get the money to pay back your loans.
Motive or no motive, how do you explain my alibi?
I'll explain it step by step.
When he took the money, Tanaka-san didn't throw it away,
instead just discarding the briefcase and the electromagnets.
He then followed the canal and went to Nishizawa-san's home.
You then knocked Nishizawa-san unconscious, put him on the boat and brought him back to your flat.
Your flat block is in Tsukuda, so you
could take the waterway to get there.
In your flat, you made Nishizawa-san
ingest a large amount of sleeping pills,
and began preparing to make your murder look like a suicide.
You then called your girlfriend from your home phone, and at the same time,
filled the bathtub with Nishizawa-san in with hot water.
What I found suspicious was
that you happened to be talking to your girlfriend from your
home phone at exactly Nishizawa-san's estimated time of death.
It looked like an obvious attempt to create an alibi.
You also made a huge mistake.
You didn't realise that petal from the turmeric cherry
blossoms near your flat got stuck to Nishizawa-san's clothes.
After having created an alibi by being on the phone with your girlfriend,
you used the canal once again to return to Nishizawa-san's home,
and put his corpse in his own bathtub.
In other words, you changed not the estimated time of death, but the location of the murder.
However, you failed to spot the turmeric cherry blossom petal.
Your debts were 20 million yen,
and you initially intended to keep the entire 24 million yen,
but since the crime had supposedly
been done only to carry out a grudge
and then commit suicide after leaving a will behind on the computer,
you were forced to throw the remaining four million yen into the river to support Nishizawa-san's will.
Is that so, Tanaka-san?
I-It's all a fabrication! A hoax!
I saw this mister riding a bike over Ōyoko River.
That was close!
A bike passed by me before the money was stolen,
and then again after the theft had been carried out.
It had the same number plate as this one.
This is your bike, isn't it?
I found it parked in the company's parking lot.
You took a route without any
surveillance cameras, but I saw it.
Damn it! And I thought you were a good person!
Ishida-san, I'll be reporting your
accounting fraud to the Second Division.
You'd better be prepared for them.
As I expect the Tax Office won't stay silent about it.
Ah, that... is a problem...
Can't you let it slip by just this once, detective?
Of course not!
Right.
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
Well, that's Mouri-kun for you!
Please let him know that he did a great
job even though he was sick, Conan-kun.
Sure!
Even though I had to re-edit the whole thing...