To take advantage of the holiday week, we, the Detective Boys
started off by going to Kyōto.
We're finally in Kyōto!
Isn't this exciting?!
Yeah!
But if we're not gonna get on the boat till tomorrow, then why'd we arrive a day early?
The answer for that, of course, is that since we've come all the way to Kyōto, we should enjoy the food here!
And especially the Kyōto confectionary!
Right!
Then tonight, I can sip local sake while watching the cherry blossoms!
Hold on a minute.
Don't you get it?
We didn't come all the way here to Kyōto to drink sake or eat sweets!
We came here for a sailing experience on the Hotaka, an Aegis warship!
You're only here to accompany us!
Still...
We might as well take advantage of the opportunity.
Right?
Right!
Is that your best excuse?
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, deductions, today, or tomorrow!
A shocking case in Kyōto on the day before the Aegis warship sailing experience!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Our special dough glazed with rice bran oil, a release agent,
is poured into the Kyō no Tori moulds, and...
Those look really tasty!
They don't just look tasty, they are tasty!
Ran had some at my house and got hooked on them, so we came all the way here to buy some.
So this is why they came after all...
What?! No way!
What's wrong, Ran?
Listen to this, Sonoko!
They're all sold out of the chocolate ones!
Don't scare me like that, I thought something had happened...
But we came all the way to Kyōto to buy some...
This isn't the only branch selling chocolate ones though, right?
Yes. They're also sold at the Arashiyama, Shiokōjidōri, Shinkyōgoku and Shirakawa stores.
Hey, is it true? I heard all the chocolate ones vanished!
The chocolate ones vanished?
What does he mean by "vanished"?
Kōzō Umehara (63)
Umehara President
Yeah! How did this happen?!
We don't quite know how.
You don't know?
I'm sure that the Umehara chefs delivered them this morning, but well...
Here's 40 boxes each of ogura, matcha and chocolate flavour.
Oh, thank you so much.
Well then, shall we unpack them?
Huh? You haven't finished putting them out yet.
Huh? What the...?
How odd. They were all lined up a while ago, right?
Yeah. It's so strange...
Anyway, customers will be here soon,
so we better put them out quick.
Huh? There's none here! There's no chocolate ones!
What?!
Who took them?! Where'd they go?!
H-How'd this happen?!
So the workers are going around the other stores now to get some more...
Hey, this really is a disaster.
The chocolate ones vanished at the Shirakawa and Shinkyōgoku stores too.
What's going on? The Uzumasa store doesn't have chocolate ones either.
There weren't any at Shiokōjidōri either.
W-What?!
Then the chocolate ones are missing at all five stores?!
I-It certainly seems that way...
But that means...
What's going on here? What's all the noise for?
Uncle! How can you go picking out souvenirs at a time like this!
A case turned up!
The sweets that were here vanished!
Come on... I'm a Great Detective!
Something as simple as a sweet or two just isn't worth my time...
A Great Detective?
Yup! He's the famous Kogorō Mouri, also known as...
Sleeping Kogorō?!
The one and only! I am the Great Detective, Kogorō Mouri.
I beg you! Please, lend us your skills!
B-B-B-But...
I was just about to go have a drink and watch the Kyōto cherry blossoms...
Please, don't be like that, help us!
Right, Dad! It's a huge case!
A huge case...?
Hey, hey!
Isn't that thing stuck to the ceiling a surveillance camera?
We only have video from when the store opened at 10 AM, though...
What?
The shelf with the missing sweets on wasn't recorded?
Yes... The Kyō no Tori are right under the camera...
Oh, that's when we realized the chocolate ones were gone.
After that, we searched the whole store for them.
Pause it right there!
What is it, Conan-kun?
The woman dressed in pink in the top left video...
Doesn't she seem odd to you?
Because she passed by the shelf with Kyō no Tori?
Even if she did, she couldn't have stolen them all so quickly.
And she only came in after the chocolate ones were already gone.
I don't mean that...
It's quite cold today, right?
Isn't she too lightly-dressed for the weather?
I guess so, now that you mention it.
What's that got to do with anything?
Why, this is a surprise. Who do I find but Mouri-han?
And you are?
Inspector Ayanokōji from the Kyōto Police, right?
And just what is such an inspector doing here?
Fumimaro Ayanokōji
Kyōto Prefectural Police —
Division 1 Inspector
Well, I'm off duty for today, so I was taking this little guy for a walk.
I see...
Do you even need to walk chipmunks?
Who knows...
Even so, how is that a walk?
Still, you've come at a great time.
There's been a robbery.
It's a job for the police, so I'll leave it to you.
Huh?
We do apologise.
We'll have more tomorrow.
Isn't it a bit early to be sold out?
It's not even noon yet...
And I was really looking forward to trying chocolate Kyō no Tori...
Umm...
Why don't you make some more chocolate ones?
We already used all of today's chocolate.
The chocolate used in the chocolate ones isn't made here —
it's especially chosen imported chocolate.
Tomorrow's portion won't arrive until tomorrow.
Then I guess we'll have to wait until tomorrow for chocolate ones...
No, it had to be today...
What do you mean, it had to be today?
Today's the anniversary of the former president's death.
That's why we were bringing out a new flavor today...
Sorry, we're sold out...
Sold out?!
What?! Already?
The worst thing is that we're disappointing customers who were looking forward to them...
Is that true?
I see. Understood.
I asked a colleague of mine to go and check the Uzumasa store.
Is that a store selling Kyō no Tori?
Yes.
And they said that when the chocolate ones disappeared, someone saw a suspicious car parked outside.
A suspicious car? What's its model and number?
It was a small pink car, but it seems they didn't know what model or its number.
"A small pink car" isn't much to work on...
Umm...
I saw a small pink car earlier too.
What?!
When did you see it?
Hmm... Let's see, it was...
When the chocolate ones vanished and we were looking for them.
You saw it too?
Yes, it was parked right outside.
But you know...
If only we knew its number at least...
Then why don't you ask the other stores?
Well, if that car belongs to the thief, the other stores might've seen it too, right?
Then get a team together and have them check it out.
H-Hold on a minute, please.
If you need that many people, then you'll have to ask the Burglary Department yourself.
As I said, I'm off duty today.
Why does that matter?
I'll go check out the Shiokōjidōri store!
If you just sit around here, she'll get away!
Then I'll go to Shinkyōgoku.
Dad, you go to the last store, the Shirakawa one.
Ayanokōji-san, you stay here and wait for us to call you with our findings.
Me too?
Okay, listen up.
Ayumi, you go with Ran-neechan.
Genta, you go with Sonoko-neechan.
Mitsuhiko, you go with the old man.
Even if they only know part of the suspect's number plate, find out what, then contact me.
Understood!
I'll put all the clues together.
It'd be a small pink car...
Now I remember, I did see it parked outside the store.
Is that so? What was the number?
Oh... I don't remember that much...
Even if you remember a number or two, please tell us...
Still, I can't quite...
I think it was a Shiromi plate.
Thank you so much!
Ah, yeah, I saw it.
I think it was a Shiromi plate,
and I remember the number started with 11.
So it started with 11!
Still, I can't believe they went missing from every single shop.
Do you have any idea of what could've happened?
Maybe it's the late president cursing us...
Conan-kun, Mitsuhiko here.
All they knew was that there was an 8 in the right half of the number.
So there was a 8 in the right half.
Got it.
I see.
Now that we know it's a small pink car, and almost all of the number,
we may be able to identify the owner.
The car's owner was found.
It belongs to Mako Kawasumi, 22 years old, who lives in Shiromi, Ōsaka.
Does the name sound familiar?
No...
Not at all.
It's the first time I've heard it.
Is that so? Anyway, we're now tracking the car's location with N System.
Okay.
So you're all here...
Conan, you have some too!
Sonoko-oneesan bought us some!
The matcha ones taste great!
Don't they?
The matcha ones are what got me addicted to Kyō no Tori in the first place!
It seems like the former president didn't like them though.
Originally, Kyō no Tori were all ogura flavour,
and they only started making matcha ones when the new president took over.
But didn't they only decide to bring out chocolate ones because the matcha ones were selling well?
But the chef at the Shinkyōgoku store said...
If the late president heard we were selling chocolate ones, he'd die of shock.
So I wonder.
Perhaps it's actually...
His curse!
Stop that, Sonoko!
I forgot you hated ghosts, Ran...
Sorry...
Inspector Ayanokōji!
Detective Kurumazaki, thank you.
The suspect's car was spotted by the N System camera here, on Marutamachidōri, ten minutes ago.
Detective Kurumazaki
Kyōtō Prefectural Police —
Division 1 Detective
That's close to the Shirakawa store.
Yes. And this is the picture it took.
That's...
The woman in pink!
Mitsuhiko, are you still at the Shirakawa store?
I'm still here.
After all, Uncle Mouri started drinking and won't move...
Sounds like him.
That stupid drunkard!
Um, where are you going, Ran?
I'll grab him by the neck and drag him back here!
Ah... There's gonna be bloodshed.
Yeah...
Hey, miss, what are you doing?
Oh, this one got wet, so I'm swapping it for another.
Oh, back when...
The worst thing is that we're disappointing customers who were looking forward to them...
Hey, can I see that?
So, this is the ogura Kyō no Tori you got out of the cupboard to swap.
This is the ogura Kyō no Tori that got cried on and is being swapped for.
And this is the ogura Kyō no Tori that was on display underneath it.
Doesn't it look like the glue is oozing out?
Maybe it's from when the sticker was put on...
But the sticker on the pack from the cupboard looks fine.
Conan-kun, what're you thinking?
I might've made a big mistake...
Hey, Uncle!
Let's go back and meet up with Conan-kun and the others!
Like I said, there's no rush!
It's not like it's an important case...
It's not an important case?
Yeah! It's not an important... case...
You have some nerve, to go off to look at flowers in the middle of a case.
Ah, no, w-w-wait, Ran!
You got it wrong! I'm not!
I just wanted to—
Uncle...
...pick up some cherry blossom petals...
That woman...
Umm, excuse me.
You went to all the stores selling Kyō no Tori, didn't you?
How... How could...?!
And the chocolate Kyō no Tori went missing at all of those stores...
Mouri-han, Mouri-han...
Mouri-han!
Mouri-han isn't back yet?
Uncle should be back any minute.
So how'd it go?
Just like Mouri-han said on the phone, an odd substance was discovered here.
Could that have been...
That's right, but how did you know that?
Oh, that's what Uncle Kogorō thought it might be.
Well, well, that's a Great Detective for you.
Ah, Mouri-han.
What happened, Mouri-han?
I just punished him for drinking on the job, that's all.
Don't pay it any mind.
"Just", huh...
Oh well, works for me.
Hm? That reminds me, where's Kurumazaki...?
Oh, Uncle Kogorō called him and asked him to do something a while ago.
Mouri-han, what did you ask Kurumazaki to do?
Never mind that. Inspector Ayanokōji, did you check what I mentioned?
The ogura packs that were on display in the shop.
Yes. There was rice bran oil stuck around the stickers saying ogura.
Rice bran oil?
Rice bran oil is something we use as a release agent.
Hey, what's a "release agent"?
Oh, it's an oil we rub on the dough molds before heating them,
so that they'll lift out easily when they're ready.
But how could it have got onto the ogura stickers?
It didn't end up on them by mistake.
It was placed on them.
Before the ogura stickers were stuck on.
Here's 40 boxes each of ogura, matcha and chocolate flavour.
Oh, thank you so much.
Well then, shall we unpack them?
You only put 10 packs of each flavor on display at first.
So 10 chocolate packs needed to be prepared.
A rice bran oil-daubed cotton ball hidden in the palm of the hand was rubbed around the stickers,
then the stickers were lifted off.
And then ogura stickers were stuck on in their place.
Two people prepared the ten packs.
Then the ten ogura packs originally put on display were moved into the cupboard,
and the ten newly stickered ogura packs were moved into their place.
In other words, at this...
No. At all five stores, there never were any chocolate ones.
Detective Mouri!
Kurumazaki-han.
Detective Mouri, it was just like you said.
The chocolate that was supposed to be used today was still in the freezer in the Umehara kitchens!
In other words, there never were any chocolate ones made today.
And the only people that could be responsible for that...
Would be the sweets chefs.
How could you do that?!
The late president really hated matcha...
But he hated chocolate even more...
That's all?
It's not like that!
It's not like that at all...
That's why we didn't want to start selling chocolate ones on the day of his death no matter what.
But we're sorry —
we never thought it would end up like this...
Are you sure you don't want to file for damages?
I am. Their skills come from the late president, after all.
I see.
Umm... What's going to happen to the chocolate ones?
We won't sell matcha or chocolate ones on the anniversary of the late president's death.
Not until the chefs say so.
I've come to like the matcha Kyō no Tori though.
Thank you.
That reminds me, where's Mitsuhiko...?
Hey, guys!
Mitsuhiko! What took you so long?!
Ah, sorry...
Well, you see...
How... How could...?!
And the chocolate Kyō no Tori went missing at all of those stores...
Right! There ain't any chocolate ones anywhere!
This is the fifth store I've checked.
I've looked everywhere!
How could they be gone?!
So she was just like Ran.
Back then, nobody could've known...
That as we were sleeping, exhausted from the case yesterday...
The curtain to a huge case was slowly beginning to rise...
On the Aegis warship we were to board the next day...
An innovative winery!
A case occurs revolving around quality!
An alibi trick hidden within the fields!
Detective Conan: The Roses in the Vineyard!
Broadcast Saturday, April 27th, at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Types of grapes!
The movie's in the cinemas starting today!
With the star being Sleeping Kogorō?!
That wouldn't go well.