Mouri-san, did you get wet in the heavy morning rain?
No, not at all!
That's good.
Anyway, these fields really are vast!
Are all of these vineyards part of your winery, Yurika-san?
Yeah, I inherited them from my late father.
Also, my husband Kengo, who studied agriculture,
Mizumachi-san, a friend of mine, and I are all co-managing the Suwayama Winery together.
I see!
I'm not too familiar with working on the field, so I rely on them to help.
Yurika Suwayama (28)
Winery Co-Manager
I'm really looking forward to seeing what kinds of wine you've got!
Don't go drinking too much, old man...
This is a truly elegant wine!
You must be quite the wine connoisseur,
recognising this wine's elegant taste!
Yeah, that's right. I'm quite picky when it comes to wine.
You just pulled that out of thin air, didn't you?
I'm Akihiro Yamaguchi —
I manage several restaurants in Tōkyō.
Akihiro Yamaguchi (41)
Restaurant Manager
I've fallen in love with Suwayama Wine, so I'm here to sign a contract with this winery today.
I see. This wine certainly isn't just one step, but two steps above all others!
On top of that, one of the owners, Yurika-san, is quite beautiful, don't you think?
I'm sorry, Yamaguchi-san.
What's the matter?
I can't find Kengo-san, and he has the contract.
It shouldn't be too long until he's found, so could you wait?
Huh? Again?
Yeah... My sincerest apologies.
Yurika-san's husband, Kengo-san,
is scholarly and hard to please.
You could almost say he's too picky when it comes to wine making.
For example, the last time we met...
Did you really think I'd agree to a contract that'd reduce the quality of Sumayama Wine?!
Kengo Suwayama (33)
Yurika's husband - Agriculturist
Did you really think I'd agree to a contract that'd reduce the quality of Sumayama Wine?!
Well, his fastidiousness is the reason the wine tastes so good, so we can't blame him.
But I'm sure he can't find fault with today's contract, but still...
I feel sorry for Yurika-san.
Ah, Mizumachi-san.
Did you come across Kengo-san, by any chance?
Tomoaki Mizumachi (34)
Winery Co-Manager
No. I haven't seen him since we met this morning.
Maybe he's hiding from Yamaguchi-san?
Shūji Takashina (28)
Winery Employee
Maybe he really didn't agree with this contract either.
Don't worry, Yurika.
He may be hiding, but I think Kengo's finally ready to sign the contract.
Here, take a look at this.
It was left on a desk in the barn.
So Kengo-san did sign the contract!
That's a relief! Yamaguchi-san, the contract's been found!
And with that, the contract's complete.
We're looking forward to working with you, Yamaguchi-san.
Yurika-san, Mizumachi-san, since we're partners now, feel free to consult with me about anything.
Of course.
Anyway, where did Kengo-san go?
I'm going to go to the barn in the south field to look for him.
So Mizumachi-san...
why don't you show Mouri-san and
company around the vineyards instead?
The field to the south has Cabernet Sauvignon.
To the north, we grow grapes for Pinot Noir.
The southern vineyard is planted on red clay,
while the northern one has gravelly sand.
The soil varies in different places in the plantation,
so we choose the types of grapes specially to match.
You go that far...
The misty vineyards look beautiful!
Oh, that isn't mist, but a natural pesticide.
It's sprayed every day from 1 to 4 PM, so it should be stopping about now.
You cultivate roses here too?
Oh, no. Those aren't ornamental, but a way to combat pests.
Of course, it's not like the roses
themselves can exterminate pests.
But because roses are more sensitive to pests and diseases than grapes, they wither before the grapes are affected.
So if the roses wither, something's about to threaten the vineyards, right?
Hey, do you plant different kinds of roses in each field?
No, they're the same species.
But the colours are different.
Oh, that's not because the roses are of a different species...
Hey, Yurika-san!
Did you find your husband?
No. I couldn't find him, so I thought I'd go and check the barrel cellar in the northern field.
The barrel cellar?
Yeah.
It's where we age the wine before bottling it.
If wine's being aged there...
Will I get to drink fresh wine?
I'd be glad to accompany you there!
Certainly! Please, Yurika-san!
H-Hey, Mouri-san!
Well then, let's go together.
Thank you!
What's this...?!
I'm sorry...
He was murdered.
After having his hands and legs tied, his neck was tied to this stake.
It can't be... That wasn't supposed to...
He shouldn't be dead...
Hey! What do you mean, he can't be dead?!
Detective Momoi!
The victim's estimated time of death has been determined.
It happened this afternoon, between 1:30 and 2:30.
Detective Momoi (42)
Yamanashi Police Detective
Is that so? What were you doing at that time?
I was working alone in the southern barn from noon until then, as Yurika asked me to.
So you're saying there's nobody who can confirm your alibi?
H-Hold on!
Yurika just asked me to keep Kengo locked up in here.
I did tie the guy up, but I didn't murder him!
Please believe me!
I never asked you to do anything like that!
What? Yurika...?
Yurika-san, would you please tell us what you were doing at that time?
I, Kogorō Mouri, can vouch for Yurika-san's alibi!
She came to the train station to pick us up at 1:30,
and we didn't arrive at the winery until around 2:30.
And after that, Yurika-san was always with us.
I see.
Come to think of it, at around 3:30,
I went to the barn in the southern field to look for Kengo-san.
Well, that doesn't match up with the estimated time of death, so don't worry about that.
After that, we met Yurika-san again just after 4 o' clock.
Then at 4:30, we found the body in this barrel cellar in the northern field.
I see.
So, can I assume that both of you haven't left the winery premises anytime after 1 o' clock?
Yes, that's right.
Um, I...
Today, first thing in the morning, I saw Kengo-san and Mizumachi-san walking towards the barrel cellar in the rain.
By the way, how many people have keys to this barrel cellar?
Mizumachi-san, Kengo-san, Yurika-san and myself, four people in all.
The victim's key was inside his pocket.
And the barrel cellar was locked as well.
In a nutshell, that means whoever has a key but lacks an alibi at
the victim's estimated time of death must be the killer, right?
Hey, Detective, there's something I don't get.
Hey!
Why would the criminal carry Kengo-san's
dead body all the way to the wall?
Huh? The body was carried?
Yup. Just look at those.
Those two black lines were made by the toes of his shoes rubbing against the floor, right?
Indeed, they match with the victim's shoes.
If his toes were dragged, does that mean Kengo-san was originally face-down?
Besides, those lines are almost completely straight, right?
That'd mean he didn't resist at all.
Which would mean he was already dead when his body was moved.
Oh, I see!
So that must be why he has those strange bruises on his neck, right?
Since the rope marks on his neck extend from under his throat to the side of his neck,
it means the victim was strangled from behind as he was lying face-down on the floor.
I see. But what reason would there be for the killer to hang the body on the wall after the murder?
Huh? Why are the ropes knotted differently?
This one is just a reef knot,
but Kengo-san's hands and feet were both tied with two half-hitches, right?
Two half-hitches?
I saw Mizumachi-san using that knot a while ago, back at the vineyards.
The two half-hitches is a kind of knot that doesn't untie easily,
so it's a special knot often used in agriculture, right?
He's right, the knots were tied in different ways.
How strange.
Why would the killer only use a reef knot on the one rope, when it comes untied more easily?
If Mizumachi-san was the one who did it and he
wanted to make sure the knot wouldn't be undone,
he would've done a two half-hitches knot, right?
Perhaps the person who tied his limbs and the one who used a rope to hang him by the neck are separate people.
However, Mizumachi-san is the only one in here who doesn't have an alibi.
He's right. Everybody but Mizumachi-san has an alibi...
Oh no, I got mud on my shoes.
And they're my favourite pumps...
I see... Mud!
Now I see...
That person used that to fabricate an alibi!
Are you okay, Yurika-san?
Mizumachi-san must've done all this for my sake.
Shipping 800 bottles a year is no small feat!
We can't make that much in our vineyard.
We could harvest more grapes if we stopped doing organic farming.
And if we still don't have enough, we could always buy grapes from other vineyards.
If we stopped doing organic farming or mixed other grapes with ours,
the quality of Suwayama Wine would suffer.
The way business is going now, we might not have a choice.
You speak complete nonsense!
I'm sure that, so we could sign today's contract, he tied Kengo-san and...
That would be the motive.
Since he had no alibi at the time of the crime, I don't think there's any doubt Mizumachi-san was the perpetrator.
U-Umm...
Detective Momoi, how about you wait before arresting Mizumachi-san?
Why?
I've just solved all the mysteries.
I had previously come to the wrong conclusion.
The perpetrator wasn't Mizumachi-san,
but an entirely different person.
Could this be the renowned detective who solves nearly every case without fail, the Sleeping Kogorō?
Mouri-san, who is the actual murderer?
There was a catch to this case.
A catch, you say?
The estimated time when the victim was murdered was between 1:30 and 2:30.
And the people who had alibis at that time would inevitably be removed from the suspect list.
Yeah, that's standard investigation protocol.
But what if the murderer found a way to kill the victim at a convenient time without even being there at that time?
After Mizumachi-san tied the victim up and confined him inside the barrel cellar,
the killer entered the barrel cellar, and set a plan to murder the victim into motion.
Detective Momoi, I'll need your help to better illustrate what happened.
Oh, sure.
Let's reenact the situation the victim was in prior to his death.
Please start by lying face-down on the floor.
Like this?
Now try to bend backwards while pretending your hands and legs are tied.
T-This posture is really hard to maintain!
The biggest mystery were the rope marks on the victim's neck.
And the reason was the following:
The perpetrator used a single rope to tie the victim's neck to his legs in a way that forced his body to bend backwards.
The victim was therefore forced to keep his body bent backwards to avoid strangling himself.
And the rope left serious scars on his neck as a result.
No way...
That's why the knot in the rope that was hanging from the stake and the ones used to tie his hands and feet didn't match.
I see! So the bruises that had been left on the
victim's neck like he was strangled from behind
were due to a rope that tied his neck to his ankles, right?
But, why go to such great lengths?
Like I told you to start with, this was done for the sake of fabricating an alibi.
Using this method, the victim wouldn't die until he had run out of strength, earning the murderer some time.
Something that awful was done just for the sake of fabricating an alibi?!
After creating an alibi for the victim's time of death, the murderer came back to this cellar
and in order to obfuscate the evidence, removed the rope that had tied the neck with the ankles
and disguised the corpse as having been hung from the wall.
There's only one person who could've done that.
Yurika-san, you were the one who murdered Kengo-san!
What kind of nonsense are you saying?
At around 3:30, you said you were going to look for the victim and slipped out of the winery, didn't you?
I went to the southern barn at that time.
I didn't come anywhere near this barrel cellar.
No, that is a lie.
You haven't set a single foot on the southern field today!
In the southern field, Cabernet Sauvignon grapes that prefer a red clay soil are being grown.
The soil in the southern field was muddy due to the morning rain,
and moist red clay easily sticks to clothes.
That's why Mizumachi-san, who had been working in the southern barn, has the southern field's characteristic red clay on his shoes.
However, there's no red clay on your
shoes or the bottom of your trousers.
S-Something like that...
What kind of evidence is that?!
The one who killed my husband was Mizumachi!
No! You're wrong.
It's true that Mizumachi-san confined Kengo-san here.
However, he didn't kill him!
You can't possibly be sure of something like that!
Of course I am!
That's because Mizumachi-san didn't set a foot in this barrel cellar after he first left.
H-How do you know that?
The victim was killed between 1:30 and 2:30 in the afternoon.
Mizumachi-san had been walking around the vineyard with us since 3:30.
Therefore, the only time he could've had to disguise his actions is between 1:30 and 3:30.
However, at that time...
Right, from 1 to 4 PM, the fields around the barrel cellar in the north are sprayed with pyroligneous acid, a natural pesticide.
Conan!
Right!
Pyroligneous acid is an acidic substance that is produced from the ashes of burnt wood.
This is a blue litmus test paper.
It reacts to acids by turning pink.
It didn't change, so Mizumachi-san's clothes weren't exposed to pyroligneous acid, right?
I-It's true. So, in other words, that means...
Exactly, it means he didn't enter the
northern fields during that time span.
However, Yurika-san, you do have pyroligneous acid on you!
Where's your evidence proving that?!
It's your rose hairpin.
The hairpin?
It sported a beautiful silver shine at noon, but it's now darkened from oxidation.
Silverwork is darkened when exposed to acidic liquids.
I-It got darkened by the pyroligneous acid from the southern fields when I went to the barn looking for Kengo-san!
Such a thing couldn't have happened.
Please take a look at the roses outside.
Despite all the roses being of the same breed, the ones in the southern field are yellow.
The difference in the roses' colours stems from the substances that are sprayed through the fields, which are also different.
The northern field uses pyroligneous acid,
Pyroligenous Acid
while the southern fields are sprayed with an alkaline Bordeaux mixture instead.
Bordeaux Mixture
Just like the litmus test paper, the yellow roses turn red when constantly exposed to an acidic substance.
If you were really walking around the southern field, your silver hairpin wouldn't have been affected.
How could something like this...
How could this become evidence?
Yes, you're right.
I killed Kengo.
Yurika...
Yurika-san... You did that just for the sake of signing a contract with a restaurant?
I didn't do it just for the money... It was Kengo-san's fault!
I get it, Yurika.
We must divorce.
If you're willing to reduce the quality of Suwayama Wine, I can't stay here.
Why?!
You don't understand a thing about wine.
I made a mistake when I decided to marry you!
I couldn't forgive him...
On top of making a fool of me, he chose wine over me.
Who cares about types of grape?!
Who cares about types of wine?!
Did Dad already drink all the wine he was given as thanks?
And these were vintage bottles that'd been praised by Yamaguchi-san.
He should've let them age for a few years...
Then they'd have tasted even better, right?
Don't whine, I won't drink any more wine.
The old man won't get any better no matter how long he's aged, huh?
The Detective Boys conduct an independent investigation!
The mystery of an odd case that took place at a brick-edged flowerbed!
Detective Conan: 'The Flowerbed Vandal's Scheme'.
Broadcast on Saturday, May 4th at 6 PM!