This way, this way!
There's a huge case for you!
We need your help, Detective Mouri!
Geez, why do I have to be dragged around by these brats this early in the morning...
You're did accept their request, after all.
I didn't know Yōko-chan was gonna appear on TV this morning!
Everyone's hyped up this morning.
Totally.
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A fallen victim's surprising trick in a town centre flowerbed.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Beika Town Centre?
Yeah, it's a place which people who live locally can use to play sports and so on.
Either way, it's not somewhere you'd expect a case.
Here!
Isn't it awful?
It's a mess, it looks like a cyclone blew through here!
The flowers and plants here are all planted and even watered by children.
But recently, it gets vandalised every morning!
It must be some bad guy!
Please catch him, Uncle!
Go and ask your mother or your teacher instead.
Dad!
So Detective Mouri won't solve it after all?
He even told us we could count on him when we called him earlier...
Right, Genta-kun?
Huh?
Huh? That's weird.
What is it?
The brick I made is missing.
It was always right here before.
Maybe the flowerbed vandal
accidentally stepped on it and broke it?
Damn, talk about a horrible guy.
If Uncle won't help us, let's find the vandal ourselves!
Let's catch him!
Yes!
You can't! You're just kids.
The vandal comes out at night,
so it'll be dangerous if there's no adults around.
Come on, Dad! You have to keep your promise!
So the Great Detective finally makes his entrance.
Babysitting a bunch of brats...
Oh, you all came?
She's so beautiful!
Good morning, Yamazaki-san, Saki-san!
Toshiko Yamazaki (43)
Town Centre Staff Member
It's annoying how this gets vandalised every morning.
Miss, do you work at this centre?
Y-Yes, that's right. And you are?
Saki Okamura (24)
Town Centre Staff Member
I accepted a request to investigate the flowerbed vandal,
I'm the Great Detective Kogorō Mouri!
A detective?
Hey, stop wasting time and help me with this.
S-Sure! Excuse me.
Nice to see you.
Ah, that's not how you use splints.
If you amateurs try and fix it,
you'll just make the flowerbed even worse.
Ryūnosuke Okuda (57)
Flower Shop Owner
I asked you for a delivery, not your idle comments!
How about you leave the repairs to a professional?
I'll give you a good price.
Let's see... The saplings, fertiliser, and the charge for the repairs needed would cost...
I just told you I don't need your idle comments.
For some reason everybody wants to extort whatever money they can.
Everybody?
Then if I throw in some extras for free, this is the total.
Excuse me, Yamazaki-san already refused your offer.
Don't you butt in!
Hey, what are you doing?
Shut up!
This land belongs to me to begin with!
I'm free to do whatever I want!
Young lady, are you hurt?
No, I'm fine.
As the Great Detective Kogorō Mouri, I won't forgive you for being violent toward a beautiful lady!
A detective?
So, the vandalism occurs sometime between
when the staff leave at night, and the next morning.
When did it start?
Today's the third day.
If you would forgive me, we're busy here in the morning.
Okay, no more detective games for you!
By the way, do you know anyone who would
hold a grudge against this town centre?
There is one person at least.
Ah, that guy, right?
You kids need to get to school!
Workshop
The bricks for the flowerbed are made here?
Yes, they all vary in size and shape because they're all baked by the children.
So the flowerbed vandal's trampling
on all the children's feelings as well.
He's gonna show up again tonight, right?
If it happened three times, it'll
happen a fourth time for sure!
Let's do night patrols with old man Mouri and catch the culprit!
Hey, hey...
They're enthusiastic.
I see, interesting.
So your family live and work at that café.
I often pass by that area.
Next time, please come in.
Treating you to a beer is the least I can do.
Is that so? Then I'll come check it out tonight!
Huh? Tonight?
Geez! Don't get too friendly!
Uncle Kogorō!
We'd like to do night patrols to catch the culprit.
Okay.
Is 8 PM fine for you?
Yeah, yeah.
You're so helpful to everyone!
Yes, that's right.
Defeating the strong and helping the weak is what detectives do!
Okay, kids, Uncle will take you to school!
See you tonight, then.
Oh, right.
Hold on, Ayumi-chan.
Here you go.
It's what I promised you the other day.
Its flowers bloom at night.
I took some from my garden.
Oh, amazing! Thank you!
I have one more, so I'll give you one, too!
Thank you.
Here's your second one.
Thank you, Saki-tan.
Welcome.
Oh?
Oh, Miss!
My mother's on a trip right now, so I
work here part-time, during the night.
It's a wonderful café.
You said it was your home.
Yes, we live on the upper floors.
Do you want something to drink?
Sorry, we can't. I just came to pick up my dad.
Dad, you promised Ayumi-chan that you'd meet her at 8, remember?
Like I could leave without having tasted Saki-tan's beers!
Looks like there's no way he's leaving.
Sorry. I gave him too much alcohol.
What a mess...
We're late because of you, old man!
It's 10 PM already. The vandal might already be gone by now!
Is the children's flowerbed okay?
The flowers!
What is it?!
It's that employee, Yamazaki-san.
Ran, call an ambulance and the police!
Okay!
Kudō-kun, look at that.
This petal...
Uncle! Somebody's running away!
I won't let you get away!
You got him!
It's him!
The flower shop guy!
The victim was Toshiko Yamazaki-san,
an employee from the town centre.
The estimated time of death is around 8 PM.
There are marks all over her body from was beaten, but the direct cause of death was probably her head hitting a brick.
The wound on her head matches the nearby bricks.
The bricks are unique since they
are made by the children here.
The ones who found the corpse were...
I can't believe kids are out this late.
We were looking for the flowerbed vandal!
Uncle Mouri was here to watch over us.
Right, I got it, I got it.
And he is...?
The owner of a nearby flower shop, Okuda-san.
He was hiding in the shadows when we
discovered the corpse, and tried to escape,
so I caught him.
That man has some kind of grudge against our town centre.
And you are?
A colleague of the deceased Yamazaki-san.
Until a year ago, he ran his flower shop here, but he was evicted when the town centre was built.
But he still loathes the centre and
vandalises the flowerbed every night.
Exactly. Since I was forced to move, business has been getting worse.
Of course it got on my nerves!
Yes, I was the flowerbed vandal.
But when I arrived today, the flowerbed was already messed up and this woman was lying there.
Inspector!
Judging from the circumstances, Yamazaki-san
likely fell from the emergency stairs there.
Yes. According to forensics, there are footprints on the third floor of the stairs
which match Yamazaki-san's shoes and Okuda-san's gardening boots,
and show what appears to have been a struggle.
I figured it out, Inspector!
Around 8 PM, Okuda-san started arguing with Yamazaki-san
on that landing, and she fell off during their struggle.
He got scared and ran away,
but around 10 PM, he came back to have a look.
And so we spotted him while patrolling.
That's not it!
Those stairs are the only place where we can smoke in
this centre, so I went there this morning for a smoke.
She came to chase me out and
we may have fought a bit, but that's all.
What about at 8 PM?
Can you tell us what were you doing and where?
I was delivering flowers, but it must've been some sort of prank, as I was given a fake address.
I was driving my truck around looking for it.
Was there anyone with you or anyone who could confirm your story?
No.
I see. So you don't have an alibi.
Please come with us to the police station for now.
Hey.
Yes, sir!
I didn't do anything! It's gotta be a mistake!
Anyway, why did Yamazaki-san come here at 8 PM?
Umm...
She may have came to look for this.
I manage the accounting here, but recently the books and the money don't match up.
As if somebody'd been embezzling the money.
Embezzling?
Yes.
It was most likely Yamazaki-san.
I think she realised I knew, so she came here at night to hide the evidence.
But I had hidden the accounting book, so she couldn't find it.
I see! Then she met Okuda-san,
and he pushed her off the emergency stairs.
It makes sense.
As expected from a Great Detective. A wonderful deduction.
Nah, a trivial case like this is a piece of cake to me!
It seems somebody isn't sure we caught the right suspect.
Look.
What are those lines?
It's like a cord was dragged here.
Yamazaki-san's shoelaces must've come loose while she was fighting with someone here.
But that can't be!
Yeah.
The shoelaces on the corpse were tied up tightly.
Which means...
Inspector Takagi!
Were there any flower petals on the victim's clothes?
You mean this?
It's no surprise, she did fall onto a flowerbed.
Give it to forensics just in case.
Right!
That petal doesn't seem to be from this flowerbed.
Yeah. And it's a darker colour than when we saw it earlier.
Could it be?!
Could the bag you got this morning be...
That's right.
I see. So, that's what happened!
But there's no evidence.
But it's a good thing we caught the culprit.
Yeah.
Now the flowerbed won't be vandalised anymore.
It ain't 'good' at all!
We still don't know where my brick is!
The evidence is probably still there!
Destroying evidence, are we?
As I thought, you were the real killer.
You almost fooled me...
A beaten corpse. The bricks next to it.
Anyone would think Yamazaki-san died
falling off those emergency stairs.
Yamazaki-san and Okuda-san's footprints were on those stairs.
So nobody doubted that Okuda-san, who held a grudge against
the town centre, had pushed Yamazaki-san off.
You tried to frame Okuda-san as the killer, since he didn't
have an alibi, but you made two small mistakes.
The first one was the shoelaces on the corpse's shoes.
On the landing, there were marks from shoelaces being dragged on the floor, as well as Okuda-san and Yamazaki-san's footprints.
Yamazaki-san's shoelace probably came loose
while they were fighting.
But the corpse that fell on the
flowerbed had her shoelaces tied.
Which means Yamazaki-san didn't fall then.
Ah, the flowers blooming on the counter and
in the garden are beautiful.
Since they're blooming this late at night, they must be evening primroses.
When evening primrose first bloom in the evening, they
are white, but during the night, they slowly become pink.
And those evening primroses were your second mistake.
Since evening primroses only bloom during the night, they couldn't be being grown in the children's flowerbed.
Yet evening primrose petals were found on the corpse's back.
The scent of evening primrose guided me to you... the real killer.
Right, Okamura-san?
What are you trying to say?
Anyone could've tied her shoelaces, right?
Evening primrose isn't exactly rare either.
Even the police said the killer was that flowerbed vandal.
Yes, everyone knew the
flowerbed vandal was Okuda-san.
He had monetary problems,
so he'd been vandalising this flowerbed so you'd
pay him for new saplings and bulbs and to do repairs.
So you set up a plan to frame him.
You witnessed Yamazaki-san and Okuda-san fighting on the stair landing this morning
and decided to use that spot as the crime scene.
Then, to make sure he had no alibi, you ordered him to make a delivery at 8 PM, to a fake address.
What are you saying?
Didn't Yamazaki-san die at 8 PM?
I was working at the café from 7:00
to 9:30 and never went outside.
And you should know, you were with me the whole time!
True, the town centre is more than 5 km from this café.
It'd take 10 minutes just to travel there and back by car.
It's an interesting theory, but you
forgot the most important part.
I couldn't have been there when Yamazaki-san fell.
The key was the bricks.
You took advantage of the flowerbed
vandalism that started three days ago,
and knowing nobody would notice, started stealing bricks from the flowerbed, and lined them up in the café garden.
Yamazaki-san wasn't killed at the town
centre —
she was killed in this garden!
So your alibi is no longer valid.
In other words, you used a trick to conceal the crime scene.
You called Yamazaki-san here before opening the shop,
took her upstairs, and drugged her to make her fall asleep,
then you worked at the café's ground floor from 7:00 to 9:30, establishing your alibi.
While you were working, you left the counter to go to the toilet for about 5 minutes at around 8:00.
You tied Yamazaki-san's shoelace while she was sleeping,
and threw her out of the 3rd floor window and onto the bricks placed in the garden to kill her.
That's when the evening primrose petals got on her clothes.
Afterwards, you put her corpse in your car boot, and after closing the café, you moved her to the town centre.
This morning, you heard me and Ayumi-chan talking, and knew we intended to patrol tonight.
You went ahead of us to make sure we'd find the corpse, which would confirm your alibi.
Everything you've been saying is nothing but fantasy!
Do you have any proof that I killed her?
Some of the bricks you stole from the centre should still be in your garden.
Hey, Conan!
Yes!
Yeah! There's lots of bricks here, just like Uncle said!
Since you were summoned for your testimony just after
moving the corpse, you didn't have time to clean up your garden.
An investigation of these bricks should reveal traces proving Yamazaki-san was killed here.
Now, this is just conjecture, but...
You were the one who was embezzling the centre's money, right?
And Yamazaki-san became a danger when she started investigating...
You're right. I have debt issues...
Even though I was working the night shift at my mother's café, it still wasn't enough.
So I took money from the centre.
When Yamazaki-san noticed,
she threatened to fire me.
That's why... That's why I had to...!
I'm so glad my brick's safe.
To be made by Kojima-kun...
Let me see, what is it?
Here! Ta-da!
Don't tell me that's...
You figured it out?
Yeah, it's an eel lunch!
Again?
I guess his love for eel lunches is as strong as a brick.
A shocking job from a classmate of Ran's!
A trap was set for a female student at her school!
Detective Conan: 'The Window at the Girls' School'!
Broadcasts on Saturday, May 11th at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Stool!
Hold on!
I'm gonna solve the next case!
The old man got hooked by the title...