I'm begging you! Please reinvestigate my sister's suicide!
Now, now, don't get so agitated.
First, would you tell us your name?
Oh, right.
My name's Misaki Yanai.
Misaki Yanai (17)
Yanai Seibi Educational Institute, 2nd Year Student
I went to the same school as Ran-san and Sonoko-san until the end of middle school.
At the start of high school, she transferred to the Yanai Seibi Educational Institute, where her mum's the director.
Oh, the famous Yanai Seibi Educational Institute?
So, you said you have doubts about your sister's suicide?
Yes, Nagisa would...
My sister would never have committed suicide!
But if the police are calling it a suicide, then they must have some evidence...
There were two witnesses.
I see, there were witnesses.
And I was one of them.
I see...
But something's got to be wrong!
No, no, no...
I beg you!
Please, prove that my sister didn't commit suicide!
That isn't going to be easy, you know...
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
The client's a female student, the stage is a school campus, and the truth is astonishing!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yeah, even the forensics confirmed it.
There's no doubt, Nagisa Yanai-san committed suicide.
As I thought. Thank you, Inspector.
Well, Inspector Megure confirmed it too.
I know that!
That's why I came to see you, Detective Mouri.
Misaki...
Sheesh!
Hey, somebody help me out here.
Hey, Uncle...
Would you at least listen to her testimony?
R-Right.
Anyway, calm down and just tell Uncle what you saw.
All right...
I'm only lending an ear, miss.
Five days ago, just before 6 PM,
as the evening was starting...
Wet paint!!
Kodama-sensei asked me to come with her to a bench because she had to talk to me.
Who's Kodama-sensei?
She's the advisor for both the high school and university theatre clubs.
My sister and I were both in the theatre club.
My sister was chosen to play the main character next year in a play for the institute's anniversary festival.
Harue Kodama (25)
Theatre Club Advisor
The play's not going to take place until early
next year, so the theme hasn't been decided yet.
That is to say, whether to make it a tragedy or a comedy.
Yeah, my sister told me.
The question is whether a happy ending would be better since it's an anniversary festival,
or whether a lively performance that'd touch people's hearts would be better.
Right, Nagisa-san isn't sure either.
That's why I wanted to find out your opinion.
But she's late...
Nagisa-san told me to wait for her here.
That's the model club clubroom, isn't it?
I thought the club members left already...
Perhaps it's their advisor, Shibagaki-sensei?
He should've been in a meeting with the director since 5:30 though...
Sis?
Why is Yanai-san there...
What are you doing?!
Sis!
Nagisa Yanai (22)
Misaki's Sister
What did your sister
hang the rope from?
That room has its ceiling beams exposed.
Sis! Sis!
It's no use, that room's soundproofed!
No!
It's locked!
Why today, of all days?!
I know! Call the director's room!
Right!
Was the director's room closer?
Yeah. It'd be a lot faster than us going all the way round to the front entrance. Also, both rooms are on the 2nd floor.
That's where your mother was, right?
Oh, yeah, and that Shibagaki teacher, too.
Hello?
What? What are you saying?!
My sister's in danger!
The model club clubroom! Hurry there!
Nagisa! Nagisa!
How could you do this to me?!
Was that Shibagaki teacher your sister's boyfriend?
He was in charge of the institute's finances,
and they were planning to get married once she graduated...
How could you leave me behind like this?!
Tōichirō Shibagaki (26)
Nagisa's Fiancé
It can't be! I can't believe this!
Hey, Misaki-san.
If you saw it with your own eyes, then what makes you think it's not suicide?
There has to be a reason, right?
She had a boyfriend who promised to marry her.
She should've been as happy as can be, right?
Yeah. Would someone enjoying life really commit suicide?
There was an problem with her boyfriend...
What do you mean?
Shibagaki-sensei and Kodama-sensei
went to the same university...
And they used to be together.
She's the other witness, right?
What?! So he could've been two-timing her?!
Yeah...
And they both admitted it?!
As the police investigation progressed,
Shibagaki-sensei had to reluctantly reveal his past...
And what did Kodama-sensei say about it?
What's up with that boy?
Don't mind him, he's just a precocious little brat.
But sometimes, he's very perceptive.
'Sometimes'?
Anyway, what did Kodama-sensei say?
She admitted she'd been with him in the past,
but said she has nothing to do with him anymore.
That sounds suspicious...
And they both work at the same school...
Maybe Nagisa-san committed suicide because she was troubled about that?
There's no way she'd just quietly commit suicide.
My sister would've done something like throw the engagement ring back at the cheating bastard.
Oh, but...
Something on your mind?
That scandal only came out with the police investigation, right?
How did your sister know about it beforehand?
Oh, you're right...
Right.
Oh yeah, I was also looking after this for my sister.
See, it has 'Nagisa' engraved into it.
She asked me to go adjust its size at the store where it was bought.
When was that?
The morning of the day she died.
Then Nagisa-san didn't know about
what happened between the advisors yet.
And not just that...
She wanted it adjusted because she wanted to wear the bracelet forever, even after the wedding.
Your sister sounds like she was so happy...
That's why I just can't accept that she'd commit suicide!
But you saw her do it with your own eyes...
No!
The rope that was used was one the model club use when packaging models.
And the stool she used to stand on rolled into a corner, behind a partition.
Since the stool had casters, it probably rolled away from the jolt of her jumping off.
But this is pretty impressive. Is this a model of the Yanai Seibi Educational Institute?
Were all the models built by the students?
The club members worked together to build them, but I'm sure their advisor helped too.
Oh, Shibagaki-sensei, right?
Yeah, he's a fan of miniatures and a total war nerd.
He even contributed his entire collection for display there.
Amazing...
It's a remote-control model of the Elefant, developed by the Germans during World War II!
You do know a lot, don't you?
I guess...
You are a boy, after all.
To girls, this is the kind of stuff that rings bells.
Oh, Mouri-san, hello.
Is that okay, Takagi?
If the Inspector scolds you for bringing these photos here,
I'm not gonna take responsibility, you know?
It'll be fine, I brought them because it wasn't a case for the police.
But these kids here are trying to prove it wasn't a suicide.
Oh, I see.
Don't go 'I see' on me!
Listen up.
You know what's weird about this case?
It's what the benefit from the victim's death was...
Since in this case, everybody ended up losing out.
Kodama-san and Shibagaki-san were widely suspected of being involved in a scandal.
Director Yanai, in shock from the loss of her daughter, declared she'd close down the campus.
Even if there was a killer, nobody would benefit from this!
There's no motive behind this crime!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did something catch your eye?
Hey, it's hard to tell what it's like with just photos, so why don't we go to the scene!
To the scene?
Yeah! We might find something if we take a look around, don't you think?
You don't mind, right, Detective Takagi?
Yeah, it's not sealed off or anything, so you should be fine.
I'm not going.
I'll tell you everything later then, Uncle.
It should be about time.
Ah, there she is.
Geez! Act serious!
Oh, geez. Guess she'll never change.
Wait!
When my sister was there, I could see her whole face.
I'll go and tell her then.
I'll call you when I get there!
Got it.
The back door was locked then, right?
Yeah.
Does this far look about right?
Yeah, that should do. Try getting on it.
What about now?
Yeah, it looks perfect now!
Got it.
Crawler tracks? Looks like it crashed pretty hard into the furniture...
Hey...
Can we call this reproduction done?
Ah, yeah.
Then—
Y-You okay?
If you're worried about me, then hurry up and get off me...
S-Sorry.
Hello, Mouri Detective Agency.
Oh, Misaki-san.
As for the case, the detective agency's
statement remains the same as yesterday.
Yes, I'm aware.
However, my mother and I still can't put our minds at ease unless you come to the scene and explain it to us.
But you already know what happened...
Please, all I want is an explanation.
Very well.
Thank you!
But all I'll give is an explanation.
Yes! Thank you very much.
See you later, then.
Well, if it'll help her accept her sister's actions, I have no choice.
I guess it's just another part of being a Great Detective.
What on Earth is Mouri-kun starting up now?
He really didn't tell you?
No, he just insisted that we'd understand if we came here.
Bear in mind that due to the school closing down, we don't have much time to spare.
Hey, sorry to keep you waiting.
What's the Inspector doing here too—
Dad!
He went straight into Sleeping Kogorō mode!
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone.
I have come here at Misaki Yanai-san's request, and—
That case is already closed.
I'm aware, as you know.
The victim is believed to have committed suicide.
However, on the same day, she'd asked her sister to get her bracelet resized.
Doesn't that seem strange?
I believe I can answer that.
She probably acted upon the spur of the moment when she found out about my actions.
Oh?
In that case, when and how did she find out about that?
Well, after she died it all—
I see. So she had no way of knowing.
By the way, Misaki-san, Ran and the others checked over the case yesterday.
Sonoko-kun, could you please repeat that reproduction?
Again?
I apologise, Yanai-sensei, but please just be patient.
Sonoko-kun began by placing a step over there, but standing there didn't match the witnessed Nagisa's silhouette.
She had to move further from the window to achieve a perfect match.
Umm... It was about here.
What's wrong with that?
There's nothing wrong or right with it.
It would have been impossible
for her to commit suicide there.
As on that day, that spot happened to be occupied by a model of the Seibi Institute.
Just to check, can you tell us, Misaki-san...
How much of the room was taken up by the model?
Oh, uh... Up to this line.
As you can see, it would be impossible for her to stand there.
However, if she avoided the model and stood elsewhere,
her position doesn't match with the witnesses' testimony.
To achieve the same perspective from a position closer to the window,
a shorter step would need to be used.
Come on, the only thing here that looked like it could've been used was the stool.
No, there was something else.
Hey, Inspector...
Why would she focus so much on where to commit suicide?
It's almost like she was taking up a position upon a stage.
Now that you mention it, back then, my sister...
I could see her face up to her waist,
as if it was all perfectly measured...
I wonder if that was a coincidence?
What if it wasn't a coincidence?
What if someone had given her directions...
so that she'd be perfectly visible
to both of you in the garden.
You're saying my sister wanted us to see her commit suicide?
Correct. Nagisa-san wanted Kodama-sensei to see a 'suicide act'.
That was why she deliberately chose the best position.
Oh! That's why she told me to
wait on that garden bench that day...
My sister's suicide was an act...
What Nagisa-san thought was this.
She wanted the audience at the
anniversary festival to see her perform.
For that, she had to convince Kodama-sensei with her acting.
That way, even a tragic play could have been chosen for the festival.
It does make sense...
Nagisa-san just could've done something like that...
She decided on her plan because someone eloquently convinced her.
And the only one who could do that...
Hey! What are you trying to say?!
Nothing. I never mentioned your name.
There are many benches in the back garden,
but for some reason, every bench except the one Misaki-san sat on had just been painted.
I was told by the school staff that Shibayaki-sensei requested that all the other benches be painted that specific day.
And so, the premium seats for the play were prepared.
Also, on that day alone, the back door had been locked.
And the one in charge of the keys was...
It was you, Shibagaki-sensei.
But, Mouri-kun...
Even if her suicide was meant to be only an act, how did it turn into the real thing?
That is because her step moved from underneath her.
What?
As a step, the stool was too tall.
So the killer asked her to stand on a tank.
A tank?
The Elefant that was at the scene?!
Detective Takagi, would you bring it over here?
Most likely, it's a German cast alloy model.
Which should handle a girl's weight easily.
So you're saying she used this tank instead of the stool?
6 PM — That was the time the victim had been told to begin her performance.
If someone used a remote control at that exact moment,
then they could move the tank even from outside the room.
Shibagaki-sensei, you were using the
calculator with your left hand at the time,
but you didn't take your right hand out of your pocket!
If there happened to be a remote control in that pocket...
That's a false accusation!
I was horrified when I got Misaki's call about Nagisa's suicide!
I'm a victim too!
You're lying! All I told you was
to hurry to the model club clubroom!
I couldn't manage to say anything else!
My sister's in danger!
The model club clubroom! Hurry there!
So how did you know she'd committed suicide?
T-That was just a figure of speech!
When you arrived at the scene, was there any step here?
I could see the stool lying against the partition.
I see.
So when you went to help her, you confirmed that there was something she could've stood on.
That's nonsense! When I donated my collection, I removed the motors from all the models!
I didn't want the students to play pranks with my precious models...
Indeed, I can't see any antenna here.
Yeah, that's right!
It's an impressive deduction, but an unmovable object can't move.
It moved!
I had Conan investigate it beforehand.
The antenna was replaced with an internal one, and although the engine shows evidence of having once been taken out,
it is currently present.
Can you tell us why this is so?
It appears Shibagaki-sensei's objections have come to an end.
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
It seems like Shibagaki-sensei was embezzling the institute's money, and Kodama-sensei was asked to keep quiet in exchange for part of it.
But she got scared and broke up with him.
If the school closed down, then the embezzlement would've been swept under the carpet.
So the killer really would've benefited from the murder.
But Misaki-san's mother seems to have recovered thanks to her support.
And now the institute can keep going too.