One morning on a day off from school, we went to the outskirts of Beika to do an art project for homework.
H-Hey!
Could that be—?
It is!
It's definitely a UFO!
Like the one that Adamski saw!
I can't believe it's real!
Hey, hey...
Edogawa-kun!
Over there.
What in the world...
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A crashed UFO spotted at a riverbank.
What was the victim hiding?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Right now, we know that—
Detective Takagi!
Y-You guys!
Hey, don't bring kids into a crime scene.
Oh, but they told me they were your friends.
Still, even so you can't just—
What an unlucky guy.
A UFO from the far reaches of space landed right on top of him.
Hey, hey, hey! You can't be here!
Did you find the aliens from the UFO yet?
What? No, but—
They ran away?
Isn't that called a hit-and-run on Earth?
Yeah!
That's not it!
Hey, Detective Takagi...
The flap on this man's pocket...
It's ripped off.
Yeah, it looks like it caught on something and got torn off.
But give me a break, Conan-kun.
He's wearing really flashy clothing. What kind of person was he?
Okay, okay, okay.
The victim was 22-years old Osamu Iwabuchi-san from Beika Town.
The estimated time of death is around 1 AM.
He was crushed by the UFO twice and died.
And that's all we know right now.
Now that you know, you can leave—
You said he was crushed twice...
There were two wounds in different places on the body.
Well, there were no signs of life in the wound from the second impact,
so it seems that he died when he was crushed the first time.
Anyway, I'm going to get in trouble if Inspector Megure sees you here.
I found it!
It was here!
W-Who's that?
No idea...
I've been looking everywhere!
My flying saucer!
H-Hey, you!
What are you doing? Please get down!
I'm taking this back!
T-Taking it back? Who are you...
M-Me? I'm...
Shōzō Onuma (58)
UFO researcher
I'm a physics researcher, Shōzō Onuma.
For 30 years, I've dedicated myself
to developing this flying saucer!
So it didn't come from outer space?
Exactly. It's from my laboratory nearby.
But I wonder how it flew here, it's still incomplete.
It's strange.
To cover my research expenses,
I work night shifts at a corner shop.
I was working last night, and when I came back to the lab this morning, this was gone!
Well, when even the man who made it calls it incomplete,
then there's no way it could fly, right?
But...
Say, Dr. Onuma.
Was that truck also at your laboratory last night?
That?
Yeah, I always leave it with the key inside.
Because I don't like having to look for the key.
Then what happened is pretty obvious.
The UFO didn't fly here.
Somebody just brought it here with that truck.
I see.
I guess it's pretty simple when you put it that way.
I got excited over nothing.
But if it didn't fly here, then how did he end up underneath the saucer?
What?! Someone was pinned down by my saucer?!
Yes. We, the police, believe it was a homicide.
A homicide?!
Yes.
We think the killer knocked out Iwabuchi-san...
and laid him down by the riverbank.
Then, he took your saucer...
and dropped it from above the bridge.
Twice, too.
What...
But Detective Takagi...
Why did the killer go through all that trouble to kill him with the saucer?
That's what I'm wondering...
In any case, Dr. Onuma...
Will you take me to your laboratory?
I don't mind, but could you return this?
I'm sorry, but it's a vital piece of evidence.
Figures...
Okay, kids. Leave the rest to the police.
Yeah! We have to go and do some sketches for homework.
Good luck, Detective Takagi.
See ya!
See you later!
Oh, okay...
Can you really make a flying saucer in a tiny place like this?
Right...
Wait, what are you doing here?!
We came here to draw some sketches of this lab, of course.
Oh... I see.
It probably looks dilapidated to keep it secret.
That way, it won't attract attention.
Oh! So there's gotta be supercomputers and lots of cool stuff inside!
All right! Let's go take a look inside!
Yeah!
Somehow I don't think it'll live up to their expectations...
Let the UFO fly to outer space
So what do you think of Onuma Flying Saucer Research Laboratory?
Umm, well...
Let's look for clues to find the killer!
Yup.
Yeah.
Where did you keep the saucer?
It was hanging over there.
I wanted to dream about it flying.
So it was hanging from the ceiling...
This looks very rusty.
It must have fallen off when the killer took down the saucer.
It looks like it was weak to begin with.
Detective Takagi!
Over here...
I found this.
It's not mine.
I knew it.
I think there's a name on here.
Man'nen.
Man'nen?
Never heard it.
That hat must belong to the killer!
So the killer's name is Man'nen.
Edogawa-kun.
Look.
That's...
Yeah.
It belongs to him.
That scrap of fabric wasn't there yesterday either.
So, both Man'nen and the murdered Iwabuchi-san were here.
They probably came together.
Chiba!
From my research, Osamu Iwabuchi-san had a friend who was like a brother.
This is the victim, Iwabuchi-san.
Indeed.
And the other guy is Iwabuchi-san's friend, Sadao Man'nen.
Sadao Man'nen (33)
Debt Collector
Man'nen?!
Yesterday, they were at a restaurant...
I'll pay for all the bills tomorrow.
Right, Buchi?
We have an idea that'll make us rich.
It's plausible that they snuck into this place last night to try to get money.
But if Man'nen were the criminal, why would he kill his friend?
Also...
Do you really think they'd come here for money?
You're right.
No offence, but nothing here looks like it's actually worth much...
Yeah, there is! That treasure!
Let the UFO fly to outer space
I bought it at the end of last month.
It was supposedly the work of a famous calligrapher, and I paid ¥50,000 for it!
¥50,000?!
The seller, Ōkura-san, said it was perfect for me, so he gave me a discount.
No, that's not it...
Ōkura...
Kinji Ōkura?!
Hmm? Yeah.
Kinji Ōkura, the loan shark?
Yes.
Man'nen and Iwabuchi were hired by him as debt collectors
They were Ōkura's underlings?!
Is Ōkura-san a bad person?
We believed he was guilty of tax evasion.
He supposedly had about a hundred million in his assets,
and sometime during the beginning of the month, the revenue office investigated his house,
but they couldn't find where he hid his wealth.
In the end, no hidden assets were ever found.
I didn't know Ōkura-san was that type of person.
He's a money-worshipper.
He exaggerated that anything under a million yen was worthless.
Strange.
Yeah.
I can't imagine that he'd sell a fake scroll just to get ¥50,000.
Then maybe the two men snuck in here under Ōkura-san's orders.
Actually, Kinji Ōkura died two days ago.
He was involved in a car accident.
But he must be related to the case somehow.
The two men working under Ōkura snuck into the place of the man he sold the scroll to.
Yeah, it doesn't sound like a coincidence...
Should we go take a look?
Man'nen and Iwabuchi were with Kinji Ōkura at Beika Central Hospital when he died.
Yeah, let's do it.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
This is about Kinji Ōkura-san, who arrived here in an ambulance?
We were wondering how he seemed when he passed.
When he arrived, he was already unconscious.
Oh, right before his last breath, he said something strange...
What is it, President?
Y-You... foe...
Those were his last words.
'You foe'?
Excuse me.
Oh, UFO!
Got it.
Sorry, there's an emergency.
Oh, thank you very much.
It must be about that scroll.
Y-You guys...
He probably regretted selling that fake thing.
I agree!
Yeah.
I wonder if he's that admirable?
Hey, Detective Chiba.
Ōkura-san loved money, right?
Yeah.
Then the kind of dying message he'd leave...
Is pretty obvious, isn't it?
Kinji Ōkura-san secretly had several hundred millions worth in assets...
But his money wasn't found in his office.
Right...
They even did a thorough investigation of his home.
That was at the beginning of this month, right?
Right before that, Ōkura-san sold the scroll to Dr. Onuma at the end of last month.
So?
Would a person who considers anything below a million yen worthless...
sell a scroll only to get fifty thousand yen?
He may have had a different reason for selling it.
Another reason?
If you think about it, there aren't many places as safe as that laboratory.
There would never be any robberies.
Oh, I see! Ōkura sold the scroll to hide his money.
He went to sell the scroll, and while the doctor wasn't looking, he hid the money somewhere in that laboratory.
With no chance of it being stolen, it'd be a safe temporary hiding place.
The scroll was just an excuse to visit.
He didn't care about the fifty thousand yen.
I agree!
Yup!
And what Ōkura-san said right before he died.
U-UFO...
UFO meant the saucer research lab.
Man'nen and Iwabuchi found out about the treasure's hiding spot.
They wanted to take it for themselves, so they snuck into the place and found it.
And while they were close friends, he didn't want to share the money,
so Sadao Man'nen killed Osamu Iwabuchi...
So that's how it was.
It all fits.
Not all.
I guess not.
Hello.
Okay. I understand.
Who was that, Chiba?
It was from Beika Police Station, who we're having search for Sadao Man'nen.
He seems to owe money to others in the same business,
but he's still running away from the debt collectors.
If he has millions, wouldn't he just repay his debts?
Which means the money still hasn't been found.
It must...
But that means...
Our guess that Man'nen killed Iwabuchi to take the money for himself no longer holds true.
So Sadao Man'nen doesn't have a motive.
Then who killed Osamu Iwabuchi?
I see!
Hey, hey!
Man'nen-san's pretty strange, isn't he?
I wonder why he decided to stop looking for the money before he found it?
He stopped?
Oh, when he brought the saucer out at 1 AM.
Oh, right.
I wonder if something happened that made him stop searching?
What's the word... 'an unexpected situation'?
An unexpected situation?
Maybe something to do with the broken wire that the saucer was hanging from?
The wire it was hanging from?
Yeah, there was one wire that was rusty and had broken off.
And Iwabuchi-san was crushed twice by the saucer.
He died the first time and was crushed again.
An unexpected situation...
A torn wire...
Crushed twice...
And Sadao Man'nen has no motive to kill Osamu Iwabuchi.
Is that it?
Most likely.
I see!
This isn't a murder case!
Yes!
Hey, why isn't this a murder case?
I have no idea.
All I know is that the money's still hidden.
Either way, let's go back to the lab!
H-Hey, you guys can go now...
But...
We left our stuff there.
Oh, I see...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
How many suitcases does a hundred million yen fill?
It doesn't have to be cash.
It could be bars of gold!
I don't mind you searching, but...
When was it hidden?
Ōkura-san never came here.
He was never here?
But didn't he come to sell the scroll...?
No.
He contacted me, so I went to him.
I heard that you were building a flying saucer, so I knew it would be bad karma not to sell this to you.
It's as if it was written for me.
Ain't that right? It can be a heirloom of yours.
I'll give it to you for ¥50,000.
And that's how I got it.
Kinji Ōkura never came here?
Then he couldn't have hidden anything.
When Ōkura said 'UFO', I guess he wasn't talking about this place.
Those two misunderstood him and came here.
Then why did Kinji Ōkura sell the scroll?
He called Dr. Onuma just to sell that thing...
Let the UFO fly to outer space
I see!
You figured something out.
Well, either way, Man'nen will be coming here tonight to look for the money.
Actually, I wonder if he can wait that long.
I have to return it fast, or I'm screwed!
He's not here. Lucky me!
Are you Sadao Man'nen?
You were here last night as well, weren't you?
With your friend, Osamu Iwabuchi,
looking for Kinji Ōkura's hidden fortune.
However, you were caught in an unexpected situation.
Yeah...
It has to be here somewhere.
'UFO' must mean this place, right?
No, my only good suit!
You can buy as many suits as you want when we get the money.
Oh, yeah.
W-What the hell?!
Buchi!
A-Are you okay, Buchi?!
He was instantly squashed to death.
I knew it was rusty.
I was going to change it once I got money from my part-time job.
So it was an unfortunate accident.
You couldn't continue searching for the money.
And you couldn't just leave the body there.
If the body was discovered the next morning, the police would come.
If Iwabuchi was dead...
They would think that his best friend was also with him, and you would be suspected.
And, if during the investigation...
The police found the money, you would have lost everything.
In order to prevent that, you came up with a plan.
By moving both the body and the saucer,
you tried to make it look like Iwabuchi-san died at the riverbank.
To turn the officers' attention away from this lab.
He was involved in a UFO landing...
That's what I wanted people to think.
But there would've been an easier method to distract the officers.
You could have hidden the body where people wouldn't find it.
I see.
The police wouldn't have investigated if the body wasn't discovered.
That wouldn't work!
He wouldn't have a funeral if his body wasn't found.
It wouldn't be fair to Buchi.
But do you understand what you've done?
You've committed one crime after another.
Trespassing in this laboratory.
Abandoning Osamu Iwabuchi's body.
Taking the UFO out counts as theft.
I admit everything...
Let's go.
Yes...
Oh yeah, about Ōkura-san's hidden wealth...
Jewels were hidden inside the scroll's metal bars.
Ōkura-san's dying words weren't indicating a place...
But the UFO scroll itself.
Okay, I'll drive you guys home. Get your stuff.
Our stuff?
We forgot to do our homework!
Buried treasure?
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
That's...
A Mystery Train Pass Ring?!
On the next Conan: 'The Shadow Approaching Haibara's Secret (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Shape made by Fingers!