Here. This one's yours, Conan-kun.
'Mystery Train Pass Ring'?
You know, it's your pass to the Bell Tree Express that we're riding on next week!
It arrived at the doctor's this morning.
You show the conductor the ring and have him beep it when you get on the train!
It's apparently a steam train that looks just like the Orient Express...
Though I hope there won't be a murder on it like in Christie's novel.
Of course not...
So you're already wearing your ring?
Yeah.
Before you arrived at the doctor's house, we all put them on and took photos.
When we get to the campsite, we'll take another photo with you in it too!
Come on, don't put them on so soon! What if you lose—
Conan-kun, did you catch a cold?
Last night, old man Kogorō was coughing badly, so I might've caught his.
Then at least wear a mask...
Don't have one.
Geez...
I'll give you some medicine now then,
so take this and settle down.
Let's see, the cold medicine was...
Isn't this...?
This one's the cold medicine.
Hey, don't tell me that medicine was...
Yeah.
It's the Apoptoxin 4869 antidote.
I carry some around, just in case.
Then give me some, 'just in case'.
No way!
I can't give any to a detective from a rom-com who would grow larger whenever the whim takes him...
Just lemme have it!
Hey!
What's the point of having it if you're just carrying it around!
You pervert!
What are you doing?!
You're horrible, teasing a girl!
Ah, no...
I'm the one being teased...
Damn you...
We're almost there!
Everybody ready?
Yeah!
Seeking comprehensive answers, he solves every mystery and code!
Bourbon finally makes his move?!
Three shadows approach Haibara and me.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
So Conan-kun went camping?
Sounds fun...
He said he was going to a campsite in Gunma today.
It's a wonder he doesn't get tired of camping once a month.
If he's going to Gunma, I wonder if he'll be near Mt. Fuyuna?
The hydrangeas should be beautiful there!
He said he'll send the photos to my PC, so I'll show them to you later...
Please do!
It's Sera-san...
Hello, Sera-san?
I told you yesterday that Conan-kun was going camping, didn't I?
Yeah, in Dr. Agasa's Beetle.
It's yellow.
But why are you asking me that?
Ugh, I can't believe the doc.
How can you go camping without bringing anything to cook! Unbelievable!
Well, the doctor and Conan-kun are buying some at a shop close by right now...
Hey, hurry and set up your tent!
We're going to collect firewood.
Hey, come on!
Hey, mister! From here on is our spot!
Don't just barge in!
Hey, Genta-kun...
The campsite's for everybody, so be nice!
From here on is my area.
Not your territory.
What was that about?
To keep my hands to myself, and be obedient?
Or that I should keep my position in mind, and not bother with futile resistance?
Here they are!
That's a campsite store for you.
They've got all sorts of camping supplies!
Then should we buy some more rice too?
Genta's always whining that there isn't enough.
Indeed. Should we get some extra mess kits then?
Sure, but remember that Haibara serves up your portion.
T-That's a ricey situation...
R-Rice...
I prefer bread over rice myself.
S-Sera...
...neechan...
What are you doing here?
Pure coincidence!
I was thinking I'd check out the hydrangeas in Gunma, so I was passing by on my bike
when I realised I was hungry, came in here and ran into you! Fate must've drawn us together!
It looks like you're buying quite a bit though...
It's today's lunch and dinner, plus tomorrow's breakfast.
Since you guys didn't bring anything for me, right?
You trying to crash our camping trip?
Hey, Genta-kun!
DANGER — SNAKES!!
We've already gathered enough firewood, so let's go back to the tents!
Okay.
There's a sign saying 'Danger — Snakes' here as well.
Snakes?
Hey, guys! Check this out over here!
I can hear somebody digging a hole!
A hole?
Buried treasure?
We won't know until we take a look!
A... woman?
Being buried?
Run!
They saw me...
They saw me!
They saw me!!
Hello, Edogawa-kun?
The phone you are trying to reach is currently turned off, or—
Why now of all times!
There's nobody around...
Maybe they went to gather firewood?
She really did end up joining us...
Oh well, guess I'll try calling Haibara.
Oh, crap. The battery's flat!
If your battery's dead, how about using my smartphone?
I have the same model as you.
You want to call that Haibara girl, right?
I-It's okay. There's still the doc's mobile.
Right, Doc?
I'm trying to call with the phone I had in my backpack, but it's not connecting.
Maybe the signal's bad around here...
Should we try looking for them then?
They should be somewhere they can find firewood, right?
Are you okay, Yoshida-san?
I can't run any more...
Come on, Ayumi!
Haibara-san, there's a cabin over there!
Let's hide in the cabin for now then.
Right!
Yoshida-san, can you stand up?
Yeah...
Here, I'll support you!
Let's go!
Right.
You can rest when we get to the cabin.
Right...
Thanks, all of you.
Where are you, kids? Hey!
DANGER — SNAKES!!
Answer if you can hear me, Haibara!
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
That's...
A Mystery Train Pass Ring?!
Then they really are...
Hey, something isn't right.
For there to be police this far up the mountain...
What on Earth could've happened...?
A corpse?!
Hey! What happened here?
We got a report a while ago, so we came to investigate and found this corpse.
What sort of report?
Somebody saying they were being chased by a man who was burying a dead woman near a 'Danger — Snakes' sign.
It was a girl's voice.
We managed to get in the cabin, but do you think we'll be safe?
Yeah, we locked it up tight.
Even King Gomera couldn't break through that!
Then I'll go and see if there are any other entrances.
Hey, Ai-chan. You still can't reach Conan-kun?
No... It seems there's no reception at all here.
Anyway, it looks like somebody was here before us.
Judging from their bags, it was probably a couple.
How are things, Mitsuhiko?
It seems like there's only the one entrance.
H-Hey!
What's wrong?
No, I'm fine.
The floor was just wet...
D-Don't tell me that woman was killed here!
If so, then the killer will almost certainly return to this blood-soaked crime scene...
T-Then we have to hurry and get out of here!
Right! Let's go, Ayumi, Haibara!
S-So the guy from before really did come back?
Shouldn't we try calling out to them?
It could just be someone who came across this cabin by chance...
Make no mistake. On the other side of this door is the murderer who was burying the corpse earlier...
He's probably the black bag's owner. He would've brought the woman we saw being buried here and killed her...
But don't worry.
This door's the only entrance, so we just have to wait patiently for help to arrive.
Ai-chan, are you shaking?
It's just a little chill...
I might've caught Edogawa-kun's cold...
I see, I see... So basically...
Two hours ago, a report came in saying 'I'm being chased by a man who was burying a dead woman near a "Danger — Snakes" sign'...
And when you came and had a look, you discovered this corpse.
And the girl who made the report was most likely...
One of your friends, right, Conan-kun?
We've been calling her this whole time, but we can't reach her.
So please hurry and search this area!
Well, a search party is looking about,
but this area is almost like a maze, so they may take a while to find...
N-No way!
But fear not!
Mt. Fuyuna here is a Gunma Policeman's backyard!
We'll bring the children and the killer here in no time!
I don't know if we're supposed to be worried or not...
Still, wouldn't it be a good idea to find out whose body this is?
Judging from the state of post-mortem lividity and rigor mortis, it's been about 5 to 6 hours since she was killed...
It looks like she was hacked at by some sort of axe...
But it wasn't an instant death.
She was still breathing slightly after being placed in the sleeping bag...
You can see marks inside the sleeping bag from where she moved her bloodied hands...
Wait — who are you?!
I'm a detective, Masumi Sera.
I'm a friend of Conan-kun's.
Right?
Y-Yeah...
I don't care if you're a detective or not... But you make it hard for us
if you go around touching the corpse like that!
Sorry, sorry...
If you could solve anything with a sorry, you wouldn't need police!
Well, who's body is it?
She didn't have any ID with her.
I think she's probably a nursery teacher!
Look!
She's got bruises on her kneecaps, right?
Nursery teachers often get on their knees to try and be at eye level with the kids...
But can you really determine she was a nursery teacher just from that?
There are sports where you use your knees a lot too...
If they were from sports, she'd have marks on her elbows or hands too.
And people who sit in formal Japanese style would have marks on their shins and the tops of their feet as well.
Plus, her hair's straight, but the sides are oddly fluffy.
And even though her hair's long, the back of her neck is tanned all the way up to her hairline...
That proves that her hair was tied on both sides, and she went outside like that.
She looks to be about 30 years old...
But for her to have such a childish hairstyle,
she'd likely be a nursery teacher who goes outside to play, walk, and take trips with children.
I-Indeed.
Then I'll return to the station and investigate if there are any missing nursery teachers...
But it might take some time if she's from another prefecture...
As for the killer, the trainer footprints here are from when he was digging the hole, aren't they?
They're smudged, so I can't make out the tread underfoot, but we can at least find out his shoe size, right?
Let's see...
Seems to be about 26 centimetres.
There's a shovel left by the corpse too, but I wouldn't bet on finding any fingerprints.
The fact that it was left behind means that the killer most likely wore gloves.
So in other words, the only clue to finding the killer we have is that his shoe size is 26 centimetres.
For the rest, we'll have to wait for forensics to come...
What are you talking about? Take a good look.
Look at her hands...
Aren't they in an odd position?
I see! What is this?
Sign language or something?
Who knows...
Judging from the bloodstains,
she was desperately trying to form this shape with her fingers while on the brink of death, inside the sleeping bag...
'O' and 'K'...
san
ni
No... 2 and 3...
'ni' and 'san'... Niisan?
I see! It's 'niisan'!
The killer's her older brother!
No way...
Inspector Yamamura.
We have a report from the search party.
They found three men wandering about alone on the mountain, and they're bringing them here.
What about the children?
Were there any children nearby
when they found those men?!
Well, the report didn't say...
I see...
It's already been two hours...
There hasn't been a sound since, right?
Maybe he gave up and ran away?
Then should we look outside to check?
No way! He might expect us to think that and be waiting outside to ambush us!
But if it's just a quick peek...
Wait, Kojima-kun!
You okay, Ai-chan?
You're sweating so much!
I'm fine.
Hurry and stop Kojima-kun!
B-But...
He already opened it...
How is it, Genta-kun?
I can't see anybody.
Okay, looks like it's safe.
Hey, what's this?
We're in trouble!
It's been chained in — we can't get out!
H-Haibara-san! We've been locked in!
Say, Ai-chan, can't you smell something burning?
Now that you mention it, I can.
Don't tell me...
The mountain cabin's on fire?!
The windows! We should be able to get out through there!
It's no use!
They've been nailed shut!
No way! They won't open?!
I see... He originally planned to shut her in here and set the cabin on fire, making the death look like an accident...
But she caught on, so he murdered her with the axe instead.
But if he lit the fire afterward, he'd be caught once they found the injury on the burned corpse...
Maybe that's why he tried to bury her near the 'Danger — Snakes' sign, since people wouldn't come near...
We have to hurry and get out!
Damn it! This door won't budge one bit!
What do we do?! It's too strong for us to break...
It's okay. Calm down.
Somebody's sure to notice the smoke and come help us...
Right, Kudō-kun?
Smoke?
Hey, it's pretty far, but there's smoke rising up over there!
That's probably just smoke from a campfire!
See, there's one over there, too.
Recently, a lot of young people have been building huge wooden structures and throwing parties during the day...
We've warned them again and again, but they just won't stop...
Inspector Yamamura!
Here are the three men mentioned in the report.
I see, I see. Good work.
Well then, one by one, please tell me your name, occupation, and the reason why you came here.
Hayamichi Yonezumi (31)
Part-Time Worker
I'm Hayamichi Yonezumi, a part-time worker.
I don't know what's going on, but I came to check out the area, since I'm gonna be camping here with my buddies next week.
Chōzō Usagi (42)
Photographer
My name's Chōzō Usagi, I'm a photographer.
I'm going around taking photos of the scenery of campsites all around Japan.
Takeya Iwakuma (23)
University Student
I came to take photos too.
Photos of Japanese azalea with my mobile phone camera, to post on my blog...
Orange flowers bloom on them at this time of the year.
M-My name's Takeya Iwakuma. I'm a fourth-year student at Beika University.
You three are pretty lightly equipped, though...
I was just scouting the area...
I was just taking a look around too — my camera and equipment are in the car.
And I just came for a quick visit...
How about it?
It's still not connecting.
Knowing Haibara, she should've moved to some place with reception, but...
If she's still being chased around by the killer,
then those three must be innocent, right?
Or perhaps, though it's not a nice idea...
Someone, possibly one of those three, already killed them...
Or they're in some situation that means they can't move...
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
You don't think the killer came back, do you?
What a mess...
All the Detective Badges are back with the tents...
We have to find them before it gets dark.
I see!
So that's how it was!
On the next Conan: 'The Shadow Approaching Haibara's Secret (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Pass Ring!
We're all in danger!
A true crisis.
Don't worry. That person will save you.