I went camping with Haibara and the other three Detective Boys in Dr. Agasa's Beetle.
The doc and I went off to buy some mess kits since they had been forgotten, and happened upon Masumi Sera.
She ended up deciding to camp with us too.
Meanwhile, Haibara and the Detective Boys went into the woods to gather firewood,
and ended up finding someone burying a woman's corpse.
A... woman?
Being buried?
Run!
Unable to contact me, Haibara and the others ran for their lives,
and ended up hiding in a cabin in the woods.
How are things, Mitsuhiko?
It seems like there's only the one entrance.
H-Hey!
What's wrong?
No, I'm fine.
The floor was just wet...
D-Don't tell me that woman was killed here!
If so, then the killer will almost certainly return to this blood-soaked crime scene...
T-Then we have to hurry and get out of here!
Right!
Around the same time, we met Inspector Yamamura, who had received a report from Haibara.
Three possible suspects in burying the corpse were also found.
We're in trouble!
It's been chained shut — we can't get out!
H-Haibara-san!
We've been locked in!
Say, Ai-chan, can't you smell something burning?
Now that you mention it, I can.
Don't tell me...
The mountain cabin's on fire?!
We have to hurry and get out!
Damn it!
This door won't budge one bit!
What do we do?! It's too strong for us to break...
It's okay. Calm down.
Somebody's sure to notice the smoke and come help us...
Right, Kudō-kun?
Smoke?
Hey, it's pretty far, but there's smoke rising up over there!
That's probably just smoke from a campfire!
See, there's one over there, too.
Recently, a lot of young people have been building huge wooden structures and throwing parties during the day...
Inspector Yamamura!
Here are the three men mentioned in the report.
I see, I see. Good work.
Seeking comprehensive answers, he solves every mystery and code!
A black shadow approaching Haibara!
A small mistake left behind!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Well then, one by one, please tell me your name, occupation, and the reason why you came here.
I'm Hayamichi Yonezumi, a part-time worker.
Hayamichi Yonezumi (31)
Part-Time Worker
I don't know what's going on, but I came to check out the area, since I'm gonna be camping here with my buddies next week.
Chōzō Usagi (42)
Photographer
My name's Chōzō Usagi, I'm a photographer.
I'm going around taking photos of the scenery of campsites all around Japan.
Takeya Iwakuma (23)
University Student
I came to take photos too.
Photos of Japanese azalea with my mobile phone camera, to post on my blog...
Orange flowers bloom on them at this time of the year.
M-My name's Takeya Iwakuma. I'm a fourth-year student at Beika University.
You three are pretty lightly equipped, though...
I was just scouting the area...
I was just taking a look around too — my camera and equipment are in the car.
And I just came for a quick visit...
How about it?
It's still not connecting.
Knowing Haibara, she should've moved to some place with reception, but...
If she's still being chased around by the killer,
then those three must be innocent, right?
Or perhaps, though it's not a nice idea...
Someone, possibly one of those three, already killed them...
Or they're in some situation that means they can't move...
Everyone, hang in there!
Keep your heads low, so you don't breathe in the smoke!
Somebody will save us soon!
But when are they gonna get here!?
T-There's smoke coming up from over there too...
Is it a campfire?
No way...
Doesn't that mean they won't notice the smoke coming from here?!
N-No way...
Then all that's left is...
All three of you are 26 cm?
Really?
Our shoe sizes, right?
Is something wrong with that?
Damn it! If the killer is one of those three, then the fastest way to find them would be to figure out who and ask him directly, but...
What a mess...
All the Detective Badges are back with the tents...
Maybe we should go and search too...
If you search about blindly, you'll just get lost in the forest!
It'd be best to leave the searching to the search party, who know the mountain well...
But it's almost sunset, and even the shadows are growing longer...
If we don't find them before it becomes dark...
Shadows?
I see!
So that's how it was!
A-Ayumi-chan!
Hang in there, Ayumi!
Ayumi! Wake up, Ayumi!
Genta-kun, bring Ayumi-chan closer to the door.
We have to give her some fresh air!
Okay. Hang in there, Ayumi!
We'll move you now!
You'll be breathing fresh mountain air in just a sec.
Here, breathe in, Ayumi-chan!
Ain't it great? Hey, Ayumi!
Please hang on, Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi! Wake up, Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
W-What was that sound?!
It sounded like a door...
That's impossible — we're the only ones here...
D-Don't tell me the killer came back...
Hey, Detective.
Aren't you going to tell us what happened?
If you don't explain what's going on, we can't exactly help you any further...
I've got plans, you know...
A-Actually, a woman's corpse was abandoned on the mountain, and the killer's on the run...
That's why we rounded up the three of you, who were wandering alone on the mountain...
Hey, hey...
Can you three show me both of your hands?
What's this about?
I've been watching you guys,
but Yonezumi-san and Iwakuma-san have been only using their left hands,
and Usagi-san has only been using his right hand!
So I thought you might be hiding some sort of injury on your other hand!
Come on.
I use my left hand because I'm left-handed!
Nothing on my right hand, either...
I'm left-handed too...
I was using my right hand because I'm right-handed!
Of course, there is nothing on my left hand either...
But Usagi-san...
The culprit was right-handed too, you know?
What're you saying?
You didn't see anything but the female corpse that the killer was trying to bury and the hole, right?
The evidence that the killer was right-handed was left behind on the corpse and beside the hole!
Evidence?
The wound on the corpse was made by an axe-like object striking from the upper right downwards.
Which means the guy who hacked at her was right-handed...
And the killer's footprints next to the hole show the left footprint in front, and the right one in the rear...
If the person digging the hole wasn't right-handed, he wouldn't have left prints like that, right?
Ah, you're right!
Then, you mean he's the killer?
G-Give me a break...
If you have any defence, I'd like to hear it.
Aren't most people right-handed?
These two could actually be right-handed too, just forcing themselves to use their left hand in order to hide it...
That's kinda...
And the killer could even still be hiding somewhere in these mountains...
Sure, most Japanese people are right-handed...
But I think there's only one person wandering around this mountain today...
Who's both right handed and named 'Usagi' — and that's you!
Hold on. Look here, Conan-kun...
Where is that name in the crime scene?
The dead lady told us, didn't she?
She made this shape with her fingers inside the sleeping bag she was shoved into, right?
And how does that produce the name 'Usagi'?
It's hard to tell just from the shapes of the fingers,
but if you stack your right and left hands like this...
And shine light on them...
Could that be...
usagi
A-A rabbit!
B-But why a shadow puppet?
If she could have made this shape, she could have written something in blood too...
It's because the murdered woman was a nursery teacher!
Nursery teachers often show children shadow puppets,
and even if the killer saw her hands, he wouldn't take it to be a rabbit at first glance...
Her hands probably came apart while she was being moved...
Well, there's no use playing innocent.
If you left that big a wound on the victim's back, you must've ended up with a lot of blood splatter on you.
It looks like you changed and tried to wash it off, but it's not so easy to remove...
The blood's reaction to luminol!
Then why didn't we just take those three to the station from the start and test for that?
If we'd done that, it would've taken too long and delayed our search for the children!
O-Oh, right.
It was you, wasn't it?
My friends spotted you burying the corpse, and you chased them.
I-It wasn't me...
You're still denying it?!
It wasn't my fault, it was hers!
Shutting me in a place like that as a prank...
She's the one who wronged me!
Even though I loved her...
Even though I proposed to her...
She went and did something like that...
Umm, what's this about shutting you in?
I'm claustrophobic.
Three years ago, I was shut inside a lift for a whole day due to an accident...
Since then, whenever I'm closed up in a dark place, I panic...
But knowing that, she still attempted to shut me in!
In a pitch-black cabin where even the windows wouldn't open!
Then it was the victim who brought you up here?
Yes... Naturally, I panicked, and started swinging around the cabin axe to try and escape somehow...
and it ended up going into her back by accident!
Right...
If she hadn't pulled that prank,
then those children wouldn't have been shut in there either...
Shut in inside that mountain cabin?!
Yeah.
It's probably too late to save them, though.
Don't tell me he shut them in the cabin and set it on fire?!
Inspector Yamamura!
The search party reports that they've discovered a burning cabin!
D-Did they manage to put it out?
By the time they discovered the cabin, it was burning so fiercely that there was nothing they could do...
Hey, you two!
T-This can't be happening...
Goddamn it!
You can't, stay back!
Let me go! My friends are inside!
Let me go!
Genta! Mitsuhiko!
Haibara! Ayumi!
Here!
We're over here, Conan-kun!
We're fine!
Y-You guys...!
How'd you get out?
Some lady we'd never seen before suddenly appeared and rescued us!
She chopped the door down with the axe!
It seems she'd been living in the attic of the mountain cabin...
What about Ai-kun?
That woman said she rescued her first, and let her run away to a safe place.
And we just got a phone call from Haibara-san, so we know she's safe!
Don't tell me she took the antidote...
Where did that woman go?
She told us to hide until you guys came, and went off over that way...
You guys wait here!
We would like for the children come with us for police questioning...
They might have inhaled the smoke. They should see a doctor first!
Then if they could come to the station afterwards...
Hey, guys...
Do you remember what kind of person that woman was?
She was beautiful!
She kinda looked like Haibara...
That's why I secretly took a video of her and sent it!
Sent a video...?
Yeah!
We want to thank her properly later, so we sent it to the Mouri Detective Agency to find out who she is.
We'd promised to send him photos from the camping trip, after all.
See, here she is!
But I think we'll see her next week even if we don't look for her...
Because she...
Haibara! Where are you?
Haibara!
You're late!
I believed a certain someone would save us and waited, but...
I never thought I'd have to take the antidote and turn back to my old self.
How'd you get those clothes?
I borrowed some of the dead woman's clothes from the cabin.
I wasn't about to show up naked in front of the kids...
Well, I wasn't able to pull off this ring as my body had grown,
but I changed all of my clothes, so I'm sure the kids couldn't tell I was Ai Haibara.
Then you better hide in a tent or somewhere until the drug wears off.
They'll all be going for police questioning anyway...
Either way, you caught the killer, right?
Yeah, he was a photographer.
We figured it out from her dying message.
He said she locked him in that cabin even though he was claustrophobic.
I see... That fits perfectly then.
The rucksack with her clothes in had a book about claustrophobia in it...
She probably planned to help him get over his phobia by having him spend a night in that cabin with her...
But that ended up backfiring...
It made him panic, and he ended up killing her...
Talk about an unwelcome favour...
He could've lived fine even without overcoming his fear like that.
Maybe it was because he was a photographer...
If he kept using film cameras...
Not being able to enter naturally dark and cramped darkrooms would have been a lethal blow...
She wanted to hurry him to being his former self again...
But didn't she leave evidence saying that he was the killer?
That shows that she held a grudge!
No...
Thinking about it now, it wasn't really a dying message...
She just wanted to hold close to her in her final moments...
The shape of her beloved Usagi...
So those brats are spending tonight at an inn in Gunma, huh?
Yeah. Apparently they're still scared of staying at the campsite...
Those brats sure get caught up in a lot of cases...
Huh? I just heard some noise downstairs...
It's just the wind... it's been pretty strong today.
A password...
How do you two usually come up with passwords?
I use my birth date.
I'd use 5563 since it can be read 'Ko-go-rō-san'.
N-No, that's not what I meant...
What if it's a really long password that you can't memorise?
5-5-6-3...
A video was delivered instead of photos?
Okay?
So until your friends come, hide and don't make a sound!
A Mystery Train Pass Ring?
The Bell Tree Express, huh?
It's being hacked?!
Who is it?!