'Mystery Train'?
The Bell Tree Express, huh?
Never thought Sherry would ride such a ridiculously conspicuous train like that...
Oh, but isn't it a fitting choice for her?
Every room on that train is private.
If she's trying to escape from the Kantō region without us noticing, it would be a perfect way, don't you agree?
But I just can't believe it.
I never expected that Sherry was hiding out in the Gunma mountains.
Yeah. Bourbon, who discovered that information, had the same opinion...
He said that since it's just something she happened to tell a third party she came into contact with, it's not necessarily accurate...
But if Sherry is riding on that train,
wouldn't it be the best hunting ground?
Yeah. With nary a stop to disembark midway,
it's a moving steel prison.
And just like hunting a deer, if we just shake her with fear,
she'll likely expose herself to the barrel of the gun...
You know why I deliberately leaked this information to you, right?
You want me to keep my distance until that metal snake has returned to its hole, right?
Anyway, I'm happy to hear the name 'Sherry' from you after so long...
I was beginning to think you were showing mercy for a fellow woman...
That's ridiculous.
Just who do you take me for?
Anyway, let's talk again once the hunt is over.
Yeah...
Fine.
You win.
I'll give up on Sherry.
Though...
It won't be me who finishes her off, but Bourbon.
She mustn't be allowed to remain in this world...
Forgive me...
Silver Bullet.
Seeking comprehensive answers, he solves every mystery and code!
As the departure bell rings out, the shadows of the Organisation approach Haibara!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Tōkyō Station
Wow, it's awesome!
It's the first time I've seen a steam locomotive!
Me too!
It's so impressive!
Although, the SL appearance is just a front.
Inside it is a state-of-the-art diesel engine, I hear.
Ai-chan, you're still not better?
No...
Somebody's germs are pretty stubborn...
Then why aren't you staying at home and resting?
Hey, you brats!
You could at least show thanks for the owners of the Bell Tree Express, the Suzuki Financial Group!
We specially reserved seats just for you!
Yes, ma'am!
Of course, unlike yours, our seats are in the luxurious first-class car!
Speaking of which, isn't that the same first-class car that Kid announced he'd target soon?
That's right!
As a rule, this train only runs once a year,
but this year, Uncle Jirokichi's going to run it specially one more time to exhibit some jewel in the first-class car
and Kid-sama's sure to ride it!
So I decided I'd be a step ahead of him and leave a love letter to him in the train car! What do you think?
What do I think...?
I doubt Kid would have time to steal a letter as well.
Besides, Kyōgoku-san would be pretty upset.
My love for Kid-sama has nothing to do with my love for him!
What I'm interested in isn't any thief...
but the deduction quiz they always do aboard the train!
Sera-san, why...
are you here?
I'm a detective! Of course I'm here!
Wait, isn't your dad with you?
Huh? He was right here a moment ago...
Good to see you, Andō-sama!
It's been a long time.
May I take your luggage?
Don't worry about this.
It's a valuable item my client entrusted me with, and it's quite heavy.
Satoru Andō (41)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room C
Well, the heavy part is the solid-gold picture frame.
The painting's just a counterfeit.
The appraiser had finished with it, so I'm escorting it back to my client in Nagoya...
What? But this is the Mystery Train, destination unknown.
Why would you think it's headed to Nagoya?
Come on...
Mr. Conductor... How many years have we been meeting like this?
Taisaku Noto (52)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room A
Mari Idemari (33)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room E
Anyone can easily deduce that by checking which trains have had their schedules changed today.
R-Right...
The crux of what stimulates our intellect
Natsue Komino (75)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room D
is the mystery acted out on board this train...
Isn't that right, Sumitomo-san?
Hiruka Sumitomo (37)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room D
Yes, Mistress...
I should've expected no less from mystery connoisseurs like yourselves.
I underestimated you.
Hey, you!
What's going on here?!
Etsuto Murobashi (39)
Passenger in Carriage 7, Room B
I know I reserved my usual room on the first-class car, Carriage 8...
So why'd I get moved to Carriage 7?!
I do apologise.
As we mentioned a few days back, we had accidentally double-booked the room, so we had to move you.
That's my favourite room, and I book it every single year the moment tickets go on sale...
Where's the jackass who muscled in on my room?!
I'm the 'jackass' in question.
Please excuse me...
You see, my daughter is a friend of the owners of this train.
Kogorō Mouri (38)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room B
Anyway, you can be assured that with me on board, no matter what case awaits aboard this train,
I, the great detective Poirō Mouri,
shall instantly bring the truth to light!
Hey, Dad! What are you doing?!
I'm just saying hello to my fellow Carriage 8 passengers...
You're not allowed to smoke here!
And what's this 'Poirō' thing about?
You're Kogorō Mouri!
Oh, you heard that?
Come on, everybody's waiting for you in front of Carriage 6!
They want to take a group photo before we depart!
Oh, I see...
What's with this tense atmosphere?
Is it because they realised the old man's a detective, or perhaps...?
Awesome, awesome!
All the stations are just flying past!
It's supposed to be almost nonstop until we reach the destination!
Really?!
Of course, where the final stop is located is a mystery.
It's Nagoya...
If you look up the train schedules on the Internet,
you can figure out this train's route...
I was so excited to get on a Mystery Train, and this guy goes and ruins it...
What I'm interested in is the deduction quiz that's gonna take place aboard the train in the meantime.
The rumour goes that a culprit and victim are picked from the passengers at random, and an incident occurs between them...
The rest of the passengers become detectives,
with the goal being to figure out the culprit before the train reaches its destination.
Yes? Who is it?
Huh?
Nobody's here...
A letter?
'Congratulations, you've been selected to play the role of the detective!'
'In 10 minutes, an incident will take place in Carriage 7, Room B, so please investigate!'
Weren't all the passengers supposed to be the detectives?
Carriage 7, Room B... Carriage 7, Room B...
Here! It's this room, right?
Umm...
Excuse me...
Don't come in, moron!
Whoa, awesome! It's just like the real thing!
Let's go after them!
Yeah!
Come on! You too, Conan-kun and Ai-chan!
This isn't much of a mystery...
It's more like a game of tag...
We lost them...
All the rooms are private, so we can't tell if they went into one of the rooms...
You guys...
Is this your first time on this train?
Yeah!
In that case, you better stay in your rooms.
The deduction quiz will be announced via the speakers in each room.
So the case hasn't started at all yet?
Right...
It won't start for another hour, I believe...
Then what did we just witness...?!
Hey, Conan!
Wait!
Ai-chan, let's go!
Okay, okay.
Ai-chan?
Ai-chan, come on!
R-Right...
Could it be... Could it be...?!
Oh, Conan-kun. Something wrong?
You should at least knock before you enter a lady's room, you know!
Oh, no...
This is Carriage 7, right?
What are you talking about? This is Carriage 8.
I've just come here to visit!
That's strange...
I don't think I miscounted the carriages...
It can't be helped.
The carriage numbers are only written on the outside of the train.
And the only thing displayed on the room doors is a single alphabetic letter.
So how'd you do on the deduction quiz?
Doc?
Is this room, our room, on Carriage 6?!
Huh? Yeah.
See, the snacks you all were just eating are right where you left them!
Hey, Conan!
Isn't that weird?!
We only moved down one carriage from Carriage 8...
Carriage 7...
Carriage 7 disappeared while the train was in motion?!
Carriage 7 disappeared? That's ridiculous.
There was a guy who just got shot in Carriage 7...
We chased the culprit who shot him after they flew from the room, but we lost 'em...
And when we went back to Carriage 7 where the passenger who got shot was, it was Carriage 8!
Shot?
If that were the case, why didn't you immediately tell that to one of us conductors?
At the time, we thought it was part of the deduction quiz!
Anyway, please check at least!
Carriage 7 disappeared!
Along with the passenger who was shot!
Then you should ask the conductor in each carriage.
They'll be sitting in the rearmost part of the hallway in each passenger car, like I am...
But I'm sure you all just got the wrong idea...
In compliance with the owner's specifications, the carriage numbers aren't displayed inside the train...
The owner's specifications?
Though it means that many passengers can't tell which room is theirs, and it's a lot of work for us conductors...
Yes, how may I be of assistance?
So if you ring the bell like that, the lamp above the room lights up and the conductor will come, huh?
Awesome! I wanna try it later!
Anyway, the missing Carriage 7 comes first!
Let's go check!
Yeah!
Ai-chan, aren't you feeling well from the cold?
Ah, I'm fine. I've been taking medicine...
Then let's go!
That man earlier... I got a similar feeling to that person.
But what was that burn?
Carriage 7?!
This is really Carriage 7?
Yes...
Carriage 7 must have reappeared while we were distracted!
But how?
Then let's go to Room B again and take a look!
Yeah.
I'm opening it.
Okay.
Huh?
Uh, um... Is this really...
Didn't I tell you? It's Carriage 8!
Brats like you should just go back to your room and stay out of trouble, sheesh!
I wonder what's going on?
Maybe that conductor got confused?
Maybe. He looks pretty sleepy to me...
Hold on. Hold on... Last time...
That was...?!
Now, look here!
This room...
It really is Carriage 7, Room B...
...right?
I told you...
Sonoko-neechan, you guys got one too, right?
A card just like this!
And you were doing what the card said, right?
To temporarily switch rooms with the person playing the victim role
and confuse the detectives that would come to visit.
Right?
Amazing! You're amazing, Conan-kun!
You got it!
Someone knocked on our door and when we opened it, there was an envelope on the ground, and the card inside it said...
'Congratulations! You've been chosen to play the role of the accomplice!'
And the rest was just as you said...
'The guest playing the role of the victim in Carriage 7, Room B was waiting,
so switch with them to help enliven the deduction quiz!'
Shouldn't I be the one getting angry?
And just as the passenger who was playing the victim role and Ran-kun's party were switching,
I passed through and joined them.
So the person who played the victim role is probably relaxing in our room in Carriage 8 now...
Then where's Uncle Kogorō?
The victim guy told him to go to the dining car!
To the dining car?
He wanted Dad to play the role of the detective who explained the answer to the deduction quiz at the end...
So he asked Dad to stand by in the dining car...
Anyway, it's nice to meet you finally.
You're that girl named 'Haibara', right?
Yeah...
I've wanted to talk with you...
S-She...
It can't be...
It can't be!
Who's there?
W-What?
Just now, I thought someone was peering in through the crack in the door...
Did I imagine it?
Oh, the cuisine and wine are both excellent!
Burning off the fields...?
You figured out the disappearing corpse trick?
We haven't released the deduction quiz for this journey yet...
But I got this card!
We did too!
Let's see...
They do look like the instruction cards we usually use, but...
The trick for this journey wasn't anything like that...
So what's going on?
Well then, I guess we'll have to go to Carriage 8 and ask the victim ourselves, huh?
I'm going to the toilet first!
Me too!
What's wrong, Haibara?
Don't you feel a strange presence in this train?
Like a menacing feeling...
That's just you having read too many of Christie's novels...
This presence... isn't just one or two people.
Noto-sama, how may I be of assistance?
Noto-sama? Noto-sama?
What's goin' on?!
I didn't call for you!
But the bell just...
Dunno about that.
Geez, when I call for you, no one comes.
But when I don't need you, you come.
Ah, it's fine.
There was some kind of trouble in the room next door, but it looks like the conductor just made a mistake.
Ah! Coming!
Idenami-sama!
Hey, can't you do something about this?!
Something about...?
The sound!
There's a strange sound in my room!
I don't hear anything.
It was just sounding earlier!
Are you calling me a liar?!
Oh, of course not.
See, this sound. You hear it, right?
Yes.
It's probably a mobile phone or similar that someone left behind.
Wait, don't come in! I'll find it myself!
R-Right...
What I want to know is,
Why didn't you find the mobile phone before the train set off?!
Right, I'm very sorry.
Umm, is something wrong?
Here it is! This is our room!
Hey, mister!
The trick's been found out!
Come out and explain!
Oh, sheesh. Don't tell me he's sleeping in our room.
No way...
Mister! Wake up and undo the chain lock!
Hey, Mister!
What's wrong?
He's taking a nap on our sofa!
There's blood coming from his forehead, it almost looks like he's really dead.
Well, I'm sure it's just some sort of deduction quiz clue again.
Let me through!
It smells like...
Gunpowder...
Anyway, let's break down the door!
One, two, three!
Awesome!
Another deduction quiz?
No...
He really is dead...
What's more...
This is a locked-room murder!
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
I shall unveil the truth of this murder on the Bell Tree Express for all to see!
I just heard from Vermouth. She confirmed that Sherry's aboard the train.
What should I do...
If the Organisation really have come for me, aboard this train...
Then I can't...
On the next Conan: 'The Jet-Black Mystery Train (Tunnel)'!
Next Conan's Hint: The Conductor's Testimony!
Locked rooms!
Building blocks!
Balloons!
Eel!
Careful investigation!
Locked rooms!
Aren't they great?!