Together with the Detective Boys, Ran and company, I boarded the Bell Tree Express...
The suspicious passengers gathered in Carriage 8...
The black shadow closing in on Haibara...
And then, the deduction quiz taking place aboard the train unexpectedly turned into a sealed room murder.
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A sealed room murder and a vanished carriage.
The suspicious testimony of the passengers!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
M-Murder?!
It's really murder?
Yeah.
Somebody shot this guy in the head.
But the door was chain-locked, and you had to break through the lock to get in, right?
So wouldn't this be a suicide?
I haven't figured out how the door was locked yet.
But there's no burn mark around the gunshot wound.
That proves he was shot from a distance.
Since if you were shooting yourself in the head, you'd have to hold the gun right next to you...
But maybe he got scared right before shooting, and pulled it away unintentionally?
I don't think so.
There's a silencer attached to the gun, right?
Do you really think it's possible to hold something that long at a distance from your head and still fire it?
And look, on the sofa opposite, there's a mark from something like a gunshot.
The killer probably made the victim hold the gun and shoot an extra round,
in order to leave gunshot residue on their hand and sleeve, to make it look like suicide.
Of course, gunshot residue would've landed on the killer too,
but they probably washed it off their hands, and threw their clothes out of the window...
But the killer must still be on this train. They won't get away!
Anyway, you guys go back to your room with Ran-neechan for now.
But we want to help out, too!
Me too!
Don't be reckless!
Until I come back, lock your room door and don't open it for anyone at all!
What's with you, all of a sudden...?
You're scary sometimes...
Uhh, I mean...
Isn't it dangerous since there's a murderer lurking around?
Then I'm counting on you to take care of the kids.
Right.
Gotcha.
I should call Dad and have him come here, just in case.
Excuse me...
What's the commotion about?
Don't tell me the deduction quiz already started!
Ah, no, it's not the quiz.
There was a real murder!
An actual murder?!
How dreadful...
I can't deal with an actual murder.
Too gory for my taste.
Anyway, stop the train and tell the passengers not to leave their rooms until the police arrive!
Right!
May I have your attention, please...
In light of an accident that just took place on the train,
we are considering changing our course and stopping at the nearest station.
We apologise for the inconvenience,
but please remain in your rooms until further notice, and refrain from leaving them if at all possible.
The ominous feeling I felt before hasn't gone away...
And his attitude back then...
What was that about?!
Huh?
You're on this train too, Amuro-san?
Yes, I managed to get myself a ticket.
I just met Mouri-sensei at the dining car, too.
Hey, Ran, who's the hot guy?
He's the detective I told you about the other day, the one who wanted to be Dad's apprentice.
This is him?
Nice to meet you, I'm Sonoko Suzuki!
A pleasure...
Anyway, it seems some sort of accident happened. Do you know anything about it?
It seems there's been a murder.
Sera-san and Conan-kun are still at the scene.
Then it might be wise to have Mouri-sensei handle this.
It appears that the heavens are siding with us.
What?! You're not gonna stop until you reach Nagoya?!
Didn't I ask you to stop at the nearest station?!
W-Well...
The owner of the train, Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki said...
'Tie the scurvy jackanapes who dared to kill a man in my train up and bring them here to me!'
and so, he's waiting to ambush the killer at Nagoya...
Just how much power does that geezer have?
Well, no need to worry.
Before we reach Nagoya Station, I, the great detective Poirō Mouri,
shall unveil the truth of this murder on the Bell Tree Express for all to see!
Indeed! I'm counting on you!
So, Mr. Conductor,
when did you last see the victim, Murobashi-san?
When I was in front of Room A, Noto-sama's room.
I heard the bell ring, so I went to Room A,
only to be scolded by Noto-sama, saying he hadn't called me.
At the same time, Murobashi-sama opened the door of Room B and peeked out at me.
Was that really Murobashi-san?
Yeah. He seemed to be on the phone...
Then how about we ask Noto-san about this, 'Poirō-san'?
Very well!
Yeah. I heard Murobashi-san's voice from beyond the door as well back then...
I never thought he'd be next door, I was quite surprised.
Taisaku Noto (52)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room A
Still, why did you lie about having rung the bell and say you hadn't?
Like I said, I never rang the bell, the conductor came on his own!
But when you ring the bell, the light above the door comes on, so I doubt he'd have made a mistake...
Actually, though the rest work, Room A's light is burnt out.
So when I heard a bell ring and didn't see any of the lights on,
I thought it must've been Noto-sama's room, so I knocked on his door.
And after that?
Just after the doors to rooms A and B shut, a bell rang,
I saw the light for Idenami-sama's room, Room E, was lit and went to check it out.
Yeah.
I did ring the bell to call the conductor.
I was hearing strange noises in my room.
Mari Idenami (33)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room E
They turned out to be this wristwatch's alarm.
I found it stuck down the back of the sofa!
It must've been left behind by someone, maybe one of the cleaners.
W-Well...
If you called to have the conductor search your room,
then that may be the time the killer entered the victim's room,
since the conductor wouldn't be watching over the passageway as usual...
Search my room?!
I only called him here to complain!
I found this thing myself!
I can't stand the thought of others invading my territory.
Then even though you were in the passageway the whole time, you didn't see anyone suspicious enter the victim's Room B, Mr. Conductor?
That reminds me...
When I was listening to Idenami-sama, the door to the room farthest to me opened.
And I had the feeling somebody was peeping over here from beyond the door...
The farthest room from you would be Room A...
Just before I spotted that suspicious person,
Komino-sama was wheeled out of Room D by her maid and headed in that direction.
So those two might've seen something.
Komino-san, huh?
The Room A door?
Natsue Komino (75)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room D
That door wasn't open
when I passed by.
And of course, I didn't see anyone suspicious standing by the door.
Right, Sumitomo-san?
Yes, Mistress.
The only open door was the one to Room E, from which we heard Idenami-sama complaining.
Hiruka Sumitomo (37)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room D
Then maybe it opened after Komino-sama passed by...
But we passed by the two ladies at the entrance to Carriage 8 when we were heading to Room B,
and we didn't see the Room A door open either.
Did it really open?
Come to think about it...
Just before the kids came over, Andō-sama from Room C came over to check on things,
so maybe...
I could hear Idenami-san shouting even in my room,
Satoru Andō (41)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room C
so I left my room to find out what was going on. I thought something might've happened.
But I can't say whether the door to Room A was open or not, since I went in the opposite direction, to Room E.
Not to mention that at the time, the train was passing through a tunnel, so there wasn't any light shining through the windows,
and the passageway was pretty dark.
That's right, it was dark.
Didn't you see anything?
You arrived just after I left my room, right?
No, we didn't see anything.
By the way, you Carriage 8 passengers all seem to be quite sure of each other's names and rooms.
You know each other?
Yeah, more or less.
We board the Mystery Train together every year.
They're our regular guests who always make reservations in this first-class car before anybody else, every year.
And they always choose the same rooms, too.
So basically...
Mr. Conductor, it was all in your imagination, wasn't it?
No! I'm confident I saw it...
I see, that's how it was.
You were the one who secretly let the killer into Room B!
You said it was a sealed room, but there's actually some sort of hidden door leading to the next room, right?!
There's nothing like that in this train!
So you gathered all the passengers from rooms A, C, D and E into room B
and they each fired a bullet into the victim's body, one by one!
Am I wrong?
What are you talking about?!
That's how I would've written it!
That's insane!
Isn't that the plot of Orient Express?
And for starters, the victim was only shot once in total...
You sent it to the Mouri Detective Agency?
The footage from the camp trip last week?
Yes. We want to properly thank the lady who saved us, so we figured a great detective might be able to find out who she was.
Oh, I watched that video along with Dad.
He said there's no way to find someone with just a face and voice,
but if we posted it online, maybe someone would recognise her.
That lady had a Mystery Train Pass Ring,
so we'd all been saying we might see her here!
Haven't seen her yet, though.
Don't tell me...
The reason for this ominous feeling in my chest...
Don't tell me that they've...!
Heed my command, troops!
Breach the train the moment it arrives,
bind the confounded murderer hand and foot with lightning speed and bring them forth to me!
Why won't you answer?! Why?!
Advisor Suzuki, please stop giving my subordinates orders without permission.
Allow us Aichi Police to handle this...
What?!
bell tree
The train crowned with my surname, Suzuki, became a murder site!
You dare to tell me to just sit and wait, you fool?!
Upon capturing the miscreant, hang high the head of our filthy quarry on the central tower of Nagoya Castle!
That's too much...
Sounds like some sort of petty killing took place.
It seems fortune is smiling upon us, Bro.
Right.
It's sending that iron snake right here non-stop.
And I just heard from Vermouth. She confirmed that Sherry's aboard the train.
Then Vermouth and Bourbon will be dealing with her about now.
I don't care whether they decided to ice or capture her.
The question was whether she was inside that snake's stomach or not.
But if you've already been swallowed by the snake, Sherry,
then Nagoya shall be your final stop...
Anyway...
So the room of the deceased, Murobashi-san, was chain-locked shut,
and our conductor here never left the passageway at the time, and he didn't see anyone suspicious entering or leaving it.
Isn't it obvious it was a suicide?
But there weren't any burn marks around the bullet wound in his head.
There was a gunshot mark on the sofa opposite, too.
Everybody aboard this train's a mystery fan.
If he was planning to die, then he probably left red herrings to make it look like a murder, to make his death into a mystery.
I see.
You really are the amazing Sleeping Kogorō!
For today, please call me 'Poirō'!
Still, that Murobashi guy swapped rooms with Ran-kun, and seemed really eager to help with the whole mystery quiz thing.
I can't imagine somebody like that committing suicide.
And it seems the cue card for the mystery quiz was fake, too.
Yeah...
Congratulations!
You've been selected to play
the role of the detective!
In 10 minutes, an incident will
take place in Carriage 7, Room B,
so please investigate!
Though it looks like our usual cue cards, the contents don't match with the trick we were expecting...
I thought so...
Somebody moved Murobashi-san to the first-class carriage for some reason.
Was it because the old man took over the first-class Room B, which Murobashi-san usually reserved for himself...?
Which means it's a trick that can only be done in this carriage?
Hey, is there anything special about this carriage?
Anything special?
Rooms A to E always have the same people booking into them year after year, right?
The Bell Tree Express was finished five years ago,
but I heard that this first class carriage was created on special request by a wealthy friend of Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki.
Apparently, that friend was a huge fan of the Orient Express,
and the rooms in this carriage were made especially large so a family could comfortably fit in one.
Then, are any of the passengers here part of that magnate's family?
No...
Almost all of the family died in a large fire a month before the maiden trip.
Only one member of the family is aboard...
Who is it?!
Komino-sama in Room D.
If I recall correctly, she was the aunt of the magnate who died.
That case is on the Internet...
A fire broke out during the magnate's birthday party, and said magnate's family died along with twelve other attendees.
The only survivors were Komino-san, who was just mentioned, her maid Sumitomo-san, and four other attendees.
Could those four attendees now be the other passengers?
The cause of the fire was put down to a problem with an electric cable, but no clear reason was found.
If our murder here is a revenge drama connected to the fire in some way,
then this is looking more and more like the Murder on the Orient Express!
Let's go talk to those passengers again!
Hey, speaking of electricity, why didn't you change the dead light bulb over Room A?
Beyond the first-class carriage is the luggage car, and we usually keep spare bulbs there, but today we couldn't find any.
So the people making all the final checks before departing are the conductors, right?
Yeah.
Two or three of us go around the rooms, making sure the water works and so on.
Actually, I heard a conductor's uniform went missing, too.
You worried about something?
Ah, no. I was looking at the article on the fire too, but haven't worked out anything yet...
Well then, keep going.
Our opponent's probably sweating, anyway.
Since on a train running at 80 km/h, there's no way to escape!
Y-Yeah...
What should I do...
If...
If the Organisation really have come for me, aboard this train...
Then I can't...
I can't stay here anymore...
An e-mail?
I don't know the address...
Who is it?
'Are you ready?'
Vermouth...
Haibara-san?
You got an e-mail?
Who's it from?
Is it from Conan?
No.
It's just spam...
Ai-kun, where are you going?
The toilet.
I'm going to take some medicine for my cold, so I might be a while.
Then I'll go with her...
Leave her alone, you'll just get on her nerves.
But earlier, when we were coming back here, she was clinging onto the hem of my shirt the whole time...
I think she's worried about something...
So I want to be by her side.
Huh?
Ai-chan?
Where are you?
Okay, so until your 19th birthday,
bye-bye...
Oh, maybe it's about time I told you...
The truth is, your mother's making a terrifying drug, right now.
My lab mates are getting all hyped up about it, like it's a dream drug.
Your dad and I are putting our hopes on it and calling it...
'Silver Bullet'.
But to finish this drug, your dad and I will have to leave you and your sister.
Please understand, Shiho.
I'm sorry, Mum.
I didn't understand...
...that this drug was something that shouldn't be made...
But in order to avoid getting other people involved,
I have no choice but to rely on it now.
Just like your sister, I can read all your moves...
Now, would you step this way...
...into our area?
No...
Not now...
I can't be killed looking like this!
The tools for the sealed room trick are in there, aren't they?
Mister, can I record a video of you running?
Your maid's quite fast when she runs. Did she use to play sports?
That wristwatch you found in your room...
Has it rung again since?
When we found Murobashi-san's corpse, I could see it, right?
On the next Conan: 'The Jet-Black Mystery Train (Intersection)'!
Next Conan's Hint: The gap of the chain lock!
unajū
Eel, eel, eel!
Don't tell me that's...
One-man Shiritori!
Come on...