Together with the Detective Boys, Ran and company,
I boarded the Bell Tree Express.
Suspicious passengers gathered in Carriage 8...
And then, the deduction quiz taking place aboard the train
unexpectedly turned into a locked room murder.
Meanwhile, the black shadow of the Organization
continued to close in on Haibara.
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A suspicious person and a bizarre trick!
Fate closes in on the unstoppable train!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A fire from five years ago?
What do I have to do with that?
Don't bother playing dumb.
I just checked with the Shizuoka Police, who handled the case.
Your name was on the list of survivors.
Isn't that right, former Self-Defence Force member and sparring partner of the dead magnate, Taisaku Noto-san?
R-Right...
Taisaku Noto (52)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room A
I got this scar on my cheek
from that incident.
It's not like I was hiding it.
Come to think of it,
you were carrying something on your shoulder when we first met, weren't you?
The tools for the locked room trick are in there, aren't they?
That was just my shinai.
Shinai?
See, just shinai.
I promised I'd spar with a friend in Nagoya when I get there.
So if you don't need anything else—
Then, mister...
Would you mind running along the corridor for us?
Run?
Yeah.
We might've seen the killer running away from us.
So could I record a video of you running, mister?
Yes, I'm the same Andō who was rescued from that fire along with Murobashi-san.
Satoru Andō (41)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room C
I would've told you earlier had you asked.
By the way, what's that big black bag in your room?
That's a painting I was asked to analyse.
But unfortunately, it turned out to be a fake.
Would you mind if we took a look?
S-Sure.
It's pretty heavy.
The forgery is solid gold.
Solid gold, I see...
By the way, what was your relationship with the magnate?
The magnate was a famous art collector, and he used to show me his wide range of paintings,
though almost all of them burnt up in the fire.
You must be pretty strong for an old man to carry something so heavy all on your own.
I suppose.
Then could you try running down the corridor?
Right, I'll never be able to forget that fire.
It's thanks to that fire that I now depend on this wheelchair.
Natsue Komino (75)
Carriage 8, Room D
Hiruka Sumitomo (37)
So you injured your legs in the fire?
Right.
So I won't be running down the corridor like the others.
But your maid, Sumitomo-san, can run, right?
So I just have to run?
Yeah, just run normally.
I can't see how you're gonna figure out who the killer is from this...
Hey, granny.
Your maid's quite fast when she runs. Has she ever played sports?
Hey, answer me, granny.
Mari Idenami (33)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room E
Yes, I was the fiancée of the dead magnate's grandson,
and yes, I was rescued from the fire,
but why do I have to show you how I run down a corridor?!
Well, it's just to check something...
Anyway, could you remove the chain-lock and let us in?
If you want to come in, bring a search warrant!
That's insane...
Then, about that wristwatch you found in your room... Has it rung again since?
Wristwatch?
As you can see, I left it out, but it hasn't rung again.
Where?
Look, over there on the sofa.
We can't see it through the gap...
Huh? Hold on...
When we found Murobashi-san's corpse, I could see it, right?
Through the gap in the door, I could see a bullet mark on the sofa opposite.
Well, we even got Idenami-san to run down the corridor in the end.
But is there any actual meaning behind this?
Anyway, let's show the videos we recorded to the kids.
Yeah.
Hey, kid, you listening?
Hey!
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?!
You haven't changed a bit...
Masumi...
S-Shū-nii...
Shū-nii?
Is it really you?
But how? I thought you were dead!
That's the answer I wanted to hear.
Is something wrong?
Don't worry.
My sister's just a little anemic.
I see.
What is it?
Calling us out into the corridor like this...
Did you figure out anything?
Ah, no, the investigation's still in the works...
But that boy brought us from our rooms.
He said Sleeping Kogorō's deduction show was starting.
But Uncle Kogorō, weren't you saying earlier that you knew how the plot went?
That was metaphorical, you moron!
That's it! It's Sleeping Kogorō!
If Mouri-sensei's in that pose, then he solved the case, right?
You figured out the truth behind the murder in this first-class carriage's locked Room B.
Who are you?
Sorry for not introducing myself.
I'm Mouri-sensei's number one apprentice, Amuro.
Ai-kun's missing?
Yeah.
I even checked the toilets in the other carriages nearby.
It's an e-mail from Ai-chan.
"I'm fine, so don't worry about me."
That is Ai-kun's e-mail address...
Maybe she's with Conan-kun?
That's gotta be it.
I wish we were there, too.
Then why don't you just get up and go?
Right, the locked room murder...
I solved that mystery the second time I went to Idenami-san's Room E.
Wait, what? Are you saying I'm the killer?
I realized it when I looked into your room past the chain-locked door.
With the chain lock on, no matter how much you try, there was one sofa you could hardly see.
But when Conan found Murobashi-san's body in Room B,
he could clearly see the right-hand sofa, even with the chain lock on.
Maybe the kid misremembered?
The reason for that...
was likely that there was one extra link in the chain lock, compared to the other rooms.
The gap would be wider,
and you'd be able to see more of the room from outside.
Is that a problem?
It's a big problem.
A chain lock is normally set to a length that just barely keeps people from disengaging it even if they fit their hand in.
So by adding an extra link, it makes it possible to lock the door from the outside!
Hey, wait!
You can't go around checking the passenger list!
Sorry.
I thought I'd seen an old acquaintance on the train.
If it happens again, then please call for me.
Excuse me.
He's right, there are six!
There's five links in the other rooms' chains, but Room B has six!
So this is no longer a locked-room mystery.
But if somebody was loitering around the door, wouldn't the conductor notice?
Yeah...
And he said he was in the corridor the whole time.
Well, there was some stranger peering past a door at me...
Then who was it?
I couldn't make them out.
We'd just gone into a tunnel, so it was very dim.
Then it was probably the murderer, who then escaped into a different carriage.
It could be an outsider.
Nobody in our carriage would carry out a crime
with the risk of being recognized by a conductor who knows all of us waiting in the passageway.
But what if that risk could be removed with this little sound?
That's the room bell...
But who rang it?
It was me!
I just went into Room B, rang the bell, recorded the sound on my phone, and played it back.
Mr. Conductor, you heard the noise but didn't see a light come from any of the rooms,
so you went to Room A, right?
Yes.
The lightbulb above Room A had stopped working, so I thought it must be Noto-sama calling me.
So while Noto-san and the conductor were arguing in doorway to Room A,
Murobashi-san in Room B opened his door, right?
Y-Yes...
He was on the phone with someone.
I see. So that was the moment when the killer went into Room B.
The corridors on this train are narrow enough that opening a door blocks most of the passageway.
If Room B's door was open,
the conductor in front of Room A wouldn't be able to see the killer coming from the other way.
Yeah.
The killer probably called Murobashi-san and said
"There's some kind of disturbance outside the room. Has something happened?"
Also, this happened as we were going through the tunnel.
If the killer called Murobashi-san just before we entered the tunnel,
then the killer could go to Room B,
say that the call was cut off because of the tunnel, and ask to continue the conversation in his room.
But what were the killer and Murobashi-san talking about?
Probably about the deduction quiz that takes place aboard the Mystery Train.
The killer used fake cue cards to pretend that Murobashi-san had been picked as the victim, themselves as the murderer,
and my daughter and her friends as the accomplices.
The cards said that Murobashi-san should swap rooms with my daughter to create a vanishing corpse trick.
Of course, Murobashi-san should've been booked into Room B in the first-class car,
so the fake cue cards were just an emergency measure
and as a precaution, he picked the children to be the detectives.
That way, even if detectives arrived at Carriage 7, Room B, my daughter and her friends would delay them as part of their role as accomplices.
But the plot quickly fell through, and my daughter and the kids ended up coming back to Room B in this carriage, where the crime took place.
And then?
I understood how the killer moved Murobashi-san to Room B,
but when did they come out of the room?
Right.
If the killer quickly murdered Murobashi-san and then left immediately,
the conductor in front of Room A would've seen something!
But he didn't, which means the most suspicious person is whoever the conductor saw peering past a door.
What door was it?
The door at the other end of the corridor from me.
It was when I was in front of Room E, so I think it was Noto-sama's Room A.
Come on!
You can't say something like that without any proof!
I know exactly who you saw.
It's you...
Mr. Conductor!
I was the suspicious figure? The killer?!
No.
What you saw was yourself in front of Room E...
...in a mirror.
Exactly!
The killer covered the inner side of their door with a mirror,
and when the conductor was in front of Idenami-san's Room E,
they opened their door so they wouldn't be seen leaving Room B.
But if the killer was in Room B at the time,
then how would they open the door to their own room?
The killer attached fishing line to the doorknob and passed it through the handrail by the window.
They took it into Room B, waited for a good time, and then pulled on it to open the door.
Right.
This trick would be obvious if the position of the mirror was too close or too far from the other side of the carriage.
Therefore, it had to be the passenger in
Room C, in the middle of rooms A-B-C-D-E.
Andō-san, it could only be you!
That's strange...
I can't reach Ai-chan, Conan-kun, Dad or even Sera-san...
I wonder what happened?
I'll go check out the first-class car.
No, wait!
They seem to be in the middle of a deduction show right now, so we probably shouldn't disturb them.
A mirror?!
How on Earth could I bring a mirror large enough to cover a whole door into the train?!
The painting you said you were asked to analyse...
If you placed about three slides of
mirrored glass between the canvases,
you would have enough mirror to cover the door.
That painting was quite heavy...
But that's because the forgery's made of solid gold...
No, it's wood, covered in gold leaf.
It's the painting that's heavy.
And inside, just like Sensei said...
...there's three mirror pieces!
And seeing that one of them has a spot of paint in the same color as the door,
you must've prepared it so that the conductor wouldn't realize he was looking at a reflection.
If you'd left it as it was,
Room E's label would've been reflected too.
So, Andō-san...
How can you explain those three mirror pieces?
And please don't try to say
that they were put in before you were tasked with analyzing it, and you never noticed.
We can just ask the client who commissioned you to analyze it.
Assuming that such a person even exists.
My, isn't that going a bit far?
That was my favourite, you know.
The one-piece in that suitcase.
Isn't it about time you stopped doing this kind of thing?
Sharon?
How unexpected.
To think that kid would get his mother involved in our feud.
I put myself up for it.
I told him that if the opponent was a star of the silver screen,
then he better cast me, the legendary Japanese actress, too.
But I'm a bit disappointed.
I always thought you might someday teach me what
makeup you used to keep your aging face so radiant...
To think that the great actress Sharon Vineyard was nothing but some aging makeup!
It's actually pretty hard, you know.
Pretending that you're older than you really are.
Anyway, what you said back when we crossed paths in the passageway...
If we outwit you again, then this time, will you give up on her for good?
What was that supposed to mean?
Exactly what it says on the tin.
Because according to Shin-chan, Ai-chan's one of us now.
Don't be silly.
Do you really think you can beat us?
Don't you know? Shin-chan's team is actually a step ahead of you right now.
Ahead?
We already took that Sera girl you left sleeping in your room back to her own room.
You work quickly, don't you?
But that's strange... The boy's still going through his deduction show.
Do you have somebody else helping you?
Who knows?
We might have a special guest on our team!
Shū...
Shū-nii...
Your chances of winning...
...are huge!
Because Shin-chan got a hold of your weak point, Sharon.
Fire?
There's a fire!
I can't find Haibara anywhere!
Ai-chan!
On the next Conan: The Jet-Black Mystery Train (Destination)!
Next Conan's Hint: The Ultimate Cast!
Gin!
Vodka!
Bourbon!
What?!
That's the order that old man Mouri drank alcohol in!
What.