Together with the Detective Boys, Ran and company,
I boarded the Bell Tree Express.
Suspicious passengers gathered in Carriage 8.
And then, the deduction quiz taking place aboard the train
unexpectedly turned into a locked room murder.
Meanwhile, a black shadow closes in on Haibara.
And the identity of the man with a burn who kidnapped Sera is revealed...
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
Their trap throws the train into a panic!
Haibara's fate hangs in the balance!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
(Destination)
But Detective, some of your deductions are hard to believe...
It's not easy to add links to a chain lock.
Taisaku Noto (52)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room A
And if the lamp above my room had been working,
the conductor wouldn't have come to my room in the first place!
And I only called the conductor because the alarm rang on a watch that just happened to be left in my room!
Mari Idenami (33)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room E
Mr. Conductor, you said it yourself, earlier, right?
That one of the conductors' uniforms was missing.
Yes.
That was probably Andō-san's doing.
Satoru Andō (41)
Passenger in Carriage 8, Room C
If he wore that uniform and snuck aboard the train amidst the pre-boarding checks...
Then he could add a link to the chain lock of the crime scene,
replace the bulb for Noto-san's room with a broken one
and hide the watch in Idenami-san's room.
And if he remotely made the watch's alarm ring
while Idenami-san was arguing with the conductor to distract him,
then Andō-san, hiding in Room B,
wouldn't be noticed
using the fishing line to open the mirrored Room C door.
Then after locking Room B's chain lock under cover of the mirrored door,
then all he had to do was close the mirrored door as though he'd just come out of his room
and approach Idenami-san and the conductor.
This way, you managed to create a situation where though the conductor never left the corridor,
he never saw anyone going in or out of the crime scene!
Unluckily, just before you opened the mirrored door,
Komino-san and her maid left their room and could've discovered the fishing line,
but in the darkness of the tunnel, it probably slipped their notice.
At least, I hope they didn't just pretend not to know anything to avoid getting involved in the case.
But why did Andō-san kill Murobashi-san?
Weren't you two friends who escaped the fire together, five years ago?
Yes.
I thought so too, until two years ago,
when I saw a painting at an auction that should've been lost in that fire!
When I traced back the ownership of the painting, it eventually led back to Murobashi.
I see.
Murobashi-san stole the paintings from the mansion
and set it on fire to hide the theft, right?
Causing a lot of victims in the process.
Yes.
If he, like the rest of us, boarded this train in memory of the magnate's family and the others who died in the blaze,
then I was planning to just force him to confess.
But while we were waiting together as murderer and victim for the children playing the detectives in the fake mystery quiz,
he said this...
These things are so exciting!
They make you really feel alive!
Doesn't it remind you of that fire where we were trapped in the smoke and barely came out alive?
And he said it so joyfully, his face flushed in excitement!
To think my wife suffocated in that fire in front of me...
Yukiko...
You seem to want to cast a smokescreen over us,
but your chances of winning...
...are huge!
Because Shin-chan got a hold of your weak point, Sharon.
Could that weak point be something about you being my friend, and therefore, untouchable?
Your partners don't know, do they?
That Shin-chan and that girl were de-aged by that drug.
Despite the fact that if you narrow the search down to primary school age children, finding them would just be a matter of time...
Shin-chan told me...
...that there's probably a reason for you to hide that they became children again from the drug.
And then there's...
Suguru Itakura.
You know him, right?
That CG creator who we actresses all knew from his work in movie special effects.
I was shocked when Shin-chan told me that you'd ordered some kind of system from him.
I'd heard from my actor friends that you clashed with him on some film set and had been at each others' throats since.
Well, you being you, you probably changed your voice when talking to him over the phone.
But that system you put so much effort into ordering...
Does that have anything to do with why you're hiding their de-ageing?
That's enough, Yukiko.
Just give up!
I've already seen through your ridiculous plan!
P-Plan? What do you mean?
When she learns that we're on board the train, there's only one thing she'll do.
She'll take the antidote and go back to her normal body.
If she was killed as a child and found on board,
those children would cry and kick up a fuss.
But if she went back to her normal form,
even if they find her corpse,
then to the children, she'd just be a woman they once happened to meet.
They'd be more worried with finding their missing friend,
and would therefore be more likely to escape the Organisation's notice.
Of course, your son and that Dr. Agasa will know otherwise,
but they'd never dare say that the corpse was their friend, as she looked before she became a little girl.
Right. You must've predicted that's how she'd react,
and you were going to take her in before she took the antidote.
Then you would've disguised as her and appeared to die in front of us,
thus letting her escape the Organisation's eyes.
But the fact that she isn't in this room
means you haven't been able to take her in yet.
W-What are you talking about?
You looked into my suitcase before you threw it out, didn't you?
Did you see any disguise kit in there?
Sorry.
But I already got rid of it before I dealt with the suitcase.
The disguise kit you'd hidden in this washbasin,
as well as the bulletproof jacket set up to release fake blood.
B-But you haven't found her yet either, so you haven't won either...
No problem.
We've already made preparations to smoke her out.
Andō-san, let's leave the rest to the police.
Hey! What's all that smoke?
Hey, don't tell me...
I'll check.
Fire?!
There's a fire!
Everyone, we have to evacuate to the front of the train!
Wake up, Uncle!
You too, granny, hurry!
This is an emergency announcement!
A fire has been reported in Carriage 8!
For your safety, the passengers in Carriages 6 and 7 should evacuate to the carriages at the front of the train!
No way!
A fire?!
This is Carriage 6, isn't it?
Yeah.
Then we better escape!
Calm down, everyone! Don't run, there's nothing to worry about!
Just as we thought.
All the passengers in Carriage 8 are pyrophobic.
They've stirred the place into quite a panic!
Looks like it.
So here's the big question.
In this situation, where do you think she'll go?
She'll run to the front carriages, of course!
Nope. Just the opposite.
What she'll do, is most likely...
You really are Hell Angel's daughter.
You look just like her.
A pleasure to meet you.
My codename is 'Bourbon'.
Ah, Mouri-kun.
Dad! Where's Conan-kun and Sera-san?
The four-eyed brat was with me until just now.
But I thought that tomboy went back to you some time ago?
She's not with us.
Maybe she mistook which carriage she was in and got the wrong room...
Hey, Uncle?
Where's Ai-chan?
She went that way, right?
Isn't she with Conan-kun?
Isn't she with you?
She went to the toilet and never came back!
Then maybe she ran to a carriage further up?
That's what we thought, but we haven't been able to find her!
Gah, brats are all the same...
Right. Knowing her, she'd go straight to Carriage 8, the source of the fire.
She'll realise that the fire is a trap by us to draw her out.
I see! She thought you'd be waiting for her at the
front of the train, so she went to the back instead!
You don't get it at all.
Her friends will also be evacuating into the front carriages.
If she, who's being targeted, goes there,
they might end up getting involved.
That's why she'd decide to head into the fire instead.
Even if she knows we'll be waiting...
As she would prefer to die alone.
My phone...
Shin-chan...
Oh, what's wrong, Shin-chan?
Mum! We're in trouble!
I can't find Haibara anywhere!
Is she with you?!
No, she hasn't come to my room!
Maybe she evacuated to the front of the train?
It'd be easier to hide herself in a crowd.
Okay, I'll check the front.
Mum, you stick to the plan!
Okay!
With that, your son will also head to the front carriages.
And here's an e-mail from my partner.
Oh, I'm sorry,
but we seem to have found her in Carriage 8.
Looks like we win.
'Bourbon'.
Do you recall hearing this codename before?
I've met your family before.
Yes, I've heard of you.
You're a member of the Organisation, and the rival to my sister's boyfriend, Dai Moroboshi.
From what my sister told me, there was a lot of antipathy between you two.
Indeed.
Just as I suspected, he turned out to be an FBI dog.
I couldn't believe the reports that he'd been killed after betraying the Organisation.
So I disguised myself as him and wandered around people close to him, to watch their reactions.
But all I could figure out from that is that he really is dead.
Anyway, my partner who helped me make that disguise is the one who's now disguising as him in my place.
The fact that you've appeared before me shows how much she terrifies you.
Now, would you put your hands up and slowly walk backwards?
We'll go to the luggage car behind Carriage 8.
One hour until the Bell Tree Express arrives!
Get ready, everyone!
What a bunch of fools.
They have no idea that when the train arrives, they're gonna be blown to pieces by the bomb we've set on the platform.
Speaking of which, how are Vermouth and Bourbon gonna escape the train?
They know about the explosion, don't they?
Who knows? Who cares?
But Vermouth asked me if she could have some of the explosives, if there were any spare.
What?
I asked her what she was going to do with them, but she completely evaded the question.
That woman couldn't be...
Now, please open the door and head inside.
Fear not.
I intend to take you back to the Organisation alive.
I'm going to destroy the link between these two carriages with an explosive, and break off the luggage car.
And after it stops, my partners will come and collect you.
Until then, I'm afraid I'll have to knock you out.
But don't worry.
You'll be sleeping at a safe distance from the door,
so you don't need to worry about getting caught in the explosion.
Apparently I do have to worry.
This luggage car is full of explosives.
Looks like there was a slip-up in your preparations.
I see.
Vermouth really is determined to kill her, no matter what...
Guess I have no choice. How about you come this way?
Sorry, but I decline.
You're as difficult as they said.
I might have to get a little rough with you.
Vermouth?
Sorry, but she's coming with me.
A grenade?!
Who's there?! Who are you?!
Damn it!
.
There. That's the end.
No way! It can't be!
Don't worry.
I waited for the sound of my partner destroying the link to the luggage car before I detonated the bomb,
so the train won't derail.
Ai-chan...
Ai-chan!
You killed Sherry?
Are you sure, Vermouth?
Yes. Bourbon watched her go up in smoke along with the luggage car.
Because of that, though, the train was stopped at a nearby station.
We passengers are all going to be questioned by the police.
It's a shame I can't meet you at Nagoya, since you've been waiting so patiently.
So that's why you wanted the explosives.
If an explosion took place on board, they'd stop the train for sure.
Yes.
You are satisfied with just Sherry being blown to bits, right?
But I was so surprised!
I had no idea Haibara-san was in Carriage 7, Room B!
It was free because it was the dead guy's room!
She said she had to rest when coming back from the toilet because her cold was making her dizzy.
Quiet. She's worn out, so she's getting some sleep.
Right...
I see...
They figured that if she'd run to a room, it'd be that one,
so Yukiko was waiting for her there and hid her.
So that kid's phone call back then...
It was an act trying to keep me stalled in Yukiko's room.
But wait — then who was that?
Who was the girl who blew up in front of Bourbon?
Don't tell me it was that special guest...
Hitomi no Melody (The melody in your eyes)
miagetara haru no ame machi ni oritekita
kimi no aruku michi nurashite yuku
kinō sasatta toge no yō na kimi no kotoba hitotsu
mada honto wa nani mo shiranai yo
sunao ni nareba kodoku nante nai yo hitori de wa nai kara
don'na mirai kimi to mirai
sono hitomi no shita e to tashikame ni yuku yo
yukkuri to orite yuku kara
But wait — then who was that?
Who was the girl who blew up in front of Bourbon?
Don't tell me it was that 'special guest'...
This sucks.
Now Kid-sama won't be able to come on board the train.
With all the crime scene investigations, they won't be able to use the train for a while.
No way!
Sorry, sorry. Sounds like things heated up a bit.
Don't tell me it was...
I didn't sign up for this! What was with those dangerous guys?!
If I hadn't hidden my hang-glider in the luggage car just in case, I'd have been fried!
Well, since it's you we're talking about, I just figured you'd be prepared.
Anyway, consider yourself out of my debt.
Damn right I am!
And remember to return that phone to the Detective Agency.
H-Hey!
Damn brat...
You're really Kaitō Kid and his accomplice, right?
Is this a joke?
The maid, Sumitomo-san, is Kid,
and the old lady is the accomplice.
She doesn't seem to be able to mimic Komino-san's voice, though.
Kid was using ventriloquism to make up for that, and she was lipsynching
while trying to mask it with the veil of her hat.
I see. That's why you made me run down the corridor.
Yeah.
I figured the old lady wouldn't be able to speak on her own.
And all the passengers rescued from that fire are pyrophobic,
but the old lady happily lit up her pipe.
Anyway, be a little grateful.
I didn't press you guys when you were trying to avoid getting involved in the case by saying you didn't see anything.
Well? What sort of favour you trying to buy?
Disguise yourself as this woman, and
shake off the bad guys going after her!
Your conversation with them will be provided through an earphone, directly from her waiting in a separate room.
Out of your debt?
You're the one who's in my debt now, Detective.
I see.
That was indeed the ultimate cast, Yukiko.
Sera-san!
I'm glad you're safe.
I found this hat in the corridor.
It's yours, isn't it?
Yeah, thanks.
Why was it in the corridor?
Everyone else is waiting, so let's go!
The detailed files from the time of Akai's death...
Can I see them one more time?
Sure.
Looks like I'm going to have to restart investigating from square one.
Don't open the door!
So Mouri-san must be here too!
The corpse was blocking the door,  so how can this be a murder?!
That's what Conan-kun said, and he was inside...
And what's more, this is an impossible crime!
Another locked room murder?!
On the next Conan: 'Conan in a Locked Room'!
Next Conan's Hint: Special Coach!
Sonoko, why tennis training?
Gotta train myself in tennis and in love!
Wait... Love?