We became involved with a murder aboard the Bell Tree Express, but managed to solve it.
Also, the man with a burn wandering around the train was discovered to be Vermouth in disguise.
Meanwhile, the shadow that was closing in on Haibara, who had taken the antidote and returned to her adult form...
You really are Hell Angel's daughter.
You look just like her.
A pleasure to meet you.
My codename is 'Bourbon'.
With help from my mother, Subaru Okiya, and even from Kaitō Kid, who had come to scope out the train,
we managed to keep Haibara from falling into their clutches.
So why didn't you tell me your plan beforehand?
Oh, well...
I was shocked!
Running for my life, I went into the unused Carriage 7 Room B.
Then your mum was waiting for me there,
and goes 'Leave the rest to me'.
I had no idea what was going on!
Then you rushed in and shoved a phone in my face saying...
Kaitō Kid's about to meet one of the men in black disguised as you,
so tell him what he has to say!
I thought it was some crazy joke!
W-Well, we weren't sure whether they were really on the train or not.
Even I had my guard down until I got the e-mail from my mother saying Vermouth was on board.
But our room was likely bugged, so I couldn't say anything to you.
Though Subaru-san hacked into your phone and saw the e-mail from Vermouth,
so he figured we were in trouble after all and went to find you.
Hacked?
And thankfully, just as predicted, you went into Room B on Carriage 7.
Just who is that Subaru guy, anyway?
Why is he living with your mum in your house?
Don't worry.
He's on our side.
Besides, she's only even there on the occasional weekend.
Anyway, the main piece of info we got was finding out Tōru Amuro, who works at Cafe Poirot,
is actually Bourbon, one of them.
That reminds me, I heard he's been on sick leave ever since that incident.
Yeah.
We don't know why he was working at Poirot,
but he's not gonna come back, is he?
Luckily for us, he seems to be convinced you died in the explosion.
Though I thought if he did come back like nothing's happened, then I'd investigate him instead, but oh well.
Anyway...
If you do something like that behind my back again, I won't forgive you!
I don't like feeling like I've been being played with!
Is that your way of saying 'thank you'?
Don't be stupid!
Come on, Ai-kun's a bit of a tsundere.
What's 'dere' about her?
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
When I woke up, I was in a locked
room! What happened to me?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
CONAN IN A LOCKED ROOM
Ah, this is just too much!
You didn't have to invite us out to Izu just to make up for the mess on the Bell Tree Express!
And with unlimited use of the nearby tennis courts, plus...
Bet the place will be filled with lively young tennis babes! Can't wait!
Wasn't it raining the last time we went?
But really, you didn't have to make it up to us.
Well, that's one reason,
but we're actually going for some special tennis training!
You mean there's a tournament coming soon or something?
Something even more important than a tournament just dropped into my life!
Anyway, take a look at this!
Sonoko-san, how are you?
Wow! It's Kyōgoku-san!
I've recently started incorporating some tennis into my karate training,
so I'm sending this video e-mail hoping that maybe we could play together next time I go back to Japan.
Wow! He's asking you out on a tennis date!
Exactly!
A romantic evening out on the tennis court with just the two of us!
In that case, you don't really need special training...
Don't be stupid! I'm a member of the tennis club!
I can't let myself get beaten by some beginner!
Then why don't you ask some of the older tennis club members to train with you?
They're too weak to be of any use!
But Dad and I aren't good enough to teach you either.
That's all sorted out. Right, Uncle Kogorō?
Yeah! I caught you a great special coach!
Special coach?
How come...?
Amazing, Amuro-san!
He's almost like Nadal!
Actually, I'm ashamed to say I haven't played since middle school.
What's this guy doing here?!
I was shocked when Poirot's manager told me that you were once a junior champion.
Well, I injured my shoulder right after that, so I can't serve as much as I used to.
But if it's just for teaching, my injury shouldn't get in the way too much.
I'm looking forward to it!
But are you okay?
I heard you were sick.
That was just a little summer cold.
I'll be back in Poirot next week!
What?!
There seem to be a lot of people in the viewing gallery.
They just think that some pro player wandered into the courts.
So, should we start with some serves?
Yeah!
The balls could get dangerous, so stand back, okay?
It's not the balls that are dangerous...
Look out!
Conan-kun!
No, Ran... Get away from him...
He's one of the men in...
...black...
Well, he's conscious and seems to be fine.
It's probably just a concussion.
But if he starts losing sensation in his hands or feet, or feels dizzy or nauseous, make sure to get him to a hospital.
Okay.
Well, then.
Thank you very much.
Good thing it was nothing serious.
Where am I?
This isn't Sonoko-neechan's house, is it?
It's the house of the lady who hit you with the racket.
It's my house.
Kotone Momozono (21)
University Student
I'm so sorry, little boy. My hands were sweaty and the racket just slipped!
I told you!
You should make sure to wrap the handle in grip tape, since your hands get clammy so easily.
Machi Umejima (22)
University Student
But what a shame.
If the battery on my mobile phone hadn't been flat, I could've recorded the 'impact scene' and put it on the Internet.
'Killer racket assaults little boy in a failed attempt at a killer serve'!
Saburō Ishiguri (21)
University Student
How can you say that when a kid's been hurt!
It was just a joke, I was trying to lighten the mood a bit.
Uriu might've died because of that sense of humour of yours!
Noboru Takanashi (22)
University Student
Hey, calm down.
Didn't we gather all the members of the circle here to celebrate Uriu's birthday?
Yeah, let's stop fighting.
Uriu-kun would be sad if he saw this.
Yeah...
Right...
Okay! Since the kid's fine...
What do you guys say to a team match against us?
We've both got two men and two ladies, so how about we do some mixed doubles?
Works for me.
Well, matches are a good way to practise.
I'm fine with a match, but can we do it after we've had some rest?
Yeah, I'm all sweaty from this morning.
And I'm pretty hungry.
Now that you mention it, so am I...
Your stomach's rumbling.
We have some hiyashi chūka noodles for lunch if you'd like to join us.
We sure would!
Would you be okay with that?
Yeah! I need to make up for the accident.
On second thought, no need to prepare mine.
I'm gonna eat the leftovers from last night's ice cream cake in my room.
Oh, geez.
If you keep eating things like that, you're gonna get even fatter!
It's fine!
We're going to help prepare lunch, so wait here, Conan-kun.
Hey, Ran-neechan, who carried me here?
Was it...
It was Amuro-san.
He was very competent, he carried out the procedures pretty efficiently before the doctor arrived.
Conan-kun?
Where are you?
If you're looking for the four-eyed brat,
he said he was going to Ishiguri-san's room
and went upstairs with him.
Apparently the AC wasn't working properly in the living room.
You're right, it's not really working.
Conan-kun?
We brought you some lunch.
He must be sleeping, just let him be.
It's not like he's gonna die from skipping lunch.
Yeah.
The AC's better in this room anyway.
Seriously?
Ishiguri still hasn't come down?
It's already past 3! The day'll be over soon!
I tried knocking several times already.
Looks like he's sleeping, so he locked the door.
What was that noise?
Sounds like it came from Ishiguri-kun's room...
Maybe something happened?
What was that noise?
Sounded like something falling...
This room's hot as hell, though.
I'm sleeping here, so I'd appreciate it if they didn't turn off the AC...
Hey, Kotone. You have a spare key, right?
Actually, I haven't seen the spare key for Ishiguri-kun's room since last night.
Guess there's no choice.
It's a bit dangerous, but we could try getting to his room from the balcony.
If his window's open, we can get in, and if it's closed then we can at least look inside.
Yeah, and we've done it before.
But the gap between balconies is pretty big, I can't do it.
Yeah, you're scared of heights, aren't you?
In that case, mind if I try unlocking the room?
It's kind of my specialty.
Seems to be open.
Amazing, Amuro-san!
You're like Kaitō Kid!
I used to have a friend in a security company
and I secretly learnt a few tricks from him.
It's certainly a useful skill for a detective to have on an investigation.
Something's blocking the door.
Conan-kun?
Don't open the door!
You can't open it.
It's Ishiguri-san's corpse that's blocking the door.
And what's more, this is an impossible crime!
Another locked room murder?!
A locked room murder?!
This?
Yeah.
The door's blocked by Ishiguri-san's corpse,
and all of the windows were locked from inside!
Conan-kun, I know that Mouri-san's turned you into a mystery fan,
but there's a mark on the tennis racket under the corpse's back,
as if it hit something.
There's a similar mark on the shelves next to the body's head.
If we assume that the copper vase, currently atop the man's shoulder, was originally on the shelf, then imagine this:
Ishiguri-san was swinging his racket in his room,
his hand slipped, and the racket hit the shelves.
Then when he bent down to pick up the fallen racket...
After that, he struggled for a bit, laid on his back and died in front of the door.
But if that was the case, the racket ought to be closer to the shelf!
And if he struggled and turned over onto his back,
then this heavy-looking vase wouldn't still be on his shoulder.
There's also a deep dent at the base of the shelves,
which looks like it might've come from when the vase fell.
I was woken up by a really loud 'thud' sound.
If that sound was the vase falling, then this can't be an accident!
How come?
Because I touched the body and the vase right after the sound.
The blood was already dry on both.
That means before the noise took place, Ishiguri-san was already dead.
And that the vase already had blood on it when it fell off the shelves, right?
I-Indeed.
The other people in the house heard the loud noise too, so why don't you talk to them?
B-But...
If that's so, then how did this blood-stained vase fall?
Dunno.
And how did they get the corpse of Ishiguri-san, who's pretty fat, all the way to the door without leaving any marks on the floor?
I don't quite know that yet.
But the one who did it is one of the three who came with Ishiguri-san to the house
and is now standing on the other side of the door.
It can't be anyone else, I'm sure of it!
That's what I'm sure Uncle Kogorō would say, anyway.
Oh! So Mouri-san's here too?
Yeah.
By the way, why are you in this room?
Ah, that.
When I was at the tennis courts earlier, a racket came flying...
...and knocked me out.
The one who threw the racket was a lady named Kotone Momozono.
This is Kotone-san's house.
It was right next to the tennis courts,
and after I was carried away and seen by the doctor,
I figured I'd rest for a bit in this room.
I was lying down on the living room sofa at first, but the AC wasn't working there, so I moved here.
But the AC isn't working here, either.
I'm not sure why, but it was off when I woke up.
I see...
By the way, what's that on the table over there?
Ah, it's ice cream cake.
It was a leftover from last night that Ishiguri-san was going to eat for lunch, but it looks like it's already melted.
What?! A locked room murder?!
If the corpse's blocking the door, how can it be murder?!
But Conan-kun, who was in the room, said he touched the body and vase right after hearing the loud sound, and the blood was already dry.
Hmph.
How can he know for sure he woke up right after the sound?
The kid's probably still woozy from the concussion.
Besides, we don't know for sure if that sound really was the vase falling.
And if a killer had been clever enough to set up a locked room, I doubt he'd use a trick that'd get found so easily.
That's because there were two things that were outside the killer's original calculations.
First, that Conan-kun was sleeping under a blanket in the room.
And second, that I was able to unlock the door to the room.
If they hadn't happened, we would've only spotted Ishiguri-san, who wasn't coming down from his room,
by crossing onto his room's balcony from the neighbouring one and looking through the window.
By the time the police that we called smashed through the window and entered the room,
the blood being dry wouldn't have seemed strange, especially with this heat.
Even if somebody had broken the window right after discovering the body,
they would've focused on Ishiguri-san's condition, not on how dry the blood was.
Then the killer could just tell the police that they'd found the body fallen by the door with blood pouring from his head.
Well done, Conan-kun!
Y-Yeah!
By the way, who is this guy?
He's a detective. My number one apprentice.
N-Number one apprentice?!
Yeah. Apparently he was bowled over by my genius deductions.
Umm, Mouri-san.
Sorry if this seems pretentious, but I've been boasting that I was your number one apprentice.
R-Really?
Anyway, how about we hear what the other three here have to say?
After all, they're the only ones here likely to have a motive for killing him.
N-No way...
One of us is a killer?!
Right. There's no doubt about that.
However, the issue is the locked room.
How did the killer manage to leave the room?
The windows were all locked from inside, and Ishiguri-san's corpse was blocking the door.
Even if the killer had the spare key, with the corpse lying there, they wouldn't be able to open the door to get out.
And it wouldn't be possible for them to move the body to block the door after leaving.
Damn... How did they do it?!
Kimi no Egao ga Nani Yori mo Suki Datta
(I loved your smile more than anything else)
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
We haven't found the spare key to Ishiguri-san's room either.
What does that key look like?
It'd be the same as this key, found in the victim's pocket.
For some reason, there was water in the vase.
I see! That's how it was!
They managed to skillfully create a locked room using a shapeless material!
BOURBON FIGURES IT OUT
On the next Conan: 'Bourbon Figures it Out'!
Next Conan's Hint: Plastic bottle!
Beware Amuro-san?
Because he's a rival to Shin'ichi-kun?
That's not it...