Under the pretext of an apology for the events on the Bell Tree Express, Sonoko invited us to Izu Plateau.
And for some reason, Tōru Amuro was also there as a special tennis coach.
Conan-kun!
Through a series of curious events, I ended up resting in the house of a tennis circle,
but when I woke up, an unusual corpse was awaiting me...
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
Deducing a locked room murder together with Bourbon? Why is he staying near me?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yes, I did go to Ishiguri-kun's room.
I went there to ask if he really didn't want to eat the hiyashi chūka noodles I made for lunch.
But he said he was fine because he had ice cream cake left from last night.
Kotone Momozono (21)
University Student
I see.
And what did you do after that?
After eating lunch with everyone in the kitchen, I had a shower.
Now that I think about it, didn't my daughter and her friend shower too?
Yes. And after that, I was with them
until Machi and I went to check on Ishiguri-kun.
By the way, when did the spare key for Ishiguri-san's room go missing?
I believe it was yesterday evening.
I thought I'd put it in the desk drawer in my room, but it was gone.
Yeah, I went to check up on Ishiguri-kun with Kotone.
Machi Umejima (22)
University Student
Was that the only time you went to his room?
I also went before I showered to tell him I was about to use the shower, since he'd walked in on me before.
Did you have your shower after Kotone-san?
Yes.
And was Ishiguri-san in his room at the time?
There wasn't any response then either, but he was probably in there.
The AC was on, after all.
So what were you doing before and after your shower?
I told you! I helped prepare lunch, did some maintenance on the girls' rackets...
Basically, I was never alone!
Yeah, I went to Ishiguri's room too, to apologize to him.
Noboru Takanashi (22)
University Student
I wanted to say sorry for the
argument we had before lunch.
Was that before or after Machi-san's shower?
I don't know when Machi showered, but it was while we cleared up after lunch, before taking out the rubbish.
By the way, that argument was about a member of the circle who'd passed away, right?
Yeah. Last winter, a guy called Uriu died.
We found him buried in the snow behind the lodge we were staying at on a skiing trip.
There was something like two meters of freshly fallen snow there.
Ishiguri joked that with all the snow, you could survive a jump from the second floor, and he probably took it seriously.
Yesterday was Uriu's birthday, so we all got together and celebrated it.
Because last year we made his birthday really awful for him.
Made his birthday really awful?
Around this time last year, we got together at this house and since it was Uriu's birthday, Ishiguri said we should give him a surprise.
We crept into Uriu's room from the balcony when Uriu was sleeping, and all let off party poppers next to Uriu's ear.
But he got so scared that he burst into tears,
and to add insult to injury, Ishiguri recorded a video of him and uploaded it onto the Internet.
I see.
You three certainly had enough motive to kill Ishiguri-san.
Motive?!
I only went to Ishiguri's room once, and I was always with you after that!
I went along with everything you said, too!
Hell, I was the one who told the kid to go lie down in Ishiguri's room since the AC in the living room wasn't working!
Is that true?
Yeah.
I saw Ishiguri-san in the corridor just after that so I asked him to take me up.
How can you kill somebody in a room when there's a child in there?!
R-Right.
Whatever the trick may be,
I was convinced that the only one who could move Ishiguri-san's heavy body would've been the man, Takanashi-san.
Yeah.
But if all the killer did was sit him up, couldn't a woman do that too?
If they leant his corpse against the door, then let go of the body as they closed the door so he'd collapse...
No. The rest of the corpse was in just the right place to block the door, so I don't think that's possible.
We haven't found the spare key to Ishiguri-san's room either.
What does that key look like?
It'd be the same as this key, found in the victim's pocket.
It hasn't been reported to be found yet.
Maybe it got thrown out with the rubbish?
Ran and I helped take the rubbish out.
What?
Though all we did was put it in Takanashi-san's car boot.
He asked us to, saying he'd put it out when he got home.
Then perhaps the key really is in the rubbish.
Check it immediately!
Yes, sir!
Did any of the others ask you to do things for them?
Let's see...
Kotone-san asked us to put her sports drink back in the freezer.
Put her sports drink in the freezer?
Apparently she likes to drink them frozen.
Remember, the plastic bottle Kotone-san had when we were all getting worried about Ishiguri-san not coming down from his room.
It was starting to melt, so maybe she wanted to freeze it again.
Or made it look that way, and the key was inside it.
A key wouldn't fit inside it.
When we came out of the shower, she took it out of the freezer and let me drink some of it, and it was almost completely frozen.
Oh, yeah!
Who was it that said she'd redo the grip tape on our rackets...?
We left them with Machi-san, right?
She restrung our rackets too, didn't she?
Inspector Yokomizo!
We didn't find anything resembling a key in the rubbish.
I see.
Also, the sports drink in the freezer was completely frozen.
It's hard to imagine a key being inside it.
What about the rackets?
We checked everybody's rackets, but we couldn't find anything like a key anywhere.
Speaking of rackets, forensics reported that a number of strings on the racket found under the corpse were twisted out of shape.
The strings?
Why?
Who knows?
Also, the shape of the victim's head injury matches with the bloodstained copper vase.
However, there was water in the vase for some reason.
Water?
Why was there water in the murder weapon?
Also, the estimated time of death is about 2 to 3 hours before the body was found.
Although depending on the temperature of the room at the time, the estimate may be off by up to half an hour.
We all ate lunch together about three hours before the body was found,
so all three of our suspects had the opportunity to carry out the crime.
Hey, you sure you didn't see the killer?
You were in the room the whole time, right?
I was sleeping...
So you wouldn't remember when Sonoko and I took hiyashi chūka up to your room, would you?
No, I was probably asleep.
Now that I think about it, Ran...
You said something weird back then.
He must be sleeping, just let him be.
It's not like he's gonna die from skipping lunch.
Yeah.
The AC's better in this room anyway.
How could you tell from outside the room?
The tips of my toes were feeling really cool.
I figured the cool air was coming through the gap beneath the door.
Machi-san said something like that, too.
He was probably in there.
The AC was on, after all.
I see. That's how it was.
They managed to skillfully create a locked room using a shapeless material!
Hey, Detective, wasn't this an accident after all?
Ishiguri's body was lying on the floor and blocking the door, and he had a tennis racket under his butt.
Doesn't that mean the vase just fell by chance when he went to pick up his racket?
Not to mention the room was locked.
And you still haven't found the spare key, right?
Right.
We're currently searching the vicinity of the house, but nothing so far.
Not like it matters, but your handwriting sucks!
It's fine as long as I can read it.
All right, he's sitting down.
I'll just tranqulise the old man like I usually do...
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
The lid on my watch broke...
Looks like I can't pull a Sleeping Kogoro in front of this guy.
After all, he's Bourbon, a member of the Black Organization.
If it came to light that I'm Shin'ichi Kudo, turned into a child by their drug,
then even if Vermouth were to keep quiet, they might discover that Haibara became a child too.
Come to think of it...
The sound we heard couldn't have even been the vase falling.
When we heard the noise, the only people in the room were the corpse and the kid.
It's not like the vase would just fall over by itself.
So was that noise just the building creaking after all?
I did hear some building noises while eating hiyashi chūka, but they sounded totally different.
Hey, speaking of hiyashi chūka, you use ice to make it, right?
Yeah.
You need icy water to cool the boiled noodles.
Hey, cut the idle chat.
But you know...
Ice melts, doesn't it?
Of course it does!
So if that vase was made of ice, it could've melted and fallen by itself, couldn't it?
You moron. That vase is made of bronze.
You even touched it!
Hold on.
If someone piled up ice cubes in one side of the vase and carefully balanced it on the edge of the shelf,
then once the ice melted, the vase could lose balance and fall by itself, right?
But if someone was carrying a pile of ice cubes around, wouldn't someone have noticed?
No.
You could even carry them empty-handed.
While making hiyashi chūka, all three of them were still in their tennis wear.
Men's tennis trousers have large pockets so they can carry tennis balls.
And as for women's tennis wear, they do sell skirts with ball pockets too.
But still, even if you managed to make the vase fall,
you still couldn't carry the body to the door, right?
There weren't any drag marks on the floor, after all.
Come to think of it, ice is all slick and slippery, isn't it?
There goes the brat again...
That's it!
I figured it out!
There was a racket under the corpse's butt, right?
Somebody could've placed ice under the racket and slid the body around!
The strings being bent proves it!
Amazing, Sonoko!
But in that case, there should be water from the melted ice on the floor, like inside the vase,
and the victim's trousers should have been wet.
We didn't find any signs of that, you know.
Oh, really?
If only there was something like ice that wouldn't leave anything behind when it melted.
Wait, you mean something like dry ice?
Since dry ice is composed of CO2, it'll just disappear.
Still, you can't exactly carry dry ice, you know.
Unlike normal ice, you can't touch it directly.
They had Ishiguri-san carry it instead.
There was probably dry ice in the box of ice cream cake Ishiguri-san said he'd be eating for lunch.
After killing Ishiguri-san with the vase,
the killer probably laid a racket with a rope looped through it over some dry ice cubes, and laid the corpse on top of it.
After leaving the room, they pulled the rope to move the corpse to the door.
Of course, they left the cord untied for easy retrieval.
I see! That's why I felt a chill on my toes when I went near the room!
The dry ice was right behind the door!
That reminds me, Machi-san, you said something similar, didn't you?
Yes.
But you two didn't notice a chill?
R-Right.
Me either.
I thought that kid might be trying to sleep, so I didn't stay by the door long.
I see.
I finally figured out who the killer is.
First off, we can exclude Machi-san from the suspect list, as her testimony supports our theory that dry ice was used.
Same goes for Takanashi-san, who knew the four-eyed brat was sleeping in the room.
Because who'd be dumb enough to commit murder right next to a sleeping kid?
Which leaves the one person who went to Ishiguri-san's room earlier than anyone else,
leaving plenty of time to allow the ice and dry ice to melt.
Kotone Momozono-san!
You're the only one who could be the killer!
Am I wrong?
H-Hold on, Mouri-san!
Is it okay for you to not do your usual thing?
Your sleeping pose!
Rare as it may be, he was just giving a decent deduction...
In other words, Kotone-san's crime agenda went like this:
First, in the middle of making hiyashi chūka, she hid some ice cubes inside her skirt pockets,
saying something like "I'll go ask Ishiguri-kun if he really doesn't want lunch!" and going to his room.
After clubbing Ishiguri-san to death near the door, she filled the murder weapon with ice, balanced it on the bookcase,
left the room, and used the previously described trick to block the door with Ishiguri-san's corpse.
Without ever noticing that the four-eyed brat was sleeping in the room.
Then she returned to the kitchen, blurting out something like "Oh my, he really doesn't want hiyashi chūka after all!"
and having completed the locked room, sat down and ate lunch as if nothing had happened.
But she wasn't able to fool this great detective!
Somehow, he looks phony when he's moving about.
Yeah...
Then where's the spare key?
The key! Ishiguri's room was locked, wasn't it?
Oh, that, probably...
It'll turn up eventually... I guess?
Oh, yeah, speaking of ice...
What about ice?
kōri
kōru
Do we call it "ice" because it's frozen water?
Who cares about that?!
Speaking of frozen water, what about the sports drink Kotone-san was drinking?
Maybe the key was inside it!
No way!
I drank some of it myself, but it was all frozen and hardly anything would come out.
Then maybe she dropped the key inside before freezing it?
Then you should be able to see it if you look at the bottom of the plastic bottle, since the key was heavy.
Then what if there's some magic water that'd freeze up the moment she put the key in?
You moron, things like that only exist in comics.
It does exist.
Super-cooled water.
Water that remains a liquid instead of turning to ice even when below its freezing point of 0°C.
If it's shaken, it quickly begins to freeze.
To make it, you'd just need to wrap a towel around a plastic bottle so it cools easily,
and leave it in a freezer at around -5°C for four or five hours.
When shaken, it'll begin to crystallize along the sides of the bottle, from the top down.
Kotone-san likely dropped the key inside the supercooled sports drink, shook it, then once it began freezing, turned it upside-down,
letting the key move to the middle of the bottle before it froze completely, and then gave it to Sonoko-san to drink.
Since sports drinks are slightly colored and freeze to a gel-like state, the key inside would be invisible.
Then if we melted the sports drink...
Yes. The evidence that Kotone-san killed Ishiguri-san would come out, I imagine.
S-Say something like that after it comes out!
If nothing comes out, I'll make sure you—
It's no use.
It's going to come out.
The spare key with my fingerprints on it.
Not to mention that I dropped the key in Ishiguri-kun's blood while panicking.
No way! I took a sip from a drink with something like that in it?!
But why did you kill Ishiguri-kun?
To avenge Uriu-kun, of course.
I loved him, after all.
You mean that joke of Ishiguri's that Uriu died to try and prove?
I mean, it was dumb of Ishiguri-kun to carelessly suggest that you could survive a jump from the 2nd floor, but that's still no reason to...
That night, after Uriu-kun's body was removed, I couldn't sleep, so I went out to the balcony and saw Ishiguri-kun, digging through the snow.
At first, I just thought Ishiguri-kun was in denial about Uriu-kun's death,
and was trying to search for Uriu-kun, who was gone forever...
Until I saw him pull out the scarf he'd been wearing.
His smiling face as he retrieved the scarf told me everything.
Uriu-kun didn't jump into the snow on his own —
he was pushed!
Don't tell me Ishiguri did that!
Yeah. Uriu-kun desperately held on to Ishiguri-kun's scarf as he was falling!
He might've planned to go and get him when he was exhausted from struggling in the snow,
but two meters of freshly fallen snow would be like like a bottomless swamp, robbing Uriu-kun of his strength,
and by the time we found him, it was already...
But my plan failed.
In order to make sure Ishiguri-kun ate the ice cream cake for lunch,
I figured I'd just fling my racket and injure some random person,
so I could invite them here and increase the number of people at lunch.
Who'd have thought I'd hit a child's head?
And who'd have thought he'd be with the great detective Kogoro Mouri?
Perhaps I, too, fell into a bottomless swamp, falling further towards my demise the more I struggled...
Yeah, the case was solved.
Thanks to Detective Mouri.
I see.
But how long are you planning to stick with that detective?
You said you were tailing that detective since he might be connected with Sherry, and so I gave you plenty of support.
But that business is over, isn't it?
By some lucky coincidence, information on Sherry landed in our lap and we sent her to her grave.
No, my interest's been piqued more than ever.
By the detective "Sleeping Kogoro", that is.