It's so good!
Drinking beer during the day really is the best!
Sheesh...
Excuse me, are you Kogorō Mouri-sama?
Oh, you want an autograph? I don't mind!
No, there was a call for you, sir.
Oh, thanks.
Uh, hello?
Hey! Long time no see, Great Detective!
Who're you?
I can't believe you've forgotten me.
It's me, Reiji Himuro-sama!
Himuro...
Himuro... Don't tell me you're that Himuro?!
Hey! What're you doing?!
Must be great, living happily with your children.
What do you want?!
Someone's about to die because of you.
What?!
How terrible...
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A carefully planned trap and a suspicious alibi! Kogorō Mouri's last chance!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Uncle! Over there!
Damn! Don't move, Himuro!
Dad!
Miss, your bill!
Hey! I happened to see you when I was looking out the window, so I thought I'd give you a ring for nostalgia's sake.
Reiji Himuro (40)
Ex-Bank Robber
Don't give me that! What was that call about?!
Who exactly is going to die and where?!
You're too late to save them.
What?! What do you mean?!
Stop it, Dad!
Oh, isn't that Kogorō Mouri?
Damn it, was this what he wanted...?
The deceased is Shingo Numao-san, 35.
He was a repairman for Taiyō Cars in Beika's third district.
He was seriously injured, dying almost instantly.
Did he fall from up there?
How's it look, Chiba?
There's no mistake, this is where he fell from.
The handrail is corroded, with a section missing.
But we can't find anything suggesting there was any struggle.
I see.
Shingo Numao (35)
Ex-Bank Robber
So it was you, Numao.
You know him, Dad?
Yeah.
I managed to catch Himuro thanks to him.
Reiji Himuro. That notorious bank robber...
That's right! Wasn't Numao...
Yes...
Himuro's partner — or rather, his underling.
He was nothing more than his errand boy.
I told him that he shouldn't always be at the beck and call of that good-for-nothing, and he agreed.
Numao...
I know you can make a new start.
Believe in me, and tell me all you know about Himuro.
I guess you're right.
It's horrible, always being used by that guy...
It's not worth him landing me a murder charge...
A murder?
Nah...
I just mean that if this keeps up, it might lead to that someday...
And where is Himuro now?
In the interview room.
Satō-kun's questioning him now.
He's always easily been taken in by anyone.
That's why he got a suspended sentence and I got stuck with rotten food for so long...
I'm glad he's finally dead.
Don't play dumb! You killed him, didn't you?
Mouri-san told us that...
How'd I do it?
For starters, when did Numao die?
Around 3:40 PM.
3:40, huh?
Well, I believe at that time a certain famous detective was holding onto me at Hokubu Department Store, publicly embarassing himself.
Great Detectives sure are dependable.
Thanks for the alibi!
Then how did you know that he would die?
I guess you can call it telepathy.
Hey, you can't!
Mouri-kun!
Himuro! Damn you!
Mouri-san!
You killed him beforehand and set up some trick to make him fall, didn't you!
Please stop! Mouri-san!
What right do you have to grab me like this to begin with?!
What?!
Mouri-san!
Hey, I'd rather you let go, you know!
That's enough, Mouri-kun!
B-But Inspector...
Well then, if you're done with this questioning, which I volunteered for, then I'll be on my way.
What the heck's 'internet flaming'?!
Damn it!
I'm just a dumb detective anyway...
What's the meaning of this, Inspector?!
Mouri-kun, don't act like you don't know.
We don't have any crime we can hold him as a suspect for.
W-Well...
Also, you acted violently in public toward someone who isn't even a suspect, as if trying to cast doubt on them.
We would've ended up having to arrest you instead if you went much further.
I didn't know you thought that way about me, Inspector!
I don't.
But that's how the world will see it.
You reacted to his provocation and lost your temper.
Take a break.
I can't believe Dad...
I know how he feels, but he drank too much.
Is that the café we were at?
It's a bit far to have spotted us by accident...
He must've been watching the old man before coming up here.
Huh? Conan-kun?
Where's Mouri-san?
He said he had somewhere else to go, and asked me to have you investigate here.
I see, that's good.
He's being criticised pretty heavily by the media, so I was worried about him.
He's fine, he's all fired up wanting to clear his reputation.
Actually, is it okay for you to be here helping Uncle, Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
Mouri-san's always helping me out.
It's the least I could do.
Is this it?
That's right.
I'd like to see what happened a bit earlier.
Earlier?
Earlier...
Ah, that's it! Play from just before that.
Hey, can we see the floor beneath?
Yeah.
Is this it?
It's Himuro.
What's that way?
The men's toilets.
Oh, he came back.
Hey, what's that on the right side of the screen?
Oh, that's probably a microphone.
There was an open recording of a radio show there yesterday.
Here, huh?
He said they'd be doing the same today too.
Yeah...
But it doesn't seem like this is the reason Himuro was here.
Oh, Detective Takagi, there was another place he wanted us to check.
Another place?
Sorry for the wait.
I'm Eguchi, from the Beika Police.
Thanks. So, uh...
Conan-kun?
Uncle Kogorō wanted me to ask you something.
What is it?
Why were you here to begin with?
Oh, I got a report while I was on patrol, saying someone suspicious was lurking in this building.
It's thought to be on the verge of collapsing, so it's off-limits.
And when I rushed over here...
Hey, stop! It's dangerous!
Geez...
Who was that report from?
He didn't leave a name.
When I tried to call him back, he wouldn't answer the phone either, so I thought it might've been a prank.
The call was recorded, wasn't it?
Can't you use voice recognition?
I see, maybe it was Himuro...
I'll contact the Communications Command Centre and Forensics.
Still, why was Numao-san here?
You didn't see anyone else, right?
No.
This is Takagi.
There's something I'd like you to check.
Yes, that's right.
What I'd like to be checked is a report made by phone at around 1:30 yesterday afternoon.
Ah!
A phone!
A phone?
Right! I just remembered, he seemed to be talking to someone on a mobile phone.
That's strange.
He wasn't holding a mobile when he fell, nor was one found near Numao's corpse.
Maybe he threw it away before falling.
Perhaps he didn't want anyone to see his call log.
Okay, let's widen the search area and look for it.
Right!
Everything's rusted...
That was close...
What's this?
So that's it, that's what happened!
Here it is! I found it!
It was lying over here!
Even if we can find Numao-san's fingerprints on this phone,
after being thrown so far, who knows whether the data inside is still intact...
Oh, and I just got a call from Uncle, asking if you'd recheck the spot where the handrail is missing.
Got it.
Hold on...
If back then, Himuro was...
Then that's where it might be!
Conan-kun?!
There it is!
This is a customer announcement. Continuing on from yesterday,
we are holding an open recording session for the popular radio programme, 'Afternoon Radio'.
But it's likely that the call records on this phone have been destroyed too...
It will be in the event plaza on the 2nd floor of this department store. To repeat...
Isn't there any other evidence...?
Continuing on from yesterday, we are holding an open recording session
for the popular radio programme, 'Afternoon Radio'. It will be in the event plaza on the 2nd floor of this department store.
So when I give the signal, start clapping loudly!
Perhaps...
Megure speaking.
Hello, Inspector. Mouri here.
There's a favour I'd like to ask.
Oh, Dad, Inspector Megure's on the phone.
Huh?!
Hello.
What is it, Inspector?
Himuro?
Hmph, so you're why I was dragged out here without any warrant, huh?
No, it wasn't... What's the meaning of this, Inspector?
What're you saying?
You told us to take him in as you could prove he was guilty.
Mouri-kun!
Dad!
This is the famous Sleeping Kogorō, right?
I'll begin with my conclusion.
He called Shingo Numao and manipulated him, making him fall to his death from the fire escape.
Can you prove it wasn't an accident?
Yes, of course.
There is a large hole in the fire escape on the way to the fourth floor,
and in an attempt to step over it, his hand naturally reached for the handrail on the left side.
But if that handrail was corroded and had become fragile...
You really like false charges, don't you?
I guess it's my fault the handrail's rusty then.
Yes, it is your fault!
What?
Detective Chiba, please explain.
Right.
That handrail had a corrosive agent applied to it.
Forensics say that if left for a week, it could easily rust away the metal.
Also, you had mentally trapped Numao.
Detective Takagi!
Right.
When Himuro-san was arrested previously, there was one case that couldn't be proven.
The case where two robbers broke into Shinkin Bank in Beika's second district.
One of the guards was murdered.
Come on, you can't blame me for everything.
I expect those two robbers were you and Numao.
So you lured Numao to this building,
then called him to say 'They found out about that guard's murder!'
And what if a police officer appeared right then and called out to him?
Hey, stop! It's dangerous!
Numao would've panicked.
We've already retrieved Numao's phone and the phone you discarded in the toilet of the department store.
If we compare their call logs, we can prove it was you he was talking to.
Satō here.
Right.
Right...
I see.
No good.
The data on both phones was corrupt, and their call logs couldn't be retrieved.
How about the voice recognition for the report of Numao being here?
The caller had used a voice changer...
Hmph. Good work, you really had me going there.
I guess even you can spin a good yarn when you want.
But without an ounce of proof, you can't prosecute me.
Right, Inspector?
You really should teach that moronic detective about little things like proof.
Well, I'll be on my way.
Dad!
What're you doing, Mouri-kun!
It's not over yet!
In a change from our scheduled programming, today's Afternoon Radio brings to you
a deduction by the Great Detective Sleeping Kogorō, attempting to reclaim his famed name!
You're late!
To get straight to the point, what were you doing at 3:40 PM yesterday?
At that time, I was preparing for an open recording at Hokubu Department Store.
I see.
Then could you replay the recording you played for the errand boy earlier?
Sure.
Go ahead and play it, Takahashi-kun.
Testing, testing. This is a test of the microphone.
Is it working?
Tanaka, is it coming through?
Yes, loud and clear.
How about the mic in back?
Yes, it's all set up.
Hmph, you can't hear anything in all this!
Well then, if you'll remove the noise of the surroundings...
Right.
Testing, testing. This is a test of the microphone. Is it working?
The police are after you! They're in front of the building now!
Hurry up, Numao!
Run to the roof!
If they catch you, this time, you'll be locked away...
No, they'll execute you!
Farewell, traitor...
Damn! Don't you mess with me!
You amateur!
What?
Ran!
Why, you...!
After that, Himuro confessed to both this case and the previous murder.
The old man's name was thankfully cleared as well.
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
Oh, Dad...
I thought we'd throw a party to congratulate him,
but he drank the celebratory toast all by himself...
Oh well.
We can do one without him.
To a Great Detective.
To a Great Detective...
Cheers!
Cheers...
Fighting up there is dangerous!
He was pushed off!
He didn't commit suicide.
Nor was it an accident.
Someone pushed him off the roof!
Hold on!
We saw him being pushed off at...
Yeah!
2 PM exactly!
In other words, he took ten minutes to fall — way too long.
On the next Conan: 'The Man Who Fell Slowly'!
Next Conan's Hint: Balcony!
There's no case I can't solve!
It's midnight!
He's so loud, I can't sleep...