On the first Sunday of the autumn school term,
Dr. Agasa was taking us back home after watching a movie.
Ah, it's exactly 2 PM!
I just saw the clock change to saying 2 PM.
Yeah, yeah, good for you.
Genta-kun, you're too loud!
Hey, look...! On top of that building!
What is it now?
A fight?
Fighting up there's dangerous!
He was pushed off!
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A mysterious slow-motion descent, and the surprising mystery of the time lag!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
THE MAN WHO FELL SLOWLY
Excuse me, is the person who made the report here?
Yes, it was me.
I was shopping, and I passed by here when...
So I quickly called 119.
I see.
That's strange...
Hey, mister!
It wasn't a suicide attempt.
Nor was it an accident.
Someone pushed him off the roof!
What?!
This is Sakai, from the Beika Emergency Department.
The accidental fall that was reported earlier may have been a murder attempt.
Yes.
The victim was 37 year-old Masa'aki Ogata-san.
His address is Central Beika...
Hey, miss, it was around 2:10 when you called the ambulance, right?
Hunh? Yeah, it was 2:10 exactly.
It couldn't have been more than five or six minutes ago that the ambulance arrived, right?
And it's around 2:20 now.
An ambulance usually takes 5 to 6 minutes to arrive, so by subtracting that time, you can estimate when it was requested.
Oh, I see!
Hold on!
We saw him being pushed off at...
Yeah!
Exactly 2 PM!
Yeah. In other words, he took ten minutes to fall — way too long.
But since this building can't be more than five storeys...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, was this building this short before?
No, it had at least five storeys...
H-Hey!
Hold on!
Wa... Hey, wait! There's a lift here!
But, look.
.
Out of order...
This spot is right above where he landed, but...
I see, so that's what happened.
The lowest two floors stick out slightly, making a balcony on the third floor.
I get it now. After being pushed down from here, the man first fell on the balcony, and then to the ground from there.
So that's why it took ten minutes.
So he was pushed off twice, poor guy...
Anyway, let's search inside the building!
The lady we talked to earlier said nobody left the building.
It's already been at least ten minutes.
The culprit could've escaped through the back door...
The back door! Maybe there's some clues to the culprit there.
We'll go take a look!
Yeah!
H-Hey, you guys...!
Then maybe we should take a look at that balcony.
Based on the position, it should be this flat...
'Ogata Finances'?
Wasn't the victim also...
The victim was 37 year-old Masa'aki Ogata-san.
Perhaps this is his office.
.
So he was a moneylender...
H-hey, Shin'ichi!
.
This looks like it was the initial crime scene.
We finally found the back door...
But it's chain-locked...
Which means the culprit couldn't have escaped through the back door.
Then how did they escape?
They must've had quite a fight.
I really don't think we should be in there without permission...
A driver's license?
'Ryōhei Honda'... Since it's on this upended sofa, maybe he was involved in the fight.
And maybe he was the culprit.
It's too early to say that.
H-Hey, you two...
The fire escape!
The culprit must've escaped through the emergency exit on the third floor...
It's all muddy.
There's no footprints, not even one...
It can't be!
If they didn't use the front door, the back door, or the fire escape, then how did they get away?
I doubt there's any other way out.
Which means...
The culprit must still be inside the building!
Hiding somewhere!
Then, let's tell Conan-kun—
Don't.
Mitsuhiko-kun?
Do you want us to find the culprit without him?
These are...
Marks of something being dragged.
And there's a bloodstain too.
The culprit must've dragged the victim in here temporarily after he fell.
And then dropped him from here...
Glasses!
They look like the ones that Honda wore in his licence photo.
They couldn't be outside the balcony unless the victim, Ogata-san,
happened to take them from Honda the moment he was pushed off, right?
If those glasses do belong to this 'Honda', then we have ourselves a culprit.
Guess there's no work for us.
But if he planned to throw him off again, why would the culprit bother carrying Ogata-san in here?
For what reason...?
You were the ones who saw Masa'aki Ogata-san being pushed off?
Still, you shouldn't mess with a crime scene.
You should know better, Agasa-san.
How embarrassing...
But since you've come all the way here, this Ogata-san must be somebody special.
He was a notorious loan shark.
Chiba...
There's a pair of glasses on the outside of the balcony.
And then there's this.
A driver's license?
Ryōhei Honda...
Ryōhei... Honda...
It looks like these glasses belong to him as well.
Yes, it's quite likely he's the one who visited and fought with Ogata-san.
Let's check with the officer dealing with his file.
Go ahead.
I'll go check the roof.
Maybe we should tell the police that the culprit's still here instead of searching ourselves.
Let's keep going, we can't give up now.
Mitsuhiko...
It's not fair.
I feel like if we just keep looking, we might be able to expose the culprit.
Mitsuhiko-kun...
Got it!
I'll go look on the roof!
I'll search the basement!
Let's start the investigation!
Yes, this is Takagi.
What? You haven't been able to locate Ryōhei Honda-san?
Right. Yes.
Got it. Thanks for your help.
Apparently he left home around noon without saying where he was going, and hasn't returned.
Yesterday, he met up with an old acquaintance, so they think he may have headed to see him again.
Looks pretty certain, doesn't it?
No, something doesn't fit.
Why would he drag him in here then take him back out?
Whoops.
Rubber boots?
Nothing odd about that.
Not with this much rain.
But this receipt's from last night.
Yesterday's forecast said today would be clear.
Nobody in this room either...
Nobody's hiding up there.
That was fast — did you make sure to check properly?
Of course!
You guys?!
What was that scream?!
It was Ayumi-chan!
She said she'd go check the basement!
Hey, Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi-kun, are you okay?!
Yoshida-san!
Are you okay, Ayumi-chan?!
I-I saw a mouse...
I'm glad you didn't get bitten.
Never mind that, I'm glad you weren't caught by the culprit...
Yeah.
Come on, Honda wouldn't still be here—
Honda?
You already identified who did it?
Er, not quite...
This is the only car here, so it must be Ogata's car.
What is it?
Rubber boots?
Yeah.
Together with a very interesting item.
A shovel...
If you think of a way to use those two objects...
It's a rather short list, isn't it?
No clues on the roof...
Is someone there?
I'm with the police.
If you're there, please answer...
Then who is this Honda-san?
You know too, right, doc?
It's too early to say for sure...
Takagi speaking.
Oh, it's you, Chiba.
Huh? Caught? Who was caught?
I got caught... by the culprit...
What?! By the culprit?!
I told you, don't come any closer!
I said I wanted a getaway car!
So it really was you, Honda.
So he's that Honda guy...
So the perpetrator really was still here.
Yeah.
Right.
Why would this man behave like this?
Why, Honda? Why did you try to kill Ogata?
Who are you?
Have you forgotten me?
I don't know... anything...
He's lost his memory.
Amnesia?
So that's why he...
You're not the kind of man to do something like this, Honda.
I was the one who arrested you eight years ago as a robbery suspect.
Me? Robbery?
Yeah.
You committed a robbery along with a man you said you happened to meet at a bar.
But with the only clue to his identity being that he had a hoarse voice,
we could never find your accomplice, and you alone ended up serving a sentence.
But you completely reformed after serving your term!
And that's not all!
After taking over your father's factory, you supported ex-convicts like you were by offering them jobs as factory workers!
I really did that?
He's a really nice guy.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
So how did you end up committing crimes again?
What connection did you have with Ogata?
That's right. What connection did he have with the victim...?
That reminds me...
Yesterday, he met up with an old acquaintance, so they think he may have headed to see him again.
Then perhaps...
I see! So that's what happened!
Honda! What happened between you and Ogata?
I told you, I don't remember anything at all!
Where am I?
I realised I must've been fighting with someone else there.
Did I...?!
Did I push him down from up here?!
I was scared of being caught.
But my head hurt and I felt dizzy, so I decided to hide for a while.
Then just when I managed to get moving again...
No clues on the roof...
Is someone there? I'm with the police.
The police?
I didn't want to get caught...
But why did I try to kill that man to begin with?!
If he himself doesn't even know why he did it, there's no way we could, is there?
Which means we'll need a detective to solve this!
Why did I try to kill him?!
You're wrong, Honda-kun!
You visited Masa'aki Ogata because he was an old acquaintance, right?
An old... acquaintance?
Detective Takagi, did Masa'aki Ogata have a hoarse voice?
Huh? Yeah, hoarse and intimidating.
Think back, Honda-kun.
He's the man with the hoarse voice you met eight years ago at a bar.
Could it be?
The man with the hoarse voice from eight years ago...?
The man with the hoarse voice I met at a bar...
It was him!
He'd completely changed his appearance.
But... that voice...
I'll follow you to hell to make you pay if I have to!
Do you get it?!
What's with you?
It really is you, isn't it.
It may have been eight years now.
But the statute of limitations still hasn't expired.
So you want me to turn myself in?
If you atone for your crime, you can live a dignified life without the weight of it hanging upon you!
I really wanted to make him give himself up...
Like I thought, he's a good guy, right?
But still...
That nice guy has...
So how did you end up trying to murder Ogata?
I can't remember...
It's the other way around.
You knew about Masa'aki Ogata's evil deeds, so he wanted you gone from this world.
He planned to murder you, take your corpse deep into the mountains and bury you there!
He prepared by inviting you here to this building,
which was empty as it was the weekend, and carried out his plan.
But he failed to kill you, and ended up having to push you off the roof.
Then when we saw...
Someone being pushed off...
It was Honda-san?
Then, Masa'aki Ogata dragged you into his office to finish you off, Honda-kun.
As proof of that, look. Your jacket's all dirty.
But wasn't it Ogata who landed on the ground?
That's right!
At the time, Honda-kun was unconscious from a strong blow to the head, hard enough to give him amnesia,
so he couldn't have pushed Masa'aki Ogata off.
Which means there was only one possible course of events.
Masa'aki Ogata intended to hide his corpse in the mountains after finishing him off.
For that plan to succeed, he had to remove every trace of Honda-kun's visit.
Oh, I should get rid of that too.
Where's his glasses?
Out here?
Oh, there they are!
As well as it being easy to slip because of the rain, remember what happened right at the time?
In other words, rather than one person falling off twice, the person who was falling changed midway!
Over a ten-minute timespan.
So that's the truth behind the long-winded fall, huh.
Unbelievable...
Honda, you may not have done anything to Masa'aki Ogata...
But you did attack and take Detective Chiba hostage.
But, Inspector!
That's the truth.
Inspector...
Come with me.
Understood.
I feel sorry for him...
Yeah.
Conan-kun.
This is something even I can't do anything about.
Even if he had was panicking and had lost his memory, that doesn't excuse his actions.
Besides, he probably understands that better than anyone.
I'm sorry for troubling you.
Don't worry...
Don't worry about the handcuffs. I know you won't resist.
But before that, we've got to take you to the hospital.
We have to have your head injuries treated, Honda-kun.
It wasn't long before Masa'aki Ogata was arrested as a suspect to the robbery eight years ago, and his recent attempt to murder Honda-san.
Kimi no Egao ga Nani Yori mo Suki Datta
(I loved your smile more than anything else)
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
Anyway, Dr. Agasa did a great job once again, huh?
Yeah.
You could say that...
A rainbow!
Wow!
Amazing!
Beautiful!
I saw it coming ever since all this began.
niji
ni-ji
Since it started at two o'clock, it had to end with a rainbow!
Another pun...?
And just when we were commending him.
What's the point?
What a long-winded joke... and isn't it a bit forced?
Just like always...
What happened?!
That's the design concept Murase-san showed to Inomata-san.
I believe this shouldn't be thought of as an accident, but a murder.
Still, why was Inomata-san there?
That's...!
THE CASE OF THE UNCONFIRMED CRASH
On the next Conan: 'The Case of the Unconfirmed Crash'!
Next Conan's hint: Wrapping band!
Guitar!
Bass!
Drums!
Who's on vocals?
Not that kind of band!