I can't believe it's gone.
They're building a block of flats instead.
It was such a great restaurant too.
It's too bad.
Ah, well, let's go.
It looks like there's lots of new construction around here.
Look over there.
Yeah, there used to be a dumpling shop there.
And over there.
That one was an old block of flats.
Oh, there too!
That was... a bookshop, I think.
Here too!
Look closely, that's just remodeling!
Here too.
What was here?
It was an old bathhouse. I used to go there quite a bit.
It says...
It's going to be a spa resort!
Geez...
Then they should've just kept it as it was!
Right.
Well, that's just the way business goes.
But it's still sad to see pieces of the past vanishing.
I guess...
What happened?!
Somebody call an ambulance!
Ran! Get an ambulance!
Right!
I can't see Inomata-san!
He was just at the smoking area! Don't tell me he was...
Damn!
Murase-san, quick, help us!
A-Ah, right!
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
A crash resounds at a building site! And there's a terrible trick behind it!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Okay, bring me up to date.
Right!
At about noon, metal pipes for scaffolding at this construction site collapsed.
The victim is Yūji Inomata-san, 56.
He was apparently the owner of the site.
The cause of death was injuries from being crushed by the pipes, and he seems to have died instantly.
Inspector, there are marks suggesting the bands securing the pipes were deliberately cut.
We should consider this to be murder, not an accident.
But why was Inomata-san there to begin with?
There was an ashtray under the collapsed pipes.
Maybe that was the smoking area?
The smoking area... I see.
Actually, we did find a half-smoked cigarette lying at the victim's feet.
Inomata-san was a heavy smoker, so he always went for a cigarette whenever he had spare time.
These are the people who were here when the accident occured.
They all worked on the site.
Masao Kaneda (27)
Inomata's Driver
The victim's driver, Masao Kaneda-san.
Tsuyoshi Nojima (36)
Building Foreman
Beside him is the foreman for this building site, Tsuyoshi Nojima-san.
Naoki Murase (48)
Architect
And finally, the architect Naoki Murase-san.
He was in charge of the design.
Would you mind telling me what you were each doing just before the accident?
Let's see... Inomata-san told me to go get coffee for a visitor, so I went to buy some at the vending machine behind the site.
And when I got back, the pipes had collapsed.
And who was that visitor?
Oh, that was me.
I came here today to ask Inomata-san for a special favor.
A special favor?
Oh, I came to talk to him about the concept for the design.
Then while Kaneda-san was getting the coffee, I placed a call to my office,
and Inomata-san went to the smoking area for a cigarette.
Not long after, I heard a loud crash, and when I looked to the smoking area...
I was on my lunch break, so I was in the office here.
Then I heard the loud crash.
So you all came running when you heard the loud crash, correct?
So nobody actually saw the pipes falling.
Excuse me.
Was this an accident?
Or...
We are also investigating the possibility that it was murder.
Well, Kaneda-san was in debt to Inomata-san.
I heard him say that if Inomata were to vanish, then so would his debt.
Hey! Hold on a sec!
I may have said that, but well...
I just... At the time, I was just pissed at him.
You think I'd murder him just because of that?!
Yes, I think you might just do it.
Are you forgetting that you're suspicious too?!
You were arguing with Inomata whether or not to cut costs in the building work!
I remember now! It was your idea to put the smoking area there too!
You put it there because of your grudge with Inomata-san!
I didn't have any grudge against Inomata-san.
Don't play dumb!
Kaneda-san, please calm down.
That reminds me, you're not above suspicion either.
You were mad at Inomata-san because he was always rejecting your design concepts!
Perhaps, but that's not enough for me to...
Hey, just calm down, everyone.
Whatever! I didn't do it!
Inspector Megure...
We found the same type of nylon used in the bands securing the pipes on the blade of a knife found where the accident occured.
And from its position, it seems this knife was what was used to cut the bands.
Right. Good work.
That decides it.
The culprit was Kaneda-san. You did it!
Why me?!
Don't pretend you're innocent.
This is yours, isn't it?
It has your name carved into it.
While Murase-san was busy talking on the phone,
you pretended to go to buy coffee, but instead hid behind the pipes
and used your knife to cut the bands securing them.
Then when the pipes collapsed, you rushed back pretending not to know what happened.
But would that really be possible?
After all, there were lots of bundles of pipes, and the one that collapsed was the one closest to the smoking area.
I don't think there'd be anywhere you could hide and still reach the bands.
If he cut the pipes right there, he'd have been in full view of Inomata-san too.
And wouldn't he have been caught up in the crash in the first place?
So I don't—
Quiet!
He must've done something about it!
"Something"...?
Anyway, the culprit has to be Kaneda.
The knife found at the scene is decisive proof.
You're wrong! I lost it yesterday...
Anyone could come up with an excuse like that!
Well then, Kaneda-san, could you explain what happened in more detail, including what happened to the knife?
I don't mind, but I didn't do it!
Excuse me, can I go to the toilet?
I also have to phone my office.
Sure.
We will want to talk to you both afterwards though, so don't leave the crime scene.
From what forensics said, it seems that knife must've been used to cut the bands.
But would someone really have cut the bands, even with the danger of getting caught up in the crash?
Also, the noise we heard...
What's this?
Hey, Mister, what's this?
Oh, that thing?
That's the design concept that Murase-san showed to Inomata-san.
It must've been rejected and thrown away.
Oh! That's the tile art from the bathhouse that used to be here!
In the bathtub, they really looked like real carps under the water.
Ah, gotta go to the toilet, toilet...
Oh, Conan-kun, there you are.
It's dangerous to go wandering around.
Ran-neechan, I have to go to the toilet, but Uncle's using it right now.
Sorry for bursting in like this...
Don't worry, I don't mind at all.
Thank you, sir!
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Are you all right?
Sorry, the floor's just been waxed, so it's easy to slip.
Don't worry, we're the ones who should be apologizing.
Oh, could we buy some tea from your vending machine?
Sure, I don't mind.
Go ahead.
Huh? It's warm.
It's still cooling.
Look.
Oh, so it is.
Huh?
Say, did someone come to service the vending machines today?
No, we've been closed today due to remodeling.
Chief! Do you have a moment?
Sure, I'll be right there!
Well then, I have work to do, but please visit us again when we re-open.
Sure!
Then let's head back.
Oh, hey, Conan-kun!
You'll fall down again!
Electrical Room
That's...
Conan-kun, what happened?
Conan-kun?
The fingerprint check is finished.
The fingerprints on the knife belong to Kaneda-san.
Good work.
Well then, if you could accompany us to the station, Kaneda-san...
How'd I end up in this?!
Excuse me, can I return to my office now?
What about me?
Well then, we'll leave it here for today, and be in contact again if we need you.
Thank you.
Will he come voluntarily?
Sorry, but could you bring a car over?
Got it.
Hey, Detective Chiba.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Mouri-san said that?
Yeah!
Hey, give me a break!
I told you I didn't kill him!
We'll be happy to take your full statement when we get to the station.
Dad?
Please wait, everyone.
The culprit is not Kaneda-san.
What're you saying, Mouri-kun?
We found his prints on the knife, and it was you who told us that he did it!
I may have said that, but I hereby retract my previous deduction.
However, the culprit is still someone present.
I thought it strange.
Why would the knife have been left at the scene?
It's possible that the culprit dropped it by mistake.
But if that were the case, there is something essential missing.
Something essential?
And what is that?
Take another look at the place that the knife was found.
The ashtray was right beside it.
And the ashtray was struck by many pipes, broken, and pushed into the ground.
Right, but why mention it...?
But how about the knife?
Oh, there's no mark in the ground.
Exactly.
And the pipes were heavy enough to kill someone.
There should be a mark from the pipes landing on the knife.
Then what are you saying?
It was planted there.
By the culprit, after the pipes had fallen.
Is that true?
The culprit probably stole the knife from Kaneda-san yesterday.
He then used it to make cuts on the inside of the bands, so they wouldn't be seen,
and tied the pipes up slightly tighter than usual.
Then after confirming Inomata-san was smoking, and Kaneda-san had left the site, he also left.
Then the culprit didn't cut through the bands with the knife?
Correct. If he had cut through the bands with the knife,
then there was the risk that he could end up crushed too.
So he used something else to cut them instead.
Something else?
Look behind me, at the building next door.
A leisure center?
From the first floor window of the building site's prefab unit,
you can see the emergency exit next door, correct?
So what are you saying?
Oh, it's Chiba!
When I checked, the first floor window of the prefab office was open,
and there was a straight line of sight to the pipes from the leisure center.
Don't tell me...
You're not saying the culprit cut through the bands on the pipes from that far away?!
That's impossible!
Well then, Detective Chiba, go ahead.
Right.
By using the breaker on the ground floor in that building,
he operated a piece of equipment on the first floor and committed the crime.
Mouri-kun, what equipment?
W-What's this?!
A pitching machine?!
Exactly.
At noon, when it happened,
the prefab unit's windows were open.
And when I checked,
I found the emergency exits at the leisure center have been left open due to the remodeling.
But the nets and panes of glass haven't been installed yet.
In other words, when it happened, there was a straight path between the pipes and the pitching machines on the first floor.
The culprit probably prepared the pitching machine to fire, then flipped the circuit breaker.
Then after checking Inomata-san was in the smoking area, he reset the breaker.
Basically, the culprit used a narrow path to collapse the pipes with a ball, murdering Inomata-san.
And the culprit is likely...
Murase-san, it was you!
You know...
If you know that much, do you have any evidence?
The evidence is your shoes.
Or to be precise, their soles.
Ran, show me the soles of your shoes.
Huh? My shoes?
Here.
What's this red thread?
Wool from the mattress at the leisure center "Fun-Fun".
If Murase-san has the same thread stuck to his shoes,
it's proof that he went to Fun-Fun.
I apologize, but may I have a look?
He does have them on his shoes.
But that's just circumstantial evidence.
Pieces of thread won't make me the culprit.
Without any physical evidence, you would be correct.
However, there are marks left behind by the ball.
As well as Murase-san's footprints.
After running to the scene, you hid the ball, which was evidence.
And where is it?
It's most likely in with that debris.
As after all, Murase-san hasn't set foot outside the building site.
Takagi!
Right.
Here it is!
That decides it.
But...
Why did Murase-san kill Inomata-san?
Was it because he rejected your concept?
No.
I...
...loathed Inomata.
He used cowardly methods to buy up land on the cheap, and built a wide chain of spa resorts.
And one plot of land he bought was a bathhouse run by my family.
Because of that, my mother was struck by illness and passed away...
And my father followed her by committing suicide.
But that wasn't why I hated him.
I knew this plot of land used to be the bathhouse,
so I incorporated that into the design concept,
hoping that I could at least leave a fragment of my memories behind.
But he...
He sneered that bathhouses were outdated...
That he wanted nothing to do with places so dirty, moldy and stale.
He insulted me.
The bathhouse...
...was full of memories of my father.
And he destroyed those memories...
That's why I did it!
Inomata trampled upon and destroyed every precious memory I had!
Murase-san.
I understand the way you feel.
However!
Having trampled upon and destroyed your memories does not make it right for you to murder him!
Also, Murase-san...
Inomata-san has a family too.
They would have precious memories as well.
And you have destroyed their memories!
Good luck, Dad!
Silence! I need to concentrate!
Now I'll show you an ultra-amazing skill of mine!
M-My back...
Well, that certainly was an ultra-amazing skill...
W—
What?!
Murder.
No matter which way you look at it.
Then let's go and see what those three have to say once more...
I doubt they ever thought they'd be suspects so quickly...
On the next Conan: Everybody Witnessed It (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Cleaning Robot!
What connects big appetites, sports and falling leaves?
Beer!
Isn't it autumn?