We got a case, Kudō!
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan!
What do you mean by "Kudō"?
Didn't you just say "We got a case, Kudō"?
Oh, yeah, that...
I meant, since we got a case,
yakudō
things are going to get lively around here.
For a murder case, that's just plain inconsiderate.
A murder case? You didn't come all the way here to ask me about a case in Ōsaka, did you?
Nah, the crime scene's here in Tōkyō. Ōtaki-han here can vouch for that!
Inspector Ōtaki of the Ōsaka Police!
Hello. It's been a while.
We called it "the closed-off murder scene where the victim was short on both legs and help", right?
Yeah, more or less.
What's with that?
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A deduction showdown between me and Hattori revolving around a puzzling sealed lift!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
What?! A man was killed under police surveillance?
Yeah.
Last month, a man in his seventies passed away in a flat in Haido Town.
That man, named Hidemichi Mizuki, was a high school teacher until a few years ago.
One of his students was a man named Kiriya Hido.
I've heard the name "Kiriya Hido" somewhere before...
He's the serial killer behind two deaths in Ōsaka and one in Kōbe.
We got a report he'd been sighted in Tōkyō, so in a joint operation with the Tōkyō Police, we put Mizuki-san's flat under surveillance.
We figured that since Hido had no relatives, if he'd turn to anyone for help, it'd be Mizuki-san, who used to look out for him.
And then, on the morning of the stakeout's third day, he didn't come out for his usual morning walk.
We thought it was strange, so we went to check his room,
and a rope had been put through the AC vents in the living room and used to hang Mizuki-san.
Then isn't that just a suicide?
You were watching his front door and windows, right?
Yeah, that's why we closed the case as a suicide, but...
The tips of his toes seemed strangely far from the ground,
They were about the same height as the top of my legs.
And surprisingly, the chair lying at his feet was...
...exactly the same as the ones we got in my kitchen at home!
Those chairs were only made in a limited amount quite some time ago, and they were all the same size.
When we tried measuring one against Ōtaki-han,
we found there'd be at least 10 centimetres between the chair and the tips of his toes!
Hey, with a 10 centimetre gap, he couldn't have hanged himself even if he stretched!
Yeah.
Which means that the chair was just a trick by the killer to make it look like Mizuki-san killed himself.
I see.
That's why the victim was "short on both legs and help".
His door wasn't even locked either,
so it's gotta be a murder.
Then could it have been that Kiriya Hido guy, the serial killer?
Oh, no.
Kiriya Hido's already been caught in Hiroshima.
Apparently he'd been staying in an Internet café for the past month.
But the police were watching the place, right?
Even if the door was open, how did the killer manage to get in unseen?
Exactly. Due to the circumstances, the murder scene was already sealed off.
We got permission from his relatives,
so we're about to go and check his flat...
So I figured you guys would wanna go too, huh?
So the flat where the crime took place has been left just as it was at the time of the incident, right?
Yeah.
Though the daughter of the victim said she'd be comin' by tomorrow to pick up her father's items.
Well, as long as we figure out how the killer got in today, that ain't no problem!
Look, Ran-chan! This lift has windows!
Lifts with windows in the doors are actually pretty common.
Stop messin' around, you two.
We ain't goin' there for a friendly visit!
I know that!
'Cause I got a special role here that only I can do!
A special role?
No doubt about it! This chair is just like the ones we got at home!
It's got exactly the same colour and design!
This case is definitely fishy, Heiji!
That's what I've been sayin'.
Mission accomplished!
We could've just measured the height of the chair, you didn't have to be here, you know.
So the problem now is figuring out how the killer slipped past the police when coming in and out.
There might be some secret exit...
Just like Inspector Ōtaki said, the rope was passed through the AC vents...
There's something directly under the rope.
Pencil sharpenings?
It looks like the man living here liked to use pencils.
But why would there be a pile of sharpenings lying here?
It's obvious from looking around that he was a neat freak —
he even had a cleaning robot!
And that rubbish bin lying on its side in the corner...
If he was a neat freak, he wouldn't have just ignored it...
Hey, Hattori.
Could this actually be...
Yeah.
The answer's probably this thing.
Hey, Heiji!
What are you doin', turnin' that thing on?
Solvin' the mystery.
Mizuki-san didn't stand on the chair when he hanged himself.
He used this long and thin bin!
He placed it right under the rope, and probably turned it over to make it easier to stand on.
As proof of that, you can see pencil sharpenings lying on the floor here.
The stuff stuck at the bottom of the bin fell out when he turned it over.
Look.
If you used this, it'd be higher than the chair and his feet would reach, right?
But Hei-chan, that wasn't like that when we were here before...
Don't worry about that.
When he hung himself, if he knocked over the bin so that it falls between the legs of the chair...
...then you'd just need the cleanin' robot to push it into the corner before goin' back to its chargin' point,
and you'd end up with the weird crime scene we found.
As proof of this, the robot only cleans along this route.
He probably got the robot to remember the route by puttin' all sorts of obstructions along it.
H-Hold on!
Then this case...
Yeah. However you look at it, it's just a suicide.
You okay, Heiji?
You're that depressed?
But why did Mizuki-san choose to die like that?
Apparently Mizuki-san stacked up a huge debt from buying and selling shares.
He seemed to have held a grudge against the stockbroker responsible for that.
He even said at a bar that he'd "drag that bastard down to hell with him".
So maybe he wanted to frame the stockbroker.
But unfortunately for him, he was being watched by the police,
so his case got cleared up as a suicide without them even suspecting it was murder.
By the way, does that broker live nearby?
You could say "nearby", all right. He moved to this block last year.
I think his name was...
Fuura-san on the second floor, right?
He's been causing trouble for everyone living here.
He introduces people to stocks while they're waiting for the lift and so on...
You make a profit at first.
But the moment you start giving him a lot of money, then "bang", you've made a massive loss.
He even caught my husband with his scam.
It was really tough trying to stop him!
I see...
The man's a damn grim reaper! He even looks like one!
With those hollow eyes, sunken cheeks, and that sickly, pale face...
Speak of the devil!
Wha—
What?!
Damn it! He's goin' up to another floor!
Ōtaki-han! Where are the stairs?
Umm, I think they were...
You live here, so you ought to know, right?
Ah, screw it! We'll find them ourselves!
Wait!
It might be coming back down.
What?
You were re-investigating a case that had been closed as a suicide?
Yeah. Something bothered me about it, so I took a day off and came over from Ōsaka,
but after investigating, it turned out it really was a suicide.
And just when I thought I'd get in the lift and go home with Mouri-san and the rest, we came across this scene.
I-I see.
The deceased is Kaizō Fuura-san, who lived on the second floor.
Kaizō Fuura (52)
Stockbroker
It seems that he was a stockbroker.
Right?
Y-Yeah!
And who's she?
This is Nanami-san from the third floor. She was about to go down in the lift with us when it happened.
Apparently she goes to the beauty salon at this time every week.
So you're saying the lift doors opened and this was what you saw?
Not quite.
Just when we caught sight of Fuura-san through the window of the lift headin' up,
he shot himself with a gun.
It's like he wanted to show us his death!
And the lift kept going upward?
Yeah. We thought about goin' up the stairs to see what floor he was going to,
but the lift came down straight away, and when the doors opened...
...it was like this!
So I guess it's a pretty straightforward suicide.
Yeah. And there's this message that seems to have been left behind.
"G-Goodbye"?
See the can of spray paint rolling around by his feet?
He might've used that to write his message before he died.
A-As his final words?
Whichever way you look at it, this time it's definitely...
...murder.
I'm sayin' that whichever way you look at this, it's definitely a murder!
This is a murder?!
Yeah.
Stop messin' around!
That case you said was a murder earlier turned out to be a suicide!
Have a good look at the surveillance camera above the floor number display.
It's been covered up with spray, right?
I-It's true.
I called the security office for these flats to check, and apparently a hand holdin' a spray can appeared on the screen and painted out the camera.
Somebody probably didn't want to be caught on camera in the lift, so they stretched their hand round and spray-painted it.
Maybe he just didn't want his death to be recorded by the surveillance camera.
But one thing was clearly shown in that recording.
Somebody's right hand holding a spray can!
Of course it'd be a right hand.
Most Japanese people are right-handed, after all.
Hold on.
This guy's holding his gun in his left hand. Wouldn't that mean he's left-handed?
Everybody knew that Fuura-san's left-handed.
I get it! He was already holding the gun in his other hand...
Are you sayin' he changed hands just to write that "goodbye"?
Besides, the watch this guy's wearing...
There's nothing strange about a left-handed person wearing a watch on his left wrist.
Not that! It's stopped.
It stopped at the time we found the body.
Then maybe it ran out of batteries or broke when he fell?
But this watch...
...is automatic!
Isn't this the kind of watch that winds up by itself when you're walking?
Look, if you shake it, it still works! Isn't that odd?
I-Indeed.
That's probably because whoever killed Fuura-san and dressed this up as a suicide put the watch on him either before or after his death.
We still don't know why.
But at least we know that the killer is still somewhere above this floor!
I called the security office on the first floor as soon as we found the body, and had them watch the stairs.
And nobody went down the stairs before you cops arrived.
Then why don't we go and check each of the flats?
O-Okay.
Why don't we start from the fourth floor?
T-Three flats?!
You only found three suspicious flats?
But this is a seven-storey building, and there must be tens of flats above the third floor!
Yeah. Apparently many of the residents moved out after the suicide last month.
Anyway, those three are the only residents who live alone and don't have anyone to verify their alibis.
Well, why don't we go and listen to what those three people have to say one more time?
Because I bet our opponent hadn't thought we'd suspect him this quickly.
Oh, no. Heiji flicked on his switch.
And it's almost time for our bullet train home. Now what?
Looks like you'll have to stay over at our place.
A-A murder?
Fuura-san didn't kill himself?
Well, the possibility came up that it was a murder.
But how would you know something like that?
Isao Mutsu (45)
Block resident
Nanami-san was tweeting about it online.
"The grim reaper shot himself in our lift."
Oh, "grim reaper" is the nickname Nanami-san came up with for him.
I thought she was just playin' around with her phone, but she was tweetin'!
Would you mind if we came inside?
O-Oh, not at all.
By the way, what's your occupation?
I'm an office worker at a building maintenance company.
We do stuff like intercoms, delivery lockers and ACs.
So you do lift and security maintenance too, right?
W-Well, yeah...
Who are those boys anyway?
Oh, don't mind them.
Oh, yeah, how were you related to the late Fuura-san?
Your name was in Fuura-san's mobile phone address book.
Oh, I was involved in some share trading.
Then did you make a massive loss on the stock market and have a grudge against Fuura-san too?
I-I did have a grudge, but not enough to kill him!
Then could you just put out your hand...
Hand...?
You're not going to arrest me straight away, are you?!
Of course not.
We just want to check for gunshot residue that might've got stuck on your hands or cuffs when the gun was fired.
We have forensics here, you see...
Yeah, I lost quite a sum on the stock market on Fuura-san's recommendations, but I don't have any bad feelings.
It's my own fault for not seeing how the shares were going.
It stinks of paint thinner in here.
Yeah, I was just adding some colour to the severed head.
S-Severed head?
We're making a slasher horror film at university right now...
Takurō Yoda (21)
Block resident
We're gonna use it in that!
That's pretty well-made...
Looks just like the real thing!
If Ran saw that, she'd probably faint.
Actually, I made it to look like my dad.
Then if you wanted, you could probably make...
...a severed head that looks just like Fuura-san, right?
So in that movie of yours, are you going to film any scenes where people get shot with a gun?
Not really.
We're filming a lot of stabbing, cutting, and slicing.
You have one of these too?
A watch like Fuura-san's.
Yeah. It was a gift from him when I first made a profit from the stock market.
Come to think of it, Mutsu-san earlier had one too.
Well, looks like yours is working just fine.
That's because I always keep it on my wrist.
I only took it off now to make sure it wouldn't get paint on it.
Anyway, we're going to check you for gunpowder residue, so could you put out your hands?
Sure, but...
I was painting, so they look like this.
Yeah, I got a watch like that from Fuura-san too.
Naoko Izutsu (32)
Block resident
To celebrate turning a profit on my shares.
Though I only wore mine once, then tucked it away at the back of a drawer.
Umm... What's your occupation, Izutsu-san?
Can't you see for yourself?
A tracing stand, screen-tone, a cutter knife, a dip pen, a mapping pen, brushes, Indian ink, and regular ink.
I'm a manga artist! Haven't you ever heard the pen name "Kotori Misono"?
Isn't that the manga series with a beautiful female detective Chiba fanboys over?
Which would suggest you could easily come up with some story
about how somebody could kill a person in a lift and make it look like he killed himself with a gun.
If I'd come up with a plot gem like that, I'd write it into my manga!
It's too good a trick to waste on killing a guy like that.
Hey, why do you have four tracing stands?
Three are for my assistants.
We finished the manuscript in the morning, so they went home.
I'd expect a manga artist's place to be full of books, but you don't have all that many.
You're right. Just a few manga volumes.
That's a bygone era now.
I'm not like manga artists from the olden days.
Umm, just to make sure, we'd like to check your hands.
I don't mind it, but...
It's a shame, really.
As you can see, I just got out of the bath.
Gunpowder residue washes off with water, doesn't it?
Mouri-san, did you figure anything out?
No, I'm clueless...
All three are a bit suspicious and a bit not...
No. The killer is probably the one who hid those things...
The problem is the trick...
How did they kill Fuura-san?
It wasn't just a message disguised as his final words...
Look! It's Detective Takagi!
Bang!
On the next Conan: Everybody Witnessed It (Part II)!
Next Conan's Hint: The sprayed characters!
sokudo
kokudō
kakudo
Angle, motorway, speed...
What're those?
Excuses for the next time I blurt out "Kudō".