Heiji Hattori, Kazuha Tōyama and Inspector Ōtaki from the Ōsaka Police visited Tōkyō to investigate a case that started in Ōsaka.
Ran, old man Mouri and I went with them to the crime scene, a room in a flat in Tōkyō.
But we confirmed it was a suicide, and easily closed the case.
But as we were waiting for the lift as we left the crime scene...
Speak of the devil!
What?!
It looked like a suicide at first glance,
but many things just didn't add up, leading to a murder investigation.
Following Detective Takagi's questioning, we were able to narrow it down to three suspects.
By the way, what's your occupation?
I'm an office worker at a building maintenance company.
We do stuff like intercoms, delivery lockers and ACs.
So you do lift and security maintenance too, right?
By the way, how were you related to the late Fuura-san?
Your name was in Fuura-san's mobile phone address book.
Oh, I was involved in some share trading.
Then did you make a massive loss on the stock market and have a grudge against Fuura-san too?
Isao Mutsu (45)
Block Resident
I-I did have a grudge, but not enough to kill him!
Yeah, I lost quite a sum on the stock market on Fuura-san's recommendations, but I don't have any bad feelings.
Takurō Yoda (21)
Block Resident
It's my own fault for not seeing how the shares were going.
It stinks of paint thinner in here.
Yeah, I was just adding some colour to the severed head.
S-Severed head?
Actually, I just made it to look like my dad.
Then if you wanted, you could probably make...
...a severed head that looks just like Fuura-san, right?
Umm...
What's your occupation, Izutsu-san?
Naoko Izutsu (32)
Block Resident
Can't you see for yourself?
A tracing stand, screen-tone, a cutter knife, a dip pen, a mapping pen, brushes, Indian ink, and regular ink.
I'm a manga artist! Haven't you ever heard the pen name 'Kotori Misono'?
Isn't that the manga series with a beautiful female detective Chiba fanboys over?
Which would suggest you could easily come up with some story
about how somebody could kill a person in a lift and make it look like he killed himself with a gun.
If I'd come up with a plot gem like that, I'd write it into my manga!
The killer is probably the one who hid those things...
The problem is the trick...
How did they kill Fuura-san?
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
A case inside a sealed lift.
Hattori and I reveal the shocking trick!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
EVERYBODY WITNESSED IT
(PART II)
Geez, that Heiji...
What's taking him so long?
Now, now...
We already decided you'll stay over at our place.
I know, but...
Ah, he's back.
So, how did it go? Did you figure out who the killer is?
No. We heard what the three suspects have to say.
And they're all a bit suspicious and a bit not...
Though all three of them could have a potential motive.
No, the killer's probably that person.
The issue is the trick...
Oh, yeah, apparently there were posters on all lift doors except those on the 2nd and 3rd floors saying 'The lift is undergoing inspection.'
I see. That's how they kept people away.
If it was a suicide, you'd think Fuura-san would put up those signs so nobody would stop him.
Yes...
Look, if we can't figure it out, shouldn't we try callin' Kudō-kun?
Call Shin'ichi?
Yeah.
At that family restaurant case earlier, he solved the case in a flash when Conan-kun called him.
You moron. He ain't figured anythin' out yet either.
You know, that might not be a bad idea.
Because it takes the two of you to do the job of one.
Hold on! Who says it takes the two of us—
Takes two...
...to do the job of one?
Hold on.
If this thing was used...
I see! That's why—
Yeah. Those letters saying 'goodbye'...
They weren't just a message, disguised as the final words of the dead.
The killer wrote it because it was necessary...
...in order to complete the trick!
What? Really?
They didn't find any gunshot residue on any of the three suspects?
Yes, we've confirmed it.
We had a report from forensics earlier.
I see.
I'm sorry for being late.
I'm Megure, of the Tōkyō Police.
I'm Ōtaki, of the Ōsaka Police.
I apologise too.
I shouldn't have been sticking my nose into a case in another prefecture.
No, no, I heard from Takagi that you've been a great help in the initial investigations.
However, is this really a murder?
You saw the deceased, Fuura-san, shoot himself in the head through the lift window, right?
Speak of the devil!
Y-Yes.
So isn't it an obvious suicide?
I thought so at first too...
But the surveillance camera inside the lift was spray-painted using a non-dominant hand,
and the watch the deceased was wearing had stopped...
That led me to believe something wasn't right.
Those points are indeed rather curious, but you saw the moment when Fuura-san killed himself.
Inspector!
The answer to your question is this.
The killer put his gun to Fuura-san's head in the lift and said something like this...
'If you don't want to get shot, keep looking out the window.'
He then shot him when the lift was passing through this floor.
And to those of us who saw it, it really looked like a suicide.
Isn't that impossible?
Regardless of the circumstances, you'd usually be able to tell, right?
If the hand on the side was the killer's hand, the position of the hand holding the gun wouldn't match with Fuura-san's body, would it?
She's right. If I was the killer, I wouldn't do anything like that. That's a pretty obvious special effect.
And if that was the case, wouldn't Fuura-san try to fight back?
It's hard to believe he'd appear calm enough to make it look like a suicide.
Are these three the suspects you...
Yeah — they're the residents from these flats without alibis.
But why are you here?
We didn't just come here for the sake of it.
We were called out.
This kid told us we'd find the truth behind the case if we came here.
That's right. I brought these three here, just like Detective Takagi and Heiji-niichan told me to.
Conan-kun!
Hey, Conan-kun, where's Heiji?
I ain't seen him for an hour now.
He said he was going somewhere with Takagi-san.
Apparently, they had some business with the shop at the back of this block.
A shop at the back?
A shop at the back...
I think...
That's it! The back!
The killer hid behind Fuura-san's back and shot him.
If he did that, it'd look more natural than a gun coming from the side, wouldn't it?
If that was the case, then when Fuura-san was killed, his head would've moved from the impact and allowed us to see the killer's face!
Oh, yeah...
Oh! It's Detective Takagi!
Bang!
H-Hey, what are you doing, Takagi?
Oh! It's Detective Takagi!
Bang!
H-Hey, what are you doing?!
But what we saw...
It was just like that!
So it was two people standing one behind the other!
Takagi and the Ōsakan detective brat just demonstrated it!
I guess if you do it well, it looks natural.
That Takagi...
Hurry back and explain, Takagi!
Ah, right!
Detective Takagi!
Ah, no...
Takagi, can we get some explanations?
I don't know. Hattori-kun just told me to stand here and watch everybody's reactions.
Watch our reactions?
How long have you been there?
Since a little before the lift came up.
That's impossible! We saw you in the lift!
T-That's because that was—
Ah! Detective Takagi's in the lift again!
In other words, this is the truth behind the trick.
A-A tablet PC?
Yeah. I had Detective Takagi borrow this from the electronics shop at the back of the block.
Then I pressed the tablet against the lift window, and played back the movie I'd made of Detective Takagi's face.
Bang!
The lift windows are divided by the letters saying 'goodbye',
so you wouldn't be able to tell it was a tablet.
In the end, even though it was all my body apart from the head,
it really looked as though Detective Takagi was on the lift, right?
In other words, with the tablet and my body,
two were needed to do the job of one!
But Hei-chan, isn't that impossible?
Hei-chan, you just pretended to be shot.
But we saw him shooting himself in the head with a gun.
If what you say is right, then while pressing the tablet to the window,
the killer would have to shoot right in front of his eyes, which is pretty dangerous.
And there's no guarantee that the move would work with the footage on the tablet.
Plus, you ought to be able to find the extra hole from this gunshot in the lift wall.
No, no. We only used one tablet because we didn't have enough time!
The killer probably used four tablets!
If you had four, then you could run footage being sure the movements would match.
F-Four?!
So everything we saw was a video?!
Yeah.
Apart from the face, the footage was all of the killer wearing the same suit as Fuura-san.
But can you really hold up four tablets in one hand?
Yeah, you're right...
The killer probably stuck the four tablets into a large board.
Then all they'd have to do is lean the board against the lift doors.
Ain't that right?
Miss manga artist who tried to hide the fact that she had four tablets, Naoko Izutsu-san?
You're the killer, right?
H-Hold on!
Anybody who had four tablets could've pulled off that trick just now!
Why does that make me the killer?
Because you hid your tablets!
That little gizmo on your desk next to the tracing stand — that was a mobile router, wasn't it?
Possessing such a thing but not possessing a PC or a tablet of some kind to get on the net is just plain weird!
I don't know what you're talking about!
Maybe my editor left it behind!
I'm bad with technology, so I don't use a PC.
Wow, manga artists are pretty cool, huh?
Because you draw a detective manga series, right?
But you only have a couple of manga volumes on your shelf!
It's amazing that you can imagine and draw all these kinds of things straight from your head!
Indeed, if it's a detective manga, then unlike with a fantasy or fairy tale, you need to have some degree of realism.
Like backgrounds to use as crime scenes, or a weapon like a gun.
It would be impossible to draw that without some kind of resource.
Come to think of it, Izutsu-san did said she has three assistants.
So with a tablet for each assistant and one for her, that makes four.
But how could she take a footage of Fuura-san of him shooting himself?
It's not like she could ask him to pretend to be shot!
That's easy.
When filming a video like this, just jerk the camera sideways and...
See! You can make it look like you're being shot!
And you wouldn't be able to see a bullet, anyway.
The objects in the background would end up being blurred, but even so, it'd be hard to tell where it is since there's nothing in a lift, huh?
It's true!
Amazing, Conan-kun!
Well, I heard all of this from Heiji-niichan.
Right, Heiji-niichan?
Y-Yeah.
Suddenly I feel like I've become Sleepin' Kogorō...
But if we didn't just happen to be waiting for the lifts at that time, then the trick wouldn't—
It wasn't for us.
The target was Nanami-san, who goes to the beauty salon at this time every week!
First, Izutsu-san invited Fuura-san to a nearby shop, pretendin' she'd like to introduce him to a new client interested in stocks and shares.
Then she said she'd go ahead and wait in front of the lift while askin' him to wear the same suit as the one in the video.
With that done, Izutsu-san, who'd arrived first at the lift, sprayed up the security camera,
then closed the doors, wrote 'goodbye', and opened them up again.
With the inspection notices, nobody was gonna press the button to call it, so the lift stayed where it was.
After that, you shot Fuura-san dead while he was stunned by the 'goodbye' on the inside of the lift.
And finally, you waited around until the time Nanami-san would go to the beauty salon.
Of course, you'd pressed the button on your own floor above the third floor which Nanami-san usually got on, and kept the door open.
Around the time Nanami-san would come to the lift, you closed the doors and put up the board with the four tablets against them.
Then you timed the footage in a way that the scene of Fuura-san puttin' the gun to his head would display as you passed the third floor.
I see. Then all she'd have to do is get off on the floor that her own room is in and get away with the board to make a perfect crime.
Nobody can ever create a perfect crime.
You can see for yourself with all the errors Izutsu-san made.
One was holdin' out your left hand when the police asked to check you for gunpowder residue.
Gunpowder residue washes off with water, doesn't it?
You held your towel, book and lighter in your right hand, so you're right-handed, right?
In line with Fuura-san bein' left-handed, you shot him with your left hand.
Because if you shot him with your right hand, the traces of residue left on the grip wouldn't match.
Another pointer was the automatic watch.
Fuura-san was wearin' a different watch than the one you used in your video,
so you switched it with the watch he'd given you, didn't you?
In order to match the times, you shook it a little to make it work.
Well, those two who wear their watches all the time probably know
that if you only shake the watch just a little, it'll stop pretty quickly.
The fact that you didn't know that shows you're the killer...
That watch wasn't mine.
The watch I got from Fuura-san was for ladies and was a bit slimmer.
Then whose was it?
It was Mizuki-sensei's.
You know, the old guy who hung himself in this block of flats last month?
'Sensei'? You mean...
He was the teacher in charge of my class in high school.
Though I had no idea we lived in the same block until I bumped into him in the lift.
Then this murder was just to get revenge on the man who pushed your mentor to suicide?
Well, there's that too.
But mostly, it's just because I got a bit sad.
Sad?
After Sensei hung himself, I remembered that he still had an album from high school that I'd lent to him.
When I asked the warden to let me into Sensei's room, I realised it...
That he'd set up a trick to make it look like he was killed by somebody while he actually committed suicide.
Isn't it sad?
If that was one of my manga, a detective would come up with a deduction and work this out.
But in this case, nobody noticed the trick and the whole thing was immediately closed as a suicide.
So I wanted Sensei's goal to be achieved.
Otherwise, as a mystery, it would never have a proper ending.
Kimi no Egao ga Nani Yori mo Suki Datta
(I loved your smile more than anything else)
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
Mouri-san, you'll let me stay over at your place, too?
Sure.
It'd be pretty hard to find a hotel at this time.
Thank you so much.
Hold on!
Are you sayin' that you, me, Ōtaki-han and the kid,
all four of us are gonna have to all sleep together in your room?!
It's gonna be a bit tight.
Then, Conan-kun, how about you come and sleep with us?
You're right.
We could fit Conan-kun between us both like a sandwich!
If you two are okay with it, then—
Watch it, you little pervert.
Oh, excuse me.
Hello? Ōtaki here.
It's me.
Director-general?!
What happened for you to call me this late?
A troublesome case just came up.
It's not really under our jurisdiction, so I was thinking of turning it down,
but since you're in Tōkyō right now, I figured I'd ask you something.
W-What problematic case?
Ōtaki, do you believe they really exist in this world?
Vampires...
If you go there for me, do take care...
The inheritance discussion in question will take place after the evening meal.
You haven't found your boss yet?
No. Even though we all split apart to search for him.
A coffin?!
You shouldn't get inside one of these things before you die!
(ONE)
HEIJI HATTORI AND THE VAMPIRE MANSION
On the next Conan: 'Heiji Hattori and the Vampire Mansion (One)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Coffin!
Hattori, are you sleeping?
I'm suckin' blood.
Ah, yeah, that's next week.