So sorry for having imposed on you like this...
And even having breakfast at your place...
It's nothing, really...
Well, it was due to an unexpected turn of events, after all!
Liar. You planned on staying over from the start.
You even had a change of clothes ready.
All right, Ran-chan, see you later!
Later!
Well then, I'll get going as well.
Please stop by again the next time you're free.
Will do! Now, please excuse me.
Oh?
Ōtaki-han, where are you goin'?
Tōkyō Station's this way, y'know?
Ah, you kids can go on home without me. I've got some minor business to take care of over here still.
I see...
The location is on the boundary between Gunma and Saitama prefectures,
a western-style mansion built in the mountain recesses.
There, tomorrow night, a meeting will be held to discuss an inheritance.
Can you attend that meeting for me?
Heizō Hattori
Ōsaka Police Superintendent · Heiji's Father
According to the client's story, the person whose will is being discussed, the master of the mansion,
has been exhibiting truly strange behaviour.
That's why he wants someone from the police to also attend the discussion.
Well, I don't have a problem with that.
Now there was a killing in the forest near that mansion a half-year ago
and some odd rumours surfaced, so I can't say this is without cause, but if you go there for me, do take care...
...that you don't get your blood sucked out.
What are you sayin' about bein' sucked?
You've been muttering 'Don't be sucked, don't be sucked' to yourself for a while now.
H-Hei-chan?!
Don't tell me, you're thinking about a woman's lips, right?
W-When did you get in here?!
We snuck in when you went to the toilet at the petrol station earlier, Inspector Ōtaki.
Didn't you notice?
That Uncle Kogorō and the others are following you.
B-But why...?
They want to gaze upon the face of the woman you're secretly meeting with, Ōtaki-han!
Though I never thought you'd have a woman over on this side.
Ran-neechan and the others said they wanted to be introduced to her.
Ah, well, she's not so good-looking as to be shown off to others.
Then will you tell us?
What kind of case is it?
It is a case, right? And since you kept it from me, that means it has somethin' to do with ol' Dad, doesn't it?
Well, actually, at the mansion I am headed to, half a year ago, a woman's corpse was found in the surrounding woods.
She was tied upside-down to a stake that was driven into the ground, in a cruel pose.
That's harsh.
That lady was employed as the mansion's maid, but...
Since the appearance of the corpse was really odd...
What do you mean by odd?
The corpse was found by an old couple. change}
But since her skin was unnaturally white, at first they mistook her for an upside-down scarecrow intended to ward off bears.
Wouldn't that just be because she died from blood loss due to a sliced artery, and was tied there?
But there weren't any big wounds like that. change of wording}
The only things were two holes punctured in the nape of her neck.
Death by blood loss with two holes in the nape of her neck?
H-Hey, that wouldn't be...
Yeah.
Ōtaki, do you think vampires exist in this world?
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
Dracula's real?!
The curtains open to a shocking case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
HEIJI HATTORI AND THE VAMPIRE MANSION
(ONE)
A-A vampire?!
Do you mean to say that killing was the work of a vampire?!
It's just a baseless rumour.
Since this area used to be governed by a daimyō who was sorta vampire-like.
Daimyō?
And? That murderer hasn't been arrested yet?
Yeah...
But wasn't there at least a suspect?
Yeah. The first one to be suspected was the master of the mansion, Hakuya Torakura-san.
Hakuya Torakura (57)
Torakura Family Head
It seems the murdered maid had confided in the mansion's chef...
'The master has been acting really weird lately,'
'and I feel like I'm in danger, so I want to quit being a maid.'
Then as expected, that master...?
Ah, no...
He had an alibi.
At the approximate time that the maid, Shimizu-san, died,
the master had been cooped up in his room sleeping the entire time.
Ironically, the one who testified to that effect was the same chef whom Shimizu-san had confided in.
I extend a warm welcome. Inspector Ōtaki from the Ōsaka police, I presume?
Ah, yes.
So you must be the client?
Rikushige Koga (71)
Torakura Family Butler
I am Koga, the butler. I was a classmate of Superintendent Hattori's father.
Say, what was it? The 'strange behaviour' the master has supposedly been showing lately?
Oh, recently the master has started doing things such as sleeping in his room all through the day to try and avoid the sunlight,
suddenly throwing out all of his beloved silver tableware, saying that he was allergic to silver...
And the other day, he smashed the bowl of his favourite soup with garlic in it into pieces...
He said, 'It makes my blood rot, so never use garlic again!', in an extreme rage.
H-Hey, that's almost as if...
Yes.
I'm sure to the maid Shimizu-san it appeared that way.
As if he had become a vampire.
V-Vampire?!
Just now, did you just say 'vampire'?
What do vampires have to do with this?
Ah, that is...
Ah, that's it! He said bumper, bumper!
We're just discussing what to do since the bumper of the rental car got dented!
Oh, so it was 'bumper'?
Hey, Heiji, let's all hurry and go inside!
It's amazing, just like a castle!
Oh?
Well then, as the sun wanes and the time for the master to rise draws near,
please relax inside the mansion until the preparations for dinner are complete.
Ah, yes, sir.
For the inheritance discussion in question will take place after dinner...
Hey, I wonder if Inspector Ōtaki's darling really is inside this mansion.
She still believes that?
This is amazing!
I've only ever seen something like this in movies or dramas. To think I'm actually experiencing it!
You said it.
It feels like we've also become aristocrats!
Who are you lot?
Ruri Torakura (38)
Asanobu's Wife
Don't tell me you lot are our brother's illegitimate children, now!
There's no way that could be, is there?
Asanobu Torakura (52)
Second son of the Torakura family
If that had been the case, there would have been no reason for Brother to have called us here.
That's right. If they really were illegitimate children, Hakuya's inheritance wouldn't go to us, his siblings.
Kamiyo Torakura (60)
First-born daughter of the Torakura family
The full amount would go to his children.
But who knows, eh?
After all, didn't he suddenly bring her here years ago?
His considerably younger, beautiful fiancée.
Jōhei Hagawa (29)
Kamiyo's Lover
It wouldn't be strange at all if he had two or three illegitimate children, you know.
Well, that fiancée unfortunately died soon after.
Oh, I see. That was pretty lucky for you guys, wasn't it?
H-Hey...
Kishiharu Tarakura (45)
Third Son of the Torakura Family
Watch it! If you keep going on about it again, you won't be laughing at the end!
W-What?
I'm sure you thought it was a stroke of luck, right?
Oh, what's this? Could it be that you and that mistress-with-kids really had an affair or something?
W-Why, you...
Can we stop talking about mistresses?
After all, I was a child born from Father's mistress.
Mina Torakura (26)
Second daughter of the Torakura family
Well, legally speaking, if there aren't any heirs besides siblings,
the inheritance would be equally divided. So let's all get along.
Umm...
Hikaru Hinohara (24)
Torakura Family Maid
The chef asked me to come and see if it'd be okay with everyone if he started serving now.
But if you're not done with your conversation, I'll tell him to wait a bit.
We can still talk while we're eating, so go ahead and bring out the food!
Either way, since you're just his wife's son, it has no bearing on you.
This is shapin' up to be some inheritance battle.
I know, right?
An incurable illness?
Hakuya Torakura-san, the master of this household, is terminally ill?
Yeah. He has half a year or so left.
Oh? Wasn't it three months?
That's why we came to this dinner party, you know.
Well, the invitation said 'if you don't attend, you won't receive any inheritance', after all.
On that note, isn't Brother late?
You're right. At this point, he'd usually be complaining about the food.
Sorry to ask you this, but could you two girls go and wake him up?
Wait, us?
If you turn right at the hallway, it's the last room.
Good idea. Hakuya might be in a better mood if he's woken up by young ladies.
Umm, he said the last room...
Must be this one, right?
But don't you think it's weird?
Would you normally ask guests to do this kind of thing?
Huh?
There ain't any bed.
Wh— No way!
A coffin?!
Oh, I see!
When they had us go to wake him, I thought everyone was smirkin'...
They were tryin' to scare us by makin' us see this old guy sleepin' inside a coffin!
You shouldn't get inside one of these things before you die!
What is it? What happened?!
T-The old man inside is—
He's just sleeping.
I'm sure Brother sleeps there lately because he figures he'll end up there eventually.
But he had blood all over him and there was a stake stabbed in his chest!
B-Blood?
Brother really went overboard with the joke this time.
It's no joke — he was really dead!
What's with this?!
It won't open!
The old man ain't in here?
No way!
Was he really in here?
Yes, I'm sure he was...
Then are you sayin' he turned into fog and disappeared?!
As if he was some sort of monster...
That can't be!
The old man really was lyin' inside the coffin!
He had a stake stabbed into his chest, blood all over, was wearin' a black cloak...
...and had long pointy ears and fang-like teeth!
Almost as if...
...he was Count Dracula himself!
He looked like...
...Count Dracula?
Come to think of it, Brother had that nickname since he was a child.
Hakuya Torakura becomes Count Dracula?
dorakyura
hakushaku
A pretty childish nickname, huh?
But, that nickname might not just be a pun on his name, you know.
If you consider the Torakura family ancestors...
You're right.
And if you add Hakuya's mysterious behaviour as of late...
Maybe he did get possessed...
...by a vampire.
She's joking, she's joking.
Brother's ears aren't pointy, and he doesn't have fangs.
If you two saw Brother like that, then he probably just dressed up as a monster to scare you.
Though I don't know what trick he used to disappear from that coffin.
Well, magically disappearing in an instant...
You typically see vampires doing that in movies and whatnot, right?
Are you trying to treat Brother as a monster?
I'm not the only one who thinks that.
Right, Mr. Butler?
You thought so too — that's why you brought these people here, right?
Y-Yes.
Since the master's behaviour has been rather odd as of late,
I asked these police detectives to be present during the inheritance discussion.
P-Police detectives?
I'm Ōtaki, from the Ōsaka Police.
And this is the private detective, Kogorō Mouri-san.
No way!
You wouldn't be Sleeping Kogorō?
The one and only!
Umm...
The meal's gone cold, so should I heat it up again?
Hey, Ōtaki-han, sorry for buttin' in, but...
Can you swab this red spot in the coffin and have the nearby police examine it?
If it's like Kazuha said, this should be Hakuya-san's blood.
In the end, Brother-in-law never showed up.
Well, the invitation said the discussion was after dinner.
Well, he never said the discussion would be in the dining room, though.
Hey, Conan-kun. Dad's not around, is he?
Uncle took the car with Inspector Ōtaki to buy cigarettes.
Hey, want to get that photo over and done with?
What photo?
When the family gathers up like this, we always take a photo together.
It started three generations ago.
But are you gonna take the photo even though the master ain't here?
Yeah. When we were taking the photo last year, Brother suddenly popped into the room and said 'Include me!', so...
Yeah.
If we all sound like we're enjoying ourselves, Brother might suddenly show up.
Mina, lift your chin a little.
Hey, Sis! Are you gonna stop messing with your hair?
You're not gonna get any younger no matter how long you mess with it!
Oh, hush, you.
Don't worry.
You're still beautiful, honey.
Thanks.
Okay, when I get in place over there, please push this shutter button.
Okay.
Get ready, everyone!
All right!
Chee—
What are you yellin' about?
Just now, behind everyone...
The old man from the coffin was...
Where is he?
He was there just then...
Between Jōhei-san and Kamiyo-san!
With a pale face, floating as if he were a ghost...
Yeah! What I saw gave off that kind of feeling, too!
Will you two stop that already?!
I'm sure you came with those detectives because you heard all about the uproar over vampires,
but don't go screaming at some imaginary thing like you're in a haunted house!
Uproar over vampires?
What's that about?
Huh? You really don't know?
Half a year ago, in the woods near this mansion,
Shimizu-san, who'd been employed here as a maid, was found dead.
All the blood from her body had been drained, and she'd been tied upside-down to a stake that had been driven into the ground.
To make things worse, there were two holes in the body's neck, so there was a huge commotion.
Everyone was saying 'vampire'!
Anyway, we should split up and look for Brother.
At this rate, he could turn out to be a monster for real!
Heiji, is this for real?
That story about the vampire...
Yeah...
If we'd told you girls, you'd have wanted to go home right away,
and we figured we'd have to go home with you too, so we kept quiet.
What? They're gone.
Over there.
Hey, you two! Where are you going?!
You want to eat something with garlic?
But didn't you just eat dinner?
But there wasn't any garlic in it!
If you just let us use this kitchen and the ingredients, we can make the food ourselves!
But lately, the master has taken to dislike garlic,
so I don't know if we even have any.
Don't trouble yourself.
We'll look for it ourselves.
Garlic to ward off vampires, huh?
Well, it's standard.
Huh? This fridge won't open.
Oh, that's a fridge the master just bought and had installed.
It's locked.
A locked fridge?
Why?
I dunno.
I heard it was supposed to have some fine meat for tonight's guests, but in the end, it wasn't used, huh?
Hey...
Was it you?
Were you the one who testified in the case half a year ago that the master had an alibi?
Y-Yes.
If I recall, you said the master had been cooped up in his room sleeping the whole time.
Yeah, I'm sure about it.
He wanted to sample the soup as soon as he woke up that day,
so he told me, the chef, to bring it to him and wake him up as soon as it was ready.
So then, you weren't watchin' the coffin the whole time, were you?
No, but there's no way he'd have come out.
Before he closed the lid on the coffin, he said that he felt like somebody'd been opening its lid
and looking at his sleeping face recently.
So he asked if I could put something on top of the lid.
Therefore, I put three sesame seeds on top of the lid.
And when I came to wake him up, they were just where I'd left them.
That means the coffin's lid hadn't been opened, right?
Which means that this coffin is what's suspicious, but...
There don't seem to be any gaps in the tiles under the coffin.
Yeah.
But why was the lid closed?
The lid only opens this far.
Normally, when someone sees a corpse, they get surprised and let go of the lid.
No, I mean, when we first tried to open the lid, it wouldn't open, right?
You're right...
Plus, for some reason, this room gives me an uneasy feeling.
What was that sound?
It sounded pretty far away.
Hey, look at that!
The forest's on fire!
A cave-in?!
You're sayin' that the tunnel collapsed due to an unexplained explosion?!
Yes, that's what I was told when I called to find out earlier.
You've got to be kidding me! That's the only road here!
It seems it'll take some time before it's restored.
Geez, this isn't the time to be searching for Brother.
Then the master hasn't been found yet?
No, even though we split up to look for him.
By the way, has anyone seen my honey?
I haven't seen her for a while.
Now that you mention it, I haven't seen Kishiharu-niisan either.
Well, Kishiharu said he was going to try and develop the photo we took earlier,
so he made his room into a darkroom.
Using an analogue camera in this day and age is pretty rare, though.
Sorry for being an analogue freak.
But thanks to that, I know what happened to our brother.
Huh? You found Brother?
Yeah. He's here in the photo.
In the photo?!
Like the girls said, he was right next to us in the room where we took the picture.
Having been reduced into a monster that can slip through walls...
Kimi no Egao ga Nani Yori mo Suki Datta
(I loved your smile more than anything else)
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
Why is Brother-in-law in this photo when he wasn't there at the time?!
I'm certain they should've been able to see the master there at that time.
The blood found inside the the coffin the master slept in really was type AB?
Counting those associated with this mansion, I believe the only one with type AB was the maid Shimizu-san, who died half a year ago.
(TWO)
HEIJI HATTORI AND THE VAMPIRE MANSION
On the next Conan: 'Heiji Hattori and the Vampire Mansion (Two)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Garlic!
Hattori, what are you looking for?
Garlic, a cross and a silver spoon!
Hey, calm down!