We got suspicious about Inspector Ōtaki's strange behaviour, and ended up going with him to a western-style mansion hidden in a forest.
There, a group of siblings in a rather uneasy mood gathered together to discuss their inheritance.
While the master of the mansion was missing, they tried to take a family photo,
but the master, who wasn't supposed to be there, was captured on it in an ominous state.
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
The mystery grows ever deeper.
Will the Dracula case ever be solved?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Wait, what is this?! It's almost like ghost photography!
Ruri Torakura (38)
Asanobu's Wife
Why's brother-in-law in this photo? He wasn't there at the time!
I have no idea.
Kishiharu Torakura (45)
Third Son of the Torakura Family
Don't tell me — you did something to the photo when you developed it, right?
Jōhei Hagawa (29)
Kamiyo's Boyfriend
Don't be stupid! You can't pull a trick like that with analogue film this quickly!
Asanobu Torakura (52)
Second son of the Torakura family
T-Then did Brother really turn into a vampire, like the rumours said?!
That's ridiculous!
Mina Torakura (26)
Second daughter of the Torakura family
Vampires don't exist outside of stuff like horror movies and novels!
Him disappearing from the casket and the ghost photo were tricks that Hakuya-niisan set up!
I don't think so.
The master's in the same place where the girls said they saw him.
And I think they really did see him there back then.
Either way, it would be prudent to find the master at once and have him explain the circumstances behind these incidents to us.
Rikushige Koga (71)
Torakura Family Butler
Yeah.
You're right.
Oh, mind if we borrow that photo for a bit?
We want to take it to the kitchen to have Ran-neechan and Kazuha-neechan confirm whether the photo matches what they saw.
And they ain't here, huh?
The chefs are gone, too.
Right now, they're all probably eating in another room.
Hikaru Hinohara (24)
Torakura Family Maid
We maids usually eat with them, but...
Since I was searching for the master, I missed it.
If I remember correctly, you were the child that the master's fiancée brought with her, right?
Ah, yes.
How did your mother die?
I heard it was an accident.
But at the time I was hospitalised in the master's hospital due to a weak constitution, so I don't know the details...
The master worked at a hospital?
Yes. He was the director of Torakura General Hospital.
He was very kind. He even paid for my hospitalisation and surgery fees!
So he's the reason you work as a maid here?
That's right!
I'm looking after the master who my mother was going to marry!
Well, what actually happened was that half a year ago, back when I was unemployed after graduating from university,
I got an invitation from the master saying 'there's an opening as a maid, so won't you come?'
That's why I'm not used to this mansion yet.
This morning, even though the master called for me, I didn't know which room, so I ended up standing him up.
So the master's going to be mad when we find him, huh?
I-It's fine! He's never been mad at me since I came here.
Though the others do complain about him being too strict at checking the cleaning.
It is a pretty shoddy job, you know.
Look here, at the floor.
There's flour or something all over!
Isn't that those girls' doing?
When I told them there weren't any gyōza skins, they said they'd make some themselves
and asked where the bread and wheat flours were...
They probably spilled some since they were in a rush.
After all, they placed the cloth for the finished skins on their lap and bundled them into clingfilm.
The first thing to come to mind with garlic were gyōza, huh?
But what's this wide gap here?
See, for about fifty centimetres, there isn't any flour!
As if something'd been dragged through here.
Speaking of which...
I told those girls that there might still be a bag of garlic in the storeroom.
If they'd dragged that bag here, then they'd probably still be here.
I found the garlic, Ran-chan!
Wow, there's so much!
Oh no...
It already started sproutin' and growin' roots...
Don't worry!
It won't taste as good, but you can still eat it as long as you cut them off.
But are we going to be okay with just garlic?
I got this, so we're covered!
A-A cross?!
Yeah! It's made from a silver knife and spoon so it's super effective!
But for this kind of thing to work, don't you have to be a devout Christian?
It's fine! Ran-chan, you celebrate Christmas, don't you?
We celebrate Christ's birthday every year, so it's gotta work!
I guess.
What?! Type AB? The blood found inside the casket the master was sleeping in really was type AB?
Yeah.
Mouri-san put in a good word and had the Gunma prefecture police examine it, and there's no doubt it was type AB.
But according to the folks here at the mansion, the master's blood type...
It's type A.
When the master was younger, he suffered a serious injury.
I still remember that we were given the honour of him using our type A blood.
Then whose blood was it?
I believe the only one with type AB blood associated with this mansion was the maid Shimizu-san, who passed away half a year ago.
Say what?
Why would the blood of someone who died half a year ago be in that casket?
Don't tell me brother-in-law kept her blood and was drinking it inside the casket!
Shouldn't that blood be examinated for stuff like DNA?
And? Is it still gonna take long for the tunnel to be fixed?
Yeah. We told them we'd like to be able to cross it before morning, but...
And if anything happens to my daughter before then, there'll be hell to pay, you hear me?!
It's fine, don't worry.
The girls are distracted makin' gyōza anyway.
And what about the master?
Still haven't found him.
Even though we looked just about everywhere...
Did Asa-nii say anything?
He says he called brother-in-law's mobile a bunch of times, but it kept going to voicemail.
And? Where's he now?
I'm sure he's in the smoking room taking a puff.
I think Hakuya-niisan left his mobile phone somewhere.
What's up?
I-It's an e-mail.
From Hakuya-niisan!
It says, 'I'll tell everyone my answer, so gather in the dining room'.
Then this was a group mail?
A group mail?
In the end, the guy still ain't shown up.
Looks like we're gonna get some rain.
Hey, aren't you worried?
You still haven't found Kamiyo-neesan, have you?
My honey's the kind who'd suddenly take off somewhere on a whim.
You'd better keep a tight grip on her. She's your sugar mama, after all.
Well, if she dumps me, I can just hook up with you again.
Asa-nii, how long are you going to be smoking for, man?
Don't tell me he didn't get brother-in-law's message since he changed phones.
What?
J-Just now, there was a strange shadow at the window.
A strange shadow?
Don't tell me brother really...
T-Turned into a vampire...
T-There's no way!
He's got to be using a rope or something to be lowered upside-down like that!
A-Are you serious?! He disappeared into the sky!
That's ridiculous. It's not humanly possible!
H-Hold on, that over there...
H-Hey, Hattori, what's that?
I-It's a bird, right?
B-But isn't it a little too big to be a bird?
Kudō?! You're bleedin', man!
No way, you weren't bitten by something, were you?!
What are you talking about? I just got rained on a bit.
That ain't rain.
The roof! There's blood drippin' from the roof!
What's above here? Are there any rooms?
Y-Yes.
In the attic, there's a smoking room.
W-What is this about the smoking room?!
The blood's probably dripping down from there!
It can't be...
Wasn't Asa-nii in there?
It's no good. His carotid artery's been cut. He's dead.
He's holding the knife himself.
So that means...
He was going to be attacked by someone, and took his own life instead.
Or...
Someone wanted it to look that way...
Which one was it?
Dear?!
Then, I've got to hurry up and find my honey, or...
That's right. Kamiyo-neesan might've already been taken by the vampirised Hakuya-niisan,
and hung upside down from a stake, like in the legends.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey.
Could you tell us about it?
About that legend.
The master said it was a story from the Edo period.
The feudal lord who once governed this area was an ancestor of the Torakura family. It's said that he was dearly loved by his people.
However, at the time, rumours began to surface about the possibility of the childless feudal lord yielding the fiefdom to his younger brother.
Then, the feudal lord suddenly invited a beautiful woman to the castle to take the role of a concubine.
That concubine happily gave birth to an heir, and everyone at the castle was relieved. However...
One stormy night, an incident occurred...
An incident?
The story goes that the concubine fell from a cliff and was found with her abdomen pierced by a tree branch.
Thinking it odd, the feudal lord used tools he obtained from some foreigners to torture the concubine's aides.
And so, the truth came to light.
They told him that they'd tricked the concubine by telling her that the young prince hadn't returned from the forest yet.
Enraged, the feudal lord impaled his younger brother and his subordinates in the same way the concubine had been impaled,
and lined them up in the same forest.
Ever since, it seems that feudal lord's been called 'Lord Impaler'.
But that doesn't fit with being a vampire, does it?
Don't you know? The model for Count Dracula,
Vlad III of Wallachia, impaled all who opposed him.
He's known as 'The Impaling Prince'.
R-Really?
Yeah. Vlad III's father was 'Prince Dracul'...
...so as his son, he was called 'Dracula'.
Now that you've heard the story, would you like to take a look at the foreign torture room?
Foreign torture room?
I see.
That feudal lord kept the tools he bought from foreigners in this room.
There's even a guillotine!
I see! It was this room!
Remember, the master called for me this morning, but I didn't know where the torture room was.
Couldn't you have just asked someone?
No, the master said 'come to the foreign torture room without telling anyone'.
He particularly didn't want the butler noticing.
Of course, when you guys looked for the master, you searched this room too, right?
It was creepy, so I skipped it.
With all of this 'Lord Impaler' stuff, this torture room and that flying monster, we better not let the girls know about this.
And done! The gyōza are all wrapped!
We sure made a lot!
Now we just gotta cook 'em!
We have to let Conan-kun and the others have some, too!
Yeah!
Oh, no.
We just wanted to say that if you're going to use the stove, make sure to turn it off when you're done.
R-Right.
We know.
Good luck.
Should we really keep quiet about this murder?
They're better off not knowing.
You're right.
Okay, you guys!
Until we come back, none of you four are to leave this dining room!
But we have to find my honey!
Leave that to us and the butler.
Call us if anything happens, Hikaru-san.
Y-Yeah.
You did tell all the other maids and chefs to stay in the same room, right?
Yes. But our opponent is a vampire.
Can we really go just the three of us against him?
Don't be stupid! There ain't no such thing as vampires!
And we're going to find proof of that right now!
Let's start with this casket.
There's gotta be some mechanism to it.
Also, doesn't something feel different in this room from the first time we came here?
But the rug and the sofa are in the same place...
Oh, right, speaking of the casket. When that incident took place half a year ago,
it seems the master asked the chef to wake him up.
Ain't that the kind of thing you usually ask a maid or the butler?
I think the master didn't trust me.
After all, he'd make a suspicious face whenever I expressed disapproval at his odd actions.
Hey, look at this.
The rug's cut in two places!
Which means that if you pull this here, take this portion out, and put the ends together again, the rug becomes smaller, right?
W-What?!
So basically, when we came in, the coffin was closer to the centre of the room, over—
A handle on the tiles?
I see. It was this kind of trick.
Next up, that ghost photo.
We've more or less figured that out, right?
I knew it.
Hey, do they always use this wall as the backdrop when they take pictures?
Yes. The chairs are also in approximately the same positions.
In this instance, I understand the two young girls pressed the shutter button on the camera,
but the master had actually asked the maid, Hikaru-san, to do it.
Why?
I don't know.
It used to always be done by the maid who passed away, Shimizu-san.
Maybe he just figured that'd be her role, since she replaced Shimizu-san.
Well, that maid seems to have incurred the master's favour.
Hikaru-san said it.
That the master was very kind and never got mad at her.
T-That's preposterous!
The only things to come out of the master's mouth about her recently have been complaints!
But she said she was invited by the master to this mansion!
Nothing of the sort!
The master said she came here crying, using her status as his former fiancée's daughter to beg him to hire her.
Though she really is a very cheery girl, and the maids and chefs seem to love her.
But if she's saying that kind of nonsense, then she must've come here with some sort of ulterior motive.
Ulterior motive?
Has she told you about her mother, Yōko-sama?
Yeah, that she passed away because of an unfortunate accident.
It was a stormy night when she passed away.
Yōko-sama suddenly said she was going to drive to the master's hospital.
I said it was dangerous and tried to stop her,
but sure enough, she drove through a guardrail on the mountain path and fell off the cliff with the car.
According to the police, it was driver error due to low visibility.
But why would she do that on a day like that?
Just before she left, the master called.
He told me to tell Yōko-sama that her daughter's surgery was a success.
So the maid Shimizu-san said that she probably wanted to meet with her daughter as soon as possible.
But at the time, Yōko-sama looked pale and didn't seem like that at all.
Why Shimizu-san?
I instructed her to pass the master's message to Yōko-sama.
Was that car Yōko-san's?
No, it belonged to the deceased Asanobu-sama.
That day was the 13th anniversary of the former master's death, so everyone was at the mansion.
By 'everyone', you mean...
Yes.
Everyone that gathered here today was there.
So if that accident, like the one in the legend, was planned by someone...
D-Does Hikaru-san know about this?
I don't know.
The master instructed me not to tell her.
I believed he meant to tell her himself.
Hikaru-san was summoned by the master.
She said she didn't want to meet him, but...
If that was a lie, and she really did meet him...
Where's Hikaru-san?
She's not here, is she?
She said she was going to refill the tea.
She went to the kitchen.
The kitchen?
Anyway, aren't the police here yet? You did call them, right?
Yes, but they said the tunnel would take until morning to fix.
Did you find my honey yet?
Not yet.
I'm hungry.
Maybe I should have some of the gyōza the girls made.
How did you know the girls were making gyōza?
They came here earlier.
They came to borrow the freezer from Hikaru-san.
They wanted to freeze the extra gyōza they'd made, so they wanted to put them in the freezer.
Oh, yeah, after they borrowed the key, Hikaru-san basically followed them to the kitchen, didn't she?
That's right! There's one place...
...that hasn't been searched yet!
The freezer!
Could it be that inside...?
It's no good. This ain't the right key, either.
I wish it had labels saying which key is for what.
Well, we'll find the right key eventually.
I guess so.
We'll make it through with this garlic power!
The guard at the mansion just reported back...
...saying there's a dead body in the forest in front of the mansion!
What?!
Oh, so you're not with the police?
But by 'private eye', do you mean you're Detective Mouri's apprentice or something?
Huh? How pathetic does a guy have to be to work under that dimwit?!
On the next Conan: 'Heiji Hattori and the Vampire Mansion (Three)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Stake!
This case's getting pretty dangerous.
Yeah, it sucks...
...blood!