Suspicious about Inspector Ōtaki's odd behaviour, we ended up going with him to a western-style mansion hidden deep in the mountains.
There, a group of siblings in a rather uneasy mood gathered together to discuss their inheritance.
The concerned parties were brought to the dining room by the mansion's master via e-mail,
and they witnessed the master ominously floating outside the window, as a monster flew away.
That's when we found the second son's dead body.
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
Danger is approaching Ran and Kazuha.
Let's solve the mystery behind this bizarre phenomenon!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
This is bad, Kudō!
Yeah! If the murderer was the maid, Hikaru-san,
then it's likely her motive was to avenge her mother's death, who was killed and had her murder disguised as an accident!
And the ones who schemed for that accident were the murdered maid Shimizu-san from half a year ago,
and the second son, Asanobu-san, who was killed just now.
And if we assume that the eldest daughter, Kamiyo-san, who still ain't shown up since several hours ago,
played a part in that plot, then maybe she's already been murdered, and her body's been locked inside that freezer!
And if the girls are about to open that freezer...
The girls are in danger!
It's open!
I opened it, Ran-chan!
Great!
Still, that's some thunder.
Yeah. Kinda scary.
Well, we made a lot of gyōza!
Right, right! We'll make it through with all this garlic power!
Damn!
So it's true!
Kazuha!
Are you okay, Ran-neechan?!
H-Hikaru-san...
Hey, you!
Gyōza?
Hikaru Hinohara (24)
Torakura Family Maid
Ah, I was so hungry...
And when I smelled the gyōza, I just couldn't resist...
I sincerely apologise for gorging on them without asking!
Still, you've made them so tasty!
Why, thank you...
Thanks...
W-Well? Did you see inside the freezer?
Y-Yeah...
And something weird was in it...
See, a large can of dried seaweed...
It's to prevent the seaweed from gettin' moisturised. My mum also regularly puts that in her fridge, but...
We don't put in the can itself, do we?
Right.
And there's nothing else inside?
Right, it's a large freezer, and yet...
It's pretty weird that the only thing in here is this can.
Then, what was the trace I saw in front of the freezer that resembled a drag mark?
And what's in the top compartment?
It's a freezer too, and it wasn't locked.
And lots of cookin' in there.
Are you the only one who has
the key to the freezer, Hikaru-san?
Well, I think my master has it too...
In that case, are you in charge of all the keys in this mansion?
No, the only keys I have are for this kitchen and the nearby rooms.
And the other maids and butlers are in charge of the rest.
Excuse me, but everyone's still awake, right?
If so, would you mind callin' them up here?
We'll treat them to a late night gyōza snack!
I doubt they'd have any appetite after that incident, though.
Although I was pretty hungry.
That... incident?
Want to know?
I don't wanna know!
Well, it's all right...
'Cause almost half of the bizarre phenomena that occurred today have been solved.
And if everyone hears the explanation, maybe their appetite will come back, right?
Hey, are you for real? You actually solved the mystery?
Yeah, pretty much.
What mystery? Don't we know exactly who the culprit is?
Kishiharu Torakura (45)
3rd Son of the Torakura Family
Ruri Torakura (38)
Asanobu's Wife
Hakuya-oniisama was the one who killed my husband, right?
So did you figure out the reason why our brother turned into a vampire?
Mina Torakura (26)
2nd Daughter of the Torakura Family
Jhei Hagawa (29)
Kamiyo's Lover
Well, I understand it's tempting to think of it that way since too much bizarre stuff has happened.
Rikushige Koga (71)
Torakura Family Butler
But come on, do vampires really exist?
You can judge it yourself after you see the trick!
Here?
Are you telling us that Hakuya-niisan's disappearance from the casket was also a trick?
Yeah, it was a mystery to us back then 'cause we couldn't see any traces of the tiles under the casket havin' been tempered with...
But the position was off to begin with!
Position?
See!
There are slits in the middle of the carpet.
And only this portion will come off if we pull it out!
And if we pull the remaining carpet towards the gap...
We can see the entrance to the secret passage!
Secret passage?
The tiles are part of a sliding door, and a narrow staircase leads to the first floor storage room!
But there's no staircase in the storage room!
Only because you didn't notice!
A hidden door that moves with the cabinets serves as a camouflage, that's why.
That reminds me, after that trip, I did notice that the storage room had somehow become narrow.
That trip?
Yes.
Half a year ago, just before the maid Shimizu-san met her fate,
the master ordered all of us from the mansion to unwind and took us overseas for a week.
Which means construction workers were called to make that secret passage during the week.
H-Hold on...
I get the passage trick, but how did Brother manage to come out of the casket?
That's easy!
There's a sliding door inside the casket, too.
And although it looks like nothing's on the casket lid, there's actually a powerful magnet inside the seams.
And it looks like it'll be locked tight if you close it...
Until you deactivate it using this remote!
In other words...
With this remote, the casket, and the secret passage, somebody can freely disappear from inside the casket!
Of course, then he came out and killed the maid, Shimizu-san.
Then was our brother the one who killed Shimizu-san?
Most likely, yeah.
It seems that the guards to this mansion weren't hired until after Shimizu-san's incident.
So the crime was performed by callin' Shimizu-san to the forest beforehand,
pretendin' to be asleep in the casket, then exitin' to the outside through the storage and goin' for the kill!
Then where is our brother?
Who knows? He might be hidin' out somewhere, waitin' for his next victim.
N-No way!
But we'll be fine if we stick together.
Our opponent isn't a monster, after all.
Because if he was a vampire who could fly or pass through walls, he wouldn't have used a secret passage, right?
It's rainin' cats and dogs!
Talk about bad weather!
Still, everybody's late!
And to think we cooked so many gyōza...
By the way, Ran-chan, what do you think Hikaru-san meant back then by 'something like that happened' ?
I dunno, but I'd rather not think about it.
If the master we saw earlier really was a vampire, then Heiji and the others might've already been bitten and turned into vampires!
No way! Are you saying we're the only human beings left in this mansion?
That...
...can't be, right?
Oh, and I'm gettin' hungry after waitin' for so long!
Then why don't you just eat some?
We can just cook more when everybody comes.
Then was the ghost photo taken in this room a trick, too?
Yeah. Anyway, go ahead to the positions you were in when the photo was taken.
O-Okay.
Now, everybody smile more!
Heiji-niichan, relax! Relax!
Heiji-niichan?
What are you saying?
There's nobody in this room but us five.
He's right behind you.
Wait, what?!
That's not a mirror?!
It's a magic mirror!
It looks like a normal mirror when one side is dark, but if we illuminate the dark side, light will come through just like with glass.
It's easy to tell them apart, too!
Just press your finger against it!
Finger?
With a normal mirror, there'll be a gap between your finger and its reflection, since a reflective coating is applied to the glass's back surface.
But in a magic mirror, the reflective surface is on the front surface of the glass,
so an object and its reflection will
appear to be touching each other!
Also, if we shine light on it from this side,
we can see a lot of clothes hanging.
A lot of clothes?
Oh, I get it!
It's the closet in the next room!
Exactly!
There's a sliding door on the closet's back wall.
If opened, the magic mirror will appear at the spot where the mirror frame of the next room is.
And someone hiding in the closet would simply shine light on their face before the photo was taken
in order to make a ghost of
someone's face appear in the mirror!
Get it now?
The culprit had to employ tricks in order to appear as a monster, but they're still human!
So the culprit really was Hakuya-niisan?
Yeah, no doubt he's one of the culprits!
One of the culprits?
Are you saying there's an accomplice?!
The master was seriously ill, right?
Without help, he wouldn't have been able to move about without being seen!
That said, the primary suspect we have as his accomplice is the eldest daughter who's been hiding for so many hours!
Excuse me, the guard at the mansion gate just reported back.
He said there's a dead body in the forest in front of the mansion!
What now?!
It's the eldest daughter, Kamiyo-san!
Tied to a stake...
She was strangled.
You're the guards, right?
Did you see anyone who went out with this person?
Well, after that Ōtaki guy and a man with a moustache went out by car, nobody left through the gate.
It can't be! Then how did they sneak out the gate?!
Did they fly or something?!
Are you serious?!
After Ōtaki-han left in his car, you've
never opened the mansion gate?
Ah, actually...
We opened the gate just once.
A van from a furniture company came by.
Our chairs were getting old, so the master ordered bulk replacements several days ago.
But when we checked the delivered items, they had a sofa in there by mistake,
so we told the van's driver to
take those back for the time being.
That's when the explosion from earlier occurred.
From earlier? You mean the collapse of the tunnel?
Yeah. We couldn't look away for a while.
So someone could have slipped out the gate unnoticed by taking advantage of that moment.
But they would still get spotted if they returned to the mansion after tyin' the body to a stake in this forest, right?
Besides, why did the killer stop midway?
Midway?
Look! There's a hole dug up next to the body, right?
So they planned to tie the body to
a stake and pin it upside down?
Yeah.
If this was the same person who killed the maid Shimizu-san half a year ago, then they might've done it to drain her blood.
Another weird thing is that there's
a bruise mark on her right biceps.
And what caught my attention the most is the fact that the fingertips on both of her hands sustained friction wounds.
Yeah, and those don't look like
defensive wounds from fightin' back.
K-Kamiyo-neesan?
She was killed in the forest?!
Are you really sure it was my honey?!
Yeah.
N-No. Why?! Why?!
By the way, who did it?
The guards should have seen them, right?
The guards said that after Inspector Ōtaki left by car, no one else entered or exited the gate!
No one else?
Don't tell me...
Maybe there are other secret passages like the one before, and someone slipped out the gate through there?
We checked around the wall surrounding the mansion,
but didn't find any place someone could have slipped through.
The guards also mentioned there are security sensors on top of the wall, so they'd know if anyone tried to climb over.
Maybe through a hidden tunnel from inside the mansion?
But the mansion renovation your brother ordered only lasted a week, right?
There ain't no way to dig a tunnel that quickly!
Seriously?!
Then just how did the killer manage to get out through the gate?!
Not to mention, carrying Big Sister!
H-He flew...
Hakuya-oniisama must've turned into a vampire, and by flapping his ominous black wings...
Calm down, Ruri!
Didn't this young policeman tell us that there's no such thing as a vampire?
Policeman? No, no!
I'm Heiji Hattori! A high-school private eye from Ōsaka!
P-Private eye?
I did think you were too young to be a police detective.
Just some high-school brat?!
Well, once my investigation progresses a bit further, I'll need you guys to gather in this dinin' room again.
Hey—
Give me a break!
I only listened to you because
I thought you were with the police.
But see how my honey still got killed?!
We'll take care of our own lives from now on.
H-Hey, wait a sec!
Oh. So you're not with the police, huh?
But by 'private eye', do you mean you're Detective Mouri's apprentice or something?
Huh?! How pathetic does a guy have to be to work under that dimwit—
D-Damn right you are!
Although I'm finally at the point where Master Mouri is about to confer his full mastership on me...
Then did you figure it out?
The trick used to rotate Master's body...
Rotate?
See, the master's head was upside down outside the dining room window, right?
But before the curtains opened, the master's shadow lit up by the lightning came from below,
and it looked as if his body was transparent, like a ghost.
This was the window where
the master's head was seen, right?
Yeah.
How's it, Kudō?
Just as I thought.
Which means that thing in question...
They really thought this through, huh?
However, that trick is pretty complicated.
It ain't somethin' you could do right after arrivin' at the mansion.
Say, do the four people just now always come to this mansion?
They were here when I was a child and my mother brought me here, but it's the first time I've met them since I became a maid.
It has been approximately a year since everyone last visited.
All of them have been calling me about the master's health and current condition, but no one actually paid a visit.
In fact, that's why I thought maybe one of them was expecting, and the others gathered here to celebrate that.
Expecting?
Because the master made some online purchases for a kiddie pool and a toy aeroplane, which I thought were gifts for the coming baby.
After all, he'd also given me a number of clothes before I became a maid.
Any chance that aeroplane was the type that flaps?
Yeah, it said so on the receipt.
I thought the box was rather big for a child's toy.
But I asked Hagawa-sama and Kamiyo-sama about whether they were expecting,
and they laughed and said, 'No, nothing like that!'
And since Kishiharu-sama, who arrived afterwards,
had a large bag with him, I thought it had to be a present,
but he told it only had a camera and items for developing photos.
I also asked the same thing to the Asanobu couple, who came a little before you,
to which Ruri-san replied, 'Could it be that Mina-san made up with Hagawa-kun?'
So you asked Mina-san the same question too?
Yeah, since she came a little after you.
But she ignored me completely.
'Made up' ? So Hagawa-san
and Mina-san were dating?
Yes.
But Mina-sama's fiery proposal apparently caused Hagawa-sama a great deal of burden,
so lo and behold, he came to be with Kamiyo-sama.
Well then, what about Kishiharu-san and Ruri-san?
They were engaged, but after Yōko-sama's accidental death, Kishiharu-sama became severely depressed.
Their engagement dissolved, and Ruri-sama fell in love with Asanobu-sama, which led to their marriage.
Apparently, Kishiharu-sama had been very fond of Yōko-sama, who was the master's fiancée.
He cried even more profusely than the master on the day of Yōko-sama's funeral.
But the maids said that you, Mr. Butler, also wept many tears, or so I heard.
Adding that you must have been
on great terms with my mother.
T-That's...
All of that sounded pretty sordid to me.
Yeah. It looks like everybody has a motive.
Ah, an e-mail from Kishiharu-san!
Asking me to bring alcohol to his room...
So he knows your e-mail address?
Not just Kishiharu-san!
I also e-mailed everyone with an 'I'll be waiting for you' the day before they arrived here.
Why go the extra mile?
Because not long ago, the master gave me
all of their e-mail addresses via e-mail.
I figured that it was a hint for me to welcome everyone before they came, so I sent the message.
The master and I often message each other.
Then when he told you to 'come to
the foreign torture room', it was...
Yes, via e-mail!
See!
'After breakfast, come to the foreign torture room without telling anyone.'
'Whatever you do, don't alert the butler.'
But I didn't see this message until after noon.
That's also why I skipped out on his meeting.
You didn't notice the e-mail?
I left my phone charging at the toilet's basin and forgot about it.
Kishiharu-san's urging me to go!
Please excuse me then!
Judging from the message...
It didn't seem like the master hated her or anything.
No way! No one's coming to eat our gyōza?
Are they all asleep?
No, I think everyone's still awake.
But I guess they're just not in the mood.
At any rate, I reckon it'd be best if you two also went to bed soon.
No way...
They're so tasty, too!
But then again, the two of us almost gobbled them all up.
You're right.
What do we do if Conan-kun and the others come to eat?
We still have some ingredients left,
so we could just make more, right?
The killer has to be that person, right, Kudō?
Yeah. But we don't have any proof.
Plus...
The way Kamiyo-san was murdered.
Yeah, we still have an unsolved trick at hand.
How did the killer pass through the gates, and murder Kamiyo-san in the forest?
Is my daughter still okay?!
Now it's perfectly clear —
our opponent ain't some vampire with wings!
Yeah.
It's an evil creature all right...
But it's a murderer rather than a vampire!
On the next Conan: 'Heiji Hattori and the Vampire Mansion (Four)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Secret Passage!
Hattori, something doesn't smell right...
Sorry, was eating gyōza.
I meant about the case.