Following Inspector Ootaki whose behavior was suspicious,
we ended up going to a western-style building deep in the mountains.
There, we met with siblings who were restless over an inheritance.
Then as it was decided to take a family picture without the
head of the household whose whereabouts were unknown...
The master, who shouldn't have been there,
appeared in the picture in a weird state.
After that, as everyone gathered in the dining room due
to being called out by a text message from the master...
we witnessed the sinister sight of the master levitated
by the window and a monster flying in the sky.
And then, we found the second son dead.
Moreover, the body of the eldest daughter
was found in the mid of the forest.
And the siblings left behind decided to wait
until dawn in their separate rooms, yet...
The culprit is unmistakably that person!
Don't you agree, Kudou?
Yeah.
But we have no evidence at all.
How in the world did that person slip through the gate...
and kill Kamiyo-san in the mid of the forest?
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
The keen perceptive reasoning of the two...
illuminates the darkness of the Dracula case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
Looks like a child but has the intellect of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Ah, my bad.
I thought I'd make Ruri drink sake to calm
down, but seems like she fell asleep.
So just take it away.
I-I see.
My apologies. And to think I made you bring it all the way here...
Not at all.
Torakura Ruri (38)
Asanobu's wife
How about you, Kishiharu-san, then? Want some sake?
No, I'll pass.
I'll just head back to my room, lock the door and go to sleep.
Torakura Kishiharu (45)
Third son of the Torakura family
I've abstained from sake since the incident of Youko-san.
I see.
Hinohara Hikaru (24)
Torakura Household Maid
I told you to get the hell out!
Jouhei...
Leave me alone.
Geez.
And to think here I was about to comfort you.
What the hell's wrong with you?
Your sister was killed, yet you're not sad about it?!
Oh well, it's not like we have the same mother...
What's more, she was a formidable love rival.
So you mean to say the two of us are meant to be together?
Hagawa Jouhei (29)
Kamiyo's lover
Don't mess with me!
How cute!
Ah!
Oh, sake?
Can I have it?
Yes, definitely.
Torakura Mina (26)
Second daughter of the Torakura Family
For some reason, I'm really in the mood for drinking tonight.
Gunma Prefectural Police
Ehh?!
Since then, one more person was killed?!
Is that for real, Hei-chan?!
Yeah.
A phone was ringing in the middle of the
forest so the gatekeepers noticed it and—
My daughter's safe, isn't she?!
Well... she's leisurely making gyoza with Kazuha, you see.
Gyoza?
And then? You haven't figured out who the culprit is, yet?
Actually...
I've already figured that out.
Yeah.
Nobody can do this trick other than that person.
Then, bind them and handcuff them already! Handcuff them!
Handcuff...
I can't do that.
I don't have evidence and there still
remains a trick which I haven't solved yet.
Say, do you believe it's possible for
someone to slip out of the gate unnoticed,
strangle someone to death and then slip secretly back inside the gates?
Huh?
Naturally, there are sensors installed over the fences
and they are set up so it'll be known
immediately if anyone tries to climb over.
The only time the gatekeepers took their eyes
off the gates was when the tunnel collapsed.
How about it?
Well, couldn't they have killed Kamiyo-san
inside of the fences, tossed her out and run for it?
Are you an idiot?
How absurd do you think their strength is?!
Something's on my knee.
I did go down on one knee while inspecting
Kamiyo-san's body in the forest, but...
What is it?
Those white crystals...
which were mixed in with the mud.
This texture...
Could it be salt?!
But why was it in such a place?
Yeah, but no matter how much they trained by lifting
barbells in the gym, it'd still be impossible, wouldn't it?
Tying a body to a stick and—
Ah!
Ba...
Barbell?!
Now, I've clearly figured it out.
That the opponent isn't a vampire who
grew wings or anything of the sort.
Yeah.
They're a demon all right...
But they're more of a bloodthirsty killer!
Ah!
A text message from the master?!
Come to the Southeast Asia room to hear
the important topic you missed this morning.
Naturally, take extra care not to be noticed by anyone and come alone.
Torakura Hakuya.
What could it be about, I wonder.
Could it be the master's safe and he knows the identity of the culprit?
But he certainly looked vampire-ish, though...
Hikaru-san.
We need to talk for a moment.
O-Okay.
Expectedly, I'm starting to feel sleepy.
Oh, no! It's already five in the morning!
We have to go to sleep fast!
Oh, a phone call.
It's from Heiji.
What's it, Heiji?
You got hungry?
There're still plenty of gyoza left!
Eh?
Yeah... Yeah...
Yeah... Got it.
Leave it to me.
What did Hattori-kun say?
Ran-chan, do you have a hairpin on you?
Eh?
Master...
Master!
It's Hikaru.
I came here upon receiving your text message.
Master~
With this...
It's the end!
Umm...
Are you alright?
You shouldn't come out!
You only need to support us by voice!
G-Got it.
Huh?
They've disappeared!
T-They've really...
disappeared.
Damn!
M-My body's stuck.
Of course, it is.
This is a passage the master made especially for Hikaru-san.
There's no way it'd fit for your body, is there?
Hagawa Jouhei-san.
Since the master has been giving Hikaru-san clothes as presents...
he must've asked Hikaru-san about
her body size and came to know it.
Right.
The tragic events that occurred tonight were
serial murders entrusted by the master to Hikaru-san.
Those tricks in their entirety which the
master tried to tell to her this morning
by sending her a text message and calling
her out to the Southeast Asia room
You were the one who snatched them away, right?
The text message which was sent to Hikaru-san's
phone while it was left charging in the restroom...
We are well aware that you looked at it without permission.
After all, Hikaru-san didn't notice that
text message until well past noon.
W-Why me?!
Didn't Kishiharu-san who arrived before
noon also have the chance to look at it?
The message said "After breakfast, come
to the Southeast Asia room," you know.
If one saw such a text message just before noon, they'd
think the master's no longer waiting, wouldn't they?
Even if that text message was unread,
They'd either think the two met somewhere
by coincidence and talked over, or...
They'd at least think the master, who had
been stood up, gave up and went to sleep.
If someone were to have looked at that text
message and go to the Southeast Asia room...
It could've only been you or Kamiyo-san who
arrived here the previous day and stayed overnight.
And since Kamiyo-san was killed...
That leaves only you.
There's also the possibility that the butler
or the maids might've looked at it, but...
The fact that the master addressed such an
important matter by a text message means...
He was confident that there isn't a rude person who'd read
others' text messages without permission in the mansion.
And then, having become curious about what it could be...
You sneaked to the Southeast Asia room and ended up seeing it.
The dead sight of the master who cut off his head using the guillotine!
They must've been left beside his body.
The master's phone, the freezer's key, the tunnel's detonating switch...
As well as the plans for those serial murders!
D-Don't spout things as if you saw them happen yourselves!
Well, there are plenty of tricks in those
serial murders which couldn't be done...
unless the master's head was severed!
One of which is the trick behind the master's sudden disappearance from inside the coffin.
It'd have been rather easy if the master did it himself, however...
If it was someone else using his body, they wouldn't
have been able to do it unless it was just the head.
Despite us rushing over immediately upon hearing the screams
of the ladies as they saw the master dead inside the coffin...
You sneaked to the storage room below it and
used the secret passage to retrieve the head, right?
Most likely, of what Kazuha saw, only the head was real.
As for the body, you stuffed the clothes
with something to shape them up.
Were the body to be real as well, it'd have swayed and made noises
when you pulled it out of the coffin and it'd have been exposed.
Then, using the remote, you released the lock on the coffin's lid.
And while everyone was taken aback by the master's disappearance,
You carried the master's head to the closet in the room
next to the one where the picture was taken, right?
In order to have that ghost photography taken.
And since the closet had a bar for hanging hangers to begin with,
hanging the master's head was easy.
Since you did a such thing,
you arrived to the room with the coffin
a little late than everyone, right?
That ghost photography...
If it was you, who were beside the one-way mirror, who did it...
You'd be able to use your own body position to prevent
Kamiyo-san, who was beside you, from blocking the mirror.
At that time, if you had the remote for the light used
to light up the master's face inside of the closet...
Then by pressing it at the right time,
You'd be able to make the master's face emerge inside of the mirror.
And then, the last trick was making the master
appear upside-down at the dining room's window.
A strange shadow, you say?
You waited at the smoking room for Asanobu-san to come...
And after you seized a chance and killed
him by slicing open his carotid artery...
You passed a fishing line through the hinges
of the shutters in the smoking room...
then you made both ends hang next to the window of the dining room.
You attached the master's head on one end...
And hooked the other end to the window frame of the dining room.
So once the window had been opened, the thread
would be released and the head will fall down.
W-Wait a sec!
Didn't he disappear upwards when I opened the window?
If that was just the head, then couldn't
someone have been up there and pulled it up?
A convex lens.
The upper right pane of that window alone became
a convex lens just like a magnifying glass.
Through that lens, things appear inverted at a certain viewpoint.
That's why even though it fell downwards, it appeared as if it went upwards.
Moreover, the three panes below the convex lens are ordinary glass.
Naturally, if the head were to be seen
as it fell down, the trick won't work.
That's why this trick couldn't have
been done by anyone other than you,
who blocked the view of the lower three
panes with your own body at the time.
Where the head fell into was an urn left in advance in the
veranda outside that window, along with the flowerpots.
When we went to check afterwards, only that urn was
set aside and the master's head was still inside of it.
Well, had Hikaru-san not told us "The master's shadow which
was lit up by lightning appeared from below on the curtains,"
we wouldn't have noticed.
Right after that, The huge bird we saw was...
a wing-flapping airplane.
If you left it on the roof outside of the smoking room and
started its motor by a remote just before opening the window...
It'd fly away in the sky just as you open
the window and that was your setup.
Well, the airplane is bound to be found later somewhere in the forest.
In-In that case, what about the one who killed honey in the forest?
Are you saying I'm the one who did that as well?!
The gatekeepers only looked aside for a single
moment, and honey was tied to a stick, right?
For me, who never left the mansion, doing such a thing is just—
Ice wheels!
You attached ice wheels to the stick, which the
strangled Kamiyo-san was tied to, just like a barbell!
Then you blew up the tunnel and in the instant
the gatekeepers were distracted by it,
If you'd rolled it from the top of the stairs in front of the gate...
The body will, while suffering injuries
to its fingertips, pass through the gate,
bump into a tree and stop in the middle of the forest.
Then, you just had to estimate the time necessary for the ice to melt...
and ring Kamiyo-san's phone to make the gatekeepers discover it.
Tonight's hot and humid, and what's more rain had been falling down.
And since it seems the ice was made with salt mixed in, it melted easily.
Incidentally, the ice wheels were made by the key-locked freezer.
You put up the seaweed can in the
middle of the pool intended for kids...
and in order to make two wheels, you divided
it up at the halfway mark by a paper or something.
And since you took out those wheels from the
freezer and rolled them all the way until the stairs...
Of the flour the ladies spilled on the flour, only
the portion about the width of the wheels came off.
Geez. Even though these brats have no
evidence, they dare say whatever they like!
As for evidence, you have it on you, right?
The reason why you didn't delete the master's
text message from Hikaru-san's phone...
was to pin all of the crimes on her, afterwards.
H-Hey...
That's why we thought you'd call Hikaru-san somewhere to silence her.
Because you had this murder plan which was
made for Hikaru-san by the master on you.
That's the evidence, Hagawa Jouhei-san.
Since it says on this plan, "Call Hagawa-san to the Southeast Asia
room, kill him, lock the door, and get out through this passage,"
You wanted to make it seem as if Hikaru-san
called you out, according to the plan...
And as she attacked you, you killed her in self-defense, is that it?
And then, if you left the plan beside
Hikaru-san's body and called everyone...
Your plan of the bloodthirsty killer being killed by their
own victim while on spree would be completed, right?
Damn!
How could such brats figure it out...
It wasn't supposed to come to light!
It was when you said to examine the blood found inside the coffin
more throughly that I had my eye on you and began to suspect you.
W-Why?
That was just blood that dripped
when I put the head inside the coffin.
That blood was determined as a different blood type
from the person's blood type itself, you know!
It was obviously an error made by the police!
The blood spot we found at the coffin
back then, was it really of type AB?
Actually, shouldn't we have that blood examined more in depth?
Like checking the DNA.
The master probably had cancer.
At its terminal stage, it is also possible for the blood type to change.
If it's type A, it becomes type AB.
And if it's type O, it becomes type B.
For one to be able to say it was a lab test error from the very beginning...
they can only be the culprit, who actually
placed the master's head inside the coffin.
Well, it seems that your blood, due to following this plan...
has pitifully changed into the blood of a brutal bloodthirsty killer.
My dear daughter?!
The beginning of that plan opened with "my dear daughter"?
Yeah.
To keep the mansion's fine butler from figuring it
out, it seems that the master has lied to him, but...
From the will and the DNA test found in the
master's room, there's no doubt about it.
So he really tried to make his daughter commit serial murders?!
That's right.
He deliberately put on fake fangs to make everyone believe
the crimes were his doing after having turned into a vampire...
The motive was revenge to Youko-san who was ought to be his wife.
Apparently, Hagawa-san, who was arrested, has spilled the beans.
Youko-san's accidental death was plotted by the maid
Shimizu-san, Kamiyo-san, Asanobu-san and himself.
In that case, as we thought, the incident
of Shimizu-san from half a year ago...
...must be the deed of the master.
While the will said that he sucked the blood himself,
the master was a doctor so he must have made
her take a drug which works as a blood thinner,
then he inserted a catheter in her artery and drew the blood out.
Moreover, the reason he tied Shimizu-san
to a stick and put it upside-down...
was to make the ice wheels trick harder to figure out.
Nevertheless, had Hikaru-san been the first to see the plans...
It would've been alright.
Eh?
This was written at the end of the plans.
"However, if you're to forgive everything...
Torakura Hakuya
then along with the revenge flames invested in my body,
dispose of this letter."
I believe Hikaru-san would've surely chosen the latter.
I bet.
However, that Hagawa guy is really an outrageous bastard.
To think he anticipated he'd be able to go back with Mina-san...
He put his lover to death according to plan,
and still tried to seize the money...
Well, there is no denying he was a foolish man.
You should take good care as much as possible!
Women are scary.
Huh?!
What are you saying?
Ah, w-wait...
This smell...
Just how many gyoza did you eat?!
Next Episode
To tell the truth, this letter was delivered to my place.
Izumi Jisaborou-shi's life is being targeted.
Huh?
I can't let my guard down in front of any of them.
However, let's trust the little boy who saved me.
Next on Conan: Dancing Demon at the Nou Mask Mansion (Part One)
Spoon
Look Forward to Next Episode
Well done, Kudou.
Up next, after gyoza, is Okonomiyaki at Osaka.
Actually, lemme have some gyoza.