The plan takes all contingencies into account.
Everything is set to make it look like an accident.
I've already prepared the poison.
Soon we'll find out whether his blood is as red as ours.
Fortunately for us, the museum will be closed next Sunday.
No staff members beside us will be there.
Very well.
We should get this over with as soon as possible.
Speaking of which, Seikanji-san...
You're in a hurry since you have to repay your loan soon, right?
What are you...?!
If you're going to bring that up, I should remind you the manager's embezzlement has been found out,
and he'll be fired at the end of the month.
You're one to talk, given your heavy losses from investing in worthless shares.
I guess it's just me then.
I'm the only one who isn't in a hurry to get this over with.
Is that right?
We all know you're anxious that he could strike you from his will any day, being his ex.
Now, now. Quarrelling will get us nowhere.
We only have one common goal:
The death of Jisaburō Izumi.
That's why we have gathered here.
Moyono-san, let me confirm once more:
Should we be successful in killing Jisaburō, you'll divide half of the fortune that you inherit between us three.
The person who kills him receives 80%, and the other two receive 10% each to keep quiet.
Somehow it seems that I'm the only one losing out here, but I have no choice.
If I try it on my own and end up being exposed, I'll lose everything.
And if we work together, we'll have a better chance for success.
Very well. Then we'll carry out the plan next Sunday.
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
A dangerous conversation in the Noh mask museum.
What secrets do their three masks hide?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
What's this? Looks like they're closed.
You're right.
It doesn't matter. We have urgent business after all.
Yes?
I'd like to see the curator please.
I'm sorry.
The museum is closed today, so the curator is not available.
Excuse me! I'm Naruya Akaza.
I have an appointment with Izumi-san.
Oh, Moyono Mibu-san, right? Long time no see.
Moyono Mibu (38)
Noh Mask Museum Accountant and Receptionist
Let me open the front door.
Excuse me, Sir, you can't just walk in!
As I just informed you, we're closed today.
Ah, please don't mind me. I've come here to see the curator on urgent business.
The curator?
Urgent business?
I received this letter.
Saying that Mr. Jisaburō Izumi's life is in danger.
'Mr. Jisaburō Izumi's life is in danger.'
'The culprit will likely make his move soon.'
'I will await your arrival, Great Detective Mouri.'
And there's no name given for the sender.
What will you do, Dad?
This Izumi guy's rich, right?
If you were to protect him, maybe...
All right! Let's go, Ran!
If I ignored a letter like that, it'd blemish my reputation as a great detective!
Geez, we don't even know whether the letter's for real or not...
Actually, I just wanted to go see the Noh masks.
And so I decided to come and investigate.
And who are you?
I probably should have said earlier. Here's my card.
You're the great detective, Sleeping Kogorō?!
Well, people call me that, yes.
I'm an old acquaintance of Izumi's.
But I'm surprised that you'd bring a kid along when investigating a murder threat.
Naruya Akaza (40)
Acquaintance of Jisaburō's / Promoter
Well, the kid really wanted to see the Noh masks.
I see.
Your daughter has very refined tastes, it seems.
Thank you.
How on earth did that leak out?
Seinosuke Nagata (60)
Noh Mask Museum Manager
Tatsurō Seikanji (45)
Noh Mask Museum Executive
Who'd have thought a great detective like him would come here?
It might be better to put our plan on hold.
Where is the curator?
It's just about time for his visit to the mansion god.
That's why Akaza's leading them there.
I-It's too late to stop!
Don't tell me you put a trap there?
This is bad.
What's the mansion god?
There has been a shrine to his ancestors in the northwest of the grounds since ancient times.
Is Mr. Izumi a very religious person?
Well, a lot of people resent him, so he certainly has a good reason to pray.
Ah, there he is!
Good morning, Curator Izumi.
Jisaburō Izumi (65)
Noh Mask Museum Owner
Akaza-kun. Right on time, it seems.
Hatsuho Toba (28)
Jisaburō's Assigned Nurse
And? Who would you be?
I'm used to threatening letters, you know. No need to fuss about it.
The sender went out of their way to send it to me.
I don't think it's just an empty threat.
Run!
Over there!
If it hadn't been for these kids, I would have been crushed by that lumber.
Go get me another wheelchair!
Y-Yes! I'll do it now.
Not you.
What are you waiting for?!
Y-Yes, of course.
Damn! Lucky old geezer.
I can't let my guard down around anyone here.
But I think I can trust the boy who saved me.
And the young lady as well.
Mister, you never know what may happen.
So you should take precautions, don't you think?
That's true.
But what kind of precautions?
For example, what's exhibited over there?
Medals and odoshi.
They're plaited cords, arranged in belt form and used as decoration.
Odoshi are a part of traditional armour.
Then they're probably very sturdy, right?
What about it?
Is that a wasp? It's rather big!
It's going to kill me!
Don't exaggerate.
That's not it — it's a hornet.
Curator Izumi's already been stung once.
Oh, no! He could die from anaphylactic shock!
There's another one!
Why, you! How about this? And this?
Hey, that's my jacket...
What do you think about my cherished collection, Mr. Sleeping Kogorō?
Well, the masks really are splendid.
Do they fit me too?
The museum staff usually wear masks to enhance the atmosphere.
They're called kuwaemen. You can wear one just by holding onto this protrusion here with your teeth.
Though of course, you can't talk while wearing it.
That's why the curator says they help preserve a quiet atmosphere.
The creator of these masks was a friend of mine, Kodō Matsumoto.
He got married a number of times...
But in the end I was the one who looked after him until he died.
It's because you have an eye for artists.
As a result, I was given the opportunity to exhibit his works posthumously.
With that accident happening and the hornets flying around, it seems like that letter was telling the truth.
This museum was originally a mansion built during my grandfather's time.
The only thing that remains from that time is the mansion's heart, this fireplace.
This place is called the yokoza, it's where the master of the house would sit.
Did you know that, kid?
Huh? Know what?
It's still raw!
Under the glow of the fire, the whole family would amuse themselves with stories.
面
白い
And look! In the light of the fire the mask looks white, right?
面白い
The word 'omoshiroi', meaning 'interesting', evolved from that.
Oh, that's interesting.
There used to be a lattice up there known as a fire rack, to which the pot-hook was fastened.
But it's gone now because it got in the way.
That wooden fish is a charm to keep the fire in check, I think.
Damn! Not again!
I can't believe that chestnut popped out just then!
We've all gone and failed, it seems.
Let round two begin!
This is lunch?
I ordered some catering as thanks for saving me.
Very kind of you. I accept!
I don't care about you. The kids are the ones who saved me!
I've brought a little something.
Washed-rind cheese from Burgundy.
You just returned from France, didn't you?
Then should I open some wine as well?
Looks delicious!
The smell's so strong that some people call it 'the smell of God's feet'.
But if you give it a try, it has a rich, milky flavour.
You usually just scoop some up with
a spoon and eat it as-is.
Executive and manager, come and join us.
No, we couldn't.
Or are you confessing to being the culprit behind those three pranks?
D-Don't be silly.
Well, if you insist.
Yes, come, come. Sit wherever you wish.
Since if we all eat together, I'll know it's not poisoned.
Hatsuho, will you be so good as to taste it?
Yes.
It's delicious!
I should hope so. What do you think, Akaza-kun?
Which of these two white wines would fit better?
I'd have to know what it tastes like first.
Then take a spoonful, too.
All right then.
It's a truly profound taste that...
This scent clearly shows he was poisoned.
That's insane!
Who put poison in there, and when?
Nobody move!
Where are you going, Mr. Executive?
Ah, well, to call the police.
We'll take care of that, so please stay here.
Ran!
I'm on it.
Don't touch the cheese!
Dad, I can't reach them. Seems like we're out of range here.
There's a phone in the kitchen over there. I'll go make the call.
Then tell Inspector Megure from Police HQ that Kogorō Mouri asked you to call.
Ah, yes.
Hello? Is this the police? One of our guests has been poisoned.
Please come quickly.
Even if they race here it will take the police 20 minutes.
Do I have to stay covered in cheese in the meantime?
No, that won't do.
Toba-san, was it?
Ah, yes.
Please clean just his immediate surroundings and leave the rest as it is.
Understood.
They'll be here soon.
Moyono Mibu...
She couldn't have put in the poison.
Executive Seikanji and Manager Nagata....
Those two didn't get close to the cheese either.
And either way, Toba-san tried the cheese first, so there was no poison in it at that point.
Was it put in afterwards?
No, no one had the chance to do that.
Which means that maybe the poison wasn't in the cheese, but on the butter knife.
Say, where did you get this butter knife from?
There was one on everyone's bread plate.
And without knowing who would sit where, it would be impossible to target someone specifically.
Hey, kid, we're leaving!
This is much better.
Don't you think so, Mouri-san?
Absolutely!
Please be patient until the police arrive, everyone.
Ran! Where's the brat?
What's this? I thought he was over there.
I'm getting some coffee for the curator, so I'll look for the boy as well.
Thank you.
That call to the police earlier was a bit weird.
Wait, isn't this an internal phone?
You in there, kid?
Kid?
That woman...
That's...!
Mouse! There's a mouse!
Did the coffee spill?
I'm sorry.
Excuse me, the curator's wondering when the coffee will be ready.
Right away!
I'll help!
No thanks!
This time she didn't have a chance to slip any poison in.
So there was a motive for killing Akaza-san?
He flattered me a lot, but apparently he was a vicious businessman.
Excuse my tardiness.
I don't want to die like Akaza.
Please stop joking.
Please don't worry.
No one would be foolish enough to try to poison you when the police are on their way here.
That's true.
Conan-kun, that was an internal phone, wasn't it?
And Dad seriously still believes the police are on their way?
Anyway, let's find a phone!
There's a phone!
What's the matter?
We need to call the police quickly.
I thought Mibu had already done so.
She was just pretending.
Ran-neechan, run away!
Don't move, Missy.
...so I said, aren't you gonna drink the whole thing?!
You didn't imagine that the three of us were working together, did you?
Wait here until we've dealt with the curator.
Then that Nagata guy's in on it too?
Damn!
Curator Izumi's in danger!
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
Oh, it's you.
Too bad, you were so close.
On the next Conan: 'Demons Dance at Noh Mask Mansion (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Chisel!
I heard there'll be some info about the movie today.
What? Lupin vs. Kogorō, is it?
It's Lupin vs. Conan.