Uncle Kogorō, Ran and I went to a Noh mask museum on the edge of the city,
because a letter warning of a plan to murder the owner of the museum had arrived at the Mouri Detective Agency.
The museum was closed, and in addition to the owner, Jisaburō Izumi,
Jisaburō Izumi (65)
Noh Mask Museum Owner
Hatsuho Toba (28)
Jisaburō's Appointed Nurse
his appointed nurse, Hatsuho Toba-san,
Tatsurō Seikanji (45)
Noh Mask Museum Executive
museum staff members Tatsurō Seikanji-san, Moyono Mibu-san and Seinosuke Nagata-san
Moyono Mibu (38)
Noh Mask Museum Accountant and Receptionist
Seinosuke Nagata (60)
Noh Mask Museum Manager
and Naruya Akaza-san, who had come to talk to the owner, were also there.
Naruya Akaza (40)
Acquaintance of Jisaburō's / Promoter
While the owner was showing us around the museum, his life was endangered several times,
but it was Akaza-san who ultimately ended up dead.
Ran and I found Moyono-san to be suspicious and sneaked into the office to call the police.
We need to call the police quickly.
I thought Mibu had already done so.
She was just pretending.
Ran-neechan, run away!
Don't move, Missy.
You didn't imagine that the three of us were working together, did you?
Wait here until we've dealt with the curator.
Then that Nagata guy's in on it too?
Damn!
Curator Izumi is in danger!
Seeking comprehensive answers, he clears all mysteries and codes!
The three culprits hatch an ominous plan!
Let's solve the murder mystery!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
...and fell asleep just like that.
What's this?
Hey, Missy!
It couldn't be.
Did they escape?
Those brats!
Awesome.
To tell you the truth, Mouri-san, this woman's actually the daughter of the mask artist Kodō.
Though her mother divorced him and went back to her maiden name, Mibu.
Sir!
You shouldn't mind.
It's not like it's a secret.
Whenever he was in a good mood, Kodō would carve masks over there.
You used to play there as well.
She was furious when she heard that Akaza was selling her father's creations on the cheap.
Of course, this means that she had a motive to kill him.
Please don't take that seriously, Mr. Great Detective.
I'll go and get some fresh tea.
Thank you.
The Inspector's really taking his time.
I'll go check the entrance hall.
She's a very attentive girl.
I don't know what I'd do without her.
Looks like the weights weren't enough.
Oh, it's you. Too bad, you were so close.
What's this? A vengeful spirit mask?
Nagata-san!
Why?
Fire!
Let's enter through that small door there!
Damn! It won't open!
The peg must be fastened.
Peg?
It's a little bolt for fastening sliding doors.
Those brats!
Curator!
It's all right!
Dad! Open this little door!
Dad!
Coming!
Take the curator outside!
I understand.
I'm opening it now.
Okay!
Where's the curator?
Toba-san took him outside just now.
And Moyono-san?
She went to get some tea a little while ago.
F-Fire?!
Damn it, how did that happen?!
Let's get out of here!
What's this? I can't open it!
Let's use the small door!
Our exit!
Over there! There's a door!
Ah, good thing you're here. Help me out here!
We've got about 20 minutes until the fire brigade arrives.
That was close.
This is...
The Noh theatre.
There's an exit!
The fire has already spread!
Dad, over there!
A demoness mask?
It's that woman! Hey, come down here!
Don't run away!
More importantly, how do we get out of here?
The ladder! If we climb up the ladder, we should be able to get outside through that small window.
That window up there...
Just close your eyes and you'll be fine.
You can do it, Dad!
This is bad, Ran-neechan. The next building's too far away!
Now what?!
We'll use the ladder as a bridge!
A-A bridge?!
Hurry up, Dad!
Don't be so hard on your father...
All together now!
We did it! This way we can reach the window via the ladder.
Don't look. Don't look. Don't—
Keep your eyes closed.
Just a bit further, Dad!
Somehow, it feels like we've suddenly come back to the present.
They must have built this annex more recently.
Either way, let's move! That woman was here.
There's gotta be a way out!
An internal phone?! Where's it coming from?
Yes? Ah, Toba-san. So you're safe.
Yes. I took the curator and went to the kitchen.
The fire hasn't reached here yet.
Be careful! To be safe from that executive and that Mibu woman, you should stay hidden for a while.
We informed the police, so it shouldn't be much lo—
Stop it, Sis!
What's happening?
'Sis'?
So Hatsuho-san is Moyono-san's little sister?
In any case, we should hurry. Something could happen to them!
Someone's lying there.
No way!
It's the executive.
That's the third victim!
Where are the others?
In the kitchen. Let's go!
Damn. We're too late!
Hatsuho-san!
Are you all right, Hatsuho-san?
I knew of the plan my sister and the others were hatching.
Yet in the end I had no choice but to kill her.
Stabbing my own sister!
I'm a horrible sister!
It's not your fault.
She might have killed you instead.
Even though the curator'd been warned, he...
What's that?
An iron skewer, and there's something floating there.
What is this?
Inspector Megure!
Naruya Akaza-san, Tatsurō Seikanji-san, Seinosuke Nagata-san, and Moyono Mibu-san have all been confirmed dead.
Curator Izumi narrowly escaped death.
That's good.
We can't question him yet, but since the wound has the same shape as the chisel that Mibu-san was holding,
we can conclude that she was the one to attack him.
Right.
A chisel?
Stop it, Sis!
I see!
That's how it was!
I didn't manage to stop her.
My sister bore a grudge against the curator.
Because he sold our father's creations cheaply overseas through Akaza-san.
And what was your opinion of him?
My sister and I have different mothers and grew up separately.
And the curator was very kind to me.
That's why you wanted to protect him when you heard about the plan to murder him.
Yes. So I sent a letter to Mouri-san,
but I couldn't stop my sister's madness.
Was she also the one who killed her accomplices: the executive and the manager?
Yes, I think so. She said that if the two of them died, she'd get all of the money.
I see.
Inspector.
Even though I hadn't planned it, I nonetheless killed my sister.
You grabbed a skewer from the kitchen, right?
I wanted to protect the curator, but please...
The fact that you killed Mibu-san remains unchanged, but it was a clear case of legitimate self-defence.
We'll need to hear a few more details at the station later.
I understand.
Mouri-kun! You'll have to come, too.
Of course.
Hey, the case is already...
...closed.
Not at all, Inspector.
Far from being closed, the culprit is cackling with glee over there.
What are you saying, Mouri-kun?
Dad, Hatsuho-san is the victim here.
The first mystery was how Akaza-san had been killed.
How did the culprit manage to poison the victim?
Right after Hatsuho-san ate a bit of cheese, Akaza-san ate the same cheese and died.
Does that mean the poison had been applied to Akaza-san's butter knife?
However, seats were chosen freely at that time, so it was impossible to target someone specifically.
There's only one way it could've been done.
With the spoon that was used to take some cheese the first time.
By applying poison only to the underside of the spoon, the cheese taken with the spoon would be fine,
but at the same time, the remaining cheese would be poisoned.
When Akaza-san died, the spoon that had fallen to the ground was replaced with a clean spoon while no one was looking.
Because the trick would have been easy to see through if the spoon had remained the way it was.
The only one who could have done that was whoever cleaned the cheese off the curator's clothes.
You, Hatsuho-san! You're the only one.
The real reason you sent me that warning was so you could use me as a witness.
To make me testify that the three villains died and you survived through legitimate self-defence.
When the fire confined me to the house for a while, you used the opportunity to kill everyone.
But it would have been problematic if I had died.
That's why you let us see your face through the window.
Then that demoness mask wasn't Moyono-san?!
Indeed.
And the climax of the play was the call on the internal phone.
At that point you had already stabbed the curator and killed your sister.
But she shouted 'Stop it, Sis'!
That was just an act.
I wouldn't be capable of something like that.
My sister stabbed the curator with a chisel!
I didn't have the opportunity to grab a weapon like that!
I see.
It's true. Moyono-san could have done that.
After all, you tempted her to.
Inciting her to kill him with the tools that your father loved.
Nonetheless, you grabbed some skewers.
Skewers aren't anything like a chisel!
You killed your sister with a skewer.
Moyono Mibu was a bad person, but maybe she trusted her sister?
No, I don't think so.
She must have guessed that her younger sister was the one to send me that warning.
So she would have considered you to be untrustworthy.
So you went and killed the curator to convince her otherwise.
When Moyono-san let down her guard as a result,
you stabbed her with that skewer right from the front.
B-But the curator's wound was caused by a chisel, right?
That's right. That was your last fortification.
Unfortunately for you, fatal evidence of your trick remained.
Being the culprit, you were really quite busy.
It was just your bad luck that you didn't have time to get rid of the evidence.
Conan! Bring it over here!
Coming!
Here it is.
And what is this?
They look like simple wood chips.
According to Uncle Kogorō, she made these herself.
A V-shape is carved into them.
Like the shape of the blade of a chisel.
A chisel?
I see!
She brought two skewers with her from the kitchen.
Combining the two skewers so the cross-section formed a V, she used these two wood chips to hold them in that shape.
Then she stabbed the curator with the resulting weapon.
Isn't that so, Miss?
I give up! I give up!
You win, kid.
That's right. That's Hatsuho Toba's special murder weapon.
Making it look like a chisel the first time and then using only a single skewer the second time.
T-Then it really was you?
Yep, I'm the culprit.
Why would you kill your own sister too?!
It's obvious, isn't it?! She was the curator's lover.
While my mother and me were living in poverty, she was living in luxury using the curator's money.
Now she suddenly wants to avenge our father?
That's bull.
That bastard Akaza sold off valuable Noh masks on the curator's orders.
And on top of that, he took after the curator and tried to make eyes at me.
Disgusting. This museum's just for show.
Burning it down and building a park instead is a much better use of the space.
Inspector! Sorry to have made you wait.
The speech is over now. Go arrest me or whatever!
Hey, Takagi!
Y-Yes?
Hello?
Ah, yes, I understand.
Curator Izumi has regained consciousness.
Is that so?
So he didn't kick the bucket after all.
I thought his reaction had been lacking.
The force of the stab sent the wheelchair into the pond and I didn't finish him off.
I guess my endgame still needs some work.
Ah, that's right.
The curator wanted to give his thanks to the boy.
What's that about, Conan-kun?
I helped him out a bit.
Say, Mr. Curator, if you wrapped a sturdy plaited cord like that around your body,
wouldn't it give you some protection if something happened?
I see! Even more so if it's an odoshi.
It'd probably be effective against sharp weapons, too.
I'm glad.
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
The case took a rather ironic turn, I guess.
With the people who had planned to kill the curator ending up killed instead.
What is it, Uncle?
The case left a rather bad aftertaste.
To think that everyone involved was a bad person.
But in any case, it's like this!
It's a murder case so apologising won't make it better.
But if you think you did something bad you should apologise.
To the Noh masks.
Even if there's Noh excuse!
Get it?
Too funny!
I was wondering what you were going to say and then it's something like that.
Why were these chocolate bars thrown away?
'And the lone survivor laughs loudly'.
On the next Conan: 'A Devilish Cycle'!
Next Conan's Hint: Chocolate bar!
Initial K participates in Lupin vs. Conan?
K for Kogorō, of course.
No, for King!