The old man was invited to the vacation home of Chika Kaidō-san, a mystery novelist from Shizuoka,
Chika Kaidō (40)
Mystery Novelist
Kōko Shimura (29)
Chika's Apprentice
Yūichi Kaidō (41)
Chika's Husband
who apparently wanted to hear his tales of life as a detective.
You know, Mouri-san, those two are in a relationship.
Yes?
Those two...
My husband Yūichi and my apprentice Kōko.
In other words, I'm just in their way.
But there's no way I'll let them do as they please.
Since I'm a woman who's as tough and strong as a demon!
Chika-sensei may look strong, but she's actually very frail.
She's very worried about her writer's block, and has to rely on sleeping pills to fall asleep.
She may seem bold, but she's actually very sensitive.
I was surprised when I saw her looking absentmindedly at the knives in the kitchen.
It seems like she's finding life very hard.
I think she was considering suicide.
Well then, have a good night, Mouri-san.
Yeah.
Good night!
What's with them?
They called me here, yet they won't even listen to me.
All they talked about were their private problems.
Oh, that's a beautiful moon.
You're right.
Tonight should be a good night for working on my manuscript.
The clearer the night sky, the darker it gets...
A grand backdrop to a farewell...
Even I had no idea what they were planning...
...until the case occurred.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
A three-way struggle of murderous intent, the outcome of which is unknown until the next day!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Oh? Kaidō-sensei was laughing last night?
Yeah. It was around 2 AM, when I woke up to go to the toilet...
What was so funny?
I wonder what was so funny?
Yeah.
Are those three still sleeping?
But it's already past 8. One of them has to be awake.
Let's go and see!
The curtain's still closed.
It looks like everyone's still...
Uncle! Look!
Kaidō-san! Chika-sensei!
Damn it! I'm gonna break the door down!
Judging from the rigor mortis, she passed away late last night.
Since there aren't any apparent injuries, she must have died from illness or poisoning.
Anyway, we have to inform Kaidō-san!
It's Mouri! I'm coming in!
Too late. He's dead.
And there aren't any apparent injuries either.
Sleeping pills?
Could it be?
Her too?
Anyway, Ran, call the police!
Okay!
Say, Uncle, this carafe...
It matches the glass next to Shimura-san's body, doesn't it?
Seems like it.
It's wet.
Hey, the floor here is wet!
She probably spilt some water from the carafe.
Only empty cans of beer, two
chocolate bars and tissues in the bin...
Hey, why did she throw these chocolate bars away?
They're not even opened.
Who knows?
It seems she was still working when she died.
Then maybe she wrote a dying message?
No way!
Something showed up!
'An ironic cycle.'
'The wrong target.'
'And the lone survivor laughs loudly.'
It doesn't look like a dying message.
Is it a list of ideas for her novels?
Dad, the police are on their way!
It's been a while, Mouri-san.
Long time no see, Yokomizo!
Yes!
Ōkawara, this is the great detective, Kogorō Mouri-san.
Detective Ōkawara (25)
Shizuoka Police Detective
I'm Tomonori Ōkawara.
I hear you've helped Inspector Yokomizo a lot.
No, not that much.
But we, the police, are working hard every day, to grow into a better organisation that won't need to rely on people like you anymore.
A-A-Anyway, Mouri-san, can you show us where the bodies are?
Yes, this way.
Inspector Yokomizo, why do we have to share the crime scene with these people?
Don't say that.
There was a box of 20 chocolate bars on her desk.
There were 17 bars still in the box, and the wrapper of an eaten bar next to it.
A syringe was also found in the closet in the room of her husband, Yūichi Kaidō.
An examination at the scene showed that all three of them died from poisoning, so their bodies were sent for forensic autopsy.
Hey, Dad, was this suicide or murder?
Because I have no idea.
Hey, apparently Chika-sensei loved those chocolate bars, and always ate them while working.
So why'd she throw away those two bars?
Also, Chika-sensei was taking five sleeping pills every night, but it seems her husband Yūichi-san didn't agree with her taking them.
But there was an empty bottle of sleeping pills next to her husband's body.
In other words, those were Chika-sensei's pills.
But where did you find that?
It was in the living room.
Let's see...
'I like taking long baths, followed up by drinking a cold beer.'
'But my doctor told me to stop...'
But there was an empty beer can in her bin, right?
It also says that she bought that water carafe after she was told to quit drinking beer, so she could drink water after her baths.
And that the assistant who went to buy it with her liked it a lot!
The assistant, would that be Shimura-san?
This article?
What?
¥1,200,000!
That carafe's worth that much?!
That's what you're worried about?
Chika-sensei passed away?
W-When?
First, who might you be?
Akio Toda (33)
Editor assigned to Chika
I work for the monthly magazine 'Deduction Paradise' — I'm in charge of Chika-sensei.
My name is Toda.
She was so happy when we spoke over the phone yesterday...
Sorry for questioning you here.
No problem.
So, you called her yesterday?
Yes, on her mobile.
She didn't answer the first time, but on my second try at around midnight...
So how's your work coming along?
It's going to be a masterpiece, Toda-kun.
It will turn the Japanese mystery world upside-down.
Anyway, she was full of motivation.
So it's probably not a suicide.
Okay, got it! Thank you!
We've got the autopsy results and the forensics report.
First, Yūichi Kaidō-san died at around 11:30 PM.
There was poison mixed in with his sleeping pills.
Then at around 1:00 AM, Kōko Shimura-san died.
Poison was placed on the inside of the glass she used to drink tea.
Finally, Chika Kaidō-san died at around 2 AM.
The chocolate bar she ate had poison injected into it.
Also, there was another poisoned chocolate bar in the box.
But no poison was found in any of the other chocolate bars, including the two in the bin.
Which means that all three of them were likely murdered.
Yes.
Why murder?
If it was suicide, then they would have taken the poison directly.
They wouldn't need to add it to medicine, glasses or chocolates.
That's too much trouble.
So they were likely poisoned by someone else.
Also, all three were killed by different poisons.
What?!
But wouldn't that mean...?
Yes.
There might be three killers.
It's true, a single killer wouldn't need to prepare three different poisons to kill three people.
But to think that three different culprits committed their crimes on the same day...
Inspector, the three items that were used for poisoning all belonged to Chika Kaidō-san, right?
Yes.
So couldn't we suppose that there were three culprits, but only one target?
Chika Kaidō-san.
What? Then her husband and Kōko Shimura-san...
...were sadly killed by mistake.
Say, Uncle?
What?
Didn't Chika-sensei say something odd yesterday?
That she was just in the way of the two of them.
Is that right, Mouri-san?
Her husband and Kōko Shimura-san were having an affair.
Right?
Is that so?
It seems her husband wanted a divorce.
But Sensei had too much pride,
and would never accept a divorce...
In other words, the only way for them to be together was to get rid of Chika-sensei...
So two of our three culprits are Yūichi Kaidō and Kōko Shimura.
I see. That explains what they said yesterday, right?
Chika-sensei may look strong, but she's actually very frail.
I think she was considering suicide.
They were probably taking precautions to make her death look like a suicide.
Using you as a witness.
We did find the poison used in the chocolate bars in a syringe in Mr. Yūichi's room.
That settles it.
And we also discovered his fingerprints on all the chocolate bars in Chika Kaidō-san's study.
On all the chocolate bars?
Including a third culprit, 'X', they all planned to murder Chika Kaidō-sensei.
But in the end, ironically, it wasn't just Chika-sensei who was poisoned, but also Yūichi Kaidō-san and Kōko Shimura-san.
But just who is the third culprit X?
Editors are always driven to tears
by their writers' fickle demands...
Right, Toda-kun?
Mouri-san, your reasoning is a bit...
Your grudge against Chika-sensei got bigger and bigger.
No way...
If you think logically, we first have to find out who stood to profit from her death.
A novelist suddenly dying will make big news.
That'd make all the books and magazines linked with that writer be hot sellers, right?
I see!
No, you don't see! I didn't do it!
I really didn't do it!
Why were Yūichi-san's fingerprints on all of the chocolate bars?
Also, why were there empty beer cans in her bin, when she should have stopped drinking?
There's also the fact that the old man saw her laughing loudly last night.
Damn it. There's too many things that don't make sense!
But what really worries me...
Since I'm a woman who's as tough and strong as a demon!
Why did she make sure we knew that?
Does everyone else really suspect Toda-san?
He doesn't look like a killer to me.
It's all right. Uncle's sure to find the real killer.
So that's what it meant!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Take this. I'm going back to the house.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Say, Inspector Yokomizo, did you find Yūichi-san's fingerprints on that syringe?
No, it seems it was wiped clean.
It didn't have any fingerprints on it.
But isn't that strange?
Why wipe them off the syringe but
leave them on the chocolate bars?
You're right.
Toda-san, you called Chika-sensei twice yesterday, right?
Yes. The first time was around 11:30 PM.
But she didn't answer.
I found out why the second time I called.
She told me that she'd been in the bath since 11:00 PM.
Why are you asking that?
Uncle really is a great detective.
He said he solved all the mysteries.
Right, Uncle?
Uh, no...
So, the third culprit, X, Toda-kun...
...it's not you.
You're changing your mind now?
Toda-kun, I've heard that Chika Kaidō-sensei had writer's block.
Yes, it's true. She's had it for a long time now.
So what if she had a writer's block?! That's irrelevant!
If she'd actually been murdered, I'd agree.
The third culprit, X, was herself. She was the one who poisoned the chocolate bars in order to commit suicide.
So Chika Kaidō-san killed herself.
No, it wasn't suicide.
But you just said she—
Using her own words, it's an 'ironic cycle'.
She was a very proud writer.
She couldn't get over her writer's block, so she wanted to disappear from this world...
But she couldn't bear the thought of making her husband and pupil happy by committing suicide.
That's why, as a parting gift, she decided to frame her husband as the one who killed her.
First, she injected some poison into two chocolate bars for her own suicide.
Then she hid the syringe in Yūichi-san's room.
Meanwhile, her husband Yūichi-san, and Shimura Kōko-san, who were unaware of her plans,
were also independently planning to poison her.
Chika-sensei went into the bath at 11 PM.
During that time, Kōko Shimura-san switched Chika-sensei's sleeping pills with poisoned ones.
Then at around 11:30 PM, Yūichi Kaidō-san poisoned the glass Chika-sensei uses after her bath.
At that time, Yūichi-san, who was perhaps trying to calm himself,
took Chika-sensei's sleeping pills and swallowed some, becoming the first victim.
Then at around midnight, when getting out of her bath, Chika-sensei got a call from Toda-kun.
She probably knocked the water carafe over by accident.
It will turn the Japanese mystery world upside-down.
But she probably didn't want to drink water from the carafe that she knocked over, so she went to the kitchen, and then changed her mind...
Thinking she would die soon anyway, she brought the forbidden beer to her study and drank it.
Then, a little bit before 1 AM, possibly being unable to fall sleep, Kōko Shimura-san went to the kitchen and used that glass to drink tea.
Making her the second victim.
Finally at 2 AM, Chika-sensei went to the kitchen again, and found Kōko-san's dead body next to her water glass...
She concluded that her husband put poison on it...
And understood everything.
They both tried to kill her, but ended up killing each other by accident.
No longer in the mood for committing suicide, she threw away the poisoned chocolate bars.
I'm alive! I'm going to live and make a novel about their foolish acts!
And that's how the third victim, Chika Kaidō-sensei, died.
Hold on, Mouri-san. Do you really think that she ate one of the chocolate bars she had prepared for her suicide by mistake?
She found herself part of another ironic cycle.
Eh?
It was the first phone call Toda-kun made, at 11:30 PM.
It probably happened right when
Yūichi-san was setting up his poison.
Startled by the ringing phone,
he knocked down the chocolate bars.
At that time, the position of the poisoned chocolate bars changed.
It's the only way to explain his fingerprints being on all of the chocolate bars.
So what do you think, Ōkawara?
Do you understand now why I'm
so eager to ask Mouri-san for help?
Yes! He truly is a great detective.
See.
I'm glad you finally managed to recognise my greatness.
Hey Dad, those words are a little...
Fail. I can't imitate his laugh.
A case in a flat starts with a ticket stolen in a café.
What is the surprising truth hidden in the washing machine?!
Detective Conan: 'A Dispute over a Platinum Ticket'!
Broadcast on Saturday, 23 November at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Washing machine!
Phone-in competitions start today!
A mini-drama with Conan-kun and that guy!
Daddy!