Please wait a moment.
You're really lucky to have tickets for the Black Roses concert, Haruka.
They were a present from my boyfriend.
From that failure of a guitarist?
The concert's on the same day as his birthday, and he said he wanted to celebrate it with me.
I'm surprised he can afford that.
Here you go.
Even though I clicked it at exactly 10 o'clock, I didn't get through.
I'm sorry, Sonoko.
I told you, didn't I? It's their one and only concert in Japan.
So it's not like it's easy to get tickets.
For things like this, you gotta line up in front of the store!
Ta-da!
Sonoko, don't tell me that's...
Two arena seats for the Black Roses Tōkyō concert!
I went through a lot of trouble to get these!
They're gone!
I'm sure I put them here.
Who was it?! Who stole my tickets?!
No, no. This is mine.
Thief!
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
An incident takes place in a coffee shop.
Take good care of your rare tickets!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
The next day
And then she dragged me to the nearest police station, and it took three hours until I was acquitted. Three hours!
But why didn't she write down her seat numbers or something?
Apparently her boyfriend got the tickets from a friend and didn't write anything down.
It really pisses me off!
Especially after I stood in line all night on Saturday in order to get my hands on these tickets.
May I help you?
I'll have an extra-large iced coffee latte with vanilla ice cream,
caramel syrup and chocolate chip topping. With only a little ice please.
Kaori Kosuda (20)
Coffee Shop Part Time Worker / University Student
Extra-large iced coffee latte with vanilla ice cream, caramel syrup and chocolate chips with only a little ice, right?
Really, Sonoko, show some restraint.
It's no problem. Today's orders are on the house, so please don't hold back.
Jirō Kirima (26)
Shop Manager
Welcome!
Look, Conan-kun, that's her.
Haruka Kona (23)
Office Lady
She's the one who accused us of stealing yesterday, Haruka Kona-san.
Miss, about yesterday...
Excuse me...
Please look at this!
After closing time last night, those concert tickets were put up on an internet auction site!
No way! ¥50,000 for one ticket?
The price quintupled overnight.
It's not just about the price — look at the user name.
'Coffee rumba'?
It's exactly the sort of name a barista would use, don't you think?
Are you saying one of our employees was the thief?
You can't just accuse people like that!
Anyway, I'd like to talk to the people who were here yesterday.
The three people working here at that time yesterday were me, Kosuda here, who was handing out cake samples,
and Masako Mooka, the cashier.
Masako Mooka (20)
Coffee Shop Part Time Worker / University Student
Then go get her as well!
Actually, she hasn't come in yet today.
It's no use. She won't pick up the phone.
She didn't come to university today either. I wonder if something happened.
Is she your friend?
Yes, we study together at university.
She's supposed to take over for me when my shift ends today...
You're right. She should already be here by now.
Should I check up on her on the way home?
Would you be so kind?
Of course.
Wait! In that case I'll come too.
Then we'll come with you as well! Right?
Y-Yeah.
Masako?
Masako, are you there?
It isn't locked.
Masako?
Conan-kun!
It's no use. She's already dead.
Ran-neechan, call the police.
All right.
Is this the auction site?
So it really was her.
Sir!
How could this happen...
And you are?
I'm the manager of the coffee shop where Mooka-san worked.
My name is Jirō Kirima.
I see.
In that case, can you tell me what Mooka-san was doing last night?
Yes.
Mooka-san had the late shift together with Kona-san here and was working until 9 PM.
Afterwards, we did some light cleaning and got changed.
We probably left the shop around 9:15 PM.
It takes about 30 minutes to get here from the shop, so she'd have been home at around 9:45 PM.
About 30 minutes later, the tickets turned up on that auction site.
Inspector, according to her next-door neighbour, Uruma-san, the victim was doing her laundry between 10:20 and 11 PM.
What?
Did she always do her laundry so late?
Yeah, she'd often turn on the washing machine or bring home her boyfriend late at night.
Ten Uruma (30)
Masako's Neighbour
She was a lax woman who was always behind on her rent.
Rin Manda (50)
Flat Landlady
I see.
In 40 minutes, the laundry should have been finished, shouldn't it?
I'll take a look!
Stop, Conan-kun!
You can't just look at a girl's laundry.
Right.
Inspector, the clothes have been left in the machine after being spin-dried.
And judging by the bag lying next to the corpse, the victim was planning to go somewhere while the washing machine was running.
That's when the burglar came upon her and she was killed.
But isn't that strange?
Well, if the washing machine is running, wouldn't you normally assume that someone is inside?
I see. That's certainly true.
After starting the washing machine, the victim probably left her flat in order to go to a nearby shop.
But she returned right away because she noticed that she'd forgotten something.
And that's when she encountered the killer.
But what did she forget?
She probably forgot the gas bill payment slip that's lying on the table.
The payment was due yesterday.
It might be as Conan-kun says.
Yes.
So after killing the victim, the culprit took the tickets and banknotes from her purse and escaped.
In that case, the killer must have known that the tickets were very valuable.
That means you might have been in danger as well, Sonoko!
But if I was a burglar, I'd steal the laptop first.
And Uncle Kogorō said that a professional burglar opens the drawers of cabinets
in order starting from the bottom because it's more efficient.
But this cabinet isn't like that at all, is it?
So we have to consider the possibility that the killer just made it look like a burglary.
First, we should find out more about the victim's friends.
Mooka-san's boyfriend?
Yes, do you remember what kind of man he is?
The thing is, I never actually met him.
Mr. Manager, you should really be upfront with the police.
W-What are you trying to say, kid?
You were going out with the woman who died, weren't you?
On your phone, you had her as 'Masa-chan' instead of using her full name.
And on the shift schedule in your shop, you both had the same days off, right?
I happened to notice that.
Is that true?
We'd been dating for two months.
You probably have a spare key, right?
Yes.
I see.
If you have a spare key, then you could easily have waited for her to head out and then entered her flat.
I-I would never...!
Then please tell us what you were doing last night.
L-Last night I ordered in some spare things used in the shop, like pens, before I left at around 10 PM.
It is common for couples to get into fights because of even slight disagreements,
and Masako-san did intend to resell a customer's tickets.
Since Kirima-san is the shop manager, it's possible they got into a fight about it.
But something doesn't feel right.
Well then, what were you doing between 10:20 and 11 PM?
Ah, that's right!
Say, mister, how come you remember the time the washing machine was running so precisely?
That's because it was really noisy.
After about five minutes, it stopped once, so I thought she'd noticed the noise.
It stopped once?
Yes.
But after a while, the noise started again.
That's why I remembered it.
I see. So that's the reason for the noise.
Huh? But why is that the only thing that...
That's...
I see! So that's how it is!
Honestly! I only take my eyes off you for a second and this happens.
Sonoko-neechan...
You're still 10 years too young to be interested in women's underwear.
I really need to tell Ran to raise you properly.
Sonoko?
Sonoko-kun?
I'm getting impatient.
I know who the killer is, so let's put an end to this!
What?
The victim started doing the laundry last night, but didn't take her clothes out of the machine once they were finished.
Therefore, the incident took place while the machine was running -- between 10:20 and 11 PM.
But if you look closely at this washing machine you'll notice something weird.
Something weird?
Detective Satō, try turning the tap there.
The water is turned off.
That's right.
Even though the clothes hadn't been taken out of the machine, the water has been turned off. Which means...
Someone turned off the water and drained the machine in order to take something out of it, wouldn't you say?
But what would that be?
Tickets for the Black Roses concert, of course.
But why would those be in the washing machine?
Because the killer thought that they were in the coffee shop apron that Masako-san took home.
Yesterday, the thief put the tickets into the pocket of their own apron after stealing them from Haruka-san's bag.
However, when the shop closed, Masako-san mistook said apron for her own and took it home.
That's why the culprit came here in order to retrieve the tickets they had stolen.
Wait a second!
That sounds like you're saying that I'm the culprit!
Isn't that so, Kaori Kosuda-san?
Last night, when you came here, you saw Masako-san put the apron into the washing machine and turn it on.
While you were wondering what to do, Masako-san went out to do some shopping while the washing machine was running.
That's when you turned off the water and made to take out your apron.
However, Masako-san noticed that she'd forgotten something and returned straight away.
After killing Masako-san, you ransacked the room to make it look like a burglary
and set the washing machine to spin dry to make it look like the laundry had finished before going home.
That's enough nonsense!
Who's going to believe a fantasy like that?!
But it seems like you forgot to turn the water back on.
That's all just guesswork.
Where's your proof?
I have proof.
The apron you're carrying is the proof!
The apron?
I see!
If Masako-san took Kaori-san's apron home last night like Sonoko says,
then the apron Kaori-san is carrying right now is really Masako-san's apron.
I see.
The manager should know what my apron looks like, right?
Please take a look.
Right.
Can you tell which apron it is?
This is Kosuda-san's apron.
She only started working for me last month,
so her apron is still as good as new.
Now you understand, don't you? I'm not the culprit!
Your deduction is wrong!
Uruma-san, you said the washing machine was unusually loud yesterday, right?
Yes. There was probably something hard inside.
Detective Satō, please take a look inside the washing machine.
Okay.
So this is the apron in question.
What is it?
There's a red felt-tip pen inside.
Yes, a red felt-tip pen.
It's a pen the shop uses to note down special orders on receipts.
The pink towel and shirt inside the washing machine were originally white, and were dyed pink by the pen's ink.
Judging by the big stain on the pants pocket, it looks like she left the pen in the pocket when she put them into the machine.
Indeed.
Inspector Megure, could you take another look at Kaori-san's apron?
S-Sure.
If my deduction is correct, that apron should have turned pink too.
That's too bad.
The Marin Coffee aprons are black.
A red felt-tip pen won't...
It's pink.
The care label has been coloured pink.
Kaori-san, in order to erase the evidence of what happened,
you took your own apron out of the machine after the crime and replaced it with Masako-san's,
and set it to be spin-dried together with the rest of the clothes.
That's why the care label of the apron inside the machine is white, while the one on your apron is pink.
No way...
Kosuda-san, why did you...
That's because Kaori-san is the one who originally bought those tickets.
What are you saying?
My boyfriend was the one who...
I saw on the shift schedule earlier that most of the staff were working last Sunday, and only Kaori-san had the day off.
You took the day off because you were going to
queue up in front of the ticket shop all night, am I right?
Is that true?
I just wanted to see his happy face.
Of my boyfriend whose birthday is on the day of the concert.
Your boyfriend? It couldn't be...
He's a guitarist. Completely unsuccessful though.
But he said he couldn't go that day because of work, and that he'd give the tickets to a colleague from the record company.
A friend at a record company... he must've meant me.
I noticed when you came to the coffee shop yesterday.
From that failure of a guitarist?
The concert's on the same day as his birthday, and he said he wanted to celebrate it with me.
To think he'd do something like that... I just couldn't stop myself!
Looking back now, Masako must have noticed what I was doing.
Everything was just as you said.
When Masako headed out, I came here to get the apron back.
But Masako caught me red-handed...
I was really surprised, you know.
I never thought a quiet girl like you would steal something from a customer.
Don't you think it's time you accepted the truth?
He only used you because it was convenient for him!
You're wrong!
He didn't even come close to loving you!
You're wrong! He told me he loved me!
He loved me!
He loved...
M-Masako?
When I came to my senses, I got scared and...
And so you decided made it look like a burglary, right?
But you know, the moment you covered up the crime and disguised the crime scene,
you were reduced to something even worse than the guy who cheated on you:
A lying coward.
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
onaji koto de waraiatta ne
futoshita shunkan ni iron'na kimi o omoidasu
'boku ga genjitsuteki sugita' to ima ni natte kuyande'ru
'kimi to no yume no tame ni' motto ikiru beki datta
kimi no inai akimatsuri
ima no boku wa younger than yesterday
hanabira ga mau yō ni kimi wa waratta ne
motto warawasetakatta
hareteiru no ni tsumetai ame ga futteiru
kimi no egao ga nani yori mo suki datta
min'na hitori ja ikirenai
kimi no kaeru basho de
boku wa zutto aritsuzuketai
But the worst one of all was that guitarist who deceived the two of them.
Yeah! Exactly!
Although I really don't remember a thing.
If it were me I'd beat him up.
You two-timing bastard! You're the worst!
You reap what you sow, I guess.
The stage is Kumamoto and Aso, the country of fire!
Top-secret development data gets stolen!
Where will the case lead the Detective Boys?!
Detective Conan: 'The Mystery Tour of Fire and Water (Touring Aso)'!
Airs on Saturday 30th November at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Stuffed Animal!
Next time's in Kumamoto!
That means horsemeat and garashi renkon!
No, it means a Mystery Tour.