Only the light of deductions can cut through dark shadows and gloomy darkness!
Find the confidential data in Aso and Kumamoto, the country of fire!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
We, the Detective Boys, came to Kumamoto with Ran and old man Kogoro for a sightseeing trip.
Kumamoto is filled with many water sources, and is said to be the city with the best groundwater in Japan.
Here, you can get mineral water from the ordinary water supply.
It's tasty!
Yeah!
But the most famous thing about Kumamoto is...
Akaushi steaks and horsemeat!
Not to mention karashi renkon!
There's so many great side dishes to go with a sip of kuma shochu...!
No, I wasn't talking about food...
I'd like some nice healthy taipien!
Anyway, the most famous thing about Kumamoto is...
Look, Conan-kun!
It's Mt Aso!
Yup, Kumamoto is known not only as the capital of water, but also as the country of fire.
Before we go and look at the crater,
let's go and learn about volcanoes here!
Whoa! Awesome!
Now that he's here, Genta-kun's
enjoying it more than any of us.
Mt. Aso is actually
just a nickname, and officially...
Takadake...
Nakadake...
Nekodake...
Eboshidake...
and Kijimadake...
...make up the
Five Aso Mountains.
And the crater we're going to see later is...
Nakadake.
I'm sorry!
Are you okay, little boy?
Yeah, I'm fine.
But don't call me a little boy.
Justin Takamori (7)
Tourist
I'm Justin!
My name is Justin Takamori.
Justin?
You're so cute!
Yeah, everybody says that.
But you're even cuter than me, miss.
That smile...! That wink...!
He knows exactly how to act
to get whatever he wants!
Looks like you've got a rival.
But you're still just number two.
Then who's number one?
My mummy, of course!
Justin!
I thought I told you not to walk off by yourself.
Jessica Takamori (30)
Justin's Mother
Sorry, Mummy.
That's right!
I've got something good to show you!
Something good?
Whoa, awesome!
You've really got a lot of stamps.
Right!
He's still a kid in that respect.
And an unpleasant one at that.
Say something?
Nothing at all!
Now you're acting like a kid.
You really do have a very cute son.
Thank you.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm a detective, you see...
My card... My card...
Huh?
Where are those shiny cards...?
Where are they?
We should get going, Justin.
Say goodbye to your friends.
Okay, Mummy!
Bye!
Here they are! Have a look at this...
What're you doing, Dad?
We're leaving!
R-Right.
Next, we're finally gonna see the crater!
This is better than I thought!
It's really breathtaking!
You don't get to see a crater like this every day.
We're really lucky!
Huh? Why's that?
It's because Nakadake is an active volcano.
At times, it releases poisonous gases,
and has to be closed off.
Right.
Just seeing this makes
the whole trip here worthwhile.
They've got all sorts of animals here!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Kumamon stuffed toys!
Can I go have a look?
Sure. But if you buy souvenirs now, you'll end up carrying them everywhere,
so let's get them when we're leaving.
I see...
Okay!
Kuma-san! Kuma-san!
But we'll just end up forgetting again, won't we?
Look! Look!
They're begging for food!
Go! Hurry up!
Ahh, I'm stuffed!
I see you've still got that good appetite.
Huh?
Jun Kouda (26)
Kumamoto Police Detective
A man just took the bag and left behind a Kumamon.
Roger. We'll arrest him when he's somewhere more isolated.
Keiji Kosugi (41)
Kumamoto Police Detective
Ensure that you—
Hold on!
Namie Kajiyama (28)
Kumamoto Police Detective
A girl just...
What?!
Mister!
This is yours, right?
Damn!
Stop!
Ayumi!
You won't get away!
That cheeky kid?!
Move it!
Watch out!
Mummy!
Justin! Justin!
Stop!
Hey, are you okay?
You again, huh?
Justin, did you hurt yourself?
I'm fine!
The lawn gave me a soft landing!
Glad to hear it.
Where's my Kumamon?
Without it, my company...
My company's done for.
What happened?
No idea.
Here. You'll be fine now.
Okay.
What should I do? If I don't get it back...
What exactly happened here?
Are you that girl's guardian?
Well, something like that...
Let me introduce myself. Have a look at this.
Kogoro Mouri...
Then you're that Great Detective?
It seems like I got in the way of your investigation.
If you wouldn't mind, could you tell me about the case?
The truth is, a thief broke into my company,
Kumamon Foods, two days ago.
Kumamon Foods?
Kumamon...?
My name is Monkichi Kumada. Kumamon for short.
It's a nickname I've had ever since I was a child.
I see. So he's the original Kumamon.
Director, you wanted to see me...?
You're late, Inoue!
I apologize.
But why are the police here?
I called them here!
But never mind that,
you tell this man about the break-in.
S-Sure.
Mitsuo Inoue (32)
Kumamon Foods Employee
When I arrived at work that morning,
the lock on the door had been broken.
So I rushed inside to check on things,
but nothing seemed to be damaged,
so I let out a sigh of relief...
But my stuffed Kumamon was missing.
Kumamon's Kumamon...
And that's not all.
Something didn't quite seem right,
so I checked inside the desk,
and the USB memory stick
with our confidential data had vanished.
It was development data
on the new sensations and tastes
of completely new types of sweets
we designed all by ourselves...
And we haven't patented them yet.
We may be a small company, but we've
been developing lots of new products
and making money
from selling the patents.
But if our competitors
got hold of that data...
We'd be doomed if it went somewhere like
the industry leader, Higo Foods!
So the thief contacted you?
Yeah.
The next day,
I got a call from the thief.
I'll let you have the USB memory stick with
your all-important data for only ¥10,000,000.
But if you tell the police,
the deal's off. Got it?
So today was the day
of the exchange?
Yes.
He said that he'd put the USB memory stick with
the confidential data inside a stuffed Kumamon
and trade it for a bag
containing ¥10,000,000.
Why would the thief go
through all that trouble?
He probably did it
just to spite me.
What should we do, Director?
Didn't the thief say the deal was off
if you told the police?
Quiet!
The police told me
they'd catch the thief.
Yet still...
Kouda here. We've arrested
the fleeing suspect.
We also recovered the stuffed toy.
I see. Good job.
You don't look so good.
Is your wound hurting again?
Wound?
Detective Kouda was stabbed
by a thug and hospitalized.
He only left the hospital yesterday.
But that's not important.
We couldn't find the USB memory stick
anywhere in the stuffed toy he was carrying.
What?!
That can't be!
He didn't have it with him?
No, we couldn't find it.
Also, he claims that he was just asked
by someone he met at a bar to swap the toy for a bag,
and knows nothing about the theft.
Then he knows what
the thief looks like, right?
He said that he was wearing sunglasses
and a mask, so he never saw his face.
Damn!
Maybe his plan was just to get the ¥10,000,000, and he never put the USB memory stick in the toy.
Say, Ms. Detective.
When the man was running away, he crashed into a young boy, right?
That's right... a cute half-Japanese boy.
That boy was carrying
a stuffed Kumamon too.
So maybe they got mixed up
when they collided?
Is he right?
Yes.
There was a half-Japanese boy
and his foreign mother there.
Okay, then find them right away.
But we don't have any
clues to find them...
Well actually, we know that boy.
His name's Justin.
Then you know
where they were headed?
No, I don't...
But Justin had a stamp book.
So maybe he went somewhere
he can get it stamped?
But there are a lot of tourist attractions
with stamps around here.
But he showed us his stamp book
at the Aso Volcano Museum.
He already had stamps for Aso Ropeway
and Aso Farm Land at the time,
so I think we can
exclude those two.
I see.
And so the closest tourist attraction other than
those two would be Aso Shrine, right?
Do they have a stamp there?
Y-Yes, they do.
I'm a bit shocked though.
You've got amazing memory
and observation skills.
Do I?
Okay, Kajiyama, you and
that boy should head to Aso Shrine.
I'll go to Kumamon Foods
with Director Kumada.
The thief may attempt further contact.
Right.
So...
How... did I get
myself into this?
I really want to find
Justin-kun myself!
It's my fault
that he got involved.
You haven't done anything wrong, Ayumi-chan.
Right! Don't worry about it!
If we let this case go, it'd be
a blot on the Detective Boys' name!
Right!
I'll take responsibility for the children.
Please hurry to Aso Shrine!
Understood.
A half-Japanese boy and his foreign mother?
Yes, they were here.
You sure, mister?!
Yes. He used the stamp here
about an hour ago.
That's Justin for sure!
Yeah!
Did they happen to say
where they were headed next?
Hmm... I think he
said something like...
I want to go and see
the big pig falling asleep.
The big pig falling asleep?
There's a big black pig
at Aso Milk Farm.
And it's usually always sleeping.
Okay, that's it!
But you know...
Have a look at this.
If we follow Justin's
route so far...
Aso Volcano Museum...
Cuddly Dominion...
Aso Shrine...
He's heading north.
But Aso Milk Farm is
over to the southwest, see?
It's true.
When you see it on a map,
it's a complete U-turn.
Also, Aso Milk Farm
is only open until 4.
Ran-neechan, what time is it?
It's 3:40.
It's quite far away,
so even if he left an hour ago,
he might not make it
before they close.
And whether he did or not,
it'd be closed for sure when we get there.
There's El Patio Ranch
to the north...
But I don't think
they've ever had any pigs.
The only other main tourist
attractions to the north are...
Kokuzo Shrine and Daikanbo...
Daikanbo?
That's it!
buta = pig
Justin didn't say a big pig, he said a big Buddha!
What's a Buddha?
It's how you say hotoke-sama in English.
Justin's mother is a foreigner.
She probably taught him
the name Buddha.
A big Buddha falling asleep...
But that's...
The image of the sleeping Buddha made by
Mt Aso when seen from Daikanbo.
Kosugi-san, we figured out
the boy's whereabouts.
He's at Daikanbo.
Well, that's just what the brat says,
we don't know for sure.
I feel that I can
trust his deduction.
It's true!
It looks like a sleeping Buddha!
We better hurry up
and find Justin first.
Yeah.
No! You can't!
That belongs to Justin!
What're you doing to my mummy?!
Give it back!
Stop!
Let me go!
What are you doing!
Kajiyama!
Kosugi-san, follow that car!
The thief kidnapped the boy!
What?!
He probably plans to hide
when he gets into Kumamoto.
Kosugi here.
It's Inoue, from Kumamon Foods.
We just got a call
from the thief.
What?
If you follow me,
I'll kill the boy.
Kajiyama.
The chase is off.
What? But...
The thief threatened
to kill the boy.
Understood.
Justin...
He was trying to save me...
Don't worry.
I'm sure he'll be fine.
Strange.
How did the thief know
that Justin was at Daikanbo?
Actually, how did he know that Justin had
the stuffed toy with the USB memory stick to begin with?
We didn't find out about the mix-up until
after the fleeing man was arrested...
...and the only ones
who know about it are us,
Detectives Kosugi and Kajiyama
from the Kumamoto Police,
and Kumada-san and Inoue-san
from Kumamon Foods.
But when the thief kidnapped Justin,
Kumada-san and Inoue-san were at their company,
and we were at the scene,
and all have alibis...
Does that mean one of them
is working with the thief?
And just who is the thief?
A child was kidnapped?
What on earth are the police doing, anyway?
Where're you taking me now?
Shut up, and follow me!
Here it is!
Seize that ruffian!
That kid's doing it on purpose,
to tell us where he's been.
He's pretty sly.
If it's him, I'm sure he'll...
On the next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Stamp book!
The Detective Boys are busy even in Aso!
Tha' so?
kuma mo torokeru
They're also being charmed by the bears.