When we came to tour Aso, Kumamoto,
somebody stole Kumamoto Foods' secret data.
Then we got involved in a case where
the culprit demanded $100k.
The culprit put the USB containing the secret data
犯人は機密データの入った
USBメモリを
inside a Kumamon doll, but...
After a strange turn of events, that doll
fell into the hands of Justin,
who we met during our trip.
We used Justin's prior words as clues
and somehow managed to successfully find him.
Immediately after,
right in front of our eyes, Justin
was kidnapped along with the doll by the culprit.
Is there a spy near us?
Also...
who in the world is the culprit!?
The darkness of the shadow and the depth of darkness!
What'll pierce through is the light of truth!
A mystery has gathered in Kumamoto!
The unveiling of the USB!
He sees the single truth!
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult!
His name is
Detective Conan!
In the end, there were no news from the culprit, so
we welcomed the morning at a hotel in Kumamoto City.
俺たちは 熊本市内のホテルで
朝を迎えた...
You know...
This ended up being a weird trip...
Wha—?
Hey, Genta-kun!
Sorry...
I didn't mean it that way.
Ayumi, it's not your fault.
Even if you say that,
she'll still feel responsible.
Yeah.
Ah... Mouri-san!
Kajiyama Namie (28)
Kumamoto Prefecture Detective
I have something to say.
A message from the culprit?
Yes, he said to bring the $100k to Kumamoto City.
Kumamon Foods got the call.
We just met up with Kumada-san and
now we're gathering at the conference room.
それで今 熊田さんたちがみえて
ここの会議室に集まっています。
Understood.
Ran, take care of the kids.
Okay.
Huh? Conan-kun?
I'll go look for him.
Okay, thanks.
Yes.
Right now, I'm with the police.
Takamori Jessica (30)
Justin's Mother
What should I do...?
Here.
Thank you.
Inoue Mitsuo (32)
Kumamon Foods Employee
A child was kidnapped, you say...!?
What in the world is the police doing!?
We have no excuse.
So did the culprit state the place of the transaction?
それで 犯人は取り引き場所を
指定してきましたか?
No, he said he'll contact us later.
Why did a case of our data getting stolen
end up being a kidnapping case?
Hm?
Hey, Inoue!
What do you mean it was just stolen!?
That data is extremely
important to our company and
you know that, right!?
However, what's important
now is the child's life, correct?
What!?
Are you talking back to me!?
Now, now, what good is it
to fight amongst ourselves?
For the time being, let's just
wait until the culprit contacts us again.
What is this uneasy feeling...?
A child's life is more important
than some data; that's true, but...
Kudou-kun.
Haibara? Don't startle me.
I have something to say.
Hm?
Kumamoto Ramen
Three orders of Kumamoto Ramens!
Takamori Justin (7)
Tourist
Why do you want my Kumamon?
Hey! Why?
Remain silent and eat.
No! Stop! This is Justin's!
What are you doing to Mommy!?
People who do terrible things to Mommy—
I, myself, will take them to the police!
A business card?
Yes, most likely her husband's.
Because it said, "Takamori Naoto."
Then, Jessica-san was calling her husband?
But, usually, you would have your
husband's number in the phone book, right?
けど 普通 旦那さんの番号なんて
携帯に登録してあんだろ。
I don't know about that,
but that business card was from Higo Foods.
Takamori Naoto
Higo Foods
Higo Foods...? Isn't that...
But if that data was taken by another company...
If it went to the hands of market
leaders like Higo Foods, we'll be doomed.
Justin's dad is a Higo Foods employee.
This is either just a coincidence or...
Hey!
Where are you guys off to?
We snuck away from Ran-san's watch.
What are you two doing? Let's go!
Like I said, where are you guys going?
We, the Detective Boys, will go find Justin-kun.
That's too dangerous.
Oh, no... We've been caught.
The injury on your arm...
You got hit by the culprit's accomplice and
got hurt, didn't you?
However, next time, it
may not just be a small injury.
Huh? Was Inoue-san there at that time?
President, you called?
You're late, Inoue!
My apologies.
Why is the police here?
I'm pretty sure you came rushing in later, right?
確か あとから社長に呼ばれて
駆けつけたんじゃなかった?
I heard about it from the Pres.
That a girl named Ayumi got hurt.
You're Ayumi-chan, right?
Yes... but it was my fault!
All because I got in the way...
If you insist, I shall accompany you.
Originally speaking, it's our company's
responsibility for letting it get stolen in the first place.
元はといえば 機密データを
盗まれた我が社の責任だからね。
During the second call from the culprit,
I heard the sound of a streetcar in the background.
But, the streetcars in Kumamoto—
There are two lines with
a total of thirty-five stations.
With only that clue...
What's that?
It's this...
There's no mistaking it;
this is Justin's stamp book.
He most likely lost it on
purpose to tell us his whereabouts.
Was he with somebody?
About that... He was with some
strange guy with sunglasses and a mask.
Could he be the father?
So he's still with the culprit, eh?
So, do you know which way they went?
Umm... I think the arcade—
they walked in the direction of the castle.
Shimotōri Arcade
Mouri Ran
Oh, no! Did I get caught?
Hello, Ran-neechan?
Hey, Conan-kun, where are you!?
Is everyone with you?
What are you brats doing together!?
It's not just brats;
Inoue-san is with us, too.
What did you say!? Who's with you—
That half-Japanese boy
just now was really cute, yeah?
Definitely!
Give it a rest already!
Excuse me!
Hm?
Rice Balls
Th-That half-Japanese, what was he like?
Like this...
It's Justin!
Where did you take this photo?
Up ahead, near the karaoke place.
Karaoke
I see...
He's not here.
He probably went somewhere else already.
Excuse me.
Did you see a half-Japanese
around the same age as us?
Ahh~! We did, we did!
He was near that convenience store over there.
He even winked at me~.
So awesome!
I wonder if he was a model?
Thought so.
Yeah.
That kid is doing it on purpose
in order to tell us his whereabouts.
Way to go.
Hubuki Subs
Katou Kiyomasa Public Statue
Hey, look at that boy!
S-So cute~!
Wow, so mature!
Oh, how cute~
You're right! Wow, lovely!
What are you doing, you bastard!?
He's hopelessly noticeable.
Sakura no Baba Jōsaien
Quietly play here.
Don't do anything funny
because I'll be watching the whole time.
Fine.
Did you prepare the money?
Yes, I have it right here.
Listen closely.
At Kumamoto Castle, place the bagful of money underneath the large ginkgo tree.
If I see even a tiny glimpse of the
police, I won't guarantee the kid's life!
If it's him...
Ahh~...
Let me go! What are you doing!?
If it's him, he'd definitely...
At Kumamoto Castle...?
He told me to place the bagful of money underneath the large ginkgo tree at Kumamoto Castle.
金の入ったバッグを
熊本城の大銀杏の下に置けと...。
Kosugi Keiji (41)
Kumamoto Prefecture Detective
This is probably our last chance.
This time, we must
capture the culprit without fail!
But what if, because of the previous fiasco,
the culprit was watching us,
so there's a chance that he saw our faces?
ここにいる全員の顔が
割れているおそれがあります。
Yeah...
If the culprit figures
out that we're on the lookout...
... the child's life will be in danger.
I have an idea!
Leave this up to me, Mouri Kogorou!
Wha—
A-Are you going to be okay, Dad?
Hope you find your friend soon.
Thank you.
Like that ramen employee said earlier...
The culprit behind the
kidnapping could be the child's father?
"The culprit behind the kidnapping"...?
Conan-kun!
A person said that
she saw Justin at Waku Waku Za!
"Waku Waku Za"?
Now where are you taking me?
Stay silent and follow me!
Found him!
The culprit's with him!
You can't get away anymore!
Slowpokes!
Stay back!
Don't move or else this kid's...
Damn it! Wait!
Pass!
Give it!
Co-Conan-kun!
You brats!
Haibara!
No, I got it!
Don't get in my way!
Too bad!
Hm?
Damn it!
Leave this to us!
Edogawa-kun, you chase after the culprit!
Okay!
I'm counting on you, Haibara!
Kumamoto Castle
Honmaru Goten
Everybody!
It's the ruffian! Charge~!
I'm this castle's lord!
With a single shout from me is all it takes!
You only got them to cooperate because
Detective Kosugi showed his police badge...
D-Damn it!
You don't care what'll happen to the kid!?
He's bluffing!
Hm?
I'm right here!
Justin!
Mommy!
D-Damn it...!
Th-That voice...
You're Kouda-kun, right!?
Qu-Quit it!
Kouda...!
"Tell me when you find
Justin's whereabouts," is what
your text said,
so that's why I informed you...
Other main tourist spots
in the north would be...
Kokujou Shrine and Daikanbou...
Daikanbou...
I got it!
Justin didn't say a big pig,
he said a big Buddha!
A big Buddha sleeping... That's...!
A view from Aso—it must be Nehanzou.
I need to inform Kouda-kun.
To think it was to do this...
I-I needed the money!
I lost big time gambling and
made a huge debt with the loan shark.
They're rough when it comes to collecting!
Even though I'm a detective, they wouldn't
left me off easy and they stabbed me with a knife.
刑事だからって 容赦はしないって
ナイフで刺されて...
They threatened me
by saying that I won't live next time.
So that's what really happened
instead of a thug stabbing you.
Who's the culprit!?
Ah! Aren't you the one who
was at Cuddly Dominion when Ai-chan got in the way!?
Ah... no...
That girl's name is Ayumi.
Doesn't matter which!
You're the detective who was
chasing after that man then, right!?
I see...
Now I clearly got it!
Haibara, can you hear me?
You bastard! Why did you rob us!?
How did you know about the secret data!?
The person who stole it
was probably somebody else.
Because, I believe,
when Kumamon Foods was robbed,
Detective Kouda was still hospitalized, right?
Then, the secret data on the new product—
Where did my Kumamon go!?
We know where it is!
Come with us for a bit.
Found it!
R-Really, Ayumi!?
There's definitely a USB inside.
There's no mistaking it.
Way to go, Ayumi!
You did it!
Thank you!
With this, our company is saved!
Yup!
Here!
No, we can't hand it over yet.
Wh-What do you...
Great Detective Mouri Kogorou...
Let us now...
Dad?
What's wrong, Mouri-san?
Inoue-san, I have
something I want to ask you.
What is it?
This case was
a prank schemed by yourself, perhaps?
What in the world do you mean?
The culprit who stole Kumamon Foods' secret data
was Inoue-san—
I'm asking if it was you.
Wh-What are you saying!?
I heard from Conan that
during the transaction held at Cuddly Dominion,
昨日のカドリー・ドミニオンでの
犯人との取り引きの時
you weren't at the scene.
Despite that,
you knew that Ayumi-kun
got hit by the culprit's bag.
Looks like you got that from Pres. Kumada, eh?
あなたは それを熊田社長から
聞いたといったそうですね?
However, Pres. Kumada had a misunderstanding.
He mistakenly swapped
Yoshida Ayumi and Haibara Ai's names.
Ah! Aren't you the one who
was at Cuddly Dominion when Ai-chan got in the way!?
Ah... no...
That girl's name is Ayumi.
Doesn't matter which!
So if you really heard it from Pres. Kumada,
you should have heard that
a girl named Ai-chan got injured.
However, you didn't ask Haibara Ai;
instead, you asked
if Yoshida Ayumi was all right.
In other words, at that time...
... you were at the scene!
All in order to receive the money the robber gets.
However, your attempt failed.
In order to explain the situation,
you were to immediately report to Pres. Kumada and make it look like you just rushed to him.
Then you appeared before us.
Am I wrong?
I don't remember
telling you anything of that sort!
I-It's true I was at the
transaction spot on that day.
I'll admit that.
But that's because
I was curious about the transaction!
If you insist...
Detective Kosugi!
Your tablet has a USB port, correct?
Y-Yes, it does.
Then, right here and now,
we can confirm the contents of the retrieved USB, correct?
Ah... No, that's...
Is something wrong?
If that's really the stolen data,
there's no problem checking, right?
If you want to keep it confidential,
I don't mind just showing it to Pres. Kumada.
How about it, Inoue!?
Even if it was just a prank,
you couldn't actually use the real data.
That is...
... from the very beginning,
the secret data wasn't stolen!
H-He's always acting arrogant and
I couldn't stand being
treated like a henchman anymore...
So that's why I wanted to scare him a little bit!
Yet, the police got involved
and it became a kidnapping case!
The case got bigger and bigger, so
it became impossible for me to tell the truth!
"Lupin The Third vs. Detective Conan: The Movie" as a celebratory present!
If you call this number and listen to the limited time message,
you can get a wonderful present by lottery!
Today will be this!
Next episode: The Cold and Sweet Delivery (Part 1)
Former residence of Hosokawa Gyōbu
It seemed that
Justin's father had already passed away.
Jessica-san's phone call was
about consulting with her
husband's coworker about the case.
That's why it wasn't in her phone book and she had the business card...
I now know why Justin is always
saying that he'll protect his mother.
He probably thinks
he's filling in for his father, I guess...
Yeah, because...
... "Mommy is number one."
Next Conan's hint:
Receipt.
It was two birds with one stone, eh!?
It could be my turn next.
I can't wait for the next episode!
Huh?