I'm not letting it through!
It won't get past me!
Oh, no...
Go after it!
Bring it on!
There!
All right! Our fourth goal!
Conan-kun's so cool!
Yeah!
Hey, this ain't fair.
Maybe there's a problem with the rules.
What problem?
This is a three-on-two match where your team has more players!
And I only kicked with my left foot, you know.
Then we'll have to seal away your left foot, too.
Oh, come on.
Then I can only use my head?
But if we let Conan-kun head the ball, we might end up even worse!
Then you can't use your head, either.
Hey, hey, why so serious?
We're only doing this to kill time waiting for the Christmas cake to arrive at the doc's place, right?
So it's just another two hours, really.
Let's go!
That's low!
Haibara-san!
Okay!
Here I go!
Higo-san's signature no-spin shot!
That was lucky!
What were you doing, Haibara?!
Sorry. I should've passed the ball better.
It's not that.
This kitty jumped in front of the ball, so I couldn't kick it.
Come here.
Wow, it's so cute!
A cat?
Oh? That's Taii!
Taii?
You know that cat?
Yeah.
It's a stray cat who set up camp around the 5th district, near the Mouri Detective Agency.
It's attached to Azusa-san at Café Poirot, and every evening, it goes there to beg for food.
And so, since it keeps coming to "Poirot",
captain
the shop owner named it "Taii", after Detective Poirot's friend Captain Hastings.
It's Tai-chan then.
But is it really a stray? It's wearing a collar.
Seems it used to be someone's pet.
Ai-chan, your sweater got caught on the cat's claw and the thread's come loose.
Well, it is hand-knit.
But where's it going?
It'd be horrible if it jumped into the road and got run over by a car!
Let's chase it!
We've gotta hurry...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
The Detective Boys shut away! A surprising case in a refrigerated truck!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Huh? Where'd it go?
I don't see it anywhere.
Ah, there it is!
Behind that truck!
Oh, you're right.
It came all the way out here.
It went inside.
Oh no!
Maybe it was drawn in by the smell of fish or something in the cargo area?
Either way, if we don't get it back soon...
The driver went somewhere and isn't here.
Then we'll have to go in and bring it out!
It's cold!
It seems to be a refrigerated truck!
Tai-chan, where are you?
Tai-chan!
There you are!
Tai-chan.
Geez, that cat really gets in trouble.
You said it.
Well, come on, Taii.
Geez, you left the door wide open!
Ah, sorry.
Be careful!
Right.
W-Wait!
Excuse us!
I think I heard a kid's voice.
There's a park nearby, so no wonder you're hearing kids.
Ah, right.
They started driving without us!
Isn't that bad?
Are we going to freeze too?
It's fine.
There's still a bunch of undelivered goods scheduled for today.
Let's get out the next time the delivery guys open the door, okay?
H-Hey!
We stopped!
They'll probably be surprised with us coming out like that.
They'll probably get mad at us.
Well, we have a valid reason, so we just have to explain it to them.
Don't!
Don't you dare get out now!
H-Haibara-san?
Why are you in your underwear?
My sweater thread got caught on god knows what, and everything just fell apart and disappeared!
So stop shining that light on me already!
Oh, sorry.
They're coming!
Let's hide for now!
Hey, quit dawdling! Hurry up and deliver 'em!
I think I heard somebody inside.
Don't be stupid. That makes no sense.
R-Right.
Get on with it!
Right.
Let's see, our next delivery is...
Sasagawa-san at Beika Condo, Room 205!
Right, Sasagawa-san.
Ah, here it is!
A fruit assortment package.
Then hurry up and give it to them.
Drop it on the entryway floor on purpose like before, and make sure they remember your name and face!
They're our precious witnesses.
Witnesses?
Yeah, I know.
Meanwhile, I'll go ask the nearby corner shop to use their toilet like last time.
Hey, just to be safe, shouldn't we check the cargo area?
I'm intrigued by that voice.
Don't bother doing useless crap like that.
B-But...
Don't get cold feet.
He can't possibly make any voices, you know.
Can't possibly make any voices?
Hurry! Just go now!
Yeah.
Don't tell me those two are...
A-Anyway, please put on my jacket.
Thanks, you're a life saver!
Don't mention it.
Still, if we don't get out of here quick, we'll catch a cold!
It's fine.
With this, I can get out now.
Right!
But since you're only wearing one layer, you should probably hug Tai-chan, since it's pretty warm!
Okay.
Then as soon as the deliverymen open the door, let's have them get us out!
Yeah!
No, we probably shouldn't do that.
Looks like there was already a passenger before we came here.
What's the meaning of this?
Beats me.
I don't know who he is, or why he was killed,
but the ones who did it were probably the deliverymen from earlier.
Seriously?!
But why's he in the cargo area?
Because of the cooling equipment.
Once they put the body in here, the decomposition rate decreases and the estimated time of death will be later than it really is.
After that, all they have to do is drop the body somewhere, so that even if it's discovered,
they can just claim they were working at the time of the crime!
They wanted to make the addressees remember their names and faces by dropping the packages at the entrances
so they could testify to the cops saying "that deliveryman did hand me the package at the time".
And if they keep asking to use the toilets at corner shops, they'll appear on surveillance cameras and have alibis.
They can just say they had an upset stomach and won't be suspected.
Besides, look at this.
The cardboard box carrying the body has dented corners and smudged sides, right?
Which means they rolled the box along with the body over and over periodically to slow down rigor mortis.
Hold on.
So if those two find us...
Yeah.
They'll probably kill all five of us and lock us in here.
N-No way!
Can't we do something?
Like rushing out the door as soon as they open it!
That's no good.
Our bodies are numb from the cold, so I don't think we'd be able to escape soon enough.
Well, no need to worry.
How about we deliver those two ourselves?
To prison, that is.
So, what do we do?
How are we going to catch those two deliverymen?
Tell us, Conan-kun!
We won't be the ones doing the catching.
We'll leave that to somebody else.
Just use a mobile phone to call Detective Takagi at the Police HQ.
We'll tell him that bad guys from Cheetah Delivery Service are carrying a dead body inside the refrigerated compartment,
and that we're locked inside it.
Then ask him to set up a police cordon, and investigate the cargo area as the truck stops.
I memorised this refrigerated truck's plate number, so we're all set.
What?
A phone call?
I thought you had a more ingenious idea.
Under these circumstances, isn't that all we can do?
Yeah!
So would one of you please lend me your mobile?
I left mine charging at the doc's place.
I left mine at the doctor's, too.
Me too, I didn't wanna drop it when playing football.
I did bring mine, but it's been buzzing with a low battery warning, so I doubt it's of any use.
Well, can I have it? I'll try to resurrect the battery.
Resurrect the battery?
You can do that?
Yeah.
Just gotta take out the battery and warm it with my body temperature.
The voltage will rise and we can use it for a small while.
Well, at least we can tell Detective Takagi what's going on.
The sound of the brakes!
Those guys are coming!
Let's hide!
Yeah.
That was dangerous.
Let's see, the only deliveries for the fourth district are Yamada-san and Nishino-san, right?
Yeah.
But before that, it's about time to change the body's position.
Oh, right, it's been about two hours.
One, two, three!
Okay.
That's another two hours without having to worry about livor mortis.
What's wrong?
There are some marks suggesting the sellotape was peeled off...
Don't be stupid! There's nobody who can do that!
Huh? I think I heard a cat.
What's with you all this time?
Saying things like you're hearing a brat's voice and whatnot?
But...
Well, can't blame you for being paranoid.
You did kill a guy, after all.
Sorry.
It's my fault we're in this mess.
You couldn't help it.
Who'd have thought our earlier delivery was to the husband of the woman you're having an affair with,
or that he'd grab your collar yelling
"It's all your fault we're getting a divorce"?
I didn't want to kill him!
I only pushed him away to get away from him!
But then he accidentally hit his head and stopped moving.
Well, you made the right decision by calling me instead of the police.
We got a lot of money from the guy's wallet, after all.
B-But are you sure we won't get caught?
Don't worry.
We'll return the guy's body to his home and leave it there in a bit.
Then we'll revisit his home at the right time and call the police as if we'd just discovered the body. Everything will be fine!
R-Right.
As long as we break the window glass first, they'll just think he was attacked by a petty thief.
Besides, we have a whole bunch of witnesses that can prove our alibis!
Yeah.
I see. It was an accidental death.
Either way, we should tell Detective Takagi about this.
Ladies and gentlemen, we're about to take off.
We remind you to please turn off all electronic devices including mobile phones, laptops, and game consoles.
Sorry.
I finished checking the map around the Kyōto Police HQ where we'll be picking up the suspect.
But how do I turn this thing off?
Oh, just hold down the power button!
All because you bought a smartphone trying to look edgy...
Did you turn off yours?
Yeah, ages ago.
The number you have dialled is outside the service area or the telephone may be switched off, so your call cannot be completed.
It's no use, it's not going through.
No way!
Oh well, there's no choice then.
I'll call Dr. Agasa and tell him about this.
H-Hello, Agasa here.
Doc? It's me. Jot down what I'm about to tell you.
Oh, sorry. I'm kind of busy, hold on a bit.
Hey!
What's cooking?
Okay.
Oh, hey, sorry for the wait.
I was frying doughnuts, thinking you guys wouldn't have enough with just the cake.
Though it's not going to hold a candle to that exclusive cake from that famous shop that's on its way!
He hung up.
Well, he'll call back if it's important.
Damn, the battery's dead.
What if you warm it up again?
If it's completely drained, it won't come back, no matter how much we warm it up.
Then what now?
You guys, show me everything you have!
I'll figure something out with them.
Okay.
Right.
Let's see. I have a handkerchief, pocket tissues, a candy, and a cotton bud.
The cotton bud's a spare from when my mum helped me clean my ears.
Don't worry, it's not used.
And you, Genta?
Let's see. I got a plaster, a chocolate bar, and an anti-itch cream for treating frostnips!
Anti-itch, huh?
Yeah. I never got any frostnips, but Mum keeps nagging me to carry that anyway.
And you, Mitsuhiko?
I have a notebook with a ballpoint pen,
a handkerchief, a wallet, and a taxi receipt.
A taxi receipt?
Yes.
I saw it on the floor near the washing machine just after I got up and washed my face in the morning.
I think Mum was emptying Dad's clothes pockets to wash them, and this just fell out.
I forgot to give it back to her.
The only other thing I have is the jacket I let Haibara-san wear.
I wore it as soon as it came back from the cleaners, so I don't think there's anything in the pockets.
How about you, Haibara? Do you have anything with you?
Oh, right. All you got is your underwear.
Shut up!
But I don't think we can do anything with these.
Hey, what if we write "Help!" in Mitsuhiko-kun's notebook and drop it outside the truck?
That's a good idea!
The gap between the doors looks wide enough for a sheet of paper!
But even if somebody did pick it up, would they really call for the police straight away?
Besides, while it'd be nice if we could get the paper past the door,
if it ended up getting stuck on the door and didn't fall off, we'd be out of luck.
When those deliverymen come to open the door, they'd notice the page sticking out,
and they'd realise that there's somebody in the cargo area!
I see.
Then what do we do?
I dunno.
You don't know?
Well, you're taking this pretty well.
You're the one who got us into this mess in the first place, jumping into the cargo area.
Come to think of it, this cat...
Aha! That paw...
No, but as I expected, that...
What? If you have something in your mind, spit it out!
Yeah.
The stop before the last one this home delivery truck made
was at Beika Condo in the third district, and the stop just now was for two houses in the fourth district.
So what's next?
The fifth district, I guess?
Yeah. The territory of this cat, Taii.
The fifth district, where it goes to beg for food at Café Poirot during evenings!
I see! We'll let Tai-chan deliver a piece of paper saying "Help"!
If we stick it in its collar, I bet Azusa-san will notice it!
Let's do it!
Yeah!
But...
If those two catch this kitty sneaking out and notice this piece of paper...
There won't be any slip-ups like that.
I'll make a code that they won't figure out, even if they do see it.
A code?
Big trouble in a refrigerated truck!
Who's the Detective Boys' code meant for?
Detective Conan: A Sweet and Cold Delivery Service (Part II)!
Airing on Saturday, 21 December at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Christmas Cake!
I'd be fine with some chocolates.
You and cake don't go together, huh?
Is that so surprising?