[Receipt certificate]
[Label]
[Mail recipient]
We were playing football at a park to get some exercise while waiting for a cake to arrive at Dr. Agasa's house.
But then, chasing after Taii, the cat who made its home at Café Poirot, we ended up shut in the back of a refrigerated delivery van.
On top of that, Haibara's handmade sweater unravelled,
and with her in no sight to be seen, we ended up unable to leave even if we wanted to...
Then, we found a man's corpse among the items in the van.
We attempted to tell the police using Mitsuhiko's phone, but the battery ran out.
We then decided to think of some way to get a message outside using what we had at hand.
I've got a handkerchief, pocket tissues, a piece of candy, and a cotton bud.
And you, Genta?
Let's see. I've got a plaster, a chocolate bar, and an anti-itch cream for frostnips!
And you, Mitsuhiko?
I have a notebook with a ball point pen, a handkerchief, a wallet, and a taxi receipt.
Come to think of it, this cat...
Aha! I know what to do!
What? If you thought of something, spit it out!
Right.
The last stops made by this delivery van were to Beika House in the third district, then to two houses in the fourth district.
So what's next?
W-Wouldn't it be the fifth district, I guess?
Yeah!
The home of this cat, Taii.
The fifth district, home to Café Poirot, where it goes to beg for food in the evenings!
I see! We'll let Tai-chan deliver a piece of paper saying 'Help'!
If we stick it in its collar, I bet Azusa-san will notice it!
Let's do it!
Yeah!
But...
If those two catch this kitty sneaking out and notice the piece of paper...
We won't have to worry about that.
I'll make a code that they won't figure out, even if they do see it.
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
Where will the code deciding the fate of the Detective Boys end up?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
A SWEET AND COLD DELIVERY SERVICE
(PART II)
A code?
The taxi receipt Mitsuhiko had was printed on thermal paper.
Rather than using ink, it turns black when heated to form words.
The front of thermal paper is coated with a chemical that turns black, and another acidic chemical called the colour former.
When exposed to heat, the colour former melts and the two chemicals react, causing words to appear in black.
On the other hand, the ammonia in the anti-itch cream Genta had is alkaline, and can neutralise acid.
So if I dip the cotton bud into it, and rub it on the upper part of the letter 'a' in the word 'Card' on the receipt...
Wow! The 'a' turned into an 'o'!
It's true!
That's amazing, Conan!
Now, if I take the letters making up the words 'Card Purchases',
and erase part of the 'a' and the whole 'd' from 'Card', as well as the 'urcha', and the final 's' from 'Purchases'...
'Corpse'.
It'll tell them about the dead body!
Then, by strategically erasing part of the card number and phone number at the bottom
to show the number plate of the refrigerated van,
I can convey that there's a dead body inside this van!
That's amazing, Conan-kun!
Once I crumple this up a bit and stick it on Taii's collar like this...
Then even if they manage to capture Taii and notice the receipt, they'd think it's just some sort of misprint,
or that the letters just rubbed off somewhere.
I see.
It's perfect.
I knew you'd come through.
Uh-oh. Looks like they stopped!
Listen up, Taii! Our lives depend on you!
You must complete this mission at all costs!
A-A cat!
There's a cat in the cargo area!
Lemme guess, it probably snuck in when you left the doors wide open.
Then the noise I heard earlier must've been this cat.
Oh! There's paper in its collar!
A receipt?
What?
This is bad.
Hold it!
It turned tail and fled!
Just leave it.
Yeah.
Now we just have to rely on Taii!
Right.
Hey, a word.
If it's going to Poirot, then that man will see the code too.
Yeah.
That's why I made such a code — so that man would see it for sure!
He should figure it out straight away.
Since he's one of the men in black...
Bourbon!
Oh my, Taii! You're late today.
Drink it all up!
Huh? What's that in your collar?
A taxi receipt?
Azusa-san!
The master's calling for you.
Oh, right.
Say, aren't you a detective, Amuro-san?
Well, yes.
Then do you know what this means?
What was that?
Oh, never mind, it's nothing.
Is that so?
I'm freezing...
That's the last one for the seventh district of Beika.
Make sure you get them to remember your name and face!
Y-Yeah.
Then we better go back to the second district to drop off that parcel that needs to be delivered at a specified time,
and after that, I guess it's time to take the body back to his own house in the first district.
Hey, Conan.
It's been ages since we let the cat go,
and nobody's coming to help us!
Maybe that code was too difficult?
Or maybe the piece of paper with the code slipped out of its collar midway.
All that aside, what are we going to do?
There aren't many parcels left to deliver, and we're running out of places to hide!
You're right!
Hey. A pair like that...
Can't you do something about them with your tranquilliser watch and kick booster shoes?
That's the first thing I thought as well.
But on top of the fact that the watch is nearly out of battery, the cold's made the voltage go down and the thing's not even twitching!
Mitsuhiko-kun, are you all right?
You've been very quiet. Are you all right?
I seem to have managed to get over the cold somewhat.
I've stopped shivering, too.
Hey, wait! That's even more dangerous!
Mitsuhiko!
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
He's unconscious due to hypothermia.
And his fingertips have gone purple.
It won't be long before he gets frostbite!
No way!
Oh, Mitsuhiko...
He lent Haibara his jacket, so he was only wearing one shirt after all.
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
You've got to wake up!
Mitsuhiko!
Mitsuhiko!!
There were erased letters on the taxi receipt?
Is that what you were trying to show me earlier?
Yes, as far as I remember.
There were empty spaces between 'Cor', 'P' and 'se', so I wondered if it was a misprint.
C-O-R-P-S-E...
Corpse!
Who knows that this cat comes here every day to beg for food?
He only started coming recently. So the only ones who know are me, the master, you,
and apart from that, probably just Conan-kun.
Conan Edogawa-kun, huh?
Also, I touched its collar when I took the receipt, and it felt really cold.
Am I right in thinking it blew away in that direction?
What? You're going to look for it?
Tell the master I suddenly felt ill and had to go home early.
And there's no need to pay me for today's work.
R-Right.
If I simulate the local area by taking into account the strength and direcion of the wind, and the positions of the buildings nearby...
I should be able to model the wind currents and figure out where it was blown to.
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Please, Mitsuhiko-kun, wake up!
He woke up!
I...
I'm sorry.
You ended up suffering to help me.
Just stay still! I'll warm you up.
Ah, right! That's very kind of you!
But with you guys like that, I doubt we'll be able to run away even if we tried.
Damn.
And we should be eating a great cake at the doc's by now.
All the way from a cake shop in Yokohama!
Yokohama?
The cake being delivered to the Doc's is coming from a shop in Yokohama?
Yes.
He specified for it to be delivered around the time we get home.
This only happened because school finished early today.
Come to think of it,
those guys mentioned earlier that they were going back to the second district to deliver a parcel with a specified delivery time.
C-Conan-kun?
If you disturb things too much, they'll find out we're here!
Got it!
This is the cake being delivered to the doc's house!
Are we gonna eat it now?
Don't be stupid.
We're going to stick a message on it!
Using Mitsuhiko's pen and Ayumi-chan's cotton bud!
I don't think you should write anything on the parcel, Conan-kun!
Imagine what would happen if those two found out!
And we'd want it to be something the Doctor would notice immediately.
It's fine! He'll notice right away...
Because the delivery address isn't going to be the doc's.
So the location was right.
What's under the word 'Corpse' is probably a car's number plate.
The cat's collar was cold, so the most obvious conclusion would be a refrigerated car, but...
Specialised utility vehicles like that would have a plate number beginning with 8, and this number doesn't start with 8.
Which means it's most likely a cool goods delivery van.
And now that I know that...
Which house here belongs to 'Kudō'?
Kudō?
What are you gabbing about now?
The specified time parcel was for an 'Agasa', wasn't it?
But just take a look! This sales slip...
It says 'Care of Mr Kudō' before Agasa, see?
That's strange. It doesn't say that here.
Oh! It looks like it's this house!
Yes?
Sorry to bother you, but this is the Cheetah Delivery Service.
Is there a Mr Hiroshi Agasa in residence?
Ah, Agasa-san lives next door.
But we've got a parcel addressed to Hiroshi Agasa, care of Mr Kudō.
Oh, now I remember. It's the cake, isn't it?
He's in the other room doing some work that he can't take his hands off of at the moment, so I'll take the parcel.
What?!
You wrote 'care of Mr Kudō' in front of 'Hiroshi Agasa'? And in ballpoint pen?!
That's right.
This way, the package won't go to the doc's, but should be delivered to Subaru-san living in the Kudō house next door.
And?
So you figured out a way for him to receive the parcel, but how did you tell him that we're in danger?
Think about it!
Nobody but me would write something like that, right?
And if he looks at the handwriting and the colour of the ink,
Subaru-san should easily be able to tell that it was added on later with a ballpoint pen.
And he should also work out that the only way I could've written it would be from inside the delivery van out on its rounds.
I get it!
That's amazing!
Anyway, I spelt out our situation on the sales slip as well, just in case.
What?! But then we might be discovered at any moment!
It's all right!
I wrote it using this cotton bud I removed the cotton from.
There's no way you could write anything with that!
Oh, but you can!
Delivery sales slips usually have various layers,
like the label, the sender's copy of it, and so on.
And they're made using special paper so that if you write on the top one,
whatever you write is copied onto all the sheets underneath.
So if I remove the proof of delivery sheet that the postman would take out after having it signed by the recipient,
write on the remaining two sheets with a cotton bud, then put the proof of delivery sheet back in,
nobody will know I've written on the now bottom-most slip, the recipient's copy,
until Subaru-san removes the label in front of it!
So right now those two guys are being dealt with by Subaru-niichan?
Nah. What Subaru-san would probably do is...
Hey, why are you opening the back again?
That recipient asked me to take on a small package.
It's only a small one, so you don't mind, do you?
Oh, whatever.
H-Hey!
Conan-kun?
Just as I thought.
A mobile phone?
I see.
It's probably the most useful tool for us in this situation.
Yep!
The safest and most reliable way to catch these guys would be to explain our situation directly to the police.
Like we'd let you do that.
I thought that some parcels had moved compared to earlier, so I decided I'd take a peek.
And what do you know, not just that cat, but five more sneaking kittens had snuck in.
D-Didn't I tell you that I thought I heard a kid's voice?
Yeah. My bad.
But these kids are pretty stupid.
They should've phoned the police straight away.
S-So what should we do with these kids?
Ain't it obvious?
After we take the phone off them, we just lock them in here and let them freeze to death.
Then we line up their little bodies next to the geezer, and we'll have the ultimate impossible crime!
Since these brats have no connection to us whatsoever.
Right!
Excuse me!
This road's rather narrow, so could you please give way?
I wouldn't want to damage anything!
Right away.
It's the detective guy!
Help!
What's this? What are you lot doing in there?
Oh, no, this is just... err...
So you're a friend of the kids, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
If you've seen them, then there's no choice.
If you wanna stop them from getting killed, you better get in the van right now!
Didn't I tell you?
To give way because I didn't want to damage anything?
Would you like to have a go as well?
Oh, no, no, no.
Yay!
Okay. Conan-kun! Call the police.
R-Right.
You're an amazing detective!
You came here because you saw the code on the receipt, didn't you?
Receipt?
Oh, that weird receipt in the cat's collar?
It got blown away by the wind and I couldn't find it.
I just happened to be passing by this way.
Aw, is that all.
Then how about you come and eat cake with us in the Doctor's house?
So this is the place of the famous Dr. Agasa.
But I will have to decline for today.
I have other things to do.
Then give my regards to Dr. Agasa.
Ima aitakute...
(I want to be with you...)
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
I see.
You must've had quite a rough time.
It was so cold I thought I'd freeze into an icicle!
Mitsuhiko even passed out!
What?!
But Ai-chan warmed him up, so he felt better right away!
Thanks for that.
You caught the killers then?
Yeah!
Amuro-san, who works part-time at Poirot took care of them for us!
A-Amuro-kun?!
Yeah!
He was so cool!
But never mind that, let's eat the cake!
Oh! Right, right!
I went and forgot the most important thing.
Cake! Cake! Cake!
It's a special Christmas cake I ordered all the way from a famous bakery in Yokohama!
Be careful not to make a mess eating!
Feast your eyes on this!
Isn't this the icing on the cake?
It's completely ruined!
Now that I think about it, they did say something about dropping parcels on purpose so that recipients remembered them.
The red diamond on this turtle's back — the Blush Mermaid!
It's true! It's stuck to the turtle's back, gold necklace chain and all!
Still, it's quite the guard you have here!
No way!
'Kaitō Kid'!
How'd he manage to do it in a situation like this?!
(PART I)
On the next Conan: 'Kaitō Kid and the Blush Mermaid (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: The huge water tank!
Amuro-san's a really nice person!
Edogawa-kun...
Don't ask me.