Happy New Year!
You may have been worried about me, but with the new year, I've got my old body back,
so from now on, I, high school detective Shin'ichi Kudō, will solve any case in a flash—
What're you doing?
I'm Shin'ichi Kudō, a high school detective.
While at an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Ra—
Excuse me?!
Ah, no...
Kaitō Kid realised that his disguise as Shin'ichi Kudō had been discovered.
How will he manage to escape?!
Or will he vanish with the dew on her fist?!
You can watch it on our website!
No, you can't!
Now, let's start over...
Happy New Year!
Thanks to all of you, the TV show and the movie were very popular last year!
It was a packed year, as we even had a collaboration movie together with that thieving old man!
And as for the year to come...
It's the 20th anniversary of the manga serialisation! Congratulations!
And so...
All of us involved with the series will be giving all we can more than ever...
So please keep watching!
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
Kid's after a crimson diamond.
Time to unveil his illustrious trick!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
KAITŌ KID AND THE BLUSH MERMAID
(PART I)
Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki sponsored a special trip for the Bell Tree Express, hoping to capture Kaitō Kid.
But the men in black took over the train in their attempts to erase Sherry — a.k.a. Ai Haibara.
And even Kaitō Kid, who was on the train to inspect it, ended up caught in the explosion when a carriage blew up.
What's the meaning of this, Superintendent Chaki?!
After the explosion on the Bell Tree Express the other day,
the jewel exhibition was supposed to be delayed until we'd closed the case!
Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki was pretty hard-set on it.
He probably thought that since he'd got his hands on a gem that was likely to lure Kaitō Kid in, it'd be a shame not to show it.
Anyway, for us police, it means we get another shot at catching Kid.
But still, if that explosion was caused by some criminal targeting the jewel exhibition,
then it'll get targeted again!
We still don't know the truth behind that case!
I doubt Kid would stick his hands in something that dangerous.
Actually, a letter from Kid has already been delivered to the advisor,
saying he'll come to collect the gem on the first day of the exhibit.
Along with a message for the police, asking us to make sure that the exhibition hall doesn't get blown up this time.
And it looks like that gem can only be exhibited for a limited amount of time.
A limited amount of time?
It's not as though that billionaire's renting the gem...
Come to think of it, we haven't seen the jewel in question yet, have we?
No, we haven't.
I hear it's going to be displayed in a large glass case.
According to the advisor, the jewel can move around freely in all directions in the glass case.
M-Move around?!
What's that supposed to mean?
Great Suzuki Museum
So let's begin!
I present before you a single can of cola!
As you can see, it's been crushed, and there's nothing left inside!
And with the power of my will...
I-It went back to normal!
And once I run my finger across the can, the stay-on-tab reverts to normal!
No way!
And the cola inside remains intact!
Amazing, Sonoko!
You rock!
How did you do it? Tell me!
No can do!
Kid-sama's coming tonight, and I want to perform it in front of him to surprise him!
I don't think he'll be surprised at all.
Because look, there's a black sticker stuck to your thumb.
Plus, that can has traces of two small holes in the outside.
You're right.
Sonoko-neechan probably poured out half of the cola through the holes she'd made with a drill or something,
and then crushed the can and blocked the holes with glue.
Then she stuck the black sticker at the mouth of the can to make it look like the can was open.
I get it! If you shake the can to prove there's nothing left inside,
the cola would foam up and release carbon dioxide gas,
which would smooth out all the dents in the can with the increase in pressure.
Then if you trace around the mouth of the can with your fingers and remove the sticker,
it'll look as if the can had been miraculously mended, right, Conan-kun?
That trick was on TV the other day.
Ran! Why'd you bring that annoying little brat?!
Your uncle Jirokichi invited him, didn't he?
Because Conan-kun's the 'Kid Killer'!
More than that, I'm surprised you came, Sera-san!
I didn't think you'd be interested in stuff like phantom thieves.
I'm certainly not uninterested.
Holmes had Prof. Moriarty, Kogorō Akechi had the Fiend with Twenty Faces...
It's natural for a detective to have a mysterious rival!
And anyway, I wanted to ask you about this hat that you picked up on the Bell Tree Express.
I just picked it up from the corridor.
Then you didn't see him?
A man wearing black clothes, a black hat, and had a burn all the way down his right cheek.
So you came, Shirō's wee lass!
I must apologise for the fiasco on the Bell Tree Express the other day.
Wow, it's getting very crowded in here!
It's expected, with Kid-sama's popularity!
Since we're here, why don't we look around the other exhibitions?
Sure!
Wow! There are lots of people around that glass case!
But isn't that...
...an aquarium?
Hey, hey, don't tell me...
That's right.
That's right. The object Kid wants this time is...
The red diamond on this turtle's back — the Blush Mermaid!
Let's see...
It's true!
It's stuck to the turtle's back, gold necklace chain and all.
There are a lot of jewels stuck on its belly, too.
You wanted to display this 10 centimetre long decorated turtle in the Bell Tree Express's first-class carriage?!
Exactly!
The aquarium's made from toughened glass.
The back is a concrete wall that's two metres thick.
The top and sides are a metal mesh made from a special alloy,
and on top of that, his prey swims freely in the water.
So even the so-called 'Moonlight Magician' shouldn't be able to steal this one!
Seems to be in pretty bad taste to me.
The animal protection league's probably gonna come down on his head.
Actually, there's a story behind this turtle.
I trust you've heard about the great Italian actress who died in an accident half a year ago.
It's said that this is the turtle she kept as a pet, named 'Poseidon'!
Poseidon?
Right.
The owner of the Blush Mermaid was her, after all.
But why would she put the jewel on her pet?
The story goes that she desperately stuck the jewels onto the turtle with glue before the ship sank,
hoping that the turtle would be saved and taken in by somebody!
The jewels were both for breeding expenses and as a sign of her gratitude.
The local fishermen found it floating in the water along with the tank,
and by happy chance, it found its way into my hands!
But have you actually had the jewel appraised?
I tried, but the expert was bitten by the turtle during the appraisal.
Well, the turtle's supposed to shed its skin at some point between May and November,
and I intended to wait until the turtle shed its skin so that I could take the jewel to the expert for an appraisal before I bought it.
But I just couldn't wait.
I get it. He wanted to have a showdown with Kid while the jewel was still on the turtle's back.
Hey!
Visitors' time is over!
Everybody apart from those involved with the case, get out of here!
Stop faffing around and just get out!
Who is he?
That's Inspector Nakamori, from Division 2 of the Police HQ.
Division 2?
He's the inspector responsible for Kaitō Kid.
Yeah. When Kid-sama's involved, he's always there.
So he's the one who's always being shown up by Kid.
Hey, son! Didn't you hear what I said?!
Everybody apart from those involved are to get out of here!
Ah, wait a second, Inspector Nakamori!
Sera-san's from our high school.
And what do you mean 'son'?
He had no choice.
After all, it's the first time I've met him.
That's why you pulled my cheek, right? To see if I was Kid in disguise or not.
Right?!
Right in the balls!
That's Jeet Kune Do for you...
Since you're sweating like this, I guess you're not wearing a disguise either, Inspector!
Yo, Ran!
Dad! I thought you weren't coming!
I changed my mind when watching all of this on the news.
And anyway, I was a bit worried about you for once.
For once?
And another useless idiot shows up.
After all that effort shutting out the visitors, why do we have to show a bunch of amateurs around?
You're to watch quietly from the back, okay?
Yup!
Well then, since we have 30 minutes left until
8 PM when he shows up, I'm going to the toilet!
The nearest toilet's crowded!
Roger!
Hey, when did you go to the toilet, Sonoko?
When we were touring the museum earlier.
You didn't notice?
Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
The cheering for Kid's getting pretty loud.
How long until Kid-sama appears?
Let's see...
Huh?
Still, it's quite a guard you have here.
Yes. This time, we're ready for anything!
In addition to the twenty men around the aquarium,
we've got a hundred armed men with searchlights waiting in the passageway on the second floor with shining eyes.
And the lights have batteries!
There's no way they'll go out!
Therefore, Kid won't be able to use the cover of darkness in his plan to steal the jewel this time, as he usually does!
What?!
What's going on?!
Out of the way!
He covered the tank with the carpet!
Is he planning to steal the entire tank along with the carpet?!
Damn!
Three!
Two!
One!
Sonoko, Sera-san, you two okay?!
Never mind that, what about the jewel?!
You're joking...
I can't see it anywhere!
But there's a card in the water!
'The shy little mermaid has dissolved into foam and disappeared into my hands.'
'Kaitō Kid.'
T-The hell?
No way...
How'd he pull it off in a situation like this?!
T-The jewel disappeared along with the turtle?!
T-That's impossible!
Look for it! It's gotta be here in the tank somewhere!
Maybe in the shadow of a rock, or in the gravel!
Yes, sir!
T-This is...
Kaitō Kid's...
What?!
What does it say?
'I have taken the jewel.'
'If you don't believe me, check!'
What?!
Remove the locks on the aquarium mesh and bring me a step-ladder this instant!
I'll check the tank myself!
How is it, Uncle?
Uncle!
Is the turtle there or not?!
Which is it?
I-It's no use.
It's gone.
T-That's insane...
Damn it!
You can't!
You can't come inside!
Stay away!
'Kaitō Kid got the treasure!'
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Damn it. Why are they cheering on the criminal?
Well, there isn't much we can say.
The tank was made from reinforced glass.
The sides and ceiling of the tank were covered in a steel mesh made from a special alloy.
And while our eyes were covered by the carpet,
the deluxe turtle with the jewel on its back was stolen in a pretty spectacular way.
How do you know the tank's specs so well?
Hmph, it was on the news!
But wasn't this a little too well done?
He'd planted all the strings in the carpet and set a winch under the chandelier to pull them up!
Didn't you check them?
Y-Yes, sir, but we'd heard that the carpet and the light had both been changed a few days before the tank was to be exhibited here.
What?! A few days before?
We redid the carpet because a few days ago, a visitor sprayed cola around everywhere.
And the workers from the interior design company suggested we change the light to match the colour of the carpet.
It seemed like a good opportunity for some redecorating,
since we'd just moved all the artifacts from this room into another to make room for the tank, so I took up their offer.
But now that I think about it, those two workers could've been...
What do you mean, 'could have been'?!
Those were Kid and his accomplice!
They already knew that the exhibition was gonna take place here!
Well, I'm not going to stew over what's come to pass.
W-What?!
I've lost this time. Let's withdraw!
He's probably run far away from here by now.
Or maybe that's what he made it look like, while he's still here in the gallery!
What?!
Because Kaitō Kid always disappears into the darkness or under a smokescreen, right?
But this time, the light's been on the whole time, and he didn't even show himself!
If Kid did manage to steal the jewel with the turtle, then he should still be here.
And the guards blocking the entrance aren't making any moves,
so I'd like to pinch the face of everybody in here like this and find out if Kid really is disguising himself as one of us or not.
But I feel bad about pinching the girls' faces, so how about we split off into groups and do some body searches?
Body searches?
Kid should still have the turtle with the jewel.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah, I guess.
Is that really okay?
For me to be in the same group as you for the body search?
It's fine. We'll check you all over.
So who do we start with?
How about we go by ages and start with me?
By ages? What month were you born in, Sera-san?
More to the point, how do you even know our ages?
Well, Sera-san's a detective.
She really is flat as a board.
That spot feels nice...
Just shut up.
I don't get it.
That was an impregnable tank, with its four sides made of reinforced glass,
and the top and two sides covered with a special alloy mesh.
How did he get it out in that fraction of time in which our vision was obscured by the carpet?
Put your hearts into the search! Kid's card was in the water!
He might be hiding somewhere!
No. The trick with the card was easy.
You roll up the card and tie it up with a string that dissolves in the water,
then pass a fishing line through the card and put a small stone at the end of it.
If you hang that from the light and set it to fall from a remote controlled signal,
the card would fall and drop through the steel mesh, the thread would dissolve, and the message would be revealed.
Either way, the ones who got closest to the tank were Sera, Sonoko, the old man and Inspector Nakamori.
They got bundled up in the carpet along with the guards who were already standing in front of the tank,
so any of them could've put the card directly in the water.
But the most suspicious person at the time was...
...Ran.
Ima aitakute...
(I want to be with you...)
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
Hey! Take your clothes off!
What about you over there?
We've finished the checks here, too!
S-Sonoko?
Are you okay, Sonoko-neechan?
I'm fine.
Everybody here was just being so weak-minded that it went to my head and I got really dizzy.
There's only one person here who could slip past without a body check, isn't there?
...and you, Kaitō Kid.
(PART II)
KAITŌ KID AND THE BLUSH MERMAID
On the next Conan: 'Kaitō Kid and the Blush Mermaid (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Magnet!
I was barely in the episode!
You were there all along in disguise, weren't you?
You never know!