The Blush Mermaid, a jewel targeted by Kid, was intended to be displayed on the Bell Tree Express.
But that exhibition was cancelled, so Sonoko, Ran, and Sera and I came to the Great Suzuki Museum for its new exhibition.
As always, Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki and Inspector Nakamori had flawless security measures awaiting Kid.
But when the announced time came, the carpet was pulled up, and in the moment it was out of sight,
the jewel vanished from the huge tank along with the turtle carrying it!
I don't get it.
That was an impregnable tank, with its four sides made of reinforced glass,
and the top and sides covered with a special alloy mesh.
So how could he have stolen it in the instant that our vision was obscured by the carpet?
No. The card is easy to explain.
You roll up the card and tie it up with a string that dissolves in water,
then tie fishing line to the string and loop it through the card, attaching a pebble to the end of it.
If you hang that from the light and set it to fall by remote control,
then the card would fall through the steel mesh, the thread would dissolve, and the message would be revealed.
Well, Sera, Sonoko, the old man, or Inspector Nakamori, who were wrapped up in the carpet,
or the guards who were already standing in front of the tank
could've put the card directly in the water as well...
But the most suspicious person at the time was...
...Ran.
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
How did the diamond vanish in a flash, and who is Kid disguised as?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
Inspector Nakamori!
I found something which looks like a winch on this light.
There are also traces of thin threads buried in the ceiling and the wall.
I see. The threads attached to the winch were passed though the chandelier's brace
in order to run along the walls and ceiling and tied to the carpet.
When those were pulled, the carpet, which had been cut into shape, came up too.
I also found this IC recorder next to the winch.
Three! Two! One!
So that's where the countdown voice from before the jewel disappeared came from.
Yes.
It was set up to cut the string once the audio finished.
Not bad.
Hey, you've been unusually supportive of Kid today.
You wouldn't happen to be...
Oh, no.
I was just impressed by his methods.
Hey, take your clothes off!
I'm going to check you over!
Oh, come on, have some mercy!
Inspector Nakamori, maybe we should give up and withdraw?
Even after draining the water from the tank and examining the whole thing, you still haven't found anything.
And you finished body-searching everybody here without finding either the turtle or the jewel, right?
Damn...
Hey! What about you over there?
We've finished the checks here, too!
No turtle or jewel!
But we're not done searching Ran-chan yet!
It's fine! You can just look at her and see she's the real thing.
Right?
Then maybe Kid did already escape.
He really is mysterious, huh?
He made the jewel disappear like magic.
Speaking of magic, I saw a really similar trick to all of this on TV the other day.
They did it at the same time as the cola trick I showed you during lunch.
The coin that the magician put next to a glass jar just suddenly slid through the glass and dropped into it!
Maybe it's related to whatever method Kid used this time?
Yeah, you're probably right!
Maybe you should tell Inspector Nakamori about that trick!
Having said that...
If I told the Inspector, you'd be in trouble...
...right, Kid-sama?
N-No, I'm not—
I'll keep quiet for you.
Because I saw you earlier.
You sneaked away from us just before the carpet rolled up.
That's because you knew the carpet was going to roll up and were trying to avoid getting wrapped up in it, right?
No! That was because you'd just asked me for the time, and when I tried to check my phone, the screen was all black!
Really?
Is that true, Ran-neechan?
I thought I was getting bad reception, so I walked two or three steps towards the window, and the carpet just...
You were even following me at the time, Conan-kun!
You looked really puzzled.
Conan-kun?
Could it be?
Hey, Mr. Jirokichi!
Was the clasp of the gold chain attached to the jewel rusty?
Yes. It was made of iron, after all.
I was thinking of replacing it with a pure gold clasp after the turtle shed its skin.
I see! That's what happened!
Kid didn't steal the jewel!
He just made it look like it was gone!
And he hasn't realised the huge mistake he made with his disguise.
The gallery is now past its closing time. Would the visitors please make their way to the exits?
Hey, did you hear that?
Some kind of moan coming from the toilet.
Dunno.
Maybe somebody's having trouble getting it out.
Well, looks like Kid's gone home, so we might as well go too.
Yeah.
Come on, it's time to close things up!
We checked every inch this time and found nothing!
Plus, we searched everybody here and nobody had the turtle on them.
So we can conclude that Kaitō Kid did indeed take the bejewelled turtle away.
There's no point for the police to stick around any longer!
But we have to at least figure out how he stole the turtle from the tank!
Now, now...
It's past 10 PM, so how about we wrap up the investigation for today?
Yeah. I'm pretty hungry, too.
Okay, now I just gotta put the old man to sleep, and...
Come on, Conan-kun, let's go home.
Well, I guess I can use Sonoko as the detective.
Sonoko?
Are you okay, Sonoko-neechan?
I'm fine.
Everybody here was just being so weak-minded that it went to my head and I got really dizzy.
Nobody noticed it.
The turtle carrying the red 'Blush Mermaid' on its back wasn't stolen.
It was just made to look like it was gone!
Look like it was gone?
Yes.
If you want proof... Hey, brat, show it to them.
Got it.
Do you have a lighter, Uncle Kogorō?
Yeah, but it's just a cheap ¥100 thing.
Can you try dropping it into the tank from right above here?
Geez.
How's this gonna help us understand anything?
Huh? It didn't fall.
What happened?
It's stuck!
H-How?!
A magnet.
A magnet?
That plate is a really strong magnet, isn't it?
Those ¥100 lighters have their sparkers wrapped in iron, right?
But even if this is a magnet, that doesn't explain how the jewel disappeared.
Right.
A turtle wouldn't stick to a magnet, and the ornamentation surrounding the jewel had a gold necklace.
Gold isn't attracted to magnets.
The only thing that's attracted to magnets is the necklace clasp.
There were a lot of things stuck to the turtle's belly, too.
Oh, come on. Those were diamonds!
If they were synthetic diamonds, then wouldn't they stick to the magnet too?
When making synthetic diamonds, the iron used as a solvent is sometimes added into the diamond as an inclusion...
Inclu...?
Wow, Sonoko!
Anyway, the turtle was swimming in the tank, so there's no way you could hold it in place with just a magnet.
But I'm sure the plate was strong enough to at least attract it.
Attract it?
That was all that was needed.
Right, Mr. Kogorō?
Tell them what happened to the lighter.
It's not just a magnet!
The glass on the back of the plate is covered in glue!
Glue?
Yeah.
If a turtle got stuck on this, it wouldn't be able to move.
But how'd he get the turtle to touch the plaque in the first place?
With bait.
Bait?!
Yes. A little iron dust was mixed in with the turtle's food and spread around so that it stuck to the back of the plaque.
The turtle has a strong sense of smell, so it would've risen up from the bottom and fallen into Kid's trap.
The device used to spread the food was probably on the light.
It was set into motion when the carpet covered up the tank.
The turtle's around 10 centimetres long.
A plaque that size would've easily allowed the turtle to hide behind it without being seen.
That would mean that Kid's accomplices were mixed in with the workers who made the tank.
That's the Moonlight Magician, all right.
He's pretty good.
This isn't the time to be praising him!
Hold on.
It the turtle got stuck on the back of the plaque, then why isn't it there now?
We drained the water from the tank and searched it from top to bottom!
Somebody removed it quietly, and has it on themselves right now.
That's impossible! We body-searched everybody in here!
Except one person, right?
Somebody wasn't searched.
Do you mean me?
Now that I think about it, your bust looks a bit bigger than my daughter's...
Ran's boobs are the real deal! She isn't hiding anything!
The person hiding the turtle is the man who, before the body searches,
had his cheek pinched and was thus shown to not be Kid in disguise.
You, Uncle Jirokichi.
In order to see if the turtle was actually gone, he ordered the mesh to be removed and had the tank opened.
And when he got on the stepladder to look in the tank,
Uncle could've removed the turtle that was stuck to the glass and hidden it in his jacket's inside pocket.
Uncle's body would've hidden the turtle from everybody behind him.
Then let's have a look.
Ouch!
It's the turtle!
I'm so glad it's okay!
Then you really are Kid, huh?!
N-No! I can explain!
Explain?! How can you explain this?!
The explanation involves Kid's card, which was stuck under Uncle's foot.
The card probably said something like this...
'I can't imagine that a turtle covered in synthetic diamonds that got stuck to a magnet is carrying the real Blush Mermaid.'
'And the turtle's named Poseidon, after the Greek god of the sea.'
'But the owner was an Italian actress,'
'so she should've named it Neptune after the Roman god of the sea instead.'
'If you don't want people to know that you spent a fortune buying a dubious jewelled turtle,'
'then you'd be wise to remove it quietly.'
Is she right?
Yeah. Here's the card.
It's just like she said.
Oh geez. That's why you kept telling us to wrap things up.
I felt sorry for the turtle.
Then what happened to Kid?
Who knows?
All the devices could be triggered remotely,
so he was probably mixed in with the crowd pushing around at the entrance.
He's probably skipping home tonight looking all smug about it.
You were amazing, Sonoko!
It was nice to see the Deduction Queen again.
Y-Yeah!
Except I don't remember a thing.
Maybe if I use the left half of my brain too much, the right half becomes unconscious?
Could you wait here for a bit?
If you're going to the toilet, then I'm going too!
You know...
Don't you think that deduction earlier was a bit incomplete?
Even if you could hide the turtle behind the plaque with that trick, the long necklace on the jewel would've been dangling in the water,
so you'd be able to see it behind the plaque.
Kid himself probably had a strong magnet too.
Maybe he used it to attract the necklace around the edge of the plaque
and twisted the magnet and necklace upwards so that the necklace was hidden too.
But when did he do that?
While the tank was covered up by the carpet, obviously.
He probably shot the card at Mr. Jirokichi's feet during that time, too.
The people wrapped up in the carpet were all mangled up,
so if Kid was among then, he could've done whatever he wanted without looking suspicious.
Oh, I see.
As proof, Ran-neechan's phone went black as soon as she opened it.
Clamshell phones like that detect if they're open or closed by using a magnet,
which means there was somebody next to her at the time carrying a strong magnet.
Maybe her phone sensed the magnetic force and the screen stayed off because it thought it was closed.
But the people next to Ran-chan at the time were...
Me, Sonoko-neechan...
...and you, Kaitō Kid!
What was that noise?
Didn't it come from the men's toilet next door?
Did something happen?
Hold on.
Wasn't that...
When'd you figure out it was me?
The keyword was the magnet.
Because you were the one closest to Ran when she opened her phone.
You were holding the magnet in your left hand, right?
And the trick wouldn't work unless you pinched old Jirokichi's cheek in the first place,
then split everybody into groups for body searches.
In the end, though, it was that body search that made me realise you were Kid.
I didn't think my figure was that different.
The reason you were surprised when Ran and Sonoko wanted to group up with you for the body search
and why you thought 'you' were older than them was because you thought Sera was a boy from the year above, right?
Since normally they'd call a boy in their own class with the honorific kun, not 'Sera-san'.
Y-You mean...
This is a girl?!
Yep.
Well, you helped me out on the Bell Tree Express,
and you haven't actually stolen anything tonight, so I'll let you go this time.
I will, at least.
'I will'?
You jackass! How dare you knock me out with a stun gun?!
Now that I think about it, the underpants were pretty low-rise!
Sera-san, your underwear!
Full display!
Goddamn it!
Well, at least I got this back.
But why were you in the men's room in the first place?
Oh, that's because...
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
The girls' toilet was full so you went to the men's instead?
Seriously?
I wanted to get it over with, and I look pretty boyish to begin with.
No wonder Kid got it wrong.
Oh, right. Sera-san, weren't you asking about that hat earlier?
Yeah.
I wanted to ask if you'd seen a strange man around when you picked up this hat.
I didn't see anybody. Is that hat something special to you?
Yeah.
My late brother used to wear hats like this a lot, so I'm kinda copying him.
But you know...
This hat you picked up has a similar imprint to my older brother's well-worn hats.
But that's impossible.
What's this?
A dying message!
The culprit's name begins with 'na'.
Please. I want to help in the investigation however I can.
S-Someone murdered Nana?!
It's fine! I caught the killer already!
Okay, now everything fits!
On the next Conan: 'A Happy E-mail Brings Sadness'!
右
左
Next Conan's Hint: The 'right' and 'left' kanji!
You really got it handed to you.
Just because you're surrounded by freakishly strong women!
You just noticed?