Dad!
Is this really the right way?
Yeah.
We're not lost, are we?
Quiet!
All these country lanes are too dark anyway!
Dad, look in front!
Geez! Who'd park here!
I should teach them a lesson!
Calm down, Dad!
Uncle, over there!
No good. She's dead.
What's this?
A dying message!
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
An e-mail brings about an unexpected reaction.
Let's expose the whole truth behind the alibi trick!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
A HAPPY E-MAIL BRINGS SADNESS
Let's see... The victim is Nana Hirose-san, 27.
She was a door-to-door insurance saleswoman who lived nearby.
It looks like she was attacked when passing through this park after work.
Nana Hirose (27)
Door-to-door Saleswoman
She was strangled, and suffocated.
The killer strangled her over and over again to make sure she was dead.
They left lots of marks on her neck from doing so.
What's the estimated time of death?
Oh, between 10:00 and 10:30.
That's just before we arrived.
Are you sure you didn't see anything?
Sorry, we didn't.
If we had, we'd have told you already!
I guess. But don't worry! The victim left us a dying message!
The culprit's name begins with 'na'.
ナ
Oh! The victim's name was 'Nana'!
ナナ
I get it! She murdered herself! So it was suicide.
She probably had a split personality.
Still, something seems odd about it.
And this smell...
No, Conan-kun! You shouldn't go near the corpse!
Hey, there's a weird smell coming from her clothes.
Yeah, he's right.
It smells like gunpowder.
Shouldn't forensics check it out?
I was about to say that.
Huh?
Her face is wet, and her make-up's slightly rubbed off.
I was about to check that too.
Nana!
Nana! Let go of me! Nana!!
Who's he?
Who knows. But he seems to know the victim.
Osamu Samon (27)
Primary School Teacher
My name is Osamu Samon. I'm a primary school teacher.
左門治
And how did you know Hirose-san, the victim?
Well...
We were engaged.
I see.
Then has she seemed different to you lately?
Actually, we were supposed to have dinner together tonight, but then she sent me this e-mail...
.
I'll be a bit late.
Talking with Migita in the park.
Nana.
It was received at 9:45.
Not long before her estimated time of death.
And who is this Migita?
He was her boyfriend before me.
He kept following her, pleading her to come back.
So maybe he...
I see! I've got it!
Samon-san!
That's Migita written with the 'migi' of 'migi-hidari'
右左
and the 'ta' of 'tambo', right?
田んぼ
Y-Yes, that's right.
So she didn't write a katakana 'na'.
ナ
右
She was trying to write the 'migi' kanji and ran out of strength.
I see! Great work, Mouri-san!
Anyway, let's go and see Migita.
Please, let me come with you.
Oh, we can't...
Please.
I want to help in the investigation however I can.
I guess you can come.
But make sure that you don't get in our way!
Understood.
Are those your students?
Yeah.
Today, they held a wedding party for me.
What wonderful children.
Yes.
I don't know how I should tell them what happened.
Oh, you noticed?
Yes.
If you started writing my name, Samon,
左門
you'd end up with that dying message too.
Right. Of course I knew that.
It means that you're a suspect as well.
'Migita Bookshop'
S-Someone murdered Nana?! Really?!
Toshihiko Migita (32)
Bookshop Owner
Yes. And in the park where you arranged to meet her tonight.
Shut up!
I never arranged to meet her!
Then how do you explain this e-mail?!
I've never seen that before!
She was probably using me as an excuse to meet someone else.
And that's not all.
The victim left behind some evidence.
A dying message, that is!
She was trying to write your name, Migita-san, when she ran out of strength!
No, you can't say that for sure.
She could've been trying to write 'migi'.
But it could've been a katakana 'na', or a kanji 'dai'.
ナ
大
Or even 'inu'!
犬
Hmm, right.
That reminds me, the same thing'd happen if she was trying to write Samon's name.
Oh, you're right.
I couldn't have killed her anyway.
Since I have a perfect alibi.
I was working here all evening.
As you'll see on the surveillance footage.
Just about here... Am I glad I stayed behind.
You certainly did stay in sight of the cameras...
Oh! He left!
Oh, you came back quickly.
Even I've gotta go to the toilet sometimes.
Hmph! This is so confusing.
I see.
So the only time Migita-san wasn't recorded was the one time he went to the toilet.
Even by car, it'd take about twenty minutes to go to the crime scene and back.
Which means he couldn't have done it.
You understand now?
I've got a perfect alibi!
It may look like a perfect alibi.
But what was that I spotted?
I see.
Which means the murderer is Samon-san!
It was you!
But why?
I don't have any reason to kill her!
I haven't even met with her today!
Then you have an alibi?
Well...
It's certainly possible that you wrote that e-mail to frame on Migita-san.
I-I didn't!
No, the dying message was pointing to Migita-san.
Then there's that footage...
But that's not enough evidence.
What's this?
Could it be?!
Anyway, we'll take your full statement at the station.
N-No! I didn't do it!
Right, right, criminals always say that.
N-No, I...
Let's go, let's go.
No,
I'm telling you, I...
Could it be?
It's Sleeping Kogorō!
Dad!
The victim's dying message was not pointing to Samon-san.
But you, Migita-san!
How can you say that for sure?
M-Mouri-san?
This isn't enough to tell if she was trying to write 'migi' or 'sa'...
右
左
You can tell.
Hey, Conan!
Right!
Samon-san, take this.
Samon-san, you're a primary school teacher, right?
Why don't you write 'migi' so everyone can see?
Huh? Sure...
Huh... When writing 'migi' you write the horizontal bar after the sweeping stroke.
Look at where the horizontal bar and sweeping stroke cross.
You can clearly tell that the horizontal bar was written after the sweeping stroke.
I-It certainly was...
It's not the katakana 'na', nor 'Samon'.
Only 'migi' is written in that order.
T-That's hardly evidence, you know?
And have you forgotten? I've got a perfect alibi!
That's right!
Migita-san was always in view of the surveillance cameras!
For the whole time the camera was running, at least.
Right.
We assume that surveillance cameras are always left running.
Migita-san used that preconception.
At that one time he left to go to the toilet, he switched off the surveillance cameras.
Then, he took his scooter on a 10-minute trip to the crime scene, and attacked Nana-san.
Another 10 minutes later, Migita-san came back, turned the cameras back on, and returned within their view.
That way, even if more than twenty minutes was missing, it would look like there was no gap at all.
The surveillance cameras here don't display the time, after all.
They're easy to manipulate.
Then you really did kill Nana?!
C-Can you prove it?!
Where's the evidence that I murdered her?!
Okay, please come in.
This is a student who lives nearby.
Could you tell us what you saw?
R-Right!
It was around 10:30.
There was a programme I wanted to watch, so I went to turn on the TV.
Then...
I see. It certainly does say 10:30 today.
It was probably a drunk driver.
If you check nearby, you should find it somewhere.
That white car with the broken headlight.
You would've heard the crash loud and clear from in here.
But you never paid any attention to the noise in the footage.
Why?
Because the footage from that time is missing.
10:30 matches the time of the murder.
Migita-san, you weren't here at the time!
Damn! And I thought I fooled you all!
It was your hair.
Hair?
When you left the view of the cameras, your hair was messy, but when you came back, it was neatly flattened.
As if you had been wearing a helmet.
I figured out the trick when I saw that.
It was her fault.
.
She kept harassing me by sending me photos like these!
Damn it!
And she kept making fun of me, saying she never sent them!
.
Just as I thought. All that's left is...
Yes?
Huh? Gunshot residue?
It's fine! I caught the killer already!
Thanks.
Did they find gunshot residue on the victim's clothes?
Wow, you're perceptive.
Okay, now everything fits!
That's what happens when someone fires a gun, isn't it?
Right.
Hey! I never used a gun!
I know that.
The victim was strangled to death.
But why would she have gunshot residue on her?
It must be some sort of mistake.
I doubt it has anything to do with the case.
Oh well.
Now, Migita-san, let's get to the station!
Please wait.
This case isn't closed yet.
What're you trying to say, Mouri-san?!
The culprit is standing right here.
Yes, Migita-san certainly was the culprit.
For the attempted murder of Nana-san, that is.
Attempted murder?!
Then—
Yes. The true killer is someone else.
The true murderer of Nana Hirose-san...
Is...
Osamu Samon-san, it was you!
Uh, Mr. Detective, it's not like I'm trying to cover for him, but I killed her with my own two hands...
That's right! And you even said the stroke order of the dying message pointed at Migita-san...
The stroke order certainly did point out the truth.
It pointed out that the dying message wasn't written by Nana, but by Samon-san!
First, consider the dying message.
It could never have been written by Nana-san.
From seeing her e-mails, she usually wrote Migita-san's name as ミギタ, in katakana.
So why would Nana-san write Migita-san's name as kanji in her final moments?
I see. It does seem unusual.
But that doesn't mean that I wrote it!
No, it most likely means exactly that.
Think back.
Remember the stroke order of the 'migi' written by Migita-san.
右
And the stroke order Samon-san, a teacher, used.
But I killed her...
I'll explain everything from the beginning.
The first step of Samon-san's plan was sending Migita-san harassing e-mails from Nana-san's smartphone.
Knowing of Migita-san's personality, and his misguided affection toward Nana-san,
Samon-san took advantage of Migita-san to tempt him to murder her.
What a surprise. What makes you say that?
The e-mails' writing style.
S-Style?!
E-mails sent by Nana-san herself never included punctuation like commas and full stops,
and always ended by her signing 'Nana'.
But the e-mails that enraged Migita-san contained punctuation, and lacked her signature of 'Nana'.
It's not easy to change the style you write in.
The same goes for stroke orders!
It was obvious that they were written by someone else.
And then, your plan succeeded.
Just as you expected, Migita-san's judgement clouded by hatred, he attacked Nana-san.
You headed to the park just to be sure, and when you saw Nana-san collapsed on the ground, you were certain.
Your plan had succeeded.
But then, something unexpected happened.
When Migita-san left the scene, she was still hovering on the verge of death.
And she came back to life.
Then she washed her face with water to clean away the dirt.
That's why her face was wet and her make-up was rubbing off.
Then the final blow was delivered.
By you yourself.
You then started writing 'Migita' in the dirt with the victim's finger.
But just then, you heard us approaching, and had to rush away from the scene.
That's the truth behind this case.
It might make a certain amount of sense.
But it's all circumstancial evidence.
You don't have any actual proof.
Oh, but I do have proof.
The gunshot residue found on the victim's clothes.
Gunshot residue?
Why was gunshot residue found at a crime scene where a gun was never used?
The answer lies in the photo on your smartphone.
What do you mean?
There were many party poppers being pulled to congratulate you in that photo.
As you may guess due to their gunshot-like sounds, party poppers leave gunshot residue, due to using gunpowder.
The residue stuck to your clothes, and then to Nana-san's clothes when you strangled her.
If we check, we should find the same gunshot residue on your clothes.
You yourself said, 'I haven't even met with her today'.
So can you explain?
Why do you both have the same gunshot residue if you never met her today?
How ironic...
I never imagined that children congratulating me would be evidence against me.
But why did you kill Nana-san?
You looked so happy in those photos.
His motive was her calling off the engagement.
How do you know that?!
Your ring.
You're wearing an engagement ring on your right hand.
But Nana-san wasn't wearing a ring.
That's when I realised that your feelings were unrequited.
I couldn't bear it. As long as she was alive, my sadness wouldn't go away.
I just couldn't bear it!
Ima aitakute...
(I want to be with you...)
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
Do we really take a right turn here?
右
Yeah, I think we take a right...
左
Hmph! If you're so sure, then let's turn left!
How cruel! We go right! Right! We have to go right!
No, we go left! Left! We have to go left!
Right!
Left!
Whichever way we go, let's just get home...
Welcome to my cooking arena!
What do you think?
Once again, I've gathered a brilliant selection from across the whole country.
So rest assured...
The key.
You stay back!
The path from here on leads to our territory!
And today's fruit is...!
(PART I)
A TREASURE CHEST FULL OF FRUITS
On the next Conan: 'A Treasure Chest Full of Fruits (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Padlock!
Next time, there's a case at a TV station?!
I hope I get to meet Yōko-chan!
Show some discretion...