The parfait, the parfait!
It has to be the Tropical Strawberry Parfait!
No, I think the Strawberry Gorgeous Chiffon Cake's got it today!
And now, may I present the winner of tonight's Strawberry Battle...
The maker of the Tropical Strawberry Parfait,
Pâtissier Shūhei Kurimura!
An admirable defence
by our returning champion!
Oh, no.
I really thought the champion
was gonna lose today.
But it's pretty amazing!
That means he's been the
champion for six weeks in a row!
See you again next week on
the "Which Sweets? Show"!
Hey, delinquent girl!
Isn't it about time you went home? It's almost eight, you know.
Hey, this is research!
Ran and I are going to be part of the audience for next week's episode!
Oh, yeah! I got tickets through my father's
connections, so would you want to come with me too?
Why would I want to go to some mushy indulgent food show?
Oh, that's too bad.
And to think Yoko Okino-chan's gonna be there as a guest judge.
I humbly accept your invitation, Lady Sonoko!
You're as simple as it gets, old man.
Then, will you escort us there in a rental car when the day comes?
As you wish.
But what do I do about the last slot? The invitation was for five people.
Mom said she'd be too busy with work.
Then, how about...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
An impossible crime filmed for a TV show.
The mystery is hidden in a chest of fruit!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Can I really come along?
Yeah. Conan-kun suggested it.
R-Really?
Y-Yeah.
If you're the one inviting, then I really can't refuse!
There's something I wanna ask her, anyway.
Anyway, try not to stick out too much in the audience and catch the eye of the judge, Takeki-san.
Takeki-san?
You don't know?
He's the number one authority
among Japanese pâtissiers!
The "Legend of Sweets", Shōtoku Takeki!
What happens when somebody catches his eye?
In the middle portion of the show, Takeki-san chooses a person from the audience and hands them sample food.
Sweets he made.
Then, if they correctly guess what fruit was used to make it, they get to eat the winning sweets from that day's battle.
But if they get it wrong,
then they have to leave the studio!
Is this Takeki guy really that strict?!
Yeah. The current champion has won six weeks in a row, but Takeki-san always grades him harshly.
Though he still gets more points than the challengers...
Speaking of which, I heard that the champion in question, Kurimura-san, opened yet another branch of his restaurant!
If only he'd open one in Beika as well.
But isn't that champion a little suspicious?
Like yesterday, he just happened to have brought ice cream and jelly with him, which went well with the mystery fruit, strawberries.
What are you talking about?
Are you saying the champion's cheating?
I doubt that's even possible.
Before the chest opens, not even the TV staff knows what the mystery fruit is.
By "chest", you mean that old metal chest they open at the start of the show, right?
Couldn't the TV staff
sneak a peek inside that thing?
It's set up so they can't do that!
Every week, they have their "fruit selection master" choose a fruit and pack the chest full of it.
Master's House
After filling it up, he puts a lock on it and sends it to the TV station.
TV Station
The show's director then receives the chest, puts another lock on it, and sends it back to the master.
The master then removes the original lock and re-sends it to the station,
TV Station
where, at the start of the show, the host opens the lock with the key provided to him by the producer.
And that's the first time anyone gets to know what the fruit is!
I see. Like codes from the old days.
Code?
In the old days, they didn't have
communication devices like we do now,
so they used that trick to send and receive secret messages!
Because with that method, nobody other than the two people with the keys can see inside it.
I see! So even if the people delivering the message wanted to take a look during transit, they couldn't!
Anyway, how do I avoid standing out?
You're right. Because most of the people in the audience will be women.
Maybe if you wear something girly?
Something girly, huh?
Well, the one standing out the most is definitely gonna be that old man's mustache.
Takeki-san!
If it's about the fruits for tomorrow's show, I already packed them in the chest.
Terafumi Kasuga (45)
Food Coordinator
Rest assured that as usual, I chose the best and highest quality ones in the entire country.
In that case, let me have a look.
Oh, no. Takeki-san, even you're
not allowed to see the contents!
Isn't that what we agreed on?!
Don't worry.
It's not the contents of the
chest I'm interested in seeing.
Shōtoku Takeki (69)
Food Critic
It's the lock!
Yes, this is tightly locked.
Of course it is!
I don't suppose anybody saw you filling this, huh?
Of course not.
As usual, I locked myself
in this warehouse to fill it.
And for camouflage, I went to restaurants and suppliers and asked them to send me their spare fruit boxes,
so even the delivery
people shouldn't know.
That means if somebody on the outside knows, it could only be from your mouth, right?
The chest with the forbidden
fruit's been delivered, huh?
Then hurry and lock that thing, then send it back, Furuya-chan.
Yes, sir.
As usual, the padlock's in my desk.
Toshihide Taruoka (48)
Nichiuri TV Producer
And don't even think about peeking inside!
Takeki-san scolded me about it before recording the previous show.
Wataru Furuya (31)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
Not like I could, anyway.
There's already another lock on it, you know.
That's true.
Are we still using that annoying method?
Takeki-san could just fill it and lock it himself!
He said he wants to be surprised by the ingredient during the recording too!
Well, he's certainly
getting up there in years.
We're actually looking for a successor.
How's this?
I look a little girlier, right?
Umm...
How exactly are you dressed
any differently from usual?
I'm wearing really cute
flower-patterned underwear!
It's a little embarrassing, though.
I-I see.
Nobody can see it, so what's the point?
Anyway, where's Yoko-chan?
She's not even here, is she?
The judges are in a separate room, waiting for the sweets to be brought in, aren't they?
Don't worry, you can
watch her on that monitor!
Then it's not any different
from watching her at home, is it?!
Excuse me.
Oh, my apologies. I'll try to behave.
Excuse me, but are you the Great Detective Kogoro Mouri-san?
Ah, yes.
There's something
we'd like to discuss with you.
Okay?
Okay, start recording! Action in five!
Four!
Three!
Welcome to my cooking arena!
This week, I bring you yet another sweet evening!
Before we present today's fruit, let me introduce two very special guests I invited to my arena!
First off, appearing for the
second time on this show...
Yoko Okino-san!
And for my second guest...
The Great Detective who stuns even crying babies into silence!
Ta-dah!
The great Kogoro Mouri!
This turned into a pretty big deal, somehow.
Even though he's Takeki-san's
stand-in, he doesn't seem nervous.
Good luck, Dad!
No, it's the chefs who need luck.
Detective Mouri, do you get the chance to eat sweets often?
Yes! I'm extremely fond of sweets!
The old man really knows how to sweet-talk.
Then, does your wife make them for you often?
My wife?
No way! Nobody would eat the kind of stuff she makes!
And Mom had been looking forward to watching this too...
This isn't live, so you
don't have to let her watch it.
Hey, is Takeki-san really missing?
Yeah. The staff said they
weren't able to contact him at all.
He hasn't even come to the TV station, never mind the studio.
Ah, look! They're
gonna open the chest!
Introducing the challenger,
Pâtissière Kurea Enokido...
And the champion,
Pâtissier Shūhei Kurimura...
It's time to reveal the fruits in all their glory!
As usual, our producer, Mr. Taruoka, will hand me the key, which had been sealed in a safe deposit box at Tohto Bank.
And now, let us open up
this chest of forbidden fruit!
A padlock like that looks like it could be
easily forced open by anyone who really tried.
It may not look like it, but it seems there's
actually a custom-made electronic chip inside.
If somebody tried to pick the lock, it'd detect that there's a foreign object in the keyhole and sound a buzzer.
Making a spare key's no easy feat either!
I'm sure Kid-sama would
make short work of it, though!
Hey, Sera-neechan...
There's something I
want to ask you later.
What is it?
Just tell me now.
Okay then...
Well then, let's have a look!
Tonight's fruit is...!
Sera-neechan, have you and I...
No way!
I-Isn't that Takeki-san, the sweets judge?
No way.
Wait a sec!
Conan-kun!
You stay here!
From this point onwards,
this is our territory.
O-Our territory?
Hey, kid!
It's no good. He's already cold.
Looks like it.
Cause of death is probably this wound on the back of the head.
Judging by the rigor mortis, I'd say it's already been more than half a day since his death.
On the edge of the box, there's a faint mark here, as though blood's been wiped off it.
And this mark...
It's on the inside and the outside,
so he must've hit his head there when the chest was open,
and then died and was crammed into the chest with the apples.
Has Takeki-san really passed away?
Yeah. So please call the police immediately.
And you should have all the people in the
studio audience go and wait in another room.
One of them might have
seen something, after all.
In that case, let's ask Detective Mouri to come from the guest judges' room.
That would be a good idea,
wouldn't it, Conan-kun?
You know this guy?
That's Kenzaki-san, the guy who plays Detective Samonji.
We met on a case!
Oh, you're that really funny detective!
Really funny...?
I see.
So you're saying that somebody put the body of Takeki-san, the head judge,
into the chest of fruit to be used in the show's cook-off.
We had been unable to
contact Takeki-san for a while.
But we never expected that he was inside the chest...
You mean you started recording even with your head judge missing?
That's because they decided to make me the stand-in judge for the day.
I just happened to be in the audience and they singled me out, Inspector.
Why you? You're not exactly
what I'd call a gourmet.
I put in a special request to the producer.
I had heard that we would have to start recording soon,
and I thought Mouri-san would probably be willing to help.
He had e-mailed me
to say that he was coming to the studio.
Kenzaki-kun also said that since he knew Mouri-san, it should work well.
Isn't that right,
Producer Taruoka?
Yes.
I thought having the Great Detective Mouri-san on as a special guest would make for a good show.
But, are the stories I've
heard about this chest true?
Something about
putting two locks on it.
Right.
First, the food coordinator, Kasuga-san, fills the chest with a mystery fruit, puts a padlock on it, and sends it to Nichiuri TV.
When I receive the chest, I then put a second padlock on it and send it back to Kasuga-san.
Kasuga-san then unlocks the first padlock and sends it back to the TV station,
before I finally give Kenzaki-san the key to open the last lock at the start of the show,
to reveal the mystery fruit of the day for the first time.
Anyway, it's all a scheme Takeki-san came up with to make doubly sure the mystery fruit doesn't get leaked.
If that's the case, then the only people who could have put the body in the chest would be
either the person who put on
the first lock, Kasuga-san,
or you, Taruoka-san, who had the key for the second lock.
Oh no, no...
I only give the key to the
presenter as part of the show.
The rest of the time, it's kept in a safe deposit box at
Tohto Bank and I don't have any access to it.
I keep the padlock in a draw in my desk, and
I have one of the assistant directors to put it on the chest.
And who is that assistant director?
It's that guy over there, Furuya-kun.
I always ask him to lock the chest, and he's responsible for looking after it as well.
So is he the one who transports it, as well?
I may have to look after it, but it's not as though I've got my eyes on the chest 24/7!
And it's the younger assistant directors that transport it. I just tag along.
I mean, sometimes I go and peep into the storage area where we keep the chest,
just to check and make sure that
it hasn't been broken into or anything.
I see.
But then, if you sniff the chest, you might be able to work out what fruit is inside.
There's no way I could do that.
The edges of the chest have been sealed with the same sealing you use in a fridge.
In which case, the only one left is the person who puts on the first lock, Kasuga-san.
Come to think of it, one of the other staff members said that Takeki-san was asking for Kasuga-san's address yesterday evening.
Then maybe he went to Kasuga-san's home.
Yes.
Takeki-san did indeed come round to my house yesterday evening.
It was just after I had filled the box with the fruit, but before the staff members came to collect it.
Kasuga-san!
What are you doing here?
Takeki-san told me to come.
He said that this time, he'd catch the person leaking the contents of the chest for sure.
And that he was going to reveal it all during the show, so I'd better come and watch.
So Takeki-san came to your place to...
Check the padlock that I had put on the chest,
as well as drive home to me that I say nothing about its contents.
Because I'm the only one who knows what fruit's in the chest,
it seems he suspected me of leaking it to outsiders.
And what did Takeki-san do next?
He went home when the staff arrived to collect the chest.
Right?
Yes.
The two younger assistant directors both saw him, so there's no doubt about it.
Wait a moment!
But then that means nobody had the time to put the body in the chest!
The thing that bothers me is Takeki-san's behavior.
Why did he have to go and check on the chest so thoroughly?
Yes. It's as though he was already certain that the contents of the box were being leaked.
Maybe he really thought that the fruit was being leaked?
To Kurimura-san, who's been the champion for the past six weeks straight.
That champion apparently always has just the right ingredients to go with the mystery fruit,
so maybe he thought the
champ knew what's in the chest!
I-Is that true?
Y-Yes.
Although at the start, even Takaki-san used to say that "luck was a skill of sorts".
All that aside, isn't it strange that Takeki-san didn't even come to the TV station today, much less the studio?
Huh? Really?
We know that he left after the run-through yesterday.
If that's the case, then when did they get a chance to put the body in the chest?
I-Inspector Megure!
Apparently, Takeki-san snuck back into the TV studio last night among a crowd of extras for a period drama.
What?!
The director of the period drama was an acquaintance of Takeki-san and he apparently asked to be let in.
Something about
catching the enemy off guard.
I see.
He tried to make it look like he wasn't in the studio anymore, so that the opponent would think the coast was clear and show himself.
Takeki-san always wore kimonos as well, so it was probably easy for him to mix in with the extras.
Looks like it.
In which case, he likely went to the storage room where the chest was kept, and ambushed his killer.
Huh? Why?
There were traces of wiped-off blood where the lid closes, on the inside and outside of the chest.
Doesn't that mean that the chest's storage room was the scene of the crime?
You're right.
I see.
Takeki-san was murdered there...
...by the person who sneakily opened the chest.
By the leaker, that is!
We've narrowed it down to three suspects,
but which one is the killer?!
Or rather, how they opened
the locks is the real mystery.
I see! So that's how it is!
Then we'd better
get it started soon.
Get what started?
What, you ask? Just a little...
...magic show of mine.
On the next Conan:
'The Treasure Chest Filled with Fruit (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Apples!
I give up.
On the apples?
You give up-ples!
Hehe.