Sonoko invited Ran, Sera, old man Kogorō and me
to come with her to watch the filming of a TV show.
However, when the filming began, and the locked chest containing the fruit
which would determine the outcome of the battle between the pâtissier and pâtissière was opened,
the programme's head judge, Shōtoku Takeki-san was discovered dead inside.
Shōtoku Takeki (69)
Food Critic
The thing that bothers me is Takeki-san's behaviour.
Why did he have to go and check on the chest so thoroughly?
Maybe he really thought that the fruit was being leaked?
To Kurimura-san, who's been the champion for the past six weeks straight.
That champion apparently always has just the right ingredients to go with the mystery fruit,
so maybe he thought the
champ knew what's in the chest!
I-Inspector Megure!
Apparently, Takeki-san snuck back into the TV studio last night amongst a crowd of extras for a period drama.
I see.
He tried to make it look like he wasn't in the studio anymore, changed it to 'anymore'} so that the opponent would think the coast was clear and show himself.
In which case, he likely went to the storage room where the chest was kept, and ambushed his killer.
There were traces of wiped-off blood where the lid closes, on the inside and outside of the chest.
Doesn't that mean that the chest's storage room was the scene of the crime?
Takeki-san was murdered there...
...by the person who sneakily opened the chest.
By the leaker, that is!
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
What is the trick to the chest,
and the key evidence that points out the killer?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
THE TREASURE CHEST FILLED WITH FRUIT
(PART II)
Ah! There he is, there he is!
Isn't this Takeki-san?
Look, he's looking all around before
he goes into the storage room.
The important thing
now is who comes next.
As I said earlier, it's probably me.
Nope. The one
who came next was...
Producer Taruoka?
Why were you going in there?!
W-Well, as the producer...
I was just going to check and see if the chest had arrived or not.
Toshihide Taruoka (48)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Takeki-san emphasised it to me too—if anything about the fruit in the chest was leaked, I'd be held responsible.
You spent quite some time in there...
It looks like you were in there for about 30 minutes.
I'd completely forgotten where they had the chest, so I was looking around for it.
The storage room's
pretty big and cluttered up.
And the next one who came was...
Furuya-san, an assistant director,
along with the two other assistant directors.
It seems you took your
time in there as well.
Well, er, actually, what happened was that I finished checking the chest quite quickly, so I was taking a smoke break...
Wataru Furuya (31)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
Most areas in the building are non-smoking, and when you're an assistant director, you're so busy there's rarely any time to smoke.
I smoked about three or four cigarettes while checking my e-mail.
Though well, the storage room's
a non-smoking area too...
You've come out at last.
You were in there for
about 30 minutes as well.
If nobody else goes in after you guys,
then we'll list you two as our prime suspects.
What?!
Actually, I went into
the storage room as well.
You too, Kasuga-san?
Terafumi Kasuga (45)
Food Coordinator
Yes. I was worried after what Takeki-san had said.
And although I was confident
about the lock I had set,
I hadn't checked whether the one at the TV station had been set properly or not.
Oh, you're right!
There's Kasuga-san...
I believe I was also in there for about 30 minutes, like the two who came before me.
After all, I was checking and
double-checking the locks.
I even took a number of photos
to show Takeki-san later.
And what did you find
during your checking?
Both locks seemed to be set,
so I went home straight after.
After Kasuga-san left,
it looks as though nobody went in until a few staff members went to collect the chest the next day.
In other words...
The producer, Taruoka-san,
the assistant director, Furuya-san,
and the food coordinator, Kasuga-san...
The person who murdered
Takeki-san is one of you three.
So...
We've narrowed it down to three suspects.
But who put the body in the chest?
Or rather, how they opened
the locks is the real mystery.
If I can't figure that part out...
But anyway, why did they have to
pack so many apples in the chest?
Even the champion and the challenger combined would probably only use about ten apples during the programme.
You don't even understand that?
It's because it looks more dramatic when the chest is filled to the top!
And they always hand out the leftover fruit to the members of the audience after the recording.
But apparently the chest has a
raised bottom, so it won't be too heavy.
They usually use really rare fruits too, the kind you can't just normally buy.
I heard that's the reason why a lot of people sign up to be in the show's audience.
And so?
Do you know who did it?
Not in the slightest.
We don't even know how they unlocked the chest.
That's nothing compared to that other mystery!
Other mystery?
What do you mean?
Hey, hey...
Haven't you noticed?
Gah! How could you have not realised something so important?!
All right, now listen up!
Yoko-chan's ponytail!
In her last live TV show,
it was quite short, and today it's long.
That speed of growth is just unnatural!
Oh, those are probably exts!
E-Ex—
Short for ‘hair extensions'. In other words, false hair.
False hair?
In Yoko-chan's case, she probably could cover up the attachments under her hair band pretty well.
I-Is that right?
That's it! I get it now!
Then the killer can only be...
You just thought the exact
same thing as me, didn't you?
A tooth that protrudes
outward when she smiles...
But the issue now is the evidence.
This girl...
I'm certain I've met her somewhere before.
What? What is it?
Is there something on my face?
Oh, no. It's nothing.
Now that we've finished photographing, let's take the chest back with us and give it a thorough inspection.
Right.
Hey!
Are those all the apples
that were in the chest?
Y-Yeah.
But I thought there were a lot of apples that fell out of the chest or rolled into the lid.
We put them all back inside. Those apples must've just fallen out due to the force when we opened the lid.
Hey, didn't you say the chest was always jam-packed with the mystery fruit used in the competition?
Right. So full that some would fall out every week.
After all, as the presenter, Kenzaki-san's catchphrase when opening the chest is...
‘Feast your eyes on this
overflowing mountain of fruit!'
In that case...
...that can serve as evidence!
Hey, wait!
That brat, he's acting almost like
he does with Hattori-kun.
What's bothering you, Ran?
Waves...
Somehow, when I watch Sera-san
from behind as she hurries away...
I always hear sounds ringing deep in my ears.
Sounds of rippling waves...
As if some sort of magic were at work.
Ran!
What's this? What's this?
Are you telling me you've fallen for her?
That's not what I mean!
You only get that feeling because that tomboy's came back from overseas.
How could that be?
Well, she's from overseas,
so you hear sounds from over the seas!
Dad jokes are the worst.
'Storage Room 3'
Why can't you let us in?!
What harm could it do?
Just for a short while!
We can't! This storage room is where the chest was kept, as well as the crime scene!
Then, did you discover
anything in that storage room?
Nothing relevant to our case at hand for now.
Well, how about anything that seemed odd?
That reminds me, as we were entering the storage room to investigate,
we saw a young assistant director getting scolded.
About how he didn't wash the kitchen props that are going to be used on the set of a drama.
Kitchen...
...props?
Although I don't see how it has anything to do with our case.
Hey...
Are those three suspects still here?
We're keeping them on standby in the room.
All three of them are
demanding us to release them soon.
If I remember correctly, Producer Taruoka-san said he has to attend a press conference about this incident.
Assistant Director Furuya-san asked us to let him go grab some lunch since he hasn't eaten anything this morning.
And Food Coordinator Kasuga-san wanted to go home and feed his pet dog, I think?
Then we'd better get it started soon.
Get what started?
What, you ask? Just a little...
...magic show of mine.
A magic show?
You called us and the suspects here just to have us watch something like that?
And that tomboy is the one doing it?
Now, now...
I bet you'll be surprised once you watch it.
Hey, I don't see Conan-kun anywhere.
Isn't he with Sera-san?
Waiting Room C
This is the room.
Welcome to Masumi Sera's
Magical Mansion!
Hey! Don't tell me...
Are you sitting on the chest
that the victim was in?
Yeah, sort of.
In addition, the padlock to this chest
and the key to it are right here!
Hey, hey...
We asked the props master
to prepare a similar chest!
The padlock is from the original, though...
And? What are you starting?
Well, for starters...
I'll have you confirm that
there's nothing inside the box.
Doesn't seem to be anything in it.
Y-Y-Yeah.
All right!
Then...
I'll close the lid like so...
and pass the padlock's steel bar through the holes of the locking mechanism on the edge of the lid.
And with a ‘click', the chest is locked.
See? Now there's no way I'd be able to open the chest without the key to the padlock, right?
Huh? Yeah.
So take this key with you and leave this room for a bit!
Huh? I have to leave?
You can come back in once
Detective Takagi finishes his speech!
T-Takagi's what?
W-Wait, where's Conan-kun?
Oh, right!
Allow me to explain.
Quite literally, the key to solving this case
is the locked chest in question.
Our Food Coordinator Kasuga-san secured the chest
full of fruits with a padlock and sent it to the TV station.
Master's House
. Master's House...
. TV Station...
Upon receipt, Producer Taruoka-san instructed Assistant Director Furuya-san to hook up another padlock
and send it back to Kasuga-san.
After that, Kasuga-san opened the padlock he put on himself and sent it back to the TV station.
There, the chest was kept in storage for safekeeping until it was time for filming to start.
But the question is, how did Takeki-san's body
end up inside that chest?
. TV Station...
Of course, the fact that Takeki-san wasn't inside the box when Kasuga-san initially put on the padlock
was attested to by Assistant Director Furuya-san, who came from the TV station to pick up the chest.
Not to mention that key is
of a special type without a spare,
and the lock can't be
pried open that easily!
Obviously there isn't a secret door inside the chest, so under these circumstances,
just how did the culprit manage to...
Enough with the narratives,
just spit out the answer!
Tell us, Detective Takagi!
Rather than me explaining,
wouldn't it be quicker to see for yourselves?
Because this is the conclusive answer.
C-Conan-kun!
W-Where were you?
I was hiding behind the chest!
And wait, where's Sera-san?
Where do you think she is?
Hey, don't tell me...
Inside the chest?!
That's ridiculous!
This thing is still locked up tight!
Then why don't you try to open it?
Ta-daa!
No way!
How?!
We used this!
A rubber tube?
And it's painted the same
shade of gold as the padlock.
We asked the props master we told you about before to make this for us!
But what did you do with that?
Okay, I'll use this and
let you see how it was done.
Lemme borrow that padlock.
S-Sure.
While we were securing the padlock,
we plug the end of the bar into the tube,
and shove it in the padlock's hole...
Forcefully making it fit, like this!
See! If you do that, doesn't it look
like it's been locked up tight?
It really does!
Y-You're right. With this, you can easily disengage the padlock by twisting it.
And even the joint of the tube is disguised,
since the bar goes through these protruding rings on the chest, so you wouldn't notice it.
In other words, I used that tube
to pretend to have locked it,
and later removed the padlock
and crawled into the chest.
Conan-kun, who had been hiding behind the chest,
removed the tube and locked the padlock for real this time!
Right, the key point of this trick is the padlock.
Because it's able to be
locked without a key.
Kasuga-san, who already knew
what was in the chest from the beginning,
had no need to deploy such a trick
just to open the chest's lid.
And Producer Taruoka-san, who instructed someone else to put on a padlock,
had no opportunity to use this trick.
Which leaves us with the person Taruoka-san asked to lock and send back the chest...
Assistant Director Wataru Furuya-san.
I believe that leaves only you.
I bet you've been opening the chest in the storage room in order to let the champion in on what the mystery fruit is,
in exchange for a share of the prize money.
Little did you know Takeki-san
was lying in wait last night.
He scolded you for that and the two of you scuffled.
And in the heat of the moment you killed him, then hid him inside the chest in a panic, am I right?
W-Where's the proof to all of that?
Right there!
In your belly, Mr. Assistant Director!
Mr. Assistant Director, after you put that man in the chest,
you ate the ten or so apples that couldn't fit in anymore, didn't you?
By putting them through the blender in the storage room that was used as a kitchen prop.
After all, you weren't carrying anything when you came out of the storage room in the security camera footage.
Even if that were the case, my stomach would've already digested them.
Don't you know?
Apple seeds contain a substance called amygdalin, which can be toxic.
And if you ingest too much of it,
it'd be really bad.
Mr. Assistant Director, I bet you didn't take the seeds out when you put the apples in the blender, right?
Well, you'll be fine!
The seeds from ten or so apples wouldn't be enough to cause cyanide poisoning.
But since you haven't eaten anything since this morning, you probably wouldn't have taken a dump yet.
So they're bound to come
out pretty soon, right?
The blender wouldn't have completely crushed those seeds, which are from a rare breed of apple.
Once those come out,
it'll be case closed.
Dare I say it looks like your
luck is getting really crappy?
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
Oh! It's on the online news!
Just like you said, Sera-san...
the seeds that came out of the assistant director are a match with the mystery fruit in the show!
Champion Kurimura-san also confessed, it seems.
He revealed that he knew what the fruit was before the show.
Still, you surprised me again, Conan-kun!
I didn't know there's a
poisonous chemical in apple seeds!
I-I heard that from Shin'ichi-niichan before,
and it just kind of popped out of my head!
Really, aren't you guys close buddies!
You and Shin'ichi-kun...
N-Never mind that.
I have something to ask you, Sera-neechan.
Ah, you said that before, didn't you?
Sera-neechan, have you and I...
...met somewhere before?
Beats me. What do you think?
My bad.
I can't tell you that yet.
Not until the time comes.
My late husband collected these things.
I see.
Dad, be careful!
I know! I know!
What's the meaning of this?!
What's all the racket about?
Why did you make them
reject my successful audition?
The mistress's room!
Mum!
A DIAMOND, A PICTURE, AND A FAMOUS ACTRESS
On the next Conan: ‘A Diamond, a Picture, and a Famous Actress!'
Next Conan's Hint: Sunlight.
Speaking of light, it's time for Kogorō
the star to make an appearance!
He seems rather energetic.
Because he's not making any deductions.