This is goodbye, I suppose.
Take care of yourself.
FIN
This movie always tugs at my heartstrings!
Thank you for watching.
Misuzu Shirakawa (58)
Actress
It's an old movie, but I hope you youngsters enjoyed it too.
Yes, very much.
It was really interesting.
Should we let them take a look around the second floor too, Mother?
Kyōsuke Shirakawa (23)
Misuzu's Son
We have displays full of objects used in her movies.
Oh, we'd love to.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
A fire breaks out at a movie star's mansion,
and a picture hides a surprising secret!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
All these movies take me back.
It's like a little Misuzu Shirakawa museum.
You're making me blush.
My late husband collected these things.
I see.
This room holds clothes and props from that time.
Amazing!
This is Mother's room.
We put valuable and sentimental objects inside this glass case.
Are these real?
Of course they are!
Misuzu-san wouldn't exhibit imitations.
Is that also genuine?
Chiharu Shirakawa (22)
Misuzu's Daughter
It is.
It would be a shame to always keep it locked inside the glass case.
The picture was used in the movie "A Day Off at the Deer Cry Pavilion".
And since the finished picture didn't have a necklace, we thought we might as well add one.
I see.
Dad, be careful!
I know! I know!
What's he doing?
Hey, Mum!
What's the meaning of this?!
What's all the racket about?
Saori Shirakawa (21)
Misuzu's Daughter
Why did you make them reject my successful audition?
Miss, please calm down!
One of the producers told me!
You called them up and told them to fail me!
Audition?
Saori auditioned for a movie.
Well, your singing's terrible, and your acting also leaves a lot to be desired.
Letting you perform in public would be embarrassing.
Mother!
Don't just decide that without me!
Be quiet!
I won't let you tarnish my name.
It's been a long time since you were an actress!
No one even remembers Misuzu Shirakawa anymore!
Saori!
Leave her be!
Let's have lunch.
Please escort our guests to the terrace, Yūka.
Very well.
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Coming!
Would you like some jam?
Yes, thank you.
Sorry about that just now.
To this day, Mother's very strict when it comes to acting.
That's all right.
Mum's living in a dream world.
In a world where she is still a great actress.
There's no need to put it like that, Kyōsuke-san.
I apologize for that scene earlier, Mouri-san.
Letting you witness such an unseemly thing.
Don't worry about it.
No matter how old they get,
I guess kids will always remain kids.
Geez, children just don't know the extent of their parents' love.
Yūka!
Yes?
Yūka Nakanishi (22)
Maid
This isn't the rose jam we usually have, is it?
I'm very sorry.
I was sure that there were still two jars left when I looked yesterday.
Go and buy some right away!
Mother, don't get so angry about something like jam.
On the set, people would never forget my favorite food.
That's a thing of the past!
My apologies. I'll go get some immediately.
Kyōsuke, it's a bit early, but I shall take my medicine now.
Get everything ready for me.
All right.
Please excuse me, Mouri-san.
I'll see you later.
I'm sorry, it's all a bit...
Don't worry.
That's right. Please excuse me for a moment while I go see how Yūka's doing.
Of course.
What's up with this family?
I'm sorry about the commotion.
Not at all.
Huh? Where's Chiharu?
She went to see how Yūka-san is doing.
I see.
Say, is Misuzu-san ill or something?
Oh, she's just taking a nap.
A nap?
Yes.
She takes a nap between 2 and 4 PM every day.
She even takes sleeping pills, saying that it's good for her health and beauty.
Yūka! Are you all right?
What happened?
It's all my fault. I didn't look where I was going.
I'm sorry. I lurched to the side.
This is quite the mess.
I saw it happen.
Chiharu-neesan staggered in front of the car and Yūka drove the car into the pond to avoid her.
So it's not her fault.
You lot!
What on earth is this commotion?!
What's with that car?!
Please forgive me! I wasn't paying attention.
No, that's not it. I'm the one who...
That's enough!
Yūka, pack your bags and leave within the day!
I can't believe this!
Normally you'd ask whether anyone was hurt!
The car is insured and can be repaired.
Give it a break!
Why do you always have to be so selfish?!
Can't you ever think about someone else for a change?!
Is this how you should be talking to your mother?
I'm tired. I'm going back to bed.
It's all right, Yūka.
We'll talk to Mother later.
All right, if you would, Mouri-san.
Right.
Thank you very much, Mouri-san.
It was nothing.
All Dad did was step on the accelerator.
Can't you smell something burning?
The mistress's room!
Mum!
Mother!
Misuzu-san!
Kyōsuke-kun, take that side!
Okay!
This is...
At around 2 PM today, the actress Misuzu Shirakawa-san passed away after a fire broke out in her home.
So when you entered the room, Shirakawa-san had already passed away?
Detective Tamagawa (35)
Yes.
She took sleeping pills before going to bed
and probably slept without noticing the fire, breathing in a large amount of smoke in the process.
I see.
But the fire sure broke out in an unusual place.
Indeed.
Did your mother smoke?
No. Not just her either, no one in this house smokes.
This is...
Could it be?
Which means this is a murder case.
And the killer...
...was that person!
Well then, since the day's almost over, and we can't be sure whether or not this was an accident,
all we can do is head back to the station and wait for the forensic results.
Please wait, Detective Tamagawa.
Is there a problem?
Ah, no, no.
Dad!
M-Mouri-san?
Could this be Sleeping Kogorō?
What?
Everybody! This fire was deliberately designed to kill Misuzu Shirakawa-san.
Are you saying this was a murder?
That is correct.
And what's more, the killer is here in our midst.
But Dad, at that time everyone was by the pond.
Yes. The fire was likely caused by a concentration of sunlight.
A concentration of sunlight?
It's a fire that occurs when something like water in a plastic bottle acts as a convex lens to concentrate and intensify sunlight.
You mean that bundled sunlight was projected onto that picture, causing it to ignite, Mouri-san?
But this room faces north, so the sun doesn't shine in.
Please look out of the window.
That glass-sided building that looks like it was cut diagonally with a blade...
Does it remind you of anything, Kyōsuke-san?
That's right.
When we came to this room...
But even if that building reflected the sunlight it would merely hit the wall opposite the window.
The mirror.
No, even if it was reflected by this mirror,
I don't think the light would land on the portrait.
It certainly seems impossible.
Then let's try it out.
Like this?
A bit higher.
Okay.
Then please turn it on.
Just as we thought.
The light lands on the wall opposite the picture.
Now then, Yūka-san.
Please return the mirror that is lying on the floor to its original place.
All right.
It probably fell in the commotion over putting out the fire.
Can you see the little mark engraved on the pedestal?
Ah, yes.
A similar one can also be found on the glass case,
so please place the mirror so the markings match up.
Yes.
Please adjust the angle of the mirror as well.
All right.
The light falls onto the picture!
Please do the same with the other two mirrors as well.
In other words, this is what happened:
The sunlight reflected off the glass-sided building,
passed through the window, reflected off the full-length mirror on that wall,
and then reflected once more off the three mirrors on the glass case,
before converging to one point on the picture.
It is likely that the killer meticulously planned the placement of the mirrors in advance.
But please remember.
Just before noon, I unintentionally toppled the mirrors when we were shown around here.
Which means, chances are that the position of the mirrors changed.
Despite this, the fire broke out according to the killer's expectations.
Which means...
The killer returned the mirrors to their original positions!
Correct. And there is only one person who could have done so.
The person who remained in this room while the rest of us went ahead to the terrace:
Chiharu Shirakawa-san!
No one but you!
That's...
It couldn't be...
Is that true, Chiharu?
You killed our mother?
No! Wait a moment.
Mum only opened the window for two to three minutes.
Could a fire even start in such a short time?!
It can.
Chiharu-san.
After you positioned the mirrors, you doused the painting with an inflammable chemical,
likely the sort of diluent that is used when creating oil paintings, didn't you?
Diluent?
Yes.
Volatile solutions like turpentine and petrol have a flash point of under 50° Celsius.
You were also the one who hid the rose jam.
As expected, Misuzu-san sent Yūka-san off to buy new jam, giving you the opportunity to walk in front of her car.
You lot!
What on earth is this commotion?!
What's with that car?!
Can't you ever think about someone else for a change?!
Is this how you should be talking to your mother?
Is that what happened, Chiharu?
Is this true, Sis?
Are you the one who...
Where's your evidence?
If you're going to accuse me like this, you better have some proof of what you're saying.
Evidence, you say?
Yes. All this is nothing but speculation.
Does the fact that I was the last to leave this room prove that I repositioned the mirrors?
How ridiculous.
Yūka-san?
Y-Yes?
This room is decorated with an arrangement of lilies, is it not?
Yes, the mistress liked them.
How about the other rooms?
No. This is the only room with lilies in it.
Mouri-san, what are you talking about?!
I am talking about evidence, of course.
To put it simply, I'm talking about the lily pollen on the outside of your right sleeve.
W-What sort of evidence is that supposed to be?
Why would the pollen of a flower that can only be found in this room be on your right sleeve?
Because I touched the lilies with my arm at some point, I suppose.
So?
When did that happen?
Like I'd remember something like that.
Please recall.
The lilies are in a vase on top of the glass case.
Since the pollen is on the outside of your right sleeve,
that means that you faced the flowers and moved your right arm along the left side of the flowers in order to do something.
Well then, what was there?
That's right.
One of the mirrors we used in the experiment earlier, which served to bundle the light by reflecting it, was there!
Chiharu...
Chiharu-neesan...
Why?! Why did you kill her?!
"Chiharu-san".
That woman always called me "Chiharu-san".
Even though she called you guys just "Kyōsuke" and "Saori".
Because of something like that?
Mouri-san.
My father brought me into this family.
When my father decided to get married again with her, I was very happy.
After all, she was a great actress who I admired.
So I tried very hard to please her.
I didn't make any selfish requests.
I helped out around the house as well.
But all I got in return from that woman was "Well done, Chiharu-san",
"Thank you, Chiharu-san", "That won't do, Chiharu-san"...
"Chiharu-san", "Chiharu-san", "Chiharu-san"...
And then last week...
Oh, she doesn't matter.
Yes, it's all right.
She's just a step-child after all.
Yes, that's right. The only children through which the blood of Misuzu Shirakawa flows are Kyōsuke and Saori.
She won't get a single yen of my fortune!
Chiharu-san.
This is merely my personal opinion, but I think you tried too hard.
A familial relationship isn't born from hard work.
Maybe you should have been selfish from time to time.
You started the whole affair off on the wrong foot, I'd say.
What's this, Dad?!
You went to the racetrack again, didn't you?
D-Don't be stupid! Of course I didn't!
Geez. And you went and ate curry, too!
What are we going to do about dinner now?
How did you know?
It's right there on your shirt.
A curry stain.
I'll admit that I had some curry, but that doesn't mean I went to the racetrack.
Uncle.
Your ear.
Oh, my. How did this get behind my ear?
How strange. Mysterious things do happen, I suppose.
Know when to give up!
Your allowance will be cut by 50%!
Have mercy! That's...
You're a detective! You should be paying attention to the details!
One knife thrust to the chest.
Wasn't it Hiroto-san?
You two are the killers, aren't you?
On the next Conan: The Figurine That Was Too Good!
Next Conan's Hint: Paint!
Are you going to the racetrack again?
It's the Year of the Horse after all.
Anything to horse around.