Just look at them!
Look at these incredible figures!
And all these beautiful dioramas!
This is amazing!
I know, isn't it?
It was made by Masahiro Kitajima-san!
He's the modeller who's been getting the most attention recently.
I don't really get these little, tiny things.
Oh, how sad.
How can you not understand this incredible art?
Conan-kun, what do you think of it?
I don't know about the train tracks...
But the diorama as a whole is certainly incredible.
He's reproduced all the beauty and detail, down to each branch.
That's Conan-kun for you!
Kitajima-san is said to be a genius when it comes to accurately modelling nature.
What's more, he's even been entered into this year's world championship!
It's Kitajima-san!
Aren't you Masahiro Kitajima-san?!
How did you create such an amazing figure?!
Masahiro Kitajima (27)
Professional Modeller
Well... Imagination, I guess.
As long as you have plenty of imagination, you can make great figures.
I see. Imagination, huh?
Masahiro-san!
Reika Kameyama (26)
Kitajima's Girlfriend
Oh, Reika. I didn't know you came.
Of course I did! This is your big moment!
Stop. People are watching.
Hey, you guys.
Check out my figures, too.
Wow, how pretty!
The colours are really pretty!
Yeah, I guess so.
Shun'ichi Morishita (25)
Professional Modeller
I'm sure you all know...
But these are from the most popular robot anime right now.
Huh?
I stayed up all night making them! Aren't they great?
A grown man playing with kid's toys...
You guessed it.
A 'figure and model festival' was being held at this convention hall today,
and we've all come to see the festival.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
A case breaks out at an event hall!
These figures are coated with thick layers of secrets!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Let's go home, already. I'm starving!
Wait a little longer.
What's a good color for the Kamen Yaiba figure I'm making now...?
Someone come quick!
Conan-kun!
H-Hey, Conan...
So he was stabbed in the chest with a sharp object?
Wait, it's that man!
Kitajima-san?!
Hold it!
Outta the way!
Haibara, Ayumi... Are you okay?!
Yep! I'm fine.
Ai-chan protected me.
Honestly, get it together.
Sorry, sorry.
So you heard the screams of one of the office staff, came running, and found Kitajima-san lying here.
Does that sum it up right?
Yeah. We found him.
The murder victim is Masahiro Kitajima-san.
That's right. He's one of the top modellers, who was representing Japan.
Top... modeller?
A professional plastic model maker.
Oh, I get it. I get it.
You all go home for today.
We can't!
We even caught the culprit!
You mean Ai-chan did, right?
Inspector Megure!
I've brought Hiroto-san with me.
That's the guy!
Make no mistake, that guy's the murderer!
Kenji Hiroto (32)
Reporter for a model-making magazine
His name is Kenji Hiroto-san.
It seems he works as an editor for a plastic modelling magazine.
Is that information correct?
Yes! That's what I've been saying this whole time!
I only came to get an interview with Kitajima!
Then why did you try to run away?
I-I was scared, and did it without thinking...
A-At any rate, it was because Kitajima ended up like that.
Excuse me. Are you sure it wasn't this man?
Yes. He wasn't found to be in possession of any weapons.
Leaving that aside, Dr Agasa.
This really isn't a place for children...
I understand.
Come on, everyone. Let's go home.
Go on, go on...
But it's only getting started!
What? How boring.
I'm sorry, you guys.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
How much time had passed between when Kitajima-san died and when we found him?
Oh... A few minutes, I suppose.
And you're sure the weapon was a sharp-edged object?
That's right.
It appears to have been some sort of knife.
And you haven't found it yet?
Right. Though we're still looking for it.
The office worker who came to make tea didn't have it, either?
No, she didn't have anything like that.
So they haven't found the weapon...
The culprit's gotta be that guy!
I don't think so.
There were only a few minutes between Kitajima-san being killed and being discovered.
Meaning that if he was the murderer, it's very likely he would still be carrying the weapon
or possibly have hidden it in his immediate vicinity.
But it's nowhere to be found...
I see.
Where could the weapon have gone...?
Excuse me, Mr Detective.
What should I do?
Oh, my apologies.
The inspector has something he wants to discuss with you, so please wait a little longer.
Oh? You're that robot dude!
Oh, so you guys were here, too?
What happened, mister?
Well you see... I've been in the waiting room over there this whole time.
But then I heard a big commotion going on outside.
When I went out to check, one of the people in charge was there, and I heard that something terrible happened to Kitajima-san.
And were you with that official this whole time?
Yes. This man was always with that official.
Were there any sharp objects near Morishita-san?
No. Not on his person, nor in the waiting room.
So it wasn't this guy, either?
Oh, if it isn't Morishita!
Hiroto-san.
Aren't you the one who did Kitajima-san in, Hiroto-san?
W-What?!
You do some awful interviews, you bastard!
Picking up the figures without asking, and touching things when they tell you not to touch them!
Kitajima-san's modelling friends have been talking around,
telling each other never to accept an interview with the likes of you!
You're one to talk, Morishita.
You're suspicious, too.
You've been borrowing a lot of money from Kitajima, haven't you?
You've been unable to pay it back for years,
and were crying up a storm about it.
Shut it! Shut up!
Masahiro-san! Is it true?!
Was Masahiro-san really murdered?!
Hey, wait! You can't go in there!
Masahiro-san! Masahiro-san!
Masahiro-san!
Why did this happen...?
So 'little miss favourite' actually showed up...?
Oh? It's you, Hiroto-san?
I was wondering who that was.
And you too, Morishita-san?
I bet you two are the killers!
Give me a break.
I hear it's been hard on you too, what with all the talk about breaking up lately.
Talk of breaking up? Far from it.
I was even engaged to Masahiro-san!
Oh, really?!
Morishita, you heard about it too, right?
W-Well, yeah.
You two!
Doctor, the kids.
Oh yes, my apologies.
Come on, let go.
Come on, come on. Get a move on! We're heading home.
Aw, things were just getting good.
Just when I thought we could track down the killer.
Wait, where's Conan-kun?!
Reika Kameyama-san.
Where were you when the murder took place?
I was outside.
After I saw Masahiro-san in the hall, I got an e-mail from him.
He told me to wait for him at the plaza near the river that's next to the hall.
But Masahiro-san wasn't coming, no matter how long I stood there,
So I came back to the waiting room, to find this...
It's true. An e-mail was sent to Reika-san from Kitajima-san's phone.
11:25.
Ten minutes before the incident occurred.
Which means that Kitajima-san was murdered after he sent this e-mail.
Hey, Conan.
The policemen are...?
Yeah. They're making a big fuss about something over there.
So? Do you think you can reach it?
No good.
What's the matter, officers?
There's something in the gap between the wall and the vending machine,
but we can't reach it.
I'm little, so I think I can reach it. Let me handle this.
So that's it...?
Genta, your handkerchief!
Huh? O-Oh, right.
All right, here I go...
Got it! Pull me out, Genta!
Okay, gotcha.
This is...
A bloodstain?
Kameyama-san.
Do you recognise this brooch?
Uh, yes. That's mine.
Traces of blood were found on it...
...and according to Forensics, it's unmistakably Kitajima-san's blood.
No, that can't be. Ever since yesterday...
Yeah, I couldn't find that brooch since yesterday.
When yesterday?
Last night. When I brought a bouquet of flowers to congratulate him.
Ever since then...
Excuse me...
I just remembered something...
I... saw what really happened.
No! I'll never break up with you!
I'm going out into the world as a modeller from now on.
You'd just get in my way!
You've got to be kidding me!
Were you planning on doing this all along?!
You're terrible.
I'll never forgive you. I'm gonna kill you!
What do you have to say about that, Kameyama-san?
Y-Yes, I did say that...
But I didn't do it!
I knew you were the murderer.
Let me guess, is this what happened?
You got his e-mail, and got scared that he would say he's breaking up with you, so you went to the waiting room.
But you ended up getting into a heated argument, and...
After that, you dashed out of the hall, and tossed the weapon in the river while pretending to wait for Kitajima!
I see.
Kameyama-san.
It seems we'll need to have you give us a few more details.
No way! I didn't do it!
Hey!
So that lady did it?
But it's kind of frustrating, isn't it?
I know.
We were treated like kids to the very end.
Darn it! I'm going to take my anger out on my dinner!
The brooch... Blood splashed from the victim...
There's still something strange about this...
Yo. What's up, you guys?
That was some nice footwork back there, little lady.
Oh, thank you.
What're you here for? You come to get even with us or something?
Cut that out.
I don't even feel like arguing with you about it.
I may not look it, but I'm feeling rather down.
'Cause he escaped the scandal.
A scandal?
Do you mean one with Kitajima-san?
What do you mean by a scandal, mister?
Oops. That doesn't concern you kids.
See you.
I get it, I get it.
Can you spare me a moment?
What is it?
Kitajima-san was a hero to these children.
If he had some secret he had been hiding, can't you tell us about it?
Dreams are best left as dreams, you know.
No. For the sake of these children, I think they deserve to know the truth.
Okay, fine.
That guy's dead, anyway.
The truth is...
There were rumours flying around that Kitajima had a guy working as his 'ghost modeller', making his models for him.
What...?
A ghost modeller?!
Yeah.
Even amongst fellow modellers, that guy's models of natural elements were the cream of the crop.
But you know, he never had much skill as a modeller at first.
And now he comes out of the blue like this, only a few years later.
What's more, he's never let anyone watch him making a figure before.
Oh, so that's it.
That's why you sneaked into the waiting room, to check for sure?
Yeah.
That's right...
That's been bothering me from the start.
Ever since we came to this hall!
Conan-kun, what's the matter?
It must be this one...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
Does this colour match any colour on Kitajima-san's diorama?
Oh, that's for Kamen Yaiba.
I'm using that same colour on the Kamen Yaiba I'm making.
So when it's dried...
Yes, there's no doubt about it. It's the same colour.
So that's it. That's what happened.
Wait, huh? You guys were still here?
Hurry home and... huh?
Like we said before, Dr Agasa...
What's the meaning of this?
Gathering everyone here all of a sudden.
Please excuse me for dropping this on you so suddenly.
But there are a number of things that bother me about this case.
First is Reika-san's brooch that was lying in the hallway.
Kitajima-san's blood was on that brooch.
However, take a good look at her clothes.
There's no blood on them anywhere.
Can the blood splattered when stabbing someone really pinpoint the brooch and only land on that?
So you mean someone put his blood on the brooch intentionally, to frame her?
But that's unthinkable.
There's one more thing I found strange.
It's about you, Morishita-san.
What? A-About me?
Yes. When we first met you...
But these are from the most popular robot anime right now.
You said you stayed up all night making them, and your shirt had paint stains on it.
Yes, that shirt.
However...
Take a look at those robots.
Morishita-san made them, and they're coloured very brightly...
...in completely different colours than the ones on his shirt.
Now why would that be?
The colours on Morishita-san's shirt match paints found in his paint case.
This one!
Now, this colour just happens to be the same as one used in Kitajima-san's diorama.
There were rumours that Kitajima-san had a ghost modeller making his dioramas for him.
That was you, wasn't it, Morishita-san?
You were the one substituting for him, correct?
That's right! He was forcing me to make them!
My mother was sick, so I borrowed money from Kitajima...
But with his outrageous interest rate, my debt skyrocketed to the point I could never pay it back!
And then that bastard...
In that case, Morishita...
You're gonna make my models too, got it?
And to make matters worse, Kitajima-san was planning to enter a world championship with your figure.
I bet you really despised him for that.
And that's why you murdered Kitajima-san.
You're wrong! This incident has nothing to do with that!
But if it was true...
It would be consistent with your earlier statement.
Last night, you happened to witness the argument between Kitajima-san and Reika-san.
Then you picked up the brooch Reika-san dropped as she stormed out.
And then today, you stabbed Kitajima-san, smeared his blood on the brooch,
and tossed it in the narrow gap near the vending machine in the hallway in order to frame Reika-san.
And of course... He hadn't forgotten about calling Reika-san out with an e-mail...
So she would lose her alibi.
Can you cut the crap?
You're not going to believe this nonsense, are you?!
I didn't do it!
Right, the weapon! Where's the weapon?
I didn't have any sort of weapon anywhere!
Kitajima-san was said to be a genius with regard to his nature models.
But in reality, those were made by you, acting as his ghost modeller.
We found this colour inside your paint case.
Natural light green.
I know, because I used it on my Kamen Yaiba!
There's one natural object in this room that has the same colour.
Now what could it be, you guys?
That!
I'll never forgive you. I'm gonna kill you!
It's like Kitajima-san had been saying.
When making a figure, the most important thing is having plenty of imagination.
Isn't that why you used your imagination too, Morishita-san?
Look at these flowers Reika-san brought.
I see.
He had painted the weapon in advance, then committed the crime...
It's all Kitajima's fault!
It's because that bastard told me to make those things for him!
I'm...
I'm not the one in the wrong here!
They really praised us back there, didn't they?
And even gave us these plastic models, too!
That was nice.
But...
I know!
Conan-kun, you can have this!
Huh?
Mine too! Because I'm making Yaiba right now.
I'd get super hungry if I made it!
Yay!
Grub! Let's go grab some grub!
Hey, come back here! Make these yourselves!
It doesn't matter whether you make four or five, right?
Food, food.
Y-You guys!
Then I'll top it off with the sixth one, too...
Gah! Gimme a break!
Here.
Until I collect all seven, please don't open this.
What? Somebody died?!
On the next Conan: 'The Ex-Boyfriend Living Next to a Crime Scene (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Suicide note!
And what do four wills make...?
isho ga yottsu
OK!
yoisho!
What a great quiz, Doctor.
OK!
yoisho!
I'm slipping...