Sorry for the delay.
Geez, you're late!
Here.
What's this?
H-Hold on!
Please don't open it until I collect all seven.
But what is it?
I'll contact you once I have them all.
I promise.
Yumi-san?
Yumi-san!
Assistant Inspector Yumi Miyamoto!
Sheesh. Don't doze off while we're on patrol!
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
Assistant Inspector Yumi Miyamoto's secret?!
A new character with sharp deductions!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yumi-san, did something happen last night?
Sorry. I pulled an all-nighter playing mahjong with the guys in the Organised Crime Division.
You shouldn't stay up all night playing mahjong!
It's bad for your work, and your skin.
Yeah, yeah.
Anyway, what was that about 'collecting all seven' ?
Did I say that?
Yeah, in your sleep. Something like 'when are you gonna be able to get all seven?'
It's something my ex-boyfriend said.
When I told him we should break up because I was becoming a police officer,
he gave me a weird-looking envelope and told me not to open it until he'd 'collected all seven'.
But he never called me again since, so I dumped him.
Told him I wouldn't wait any longer and didn't want to see or hear him ever again!
And where'd you first meet?
While I was still studying at university, in a train.
He lived in a posh area, so maybe he's some spoiled rich kid? Who knows?
But what's that 'seven' thing about? Seven what?
No idea. Probably something useless.
Maybe he was a sailor?
The north and south Atlantic Oceans, the north and south Pacific Oceans, the Indian Ocean, the Arctic Ocean, and the Antarctic Ocean.
He's telling you to wait until he's conquered all seven seas!
C-Conan-kun?
Did he have a sunburn?
No. Pale white and looked like a moocher who never leaves his home.
He kept going somewhere a lot, but it wasn't on a fixed schedule, and it didn't look like a job either.
Then maybe he meant the Seven Lucky Gods round-up tour?
The thing you do during New Year holidays where you tour around shrines and temples to collect dolls of the Seven Lucky Gods?
Oh, Mum does that every year!
But that wouldn't take a lot of time, right?
Another possibility is...
The Seven Deadly Sins.
Pride, envy, wrath, sloth, greed, gluttony, and lust.
Who'd want to collect those?
But the Seven Lucky Gods thing makes sense.
He did say that on Christmas, after all.
Hold on!
Why am I talking about this with you guys?!
Geez.
And what'd you do with the envelope?
Hell if I know where I put it.
Weren't you the one who bumped into me, punk?
What're ya tryin' to say?!
You got a problem?!
Can you back up a bit and park at the side of the road?
Okay.
Hey, what are you guys doing?!
Yumi-san had a boyfriend?
Though it doesn't feel like it's the first time...
...that I met you.
Would you happen to be...
Yes?
The one who gave me a parking ticket in Haido City a while back?
Chiba-kun completely forgot me...
No, you can't cross!
If you try to cut some slack by breaking the rules even once, it'll become a habit!
You might think you can break a bad habit, but you can't!
Why can't you get that?!
It's from Sakurako!
What is it? I'm on duty right now.
What? Somebody died?!
But I'm not a detective!
Hey, is that somewhere nearby?
Y-Yeah.
Hey, wait!
Anyway, don't touch anything!
I'll be there right away!
What's with the kids? They got all serious.
A friend of mine just called me, saying somebody'd died.
Where?!
Just nearby, at Chateau Beika House.
C-Chateau Beika House?
I knew it...
Umm, have you been here before?
No way!
Only rich people would live in a place like this!
Oh, Miyamoto-sama! Long time no see!
Hey.
So you have been here before!
Shut it.
So what floor was it?
The 18th floor.
No. There's no way...
'Itami'
Whew, it was just the neighbour living next door.
So the mini-patrol ladies came here too?
But aren't you two from the traffic division?
Isn't this kind of case a little out of your scope?
Just leave it to us.
You guys aren't in charge, either!
I only came here to bring you guys back home!
Huh?
Conan-kun's gone.
He's inside.
He told us to wait here.
No way! He went inside?!
Who the hell is this kid?!
Do you know this kid or something, Ms. Housemaid?
Oh, yes. I think his name's...
Conan Edogawa.
We met in a previous murder case, didn't we?
Sakurako Yonehara-san?
Y-Yeah, in that optical illusion case.
Hey, kid.
Wasn't your speech pattern different before?
When you were with everybody else, you spoke like a normal kid,
but now you're acting almost like a detective.
Ah, no, that's...
Sakurako Yonehara (23)
Housemaid
I started working as a commuting housekeeper for this family last week, but then this happened again.
S-Sakurako.
Nae-chan!
Sorry! I panicked and called you without really thinking.
Don't worry. We just called the detectives.
Well, it doesn't look like a murder to me, but just in case, would you mind telling us the sequence of events?
O-Okay.
Well, I had a fight with my wife Chiyoko about an hour ago.
To let her cool off, I decided to leave her alone and went out with the housemaid.
Isn't that right?
Naganobu Itami (52)
Flat Resident
Yes. Since we hadn't purchased
the ingredients for dinner yet,
the master and I went
to a nearby supermarket.
My wife broke her wrist recently and couldn't do housework, so we had to hire a housemaid.
But she threw another tantrum, and I didn't want to get hurt any worse.
Just have a look at my eye.
What caused that bruise?
When my wife's in a fit of rage, she tends to throw things.
Because of that, I had to take a day off from work.
And when you came back, you found your wife had hung herself ?
No.
We finished shopping in about half an hour, and when the master and I came home and opened the front door,
I heard a 'slam!' from this bedroom door closing.
I think she was still alive at the time.
Just in case, I knocked and called for her,
but since she didn't answer, I figured she was still angry.
That's why I asked the housemaid to make me some coffee, and we chatted for about half an hour after that.
Then we knocked on the bedroom door again, and when we went in, we found her like this...
I never imagined my wife would've been that troubled about our argument.
I see.
What about the memo under her feet?
It's her suicide note.
It's her handwriting, and it details my injury, my son's exam,
and even the fact that my niece is celebrating her Shichi-go-san this year.
She put so much thought into writing it.
A-And she asked for forgiveness for departing this world!
Then it's definitely a suicide.
No.
It could be a murder.
The suicide note was supposed to have been written and ripped out from this notebook on the desk, right?
But if you look closely,
you can see there are two holes from the remainder of the torn page in the spiral binding,
but there are three holes missing on the suicide note. Isn't it strange?
Really?
You're right.
What's more, the writing on the note looks pretty shaky.
Look!
She apparently wrote a lot of notes using that notebook, but she always signed with just her given name.
But that suicide note alone has her full name.
It looks inconsistent to me.
You have a point.
Was the entryway door locked?
I'm the one who opened it, but it was definitely locked!
And who has spare keys?
Just my wife, the housemaid, my son Yasuie, and myself.
Where's your son right now?
At the driving school, I think.
He said the test was coming up soon.
And just in case, I think there's another spare key in the letterbox on the first floor.
That letterbox is locked, right?
Yes.
It has a combination dial, so I don't think anyone could've easily opened it.
Seven to the left, two to the right, and three to the left...
There's somebody else!
There's somebody else who knows the combination!
Yesterday, when I went to get the post from the letterbox,
I'd forgotten to bring the memo with the combination on it, and when I was in trouble, the person in question told it to me!
How do you know the combination?!
That other time when you were trying to open that letterbox, you dropped the piece of paper with the combination on it, right?
I was the one who picked it up and gave it to you, remember?
But you gave it to me right away!
It didn't even take you a second!
That's enough time for me.
I'm very good at memorising things.
I'm the best in Japan... Maybe even in the world!
And does this person live in this block of flats?
Yeah. He's the next-door neighbour.
He always has unshaved stubble and looks a bit scruffy. I think his name's...
It'll be faster if we just go next door directly!
Wai—
W-Wait!
Yes? What is it?
Yumi-tan!
Y-Yumi-TAN?
Do you know him?
Y-Yeah.
He's my ex.
So, to recap...
To let your wife calm down after a heated argument,
you went shopping at a supermarket with the housemaid for about half an hour.
When you returned and opened the front door,
you heard the sound of the bedroom door closing.
You knocked on the door, and there was no response.
You had no choice but to spend another half hour chatting with the housemaid in the kitchen.
Then you knocked on the door again, and this time you went in,
and you found your wife Chiyoko-san had hung herself with an electric cord, right?
Yes.
By the way, what was your argument about?
It was about stocks.
Stocks, huh?
She recently became addicted to buying stocks.
When I reprimanded her about it, she went hysterical.
I see.
Well, she's probably stressed over the fact that our son, who's graduating from university, is still unemployed.
So you have a son?
Yes.
But he's barely visited since he moved out to live alone at a flat near his university.
But he called recently, right?
Saying he wants a car once he gets his driver's licence.
And that he was going to come by and bring a catalogue of cars.
A catalogue?
But his mother yelled at him.
She said a car was out of the question when he couldn't even decide on a job, and hung up on him.
Oh?
If I recall, you were there during that optical illusion case.
Yes.
I never imagined my new job would come down to this again.
Be careful you don't end up like Mouri-kun, who brings death everywhere he goes.
I-Inspector...
Regardless, why were you, from the traffic division, the one who reported it in, Mi'ike-kun?
Oh, that's because...
Sakurako-san discovered the body first, and she decided to call her friend first: Officer Naeko Mi'ike!
Well, I happened to overhear them, so I came too.
C-Conan-kun?!
No wonder those kids were out in the hallway...
But how did you get inside this block of flats, Conan-kun?
There happened to be an adult with a child coming into the building, so we followed them in and pretended we're his friends!
You shouldn't do that!
Oh, geez.
Then, was the housemaid a classmate of yours, Naeko?
No, she's a childhood friend of mine who lived nearby back then.
And for the record, I'm a year older than her.
Anyway...
Does that mean that you, your wife and the housemaid were the only ones here?
Yes. I haven't seen my son for over a year, after all.
Then who's the guy behind Yumi-kun?
Oh, him?
I live next door, and Yumi-ta—
Shūkichi Haneda (28)
Flat Resident
I mean, Yumi-san and I have been dating. My name's Shūkichi Haneda!
He's my ex-boyfriend.
Emphasis on the 'ex'.
S-Still, why is your boyfriend here?
My ex-boyfriend said he remembered the combination to the letterbox dial where this room's spare key was kept, so I dragged him here!
Huh? You look familiar somehow.
Come to think of it, I seem to have heard your name before.
Don't tell me you're on a list of
wanted criminals or something?!
No way.
Anyway, there's a suicide note under the body's feet.
We can rule this as a suicide.
But this might not be a suicide.
That's what Conan-kun said, anyway.
What?
I see.
You're right.
The edges of the suicide note and the remains of the torn page don't match up.
The suicide note says...
'I'm sorry for causing your injuries, and I hope you get well soon.'
'Yasuie-san, study hard for your exam. I hope you'll pass and get accepted.'
'Please celebrate Ichiko-chan's Shichi-go-san
by letting her wear my kimono.'
'And please forgive me for leaving this world.' Signed 'Chiyoko Itami'.
Does anything she wrote here seem odd to you?
No.
As you can see, I have a bruise from when my wife threw an ashtray at me and hit my eye last night,
And my son Yasuie also said he's going to take a test in order to get his driver's licence.
And my niece's going to turn 7 years old this year.
Hence the Shichi-go-san.
But why did she throw the ashtray?
When she gets angry, she tends to throw things around.
I saw her doing that, too.
That's why I thought the mobile phone on the floor in front of the bedroom was her doing too.
There was a mobile phone on the ground?
Yes.
I noticed it when I was knocking on the bedroom door after we came back from shopping.
And where is that phone?
I've got it.
I thought I'd give it back to her once she felt better.
There's no incoming or outgoing calls or messages for today.
I thought it might've been used as a part of some murder trick, but...
Seems it doesn't have anything to do with the case.
But as I figured, she didn't commit suicide.
As you figured?
Because of what she said before.
She said 'I'm the bearer of good fortune and God's beloved child'!
Bearer of good fortune?
What's that supposed to mean?
Several years ago, the plane she was on was about to crash.
But miraculously, she was saved.
Were you on that plane too?
No. I was supposed to be, but I ended up breaking my foot during a ski trip right before that.
That's why I don't think she'd
commit suicide just over an argument!
But that's just her pet phrase.
Also, that suicide note seems odd.
Where?
She had a cold back when she was 7, so she couldn't celebrate her Shichi-go-san,
and she said she had nothing to do with kimonos from then until her coming-of-age ceremony.
I see.
A well-prepared move.
That's what it is.
What are you on about, Shūkissy?
She just said the deceased wasn't preparing any kind of kimono!
My name's Shūkichi!
Stop calling me Shūkissy already!
'Shūkissy''s a more fitting name for you!
When you turn up looking like that...
A well-prepared move? Could that mean...
I see!
That would also explain the odd points in the suicide note.
There's still some pieces missing before I get the full picture, but if I fill in the gaps move by move...
Isn't that right...
...Shūkichi Haneda-san?
Then this suicide note looks awfully suspicious to me.
Yes. Looks like a handwriting recognition test's in order.
Right.
I can't believe a person who just broke her wrist would choose hanging, something hard to do with one hand, as her suicide method.
Good point.
Inspector Megure!
We've obtained testimony regarding a suspicious suspect!
What?!
According to the concierge who was guarding the first floor lobby,
a suspicious individual with their face covered with a hat, a mask and glasses came and left the block of flats!
C-Chiba-kun!
I can't tell you that.
Has to be a woman. You went on a date with some woman, right?
On the next Conan: 'The Ex-Boyfriend Living Next to a Crime Scene (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Mobile phone cover!
Shūkissy?
And Yumi-tan!
That's what you're interested in?
Another new couple, huh?