While heading home from school, we came across Yumi Miyamoto and Naeko Mi'ike in a police car.
But then, a report of a case came in on Mi'ike's phone.
We rushed over to investigate, and found a corpse hanging from a chandelier.
She had what looked to be a will at her feet, so it was thought to be suicide, but...
I see...
A well-prepared move...
That's what it was.
A well-prepared move?
Could that mean...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
The suspect is Yumi Miyamoto's ex-boyfriend?!
With the case in check, it's time to play your deduction!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Inspector Megure!
A suspicious person was spotted here!
What?!
According to the concierge in the ground floor lobby,
a suspicious individual with their face covered with a hat, a mask and glasses came and left the block of flats!
C-Chiba-kun?!
When was that?
He said it was after the husband
and the housemaid left the building.
Why didn't the concierge stop this person?
He thought it was a resident, since they used their keys to come in normally.
And he said the son of this family was also here.
The son?
Yeah.
He said the son arrived before the husband and the housemaid came back too,
but he couldn't remember whether it was before or after the suspicious figure left.
Oh?
Wait, aren't you...
Sakurako-chan, from the year behind me?
Sakurako Yonehara (23)
Housemaid
Chiba-tchi! Long time no see!
So you're the housemaid here, huh?
Why can't he remember me?!
Oh yeah, maybe you don't remember, but there was somebody always with you...
Chiba-kun, go check it out.
Y-Yes, sir!
Hey, what's wrong with you, brat? Let go!
No way I'll let you go!
What are you guys doing?!
Isn't it obvious? We just caught a suspicious guy!
I'm not suspicious.
But you were looking inside
through the peephole, weren't you?!
That was just for laughs!
You'd be surprised if someone was peeping back at you, right?
Besides, I can't even see anything from the outside!
And your hair's weird, too!
W-Well, I just haven't redyed my hair brown lately.
Aren't you just making excuses and you're really here because you're intrigued?
As they say, "the culprit always
returns to the scene of the crime".
C-Culprit? What do you mean by "culprit"?
Hey, was he really peeping inside?
Y-Yeah.
He did it all of a sudden after ringing the doorbell.
I know that voice. Is that Yasuie?
P-Pops!
Yasuie Itami (22)
Naganobu's Son
So this guy's the son?
Why are you here? Weren't you supposed to be at driving school?
Naganobu Itami (52)
Flat Resident
I skipped class. I wanted to show you that car catalogue!
What car? Leave that until you get a proper job!
What's with you? Didn't you approve
of me getting a driver's licence?
With a cream caramel hairstyle like that, there's no way you'll pass!
P-Pops, why are you so mad?
And the cops are here too. Did something happen?
Actually...
What?! Mum killed herself?!
N-No way... Why?!
We haven't ruled out murder yet either.
M-Murder?!
Come to think of it, you were here earlier today, right?
Y-Yeah. I came here to show my parents this catalogue.
But nobody answered when I rang the doorbell, so I thought they were out shopping,
so I killed time by wandering around for a bit and came back for another visit.
I see. Can anyone else attest to that?
Hold on, Inspector.
Are you suspecting me?!
Huh? Isn't someone's phone ringing?
Ah, sorry, it was mine.
Geez.
But all three of your family use the same phone, huh?
Y-Yeah, it's a pretty popular model.
But the covers are all different colours, so we don't get them mixed up.
Speaking of phones, didn't you say you heard the bedroom door closing before you found the mistress's phone, Sakurako-san?
Y-Yes.
How did you know it was the bedroom door?
You can't see the door from the entrance.
All the other doors were still slightly open.
Though I thought they were all
closed when we went shopping...
Then the bedroom window was slightly open too, right?
How did you know that?
When you were out shopping,
were you with her the whole time?
No. I waited at the smoking area
until she finished her shopping.
Then you don't have an alibi either.
Were you in your flat the whole time, Haneda-san?
No, I went outside.
And the policewoman rang my bell right after I came back.
Where were you, and what were you doing?
Shūkichi Haneda (28)
Flat Resident
Well...
Hey, spit it out already!
I can't tell you that.
What are you doing, Shūkissy?! Can't you see they'll suspect you of murder?!
Come on, spit it out!
If you don't, they'll think you're the killer!
It's all right, Yumi-tan.
It looks like this case already reached checkmate.
Okay, guys. It's gotta be somewhere around here.
So if you guys find it, show someone nearby the photo I sent you to make sure!
I'm counting on you!
Yeah!
Right...
Inspector Megure!
The handwriting test results are in.
Oh, is that so?
The handwriting may be messy, but the suicide note was indeed written by Chiyoko Itami-san.
What?
Then she wasn't forced to write that by the killer?
No. Her killer would've told her to rewrite it after seeing such sloppy handwriting.
Oh, and the supermarket's surveillance cameras caught the housemaid on camera quite a few times, so her alibi checks out.
Though Naganobu-san, who supposedly went shopping with her, wasn't anywhere in the footage.
Like I said, I was in the smoking area.
So the suspects are the husband, his son Yasuie-san, who claimed to have come here and rung the doorbell without getting a response,
and then returned here after killing some time,
and myself, who was out during the time of the crime, but for some reason won't say where I was.
"For some reason", huh? You're one to talk.
I-I'll tell you my whereabouts later.
What, you can't say it in front of me or something?
Then it has to be a woman. You went on a date with some woman, right?
That's not it!
I told you already, you're my one and only!
Talk about annoying.
Inspector! I'm fine with making a culprit out of this one! Go ahead and cuff him!
Hold on, Yumi-kun.
While there are some odd points, when the husband and housemaid
returned from shopping and came through the front door,
they heard the bedroom door slam closed.
And the mistress hung herself in the bedroom in question.
Plus, the suicide note by her feet was determined to be written by her.
This can't be anything but a suicide!
"A well-prepared move".
That's what the suicide note was, right, Haneda-san?
Oh, right. Didn't you say something like that, Shūkissy?
What did you mean by that?
I dunno. Did I really say something like that?
A player foresees a certain stage of the game,
and when that stage arrives, they go ahead and make a brilliant move.
That's called a "well-prepared move",
or so I read on the Internet.
It's shōgi terminology.
Shōgi terminology? Why would
Shūkissy know something like that?
Still, why is the suicide note a "well-prepared move"?
Aren't the contents of the suicide note kind of odd?
Let's see... It says "I'm sorry for causing your injuries, and I hope you get well soon."
"Yasuie-san, study hard for your exam. I hope you'll pass and get accepted."
"Please celebrate Ichiko-chan's Shichi-go-san
by letting her wear my kimono."
"And please forgive me for leaving this world."
Signed "Chiyoko Itami".
What part sounds odd?
The exam part.
Yasuie-san's just taking a test to obtain his driver's licence.
It's not something so complicated that you have to pray for it.
T-That's because my wife tends to worry a lot.
She was even worried about my son, who still can't find a job despite being about to graduate from university.
Right. Yasuie-san's now in his fourth year at university.
Wouldn't that note make more sense if it'd been written four years ago, and the message was for her son
who was preparing for the hard-to-pass entrance exam?
T-That makes sense, but four years ago...?
If it was four years ago, then your niece Ichiko, who's turning 7 now, would be 3...
So the Shichi-go-san would also apply!
The mistress did show me a photo of that a while ago.
She pointed at the girl wearing a kimono and said "You can't tell that this kimono is 40 years old, huh?"
Then was the suicide note really from four years ago?
That can't be! I showed you the bruise on my eye!
This injury was caused by my wife throwing an ashtray at me last night, and she wrote about it on the suicide note!
Speaking of injuries, you mentioned you broke your foot before, right?
Y-Yeah.
Mum was a rookie at skiing and crashed into my Dad.
Because of that, she had to fly solo to attend the New Year's party in the countryside where we go as a family every year,
and she always used to say she almost died on the plane.
And that was four years ago too?
If her aeroplane was about to crash, then it wouldn't be strange for her to write a farewell to her family on the plane.
Of course! That's why her farewell
notice has shaky handwriting!
She wrote it in a tumbling plane about to crash!
I see.
Then she wrote her full name on the note so that whoever found the crash site would know exactly who wrote it.
If the killer retrieved the note and used it for murder four years later, then it truly is a well-prepared move.
But there's still the mystery that when the husband and housemaid returned, the bedroom door slammed shut.
Yeah.
C-Could the killer have still been in the bedroom at the time?
I doubt it.
I chain-locked the front door when I returned, and when Conan-kun arrived here earlier, the chain-lock was still on.
Then why did the door shut?
It wouldn't just shut by itself...
Hey, who did that? That was barbaric!
Was that you, Chiba-kun?
Huh?
Hey, Conan-kun, did you just shut this door?
What do you mean? I just opened the front door to see if my friends were back or not.
Oh, I did open the bedroom window slightly.
The heating in there was too strong.
When you discovered the mistress's body, the window was slightly open, right?
Is that true?
Yes.
The master closed it afterward, saying he'd feel terrible leaving his wife in the cold.
That's it!
Air flows from areas of warm temperature to cold temperature,
so when someone opened the front door, the warm air in the room flowed out the window,
causing the bedroom door to slam shut!
That's why the killer opened the bedroom window and door ahead of time!
But then wouldn't the bedroom door close when the killer opened the front door to escape?
Oh, right.
Come to think of it, the mistress's phone was in front of the bedroom door, right?
If you stick it in the gap between the hinges, you can keep the door open, right?
Look, like this!
But if you did that, the door would've stayed open, right?
So it wouldn't work, huh?
If only the phone had feet and could move on its own, then it could've worked!
I see! The phone vibrated!
The killer stuck the phone on the hinge, left the flat with the door still open,
and then called the phone from outside to make it vibrate and fall!
But there's no record of a call on the mistress's phone found in front of the door.
Then maybe it's not the mistress's at all?
After all, all three of you have the same phone model, with just a different colour cover!
It wouldn't be too strange if someone mistook their phone for the mistress's and brought it with them, would it?
I get it. The killer replaced the mistress's phone cover with his own, so he could make it seem like it was the mistress's phone.
If the killer used that trick and re-swapped the covers before handing the phone over to the police,
they could make us think the mistress's phone hadn't been used during the crime.
And the only one who could've achieved that was the one who held onto the mistress's phone before giving it to us.
Naganobu-san, it could only have been you!
Most likely, you came back when the housemaid was still out shopping, strangled your wife and hung her from the ceiling,
placed the farewell note from four years ago under her feet, opened the bedroom window, stuck the phone in the door and left the scene.
Then you called the phone from outside to make it vibrate and fall out,
met back up with the housemaid and went back home again, all to disguise your wife's death as a suicide.
After you came back home, the reason you didn't enter the bedroom and discover the body immediately
was because you needed to hide the fact that some time had already passed since she had been hanged.
Then the suspicious person the
concierge at the lobby spotted was...
The husband himself.
He probably prepared a change of clothes in the toilet at the supermarket.
Well, we can tell for sure just by looking at your phone.
That reminds me, somebody did call me at the supermarket's smoking area.
Who?
Oh, it was a wrong number.
We found the public phone!
It's one in front of a corner shop nearby!
When we showed the cashier his photo, he said that the guy did make a phone call while looking sneaky!
Well, not many people use public phones in this day and age,
so his fingerprints are probably still on it.
What they said.
P-Pops, is this true?
Did you really kill Mum?
I did it because I thought luck had finally landed on my side...
To be honest, I wasn't sure whether to go through with this murder plan or not...
Until last night.
Hey, Chiyoko! Didn't I tell you to stop playing with stocks?!
Hey, you opposed the idea, but in your heart, you really want to buy Yasuie a car, don't you?
What are you talking about?! Our debt's going out of control!
I just had an epiphany!
God will never smile at me unless we're in serious trouble.
So I took out a loan with our flat as collateral!
We had a huge fight after that, and when Chiyoko threw the ashtray at my eye, something inside me just snapped.
I figured now was the best time to carry out the murder plan I hatched in my head ever since I found the farewell note.
I figured the god of luck would be on my side.
Hey, don't tell me you knew who the killer was?
The "suicide note" raised my suspicion.
But I was only sure when I heard
those two talk by the front door.
With a cream caramel hairstyle like that, there's no way you'll pass!
He hadn't seen his son for over a year, yet he knew what his son's hair looked like under that hat.
That's gotta be from when he saw the son through the peephole, standing outside the front door while he was hanging his wife.
But he couldn't see that if the son still had his hat on, could he?
The son likes peeking back through the peephole,
and if he didn't take off his hat, which has a brim, he wouldn't have been able to peep back, would he?
But that guy was pretty boring, huh?
You mean Yumi-san's ex?
The way she talked about him earlier, I was expecting some attractive guy from a host club.
It's fine, isn't it? He has a sharp mind and helped solve the case.
meijin
Yeah. I was excited to get the chance to deduce alongside a celebrity.
Celebrity?
Is there some actor named "Shūkichi Haneda"?
Look at this man.
Taikō-meijin, congratulations on winning your fourth shōgi title!
That's that meijin called Taikō!
My mum's a huge fan of his!
But what does that meijin have to do with him?
Look closely.
In today's game, I think my "opposing rook" had a great effect.
That hair...
That was him?!
I get it.
羽田 秀吉
羽柴 秀吉
The name "Shūkichi Haneda" is similar to the legendary "Hashiba Hideyoshi",
so they named him "Taikō".
Yeah. On the day of the crime, he actually went to the Shōgi Association to participate in the preliminary match,
but he didn't tell the police because he didn't want Yumi-san to know he's a professional shōgi player.
But being a meijin's so cool!
Then what are the seven things he's trying to collect?
Well, it's shōgi, so the seven things have to be...
Many years ago
I did it, Yumi-tan!
I finally won the title of "meijin"!
Yumi-tan!
Geez. You're late, Shūkissy!
Sorry, sorry. I had a pretty long battle.
Were you playing a game or something?
No. Well, you could call it a game, I suppose.
But today, I—
Anyway, look at the news!
News?
Tenhō, the sumo champ with the Yokozuna title, just won the summer basho tournament,
so now he's conquered all six basho in a row!
Isn't he awesome?!
He won nonstop for a whole year!
If this king became someone's prince charming, I bet his bride would really feel like a queen!
Don't worry, Shūkissy. I don't expect you to be someone like that!
Giō.
Ōshō.
Ōza.
Kisei.
Ōi.
Ryū-ō.
Meijin.
The seven shōgi titles!
Shūkissy's a meijin?
That's right! He's actually—
master
It's some silly made-up title like "fishing meijin" or "game meijin", right?