Congrats, Masaru-san!
Congratulations!
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
Gunshots aimed at a newly-wedded bride and groom.
Solve the riddle of the impossible crime!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The food's all right.
Did we really do the right thing coming?
We don't even know anyone here.
It's fine, don't worry.
If I'd come by myself, what table do you think I'd be seated at?
They're all full of stuck-up old men and women.
And when I do go to an occasion like this by myself,
everyone always wants to introduce me to their sons,
and I don't get to eat in peace!
I guess it's tough, being heiress to a financial group.
Yeah, it is. I bet Masaru-san feels the same way.
Falling in love at first sight
with the caretaker of his holiday villa...
Masaru Hatakeyama (28)
Groom/Head of the Hatakeyama Group
Miho Itō (26)
Bride
How romantic!
Ladies and gentlemen, I apologise for the interruption,
but we would like to hold a round of congratulatory messages from various speakers here.
But before that, we have an announcement for all of you.
The bride and groom who have just held their solemn marriage
ceremony at the church, Masaru-san and Miho-san,
would like you to know they have already sent their
marriage registration to the ward office yesterday.
Did you know about that, Mother?
Yuuko Hatakeyama (62)
Masaru's mother
No, I had no idea.
What a selfish thing to do!
I'd like to ask for another show of applause for our happy couple.
What's going on now? There isn't even any wine left!
Kenshirō Hatakeyama (64)
Masaru's uncle
Hey, Arisa! You're drinking too much.
You be quiet! I'm only here because you insisted I come, Dad.
Arisa Hatakeyama (25)
Masaru's cousin
That girl was one of the many who wanted to marry Masaru-san.
Oh, you need some wine? I'll bring some straightaway.
Yoshifumi-kun, you're the bride's brother...
Tatsuya Ishihara (37)
Masaru's brother-in-law
You should let someone else take care of it.
It's fine. I don't really like sitting still.
Yoshifumi Itō (25)
Miho's brother
I'm more comfortable when I'm up and about.
He should've let himself relax today, at least...
Once a caretaker, always a caretaker.
Rikako Ishihara (34)
Masaru's sister
Honestly! It's hard to bear thinking that that woman
will have the Hatakeyama fortune at her fingertips.
Father will be turning in his grave!
Now, we will begin with a message
from Kenshirō Hatakeyama-sama,
the uncle of the newly-wedded Masaru-san
and the president of Hatakeyama Bank.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
I've gotta go to the toilet.
Little boy!
What is it? Need the toilet?
Yeah.
Do you know where to go?
I'll be fine.
You're the boy here with the Suzuki
Financial Group's heiress, right?
Yeah! You're the caretaker for this villa, right?
Yeah. When the villa was first built, my mum and
dad took care of it, but they both died in an accident.
What did you do before then?
I was a farmer.
But in this area, most of the crops tend
to be eaten by monkeys and boars.
So I stopped farming and took over looking after the villa.
But never mind that, didn't you need the toilet?
Oh, I forgot. See ya!
Can you believe he said that?
Hi, how are you?
I hope you enjoyed the food?
Yes. We've all eaten our fill.
I'm glad to hear it.
When we get back from our honeymoon,
the three of you should visit us in Tōkyō!
Of course. But bring us back some souvenirs!
All right, I'll make sure not to forget!
Still, should you really be away from your bride's side?
She might get jealous of you talking with two beautiful girls.
No, don't worry about that.
I trust Masaru-san.
Oh, what passion!
Huh? Miho-san, you don't look too well...
Right... I'm just feeling a little tired.
Then why don't you leave the rest to me,
and you can go back to the hotel and rest.
Yoshifumi-kun.
Yes?
Did you drink anything?
No. I don't drink alcohol.
Then I'm sorry to bother you, but
could you take Miho there in my car?
Understood.
Maybe we should get going soon too?
Right.
Then let's say goodbye to Masaru-san.
Huh? Where's Masaru-san?
He got a call from Miho-san about ten minutes ago and left.
I-It's a disaster!
What's happened?
B-By the estate cars in the c-car park...
T-The groom is collapsed on the ground!
No way!
What?
It couldn't be?!
He's been shot from close range...
Masaru-san!
Wait!
Don't come any closer until the police get here!
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan!
Quick, get the police!
Is that really Masaru-kun lying there?
Oh, Uncle...
What was that sound?!
It came from across the river...
Yeah, it sounded like it came from the hotel...
No...!
Miho-san! Miho-san!
I see...
Then, except for Conan-kun, this is everyone who was
here when you heard what sounded like a gunshot?
Yes. Conan-kun called us and said we should
all wait here until the police arrived...
Okay. Then let's go and check the other crime scene.
Right!
What're you doing, Detective Takagi?
Oh, we're looking for anything the killer might've left behind.
I've found something!
This looks like it must be the murder weapon...
Excuse me! We need to take some photos!
Bamboo...?
Why is bamboo here?
Tatsuya-kun, I'm sorry for asking at such a trying time, but
what's going to happen to the shares Masaru-kun held?
I'm concerned that the employees will be worried.
Well, he didn't have any children, so wouldn't they
go to our mother, and me because I'm his sister?
No. If Masaru-kun was to die before Miho-san, everything
Masaru-kun owned would become Miho-san's when he died.
What do you mean?
Didn't you hear the announcement last night?
Their marriage has already been registered.
But then what happens to Masaru's fortune?
If Miho-san was to die after Masaru-kun,
then Miho-san's family would inherit it.
That can't be!
I'll never accept that!
Whether you do or not, it's the law...
Then it's a stupid law!
I'm sorry to bring you all here at a time like this.
My mother had to go and lie down
in her room because of the shock.
Understood.
Out of everyone that was here yesterday,
I've had everyone who had concrete alibis for both
of their estimated times of death leave already.
Then you suspect all of us?
No, it's just that you all have deep
connections with the two victims,
and so while I know you must be angry,
I hope you will help our investigation.
Tatsuya-kun and I were by Masaru-kun's
corpse when Miho-san was murdered.
We have an alibi for Miho-san's murder at least.
Yes. The bullets we recovered from both bodies were
both shot from the gun found in the flower bed.
In other words, we believe they were
both murdered by the same person.
Then we're fine...?
But at the time, Rikako-san and Arisa-san,
you had already returned to the hotel, correct?
Are you calling me a murderer?!
Now, now, don't take this personally...
We're just discussing the possibilities.
Since the successive murders of the bride and groom have only
occurred yesterday, we have yet to discover the culprit's motive.
But we do have questions for
the bride's brother, Yoshifumi-san.
Yes?
In our investigation since last night,
we've discovered that you are several
million yen in debt to various banks.
That's...
Are you or aren't you? We need an answer.
Yes. I am indeed in debt.
But I didn't kill anyone.
Why would I kill my sister?
She's the only family I had left...
Oh, Detective Chiba, what were you doing?
Conan-kun?
I was checking the surveillance footage.
The surveillance camera just inside the entrance shows
the area by the flower bed where we found the gun.
So I thought I'd check all the recordings from yesterday...
But nobody went near the flower bed...
Then why was the gun there?
Maybe someone threw it from a window upstairs in the hotel...
What are these four imprints?
Oh, I got a call last night saying the lamppost there had gone out.
When you were there, did you see anything?
Actually...
When was that?
Let's see, it must've been...
Oh, I got the call at 9:40, so it must've been about 9:45.
9:45...?
What could that mean...?
At 9:45, Miho-san had only just left the villa...
That's half an hour before we
discovered Masaru-san's corpse.
So that's it!
But then that means...
Hey, kid!
A little kid shouldn't be walking around this early.
Oh, sorry.
There's a lot of hungry monkeys in the
area, so you'll end up getting bitten!
Right, if someone used that...!
What reason would I have to murder Masaru?!
You wanted to get rid of Masaru-san so your own husband
could run the Hatakeyama Group, didn't you? I get it!
What a ridiculous accusation, you stupid little girl!
You probably killed Miho-san because
she stopped you from marrying Masaru!
And then you even killed Masaru when he found out!
Now who's the idiot here?
Masaru-san was shot first!
You want his money so much you can't even think clearly?
That's enough, you should be ashamed of yourselves!
Inspector Megure...
Y-Y-Yes?
We should be leav—
Sonoko, is this it? Your thing?!
I didn't want to say anything if I didn't have to...
But if I don't say something, the
killer is the only one who'd benefit.
S-Sonoko-kun, you mean you've figured out who did it?
Yes... And if the police had just arrested the culprit in the
first place, there wouldn't be any need for all this arguing.
Rikako-san, there's one thing that you did get right.
Miho-san was the first one murdered.
What?!
But the only ones who went back to the
hotel early were Rikako-san and Arisa-san...
I told you, I'm not a murderer!
Me either!
I know that you two didn't kill anyone.
It happened not long after Miho-san had arrived at her cottage.
That's why she hadn't changed out of her dress...
You probably drove Miho-san back, then
wasted no time murdering her, right?
Yoshifumi-san...
W-What are you saying?
You're in a lot of debt.
When your sister was to be married, you thought she could
repay your debts, but things didn't go as you had hoped.
So you slipped something into your sister's drink.
When she started feeling unwell, you took her back to her
cottage and murdered her with a gun you'd hidden there...
Silencing the noise with something like a cushion.
After that, you used Miho-san's phone to call out
Masaru-san, and murdered him just like Miho-san.
Just hold on a minute! What about the gun?
It was found in the hotel flower beds, right?
I stayed with everyone beside Masaru-san until the police arrived!
I never had time to put the gun there!
That's what bothered me the most.
Why did the killer choose to put the gun there?
And then I figured it out.
The gun wasn't put there manually —
it landed there.
The villa and hotel roughly face each
other on either side of the river, right?
But it'd be impossible to throw the gun to the
other shore by hand after murdering Masaru-san...
So you used that instead.
But why would I do that...?
Isn't it obvious?
Even Rikako-san and Arisa-san mentioned why.
You had to make it look like Miho-san died after Masaru-san so
that Masaru-san's fortune would have been passed to Miho-san.
To do that, the gun had to be found on this side of the river.
Y-You're just guessing! Do you have any proof?
Do you remember seeing a man carrying a ladder?
A hotel employee came to replace a lamp on the path to the
cottages, and remembers seeing someone leaving her cottage.
Before Masaru-san was murdered.
In other words, you murdered Miho-san first.
Then what was that gunshot we all heard at the car park?!
That gunshot was the heart of the alibi you so cleverly devised.
Okay, come on in.
Looks like you've seen it before.
Well, it was found in your shed, so of course you would have.
W-What is that?
A suzume-odoshi.
It's a tool used to stop tree sparrows from eating rice plants
planted in autumn by driving them away with fireworks.
Apparently, they're used in this area to drive away monkeys.
Also, it was set to only sound once.
It made the sound that everyone heard.
Damn it! This was all my sister's fault!
She was marrying into a family with billions,
but wouldn't give me anything at all!
Have you ever heard of someone so heartless?!
Ran looks very depressed today.
Well, given what happened, I guess it's no surprise.
Ran-neechan, tonight you should have
a tasty meal and cheer yourself up.
I'll even make you dinner.
I saw a cooking show on TV recently which
showed how to make a really nice curry!
No! Curry's no good! It's full of calories.
We did just go through that really sad case, but when
I got back from the wedding and weighed myself...
I'd put on 2 kg! Isn't that shocking?! 2 kg!
Is that why you're so depressed...?
Ran!
Good morning.
Good morning...
Sonoko... You don't look happy...
Listen to this! When I got back from the
wedding and weighed myself, I'd put on 3 kg!
I put on 2 kg too! We've gotta
slim down before the summer!
Our swimsuits won't fit!
But isn't school weight check day coming up before that?
Ran, what're we gonna do?!
We have to exercise! Let's run, Sonoko!
Right.
Here goes!
My, my... I'll end up losing weight worrying about them...
G-Great luck?
I just witnessed a murder taking place!
On the next Conan Special:
'Jodie's Memories and the Flower Viewing Trap'!
Next Conan's Hint: A five yen coin!
Next week, an hour-long special!
It's filled with the FBI and Men in Black!