Oh, the cherry blossoms are in full bloom!
Going flower viewing at a shrine's really nice.
Yeah! And the weather's great too!
It's the perfect weather for a flower viewing.
And those lunches would be perfect in my stomach.
Oh, Genta-kun...
He really would go for dumplings over flowers.
Doctor, how about we go look around and get our fortunes told and you spread out a sheet and save us a space?
Right, got it.
Okay! Let's go!
We'll leave it to you!
Conan-kun, let's go!
Sure...
What is it?
Weren't you looking for someone?
Oh, not really.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
Conflicting info under the cherry blossoms!
A mysterious case and the FBI!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
I just had to get "bad luck", didn't I?
I got "fairly good luck"!
I got "good luck"!
I got "delayed luck", which isn't too great...
Then let's go tie up our fortunes!
Yeah!
Hey!
You managed to get good fortunes, so you should take them home with you.
Shigemori Sakamaki (66)
Flower Viewer
You only tie up your fortune to leave bad fortune behind and change your luck.
Though in recent years, some people have taken up the bad habit of tying up whatever fortune they get.
Then Edogawa-kun's the only one who has to tie up his fortune.
You just had to peek at it, didn't you?
So what did you get, anyway?
You really want to know?
I-I can live without knowing...
If you're so interested, then I guess I'll just have to show you.
G-Great luck?!
That's amazing, Ai-chan!
I'm so jealous!
How about swapping with me?
But you know, "bad luck" is really rare, so I hear some people take getting it as a sign of good luck.
So don't feel disappointed, Cool Kid.
Jodie-sensei!
Hi!
Are you here to see the flowers too?
Oh, yes! I love cherry blossoms.
I get it.
You called her out here so you to could talk in secret, didn't you?
Well, parks and shrines are often used by spies to exchange information.
So why don't we give them some space.
It looks like they want to have a private talk.
S-Sure...
But don't forget...
You often find Public Safety Officers watching places like this, so be careful.
O-Okay.
So?
You wanted to talk to me?
Yeah.
You said you saw Akai-san with a burn scar, right?
Y-Yeah...
It was at that bank robbery...
Shū...
Hold on!
Shū!
Oh, sorry...
S-Shū...
Is that you, Shū?
It is, right?
Tell me it's you!
A burn scar!
That...
That wasn't Akai-san, but Bourbon, one of the men in black, in disguise.
He was wandering around like that near people who knew Akai-san to check whether or not Akai-san was truly dead.
Since if the FBI had faked his death,
he'd know by your reactions.
Though on the Bell Tree Express, Vermouth wore the Akai disguise herself, instead of applying it to Bourbon.
The Bell Tree Express... You mean they were behind that train bombing?!
Yeah, it seems that way.
Hold on...
If that man with the burn scar was one of them...
...then that means Shū...
...really is...
Then the next time I see that man with the burn scar prancing around,
I'll catch him, rip off his disguise and find out who he really is!
Oh, I know who he is.
As well as where you can find him.
He calls himself Tōru Amuro, and he works part-time at Café Poirot under the Mouri Detective Agency.
B-But why?
I don't know... That's why I had you come here.
I wanted to have the FBI investigate him.
He should have achieved his objective, so why is he still at Poirot?
His objective?
Oh, it was...
Huh?
You're that foreign lady who was a hostage in that bank robbery just like me, right?
Tōhei Benzaki (35)
Flower Viewer
I was one row behind you to the side,
and it was my wife who covered up your eyes and mouth with tape, don't you remember?
Y-Yeah, I do, kind of.
Then was that man with a burn scar next to you your boyfriend?
He's not... But what is this?
Oh, well, if he isn't, then don't worry.
I saw him two or three days ago, that's all.
Where?! Where did you see him?!
Answer the question!
A pickpocket!
There's a pickpocket!
Are you okay?
You alright, Miss?
I'll be fine... I was just panicking since someone put their hand in my bag.
Well, you do often find pickpockets lurking in crowds.
Yes.
Ikuyo Yatani (50)
Flower Viewer
Y-Yes... You're right. I'll have to be more careful.
Well then, excuse me!
No, Genta-kun! You can't drink that water!
Huh? Really?
You're supposed to gently rinse out your mouth, then spit it out on the ground.
So? You still can't remember?
Where you saw him, I mean.
Right...
I was stuck in bed all day yesterday with this cold, so my memory's fuzzy.
You do have a very hoarse voice...
Then why don't you rinse your mouth with this water too?
No, I'll be fine.
I wouldn't want anyone to catch my cold, and I washed my hands earlier.
You wouldn't have seen him by a can vending machine selling coffee by any chance, would you?
D-Did he like canned coffee?
Yeah, he often drank it.
Even back when we were expecting them to attack the hospital at any moment...
Hey, Shū...
Have you seen that man before?
He's an agent recently stationed here to increase security.
No idea.
I'm not too good remembering friendly faces...
But I'd never forget an enemy mugshot.
Well, it's no surprise that you've seen him before.
You're both FBI agents, after all.
Yes...
But looking at him makes me feel uneasy.
Shū...
H-He must've been tired to drop his coffee like that.
But wait, what do you mean by an attack?
Ah, no, no!
That guy wasn't the burnt man.
That's enough!
Contact me if you remember, okay?
That's strange...
On the Bell Tree Express, Bourbon said that he was sure Akai-san was dead...
Why would he disguise himself as Akai-san again?
What goal could he have...?
No, Genta-kun, don't ring it so loudly!
But Dad said I should ring it with all my might!
That's right.
Yoriko Dan'no (29)
Flower Viewer
You ring these bells to tell the gods that you're here.
So if you don't ring it loud enough, the gods might not notice you, you know?
Really?
All right!
Then let's give it a great big ring!
Hey...
What sort of man was that Akai guy you were talking about?
Why?
I get the feeling he greatly resembles someone I know...
Y-You're probably just imagining it!
Besides, Akai-san's already...
What? Dead?
Really?!
Yeah, there's a big ruckus about it behind the toilets!
Let's take a look!
Yeah!
Doc? What's up?
I-It's terrible, Shin'ichi! A murder!
I just witnessed a murder taking place!
What?! You witnessed a murder?!
Anyway, come quickly!
There's a big crowd forming, so it won't be hard to find!
That has to be it!
So? Did you see the murderer?!
They were shaded by the trees,
so I could just see a silhouette,
but they were attacking again and again
with a rod about 30 centimeters long.
A 30 centimetre-long rod... Death by beating?!
H-Hey... Let me through! Let me through!
It's that woman...!
It can't be!
That's the lady who ran into Sensei earlier!
But why?
It hasn't been long since she was murdered.
Five yen coins colored black with a marker pen?
Could it be Kurobee?!
Kurobee?
It's the nickname of a pickpocket.
She was named that because she puts three black five yen coins in the bags of her victims.
But why do something like that?
kuro
go
The rumor goes that the "five" of five yen, the "black" of the pen
san
and the "three" for three coins can be read as "gokurosan",
gokurōsan
so it's like she's saying "thank you" to her victims for earning her money.
Officer, it's here, over here.
Doc!
Huh? What are you doing?
Step away from the body!
I'm Jodie Starling, an FBI agent!
FBI?!
Seal the exit to this shrine right away!
And call for detectives!
R-Right!
Then she was murdered by Kurobee?
No...
She had a purse full of black five yen coins in her bag, which means...
She probably was Kurobee.
Look at this bundle of notes wrapped in a rubber band that was in her wallet.
Inside it... Is that a GPS transmitter?!
A-A transmitter?
With a phone, you can locate it to within five metres.
But for a pickpocket to have that wrapped in notes in her wallet...
Yeah...
It's likely that one of her victims murdered her.
You can't just do this, Jodie-san.
You may be an FBI agent, but this is Japan, and you're only here because you took a day off to fly over here, right?
If you go ordering around the Japanese police, think about how it looks for us.
I'm sorry.
My usual habits just took over.
But the crime scene's quite far from the shrine exit, and it hasn't been that long since she was murdered,
so since I had the shrine exit sealed, her murderer should be trapped here...
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Oh, uh, well, I guess you did help by giving the right orders...
But are you sure?
Is this woman really the pickpocket Kurobee
that Division Three of the Criminal Investigation Department have spent years looking for?
I'm pretty sure about that.
The purse she had was filled with five yen coins colored black with a marker pen.
Kurobee is said to leave three black five yen coins in her victims' bags...
And did you really see Kurobee get beaten to death, Agasa-san?
Y-Yeah...
I witnessed it when passing by after leaving the toilet.
But it was dark with the shade from the trees, and at first I thought they were hammering in a post or something.
Then what did her killer look like?
All I really saw was their silhouette...
Though they were wearing a hat, and holding a thin rod about 30 centimeters long.
I see. So that's the murder weapon...
Did they have any other unusual traits?
Right...
Oh! Now you mention it, they were dragging their feet slightly as they left.
I even called out to them and asked if they were okay.
Dragging their feet?
Then what did they do?
They ignored me and walked away, and by the time I realized
that they had been beating this woman, they'd already mixed in with the crowd.
I see.
Inspector, if they were dragging their feet at a situation they should want to run away from...
Right. I doubt it would be an act to try and avoid suspicion.
But to find the killer among all the people at this shrine with so few clues...
It's nearly impossible.
You should be able to narrow it down.
That woman had something strange in her wallet.
Strange?
A GPS transmitter wrapped in banknotes.
W-Why would she have that?
The pickpocket Kurobee has never been caught, so there's no way of identifying that it was her
other than finding black five yen coins in your bag.
So if someone deliberately had notes with a transmitter stolen by her,
they could track her with a mobile phone,
wait for Kurobee to go somewhere quiet, and then beat her to death.
T-Then the killer is one of Kurobee's victims?
Still, pickpockets often commit thefts in groups,
so we can't ignore the possibility of
her killer being one of her accomplices.
Right.
I think Kurobee was working alone.
She herself yelled out that there
was a pickpocket here, after all.
What? What do you mean?
It's a common tactic used by pickpockets.
If you heard there was a pickpocket nearby, you'd check your wallet was safe without thinking, right?
Pickpockets use it to find where
their victims keep their wallets,
but if she had accomplices, wouldn't she have one of them yell out instead?
And Jodie-sensei, I think you'll find that your wallet is...
My wallet's gone!
She probably took it when you helped her up.
Still, if the pickpocket's dead, then how are we going to find her victims?
Well, that shouldn't take long.
Conan-kun! I found one!
It's in a bin by the racks to tie up your fortunes!
I found one too!
It's in a bin by the place I drank the water!
Oh! I think I've got one!
It was in a bin by where we rang the bells!
I asked a priest to help get it out!
I've got one from a bin near the crime scene...
The rubbish was about to be collected, but I made a fuss and had it searched.
Okay, then bring the wallets you've found over here, making sure not to get fingerprints on them.
Yeah!
Roger.
I get it! The wallets!
Pickpockets just take the money out of wallets, then abandon them, so if we check those wallets...
We may be able to find their owners.
Yes.
And these four were the only wallets you found in the bins?
The rubbish collector said that he'd started collecting the rubbish from the bin I checked.
Oh, that blue wallet's mine.
Then that makes you a suspect too.
It wasn't Jodie-sensei!
She never left our side after that woman bumped into her!
She didn't have a chance to murder anyone!
O-Oh, really?
That means that the murderer...
...is likely the owner of one of the other three wallets.
Oh? Well, it's easy to tell who owned this black wallet.
It has a driving license in it.
We saw that guy earlier!
He talked with Jodie-sensei!
He had a cold, so he was wearing a mask!
I-I see...
Though I doubt we'll find licenses so easily in the other wallets.
A photo sticker?
We know that lady too!
She taught us how to ring the bells!
Maybe she's still over there?
And the final red wallet is empty except for a "pretty good luck" fortune...
I doubt you'll be able to tell who owned that!
Wouldn't it belong to that old man?
He told us to take our good fortunes home, right?
Yeah. And I saw it!
I saw him take out that red wallet to buy his fortune when he was lined up in front of us!
I saw that too!
I did think it was a bit flashy for a guy like him!
Y-You know who owned it?
Yeah!
We'll go look for him!
Just wait here!
H-Hey, kids!
You're dealing with a murderer!
Takagi-kun, you go with them!
R-Right!
If any of them have a 30 centimetre-long rod, then that'll be the clincher, but well...
We'll know soon enough even if they don't have a rod!
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
The murderer left three black five yen coins by the corpse,
as if to say "you can have them back"!
It wouldn't be easy to find distinctive black five yen coins like these, right?
I get it!
Then whoever doesn't have the black five yen coins that Kurobee gave them would be the murderer!
That's right!
H-Hey, what's going on here?
This detective said you wanted to talk to us right away.
What are you supposing we've done?
Before I ask you for your statements, could I ask each of you to check if you have
five yen coins colored black with a marker pen in your pockets or bag?
Five yen coins colored black?
What's that about?
I wouldn't have anything that weird...
Why are these here?
Well, I found some black five yen coins.
I have some too!
Me too...
Huh?! B-But that means...
Oh, geez. All three of them have their coins?!
What exactly are these creepy black five yen coins?
W-Well, they're souvenirs left by
a pickpocket known as Kurobee.
What? No way! Then I was pickpocketed?!
I knew it! I noticed I didn't have my wallet just a while ago.
I was going to take them to the police.
Well, I didn't have much in my wallet, so I don't mind losing it, but have you caught that pickpocket then?
Well, the truth is...
We found her dead body not long ago.
And we suspect her killer is one of you three.
One of us?
That can't be...
We're victims ourselves, aren't we?
For now, we'd like to conduct body checks on each of you, and inspect your belongings and phones.
Of course, it's at your discretion, so you can refuse...
But if you do, it may cause trouble later, so we'd advise you to comply.
Fine.
Inspect whatever you want.
But my phone's all sticky since I've got greasy skin,
so if you want to check it you'll have to put up with that!
Jodie-sensei?
Did you figure something out?
No...
I was just thinking of the men in the video you took before.
Remember, when we were trying to identify the spy they sent to infiltrate the hospital,
you deliberately dropped a phone and had them pick it up, right?
The fat man who picked it up first had greasy skin.
But in the end, the next man to pick it up was the spy, and the last old man had a pacemaker...
And that's the phone that Shū...
Hey!
Why don't we put her in a Beetle an old friend of mine drives?
We can lay her down on the back seat.
Those bad guys probably think you'll carry her in a bigger vehicle on a stretcher.
They would never guess this.
T-That's probably true, but...
Then I'll give him a call.
He'll probably come right away!
No matter how smart you are, this isn't an option.
This is a job for the FBI.
We can't let any more civilians get involved.
But...
Just leave the rest to us.
H-Hey, Jodie-sensei?
T-That doesn't matter at all right now, does it?!
R-Right...
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm just feeling the shock from finding out the man with the burn wasn't Shū.
Gotta pull myself together!
What is it?
You sounded worried all of a sudden.
Oh, no, it's nothing.
So, how about it, Doctor?
Is any of those three the killer you saw?
Well, that old man with a cane does look very suspicious, but the murderer had a 30 centimetre-long rod, not a cane.
The hat the killer was wearing wasn't a hunting cap like the old man is wearing,
or a knit cap like that woman is wearing, but something like an alpinist's hat.
And the murderer didn't have a cough like that man there.
But couldn't he just be faking his cold?
I doubt that.
When we first met him, he had no way of knowing that we knew the doc, right?
He wouldn't have had to pretend to have a cold in front of us.
Well, I guess you're right.
Then how about the way they walk, Doctor?
You said they dragged their feet slightly, didn't you?
Without his cane, it looks like the old man can't walk at all, let alone drag his feet,
and the other two don't seem to be dragging their feet at all.
What?! You can't find the weapon?
Have you checked everywhere?
Yes. We even checked the drain of the purification trough and inside the offering box.
None of those three were carrying it, then?
Right. We checked the old man's cane, but it doesn't seem to have been used as a weapon.
And we checked all of their phones, but none of them had any app that could track a GPS transmitter...
Though the killer could've predicted they'd be checked, and deleted it.
Yeah...
But we'd need a warrant to conduct any further checks...
Hey, kids!
When you met those three, were
any of them acting strangely?
Acting strangely?
For example, if they had someone following them, who handed them some sort of thin rod?
All three of them were alone.
That old man told us that if we drew good fortunes, we should take them home.
That woman said that we should ring the bells loudly so that the gods can hear us when we ring them!
The other man said he already washed his hands at the purification trough,
so he must've been at the shrine for quite a while before meeting us.
Inspector Megure!
We believe we've found the killer's hat and coat!
Oh, is that so?
They've got blood splatters on
them, so there's no mistaking that.
They're covered in flower petals.
Yes. They appear to have been hidden under the fallen cherry blossom petals.
What?!
Then the weapon might be hidden in the same way!
Find it even if you have to kick through the petals!
Yes, sir!
And they made such a pretty pink carpet!
That's right. They may be small by themselves, but when many petals fall, they're almost like a pink carpet.
I see! So that's what happened!
That's why that person said that to the kids!
Which means the reason they dragged their feet was probably...
You may have grasped the truth of this case...
But I doubt you'll figure out the truth behind us.
How long are you planning on keeping us here‭?
The sun's already setting!
I don‭'‬t care whether there‭'‬s a case going on‭...
But it's got nothing to do with us, right?
I-I'm sorry! Please wait just a little longer!
Inspector Megure‭!
It's getting difficult to keep the shrine's exit sealed.
Is that so‭?
Any luck with the murder weapon?
Unfortunately, it hasn‭'‬t been found yet.
Maybe the killer already escaped with the murder weapon.
No.‭ ‬Taking into account the time between the murder and when we‭ ‬sealed the exit, and that the culprit was dragging their feet‭...
It's very likely that the killer's still on the grounds of this shrine.
They must have hidden the roughly ‬30‭ centimetre-long rod that Agasa-san saw somewhere.
That means the three people who were pickpocketed are the best suspects after all.
Yes.‭
And since we found a GPS transmitter hidden in notes in the wallet of the murdered pickpocket‭...
It must be like Jodie-san said ‬—
the killer let their wallet with the GPS transmitter get stolen,‭ ‬tracked the thief,
and killed her in a deserted location.
But none of those three seem to
have any problem with their feet.
And it seems that old man needs his cane to walk, not because his feet are hurting.
And if we assume that the killer had an accomplice and slipped them ‬the murder weapon,
we would have to search everybody who‭ ‬came to this shrine to watch the flower blossoms.
There's no need for that.
There's one part of the murder weapon that the killer still has on them.
One part‭?
Yes,‭ ‬that‭'‬s right.
The killer used it to tie‭ ‬together the murder weapon.
T-Tie together?
The weapon you saw was in one piece,‭ wasn't it?
It wasn't tied together or anything.
The killer ‬constructed the murder weapon using a‭ ‬large quantity of a certain object.
And even if you find the many parts,‭ ‬they‭'‬re hidden in such a way that they aren‭'‬t suspicious.
Approaching the children,‭ they managed to camouflage their actions smoothly.
You mean us?
Do you mean the old man who talked to us when we were drawing fortunes‭?
That‭'‬s true,‭ ‬there were a lot of fortunes tied up!
Nobody would notice if there were a few more of them,‭ ‬right‭?
But no matter how you tie fortunes together,‭ ‬you can'‬t make a weapon that can beat a person to death,‭ can you‭?
They are paper, after all‭...
Then you mean that man‭?
The man who refused the ladle Genta-kun tried handing him when we were washing our hands.
That‭'‬s it!
There were lots of ladles at the purification trough!
If you slip a ladle with an iron handle in there‭...
The police would have found‭ ‬that,‭ ‬don‭'‬t you think?
I guess.
It goes without saying that there was no such ladle in there.
That only leaves the lady we met
when we were ringing the bell...
But there were only two bells.
Didn‭'‬t you guys do something else before ringing the bell‭?
That‭'‬s right!
The offering‭!
We threw in a five yen coin!
Into the offering box‭!
Yep.
goen
Due to the saying‭ "May you‭ ‬find good ties and good fortune‭",
most of the offerings are five yen coins,‭ ‬which have a hole in the centre.
I see.‭
‬If you pass a wire or string through the hole and bind a lot of coins together, you get a long rod‭.
What's more, even if you find a large quantity of five yen coins in the offering box afterwards,
they‭'‬re mixed up with the other offerings and not suspicious‭,
which means it easily deceives the police,‭ ‬who are looking for‭ ‬a long metallic rod.
B-But,‭ ‬in order to produce a ‬30‭ ‬centimetre-long rod‭, ‬you‭'‬d need around‭ ‬200‭ ‬five yen coins‭!
And if you throw such a large quantity of coins into the box, you‭'‬ll stand out and people around you will certainly notice!
That is why the‭ ‬killer approached the children‭!
Saying the gods wouldn't hear them if they didn't ring the bell loudly.
T-Then...
The killer is...
Right.
You found her through a GPS transmitter in the wallet you had stolen,
then bashed her to death with a rod made from many five yen coins tied together.
The killer of Ikuyo Yatani-san, or rather the pickpocket Kurobee, is none other than you!
T-Then that means...
The killer is...
Right.
You found her through a GPS transmitter in the wallet you had stolen,
then bashed her to death with a rod made from many five yen coins tied together.
The killer of Ikuyo Yatani-san, or rather the pickpocket Kurobee, is none other than you!
Yoriko Dan'no-san!
You called out to the kids to ring the bell loudly to hide the noise of lots of five yen coins clanking into the offering box.
You untied the knot tying the five yen coins together, then holding onto the end of it and dangling it over the offering box,
you could get rid of all the five yen coins in an instant.
What's more,‭ ‬the murder occurred before you rang the bell‭.
Meaning that as a victim of the pickpocket,‭ your wallet must already have been stolen.
‭ ‬The fact that you apparently made an offering and rang the bell without noticing that is proof that you were lying.
You should certainly have noticed that your purse had been stolen when you tried to take it out to make an offering‭.
Don‭'‬t you know‭ that you shouldn‭'‬t open your wallet in front of the offering box‭?
If the gods see the contents of your wallet,‭ it might anger them,‭ ‬because you have so much and yet put in so little.‭
‬That is why I always put a five yen coin into my pocket before visiting a shrine.
And that's why you didn't notice your wallet had been stolen, right?
Exactly.
Well,‭ if you'd seen me put a large amount of five yen coins into the box, that might mean something,‭ ‬but like this?
Even if I didn‭'‬t see it,‭ ‬I can be sure‭...
...if we take a look at your shoelaces.
Most likely, you used one of your shoelaces to tie the coins together‭.
That's why you‭ ‬couldn‭'‬t immediately flee from the crime scene.
One of your shoelaces was missing, so you'd have lost your shoe if you'd walked normally‭!
It seems that you put your shoelace back in and tied it after ringing the bell,‭
but if you used that shoelace for ‬committing the crime‭, it should be there.
The victim's blood, that spurted when you killed her!
If you'll excuse me.
I found bloodstains.
But why did she still have her black five yen coins‭?
Weren‭'‬t the five yen coins beside the body the ones that Kurobee had left in your pocket when she stole the wallet?
Those were the coins I showed to you earlier.
Then what were those coins?
The ones left behind were the ones I found in my pocket when I was pickpocketed last year‭...
The five yen coins that killed my son!
Your son?
You mean the one on the photo in your wallet?
Yes.
The wallet that was stolen ‬last year also had my car keys.
Because I didn‭'‬t have them anymore,‭ ‬my son,‭ ‬who had asthma, ‬was locked in the car for several hours.
‬By the time we got‭ ‬to the hospital,
it was too late, and he died‭.
So I researched that pickpocket on the net and hung out in places where she frequently appeared.
But why did you put that photo in your wallet?
If it hadn‭'‬t been in your wallet, we might not have known it was yours.
When you open the wallet, the photo leaps into your sight,‭ ‬doesn‭'‬t it?
I wanted that pickpocket to see...
That what she stole wasn't just money‭,
but also the life of a little boy!
Well,‭ ‬does that mean I'm free to go‭?
Yes.
Then may I go too?
We may need to hear your testimony on the pickpocketting case later though.
As you wish.
Please feel free to contact me.
Hey, mister?
Do you happen to have bad eyesight?
Why do you ask?
Because when that pickpocket lady
saw your face,‭ ‬she was surprised.
I think that's because she stole your wallet earlier...
But why didn't you say anything at the time?
It must've been your second time meeting her, after all.
T-That‭'‬s it!‭ ‬My eyesight is bad!
If your eyesight is bad you should wear glasses, or you won‭'‬t see the cherry blossoms!
Did you come to the flower viewing‭ by yourself?
Actually, I came to buy a good luck charm‭.
What kind of good luck charm?
It‭'‬s for me,‭ ‬isn't it?
M-Motoe!
For the little one, you know.
Oh, a baby!
An easy childbirth good luck charm‭!
Didn‭'‬t I tell you to relax at home‭?
I came to look for you because I was worried when you didn‭'‬t return!
Then were you the person who taped me up during the bank robbery?
Oh my, were you the foreigner from back then?
I‭'‬m so sorry.‭ But we were threatened, so I had ‬no choice‭...
Are you okay?!
I-I'm sorry!
My wife‭'‬s condition isn‭'‬t very good.‭ ‬Would it be okay if I left‭?
S-Sure.
Morning sickness is a condition that you have in the first stages of pregnancy,‭ ‬right‭?
Yeah.
Even though looking at her size, the pregnancy should be in the sixth month already‭.
Well,‭ ‬the nausea could also be caused by something else.
Yes,‭ ‬that‭'‬s‭ ‬right, Camel‭.
It seems that the guy with the burn wasn't Shū.
He was a decoy that they planted in order to find out whether Shū really died, I suppose.
Ah,‭ ‬Jodie-san‭...
Anyway,‭ ‬I‭'‬ll tell you the details once I‭'‬ve returned.
I think the money's gone,‭ ‬but if you could check the contents of your wallet...
Right.
My cards are all there, as are the contents of the pocket.
This is from during that department store bomb threat...
Huh?
The edge of the coaster's bent...
"Run! This area's dangerous!"
Shū!
Shū...
If that guy with the scar isn‭'‬t Shū, then who wrote this?
And what for?
I'm sorry, Agent Jodie.
Hey, what's with you? If you sleep here, you'll catch a cold!
H-Hey!
Don't worry! He's just sleeping from having too much to drink.
My brother can‭'‬t hold his liquor.
T-Twins?
What a surprise.
The man you disguised‭ as had his wallet stolen.
I did find it strange that he didn‭'‬t have a wallet.
Well,‭ good thing I borrowed those‭ ‬weird five yen coins he had in his pocket.
But to go out of your way to return his stolen wallet...
It'd be a problem if he'd made a fuss about it,‭ ‬wouldn‭'‬t it‭?
It had his debit card and driving license in it, after all.
Well,‭ you should be grateful.
You know that bug that you slipped into the‭ ‬FBI kitten's sleeve when she grabbed your arm?
I got it back for you.
Thanks for that.
Well?
Did you get anything interesting...
...from that kitten?
Yeah. It was quite the harvest.
I got to hear a surprising inside story.
You‭'‬ll let me hear the outcome of that story,‭ ‬won‭'‬t you‭?
Of course, as soon as I‭'‬ve obtained‭ ‬positive proof of it.
But I can already say‭ this much...
He's a terrifying man.
That boy...
Leading near the Bell Tree Tower, a strange multi-dimensional request!
Solve the riddle of the unusual party!
Detective Conan: The Coded Invitation!
Airs at 6 PM on Saturday 19th April!