Watermelon, right? No, I didn't forget.
Get a tasty one!
I know that! Geez...
Ran-neechan, I'm going to the Doc's—
So basically, you, Kaori Kitasaka-san, are a former member of the Jōnan University Deduction Society,
and another former member of that society is throwing a party to celebrate his wedding at 4 PM today,
Kaori Kitasaka (27)
Company Employee
but you don't know where the party will be.
The reason being that the invitation has a picture puzzle on it, due to it being a party for the Deduction Society.
Is that correct?
Yes. I couldn't solve that picture puzzle,
so when I happened to pass by your agency, I figured the famous Detective Mouri might be able to help.
I understand! You can leave it to me!
The Great Detective Kogorō Mouri will have that puzzle solved before you know it!
Huh, are you sure about that?
So where is this picture puzzle?
Right...
Here.
What's this...?!
I see. This doesn't look easy to solve.
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
Solve the riddle of the unusual party near Bell Tree Tower!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
THE CODED INVITATION
I was never too good at deductions and codes, and even when I joined the Society, the Tanuki Code was all I could solve.
The Tanuki Code?
It's a simple code where you ‘remove the character た (ta)’ to read it.
ta o nuki
But then why did you join the Deduction Society?
Well...
I've got it!
The little finger to the index finger refer to trains!
Trains?
Trains have their line colour on them...
The yellow little finger means the Sōbu Line.
The yellow-green ring finger means the Yamanote Line.
The sky blue middle finger means the Keihin-Tōhoku Line.
And the red index finger means the Chūō Line!
In other words, find the place where the four lines meet,
and the thumbnail shows you where the party is.
I see! I never thought of that!
But is there anywhere like that?
Unfortunately, there isn't.
But if you use your brain...
The numbers written on this invitation tell you to look at a 1/25,000-scale map,
so if you put the little finger meaning
the Sōbu Line onto Akihabara,
the ring finger meaning the Yamanote Line and the middle finger meaning the Keihin-Tōhoku Line
on the tracks between Akihabara and Kanda,
and put the index finger meaning the Chūō Line on the track between Ochanomizu and Kanda...
Then the place that the thumbnail points to is...
Kanda-Ogawamachi!
Kanda-Ogawamachi?
Then...
kawa
...the picture of the river means Ogawa, right?
But you know, the fingers on the invitation are stretched out.
And you've got your fingers curled up, Uncle.
Hey, don't sweat the small stuff!
Oh, come on...
So how about it? Does it ring any bells?
It does.
The Jōnan University Lecture Hall is in the second district of Kanda-Ogawamachi!
Really?!
I knew it!
The party must be being held at that hall!
You're amazing, Dad!
You've gotta be kidding me...
Thank you so much! Now I'll be able to attend the party.
So how much would you...?
Oh, no, no, no.
I can't accept money for such a simple request.
What? But...
You don't owe me a thing.
You're so kind. Well then, if you're sure...
Really, thank you so much!
If you need my help again, feel free to drop in anytime!
I will. Goodbye.
But you know, if we're all working on it, then we should do something really big!
How about making an insect forest filled with all sorts of papier-mâché insects?
Or an aquarium full of fishies swimming around?
An airport could be fun too!
You really can't accept Mouri-kun's deduction?
Right...
Officially, the Chūō Line isn't red, but scarlet...
I've tried considering other lines coloured red, blue, yellow and green too, but I can't find anywhere that fits...
How about underground trains?
I considered that too, but there's no yellow line on the underground...
Bridges?
That's it!
That's what that hand meant!
Oh no! I better tell her quickly!
Sorry, I'll leave the rest up to you!
Conan-kun?
Conan!
It looks like he solved it.
Sure does.
What?! It's not Kanda-Ogawamachi?!
Right. Have a look at this map.
The river in that picture is the Sumida River, and as for the bridges that cross it...
Kuramaebashi Bridge
Kuramaebashi Bridge is yellow...
Umayabashi Bridge
Umayabashi Bridge is a yellowish green...
Komagatabashi Bridge
Komagatabashi Bridge is blue...
Azumabashi Bridge
And Azumabashi Bridge is red.
In other words, those nails meant these four bridges.
That's amazing, Conan-kun!
Uncle, you took a copy of that puzzle, right?
Hmm? Yeah...
If we place the nails on the invitation over each of the bridges, then the thumb is on top of...
The Bell Tree Tower!
Then that's the party venue?
But you know, her university's lecture hall is in Kanda-Ogawamachi...
I'm sure this is the right answer.
I even phoned the Bell Tree Tower and checked.
They said a restaurant was booked for 4 PM today, before its official opening,
to hold a wedding party for the Jōnan University Deduction Society.
Dad, you have to phone Kaori-san and let her know right away!
I know!
The number you have dialled is not in use.
Please check that you have dialled the correct number.
That's weird, the number doesn't work.
Don't call her home phone, call her mobile, Dad!
Kaori-san should still be out.
Oh, right.
Hold on, why did she give you a wrong number for her home phone?
She probably just made a mistake.
But it's her own home phone number. She should know it...
Then she wrote down a wrong number on purpose.
Some people do, you know.
They don't want their families to find out they've been to a etective agency, so they leave false information.
But Kaori-san just wanted to find out where her party was, right?
It's not something that she'd have to hide...
Then I don't know! Geez!
Just stop complaining for once!
Yes?
Oh, hello, is that Kaori-san?
It's Mouri. The truth is...
Is that so.
I was getting worried, since I'm at the lecture hall in Ogawamachi now, and the party wasn't taking place here.
So it's the Bell Tree Tower? Thank you very much.
Oh, it's no problem. Take care of yourself.
That's good, now she should make it to the party on time.
But why did Kaori-san give us her real mobile number, but a fake home number...?
And even if she was just passing by, is finding the location of a party really a reason to visit a detective agency?
Did Kaori-san say anything about her family?
Yes. She said that she's single, and lives with her parents.
Did she do anything odd when
writing down her home number?
No, she didn't! Honestly, give me a break!
Oh, now you mention it, after she wrote down her mobile number...
Should I fill in my home phone number too?
If you don't mind...
Then maybe she only wrote the last digit down wrong...
Hello, this is Kitasaka.
Oh no! I was so focused on checking the phone number that I didn't think of anything to say!
Hello?
U-Uh, my name's Conan Edogawa.
Conan Edogawa-kun?
Huh?! Conan-kun?!
Excuse me, may I...
Oh, sure.
Hello, Conan-kun? This is Satō, from the Police HQ...
Detective Satō?!
What?!
I'm at Kitasaka-san's house along with Takagi-kun.
But Conan-kun, why are you phoning this house?
Why are you at that house, Detective Satō?
Has there been some sort of incident?
Er, well...
I'll pass you over to Uncle Kogorō.
Mouri here. Did something happen at the Kitasaka house?
Mouri-san?
What happened? If you tell me, maybe I can help.
Actually, a gun's gone missing.
What? A gun?!
Yeah. It was an Imperial Japanese Army-issue Type 14 Nambu semi-automatic pistol that disappeared.
It was discovered by the head of the household, Michio Kitasawa-san,
when he was sorting through the belongings of his late father, Nobuyoshi-san, who died last year.
Of course, military guns are supposed to be handed to the police as soon as they're found,
but it seems Michio-san kept it and five bullets as a precious keepsake of his father.
I see...
And then it went missing, right?
Yes.
It doesn't look like anyone broke in to steal it,
and the only one who could've taken it would be his daughter, Kaori-san.
Kaori-san left this morning, apparently to go to the wedding party of a colleague from university,
but as she was leaving, she seemed to be deeply worried about something...
What?!
From what we've heard from her family,
it seems that that colleague was two-timing Kaori-san and the girl he's getting married to,
and eventually dumped Kaori-san in the end.
B-But that means...
Yes...
When he found the gun was missing,
Michio-san tried calling Kaori-san's mobile several times, but she wouldn't answer, so he contacted the police.
We're about to try and investigate where the wedding party will take place.
I know where the party is.
The Bell Tree Tower!
But did Kaori-san really take that gun?
When she came to the agency, Kaori-san had a large clutch bag, right?
Huh? Yeah...
And as she was leaving...
She probably has the gun in that bag.
Also, did you notice that Kaori-san
was wearing low-heeled shoes?
Y-Yeah...
I figured she should wear higher
heels if she was going to a party.
The reason she was wearing those shoes...
Would be to stabilise herself...
So she wouldn't miss her target when she fires the gun.
Then she really did...?
Kaori-san was bad at deductions and codes,
so the reason she joined the Deduction Society
might be because of she was in love with that colleague...
Damn! I won't make it in time!
What can I do?
Conan-kun?
I hope this can get her to give up on her plan!
Thank you, everyone, for coming
here for such a blissful occasion!
Did you figure out where the party was right away?
Well, how could we?
Yonekura's not even here yet!
Right. Now let's save our opinions for later, and bid hello to the bride and groom!
Congrats!
Let's begin with a word from our merry groom.
Maybe Kaori-san isn't here yet?
No. If she came here from Kanda-Ogawamachi, she should already be here!
Kaori-san... Kaori-san!
Dad!
Kaori-san!
Don't do it!
Don't do it, Kaori-san!
How did you propose to her?
Oh dear...
You really want me to say that?
K-Kaori?!
Kaori-san...
Kaori-san!
Congratulations, Nagai-san.
T-Thanks, Kaori...
I'm glad you didn't go through with it.
Little boy...
Uncle Kogorō and the detectives went downstairs.
I think they mistook someone else for you.
It was just when I was about to head into the party...
sonke na otoi koto wa
kekarete yoi katta ne
Hairy caterpillar (kemushi) &
Hairless caterpillar (imomushi)
.
At first, I didn't know what it meant.
But if I ignore the character け (ke) and also the character い (i)...
i mo mushi
ke o mushi
‘It's good that you parted ways with him.’
All my wrought-up emotions vanished
as quickly as the receding tide...
I thought that you'd know what it meant since you could solve the Tanuki Code, Kaori-san.
Huh?! Then this didn't come from Mouri-san, but from...
Conan-kun!
Kaori-san!
Say, Kaori-san...
You said that you happened to pass by the agency,
but you really came to the agency on purpose so you could get Uncle Kogorō to solve your problems, right?
Yes. I used the Great Detective Mouri-san...
I apologise.
Oh no, don't worry.
Kaori Kitasaka-san.
Yes.
I'm Satō, from Division 1 of the Police HQ Criminal Investigation Department.
I'm Takagi, from the same division.
Kitasaka-san, please come to Police HQ with us.
Right.
Little boy, your name's Conan-kun?
Yeah. Conan Edogawa, detective.
Thank you, my little detective.
Ima Aitakute...
(I want to be with you...)
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
In the end, Kaori-san and her father, Michio-san
had their case sent to the prosecutor's office under violation of the Swords and Firearms Control Law,
but they decided not to prosecute, and so the case of the shooting that never happened was put to rest.
Oh yeah, Sonoko-san invited us to visit the Tohto Bell Tree Tower tomorrow.
Are you looking forward to it?
I can't wait!
I hope the weather's good.
I should make a teru-teru bōzu.
Ugh, I'll have to spend another day with this lot.
There's lots of tasty restaurants near the Bell Tree Tower!
Nobody could have ever suspected that another shooting was waiting for us at the Bell Tree Tower...
I'll have eel rice for lunch!
A challenge from the mysterious Phantom Thief K!
Lots of tricks set up over a wide area!
What's behind the shocking calculated trap?!
Detective Conan: ‘The Secret of the Kogorō Mouri Statue’!
Airs Saturday 26th April at 6 PM!
THE SECRET OF THE KOGORŌ MOURI STATUE
Next Conan's Hint: Basketball!
The movie opens today!
The theme song's the best!
The singer's lovely, too.