I spy a Great Detective.
Eisuke Kataoka (54)
Magnate
No-one else could have found the hideout of the great Kaitō K!
So you finally show yourself, Kaitō K!
Yuzuru Sada (57)
Kataoka Family Butler
Master, it is too dangerous to be up there! Please come down!
Quiet, Sada!
I am no 'Master' of yours, I am Kaitō K!
Master!
Uh...
That's the guy who invited us over for dinner, right?
What's this about?
Oh, haven't you been here before?
My dad's the greatest lover of detectives you'll ever meet.
Seiya Kataoka (20)
Kataoka's only son
And Detective Mouri's his favourite by far.
Right. We did see a statue of the old man on the way in...
Super-cool!
Every now and again, he goes and challenges Detective Mouri, pretending to be a phantom thief.
Get down here now, you damn thief!
Sounds like quite the eccentric.
Honestly...
Yurie Kataoka (29)
Kataoka's second wife
Men are fools, through and through.
I'll give you thirty minutes! Just try and catch me!
If you somehow manage to catch me before that big clock strikes six, you will receive a wonderful prize!
I bid you good luck!
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
The vast mansion grounds hold tons of tricks!
What's the shocking reason for targeting Kogorō?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Every time I'm here, I'm impressed by this huge garden.
Yeah, it's like he's got a town in his garden.
Actually, we do call it a 'town' instead of a garden.
Makes it a great place for playing tag, huh?
We've got him! That's a dead end for sure!
Kataoka-san vanished?!
No way!
What's this?
Did you spot something, Conan-kun?
Don't you think this clock is strange?
It's all the way down here, and the hour hand and the minute hand are both pointing at six. Isn't that odd?
I see what you mean.
What if...
Right! This is the entrance to an underground tunnel.
Kaitō K!
Hold it!
Sorry, Dad...
I shall head round to the exit!
We can trap him in from both sides!
Right!
Who cares about that?!
What's this?!
Muddy footsteps, and they're new.
He came this way for sure!
Ran-neechan, over there!
We found him!
Master, please prepare yourself!
Sorry, this was not my intention...
Then hurry up and get off me...
W-Why, I do apologise!
Huh? Doesn't that way lead to the...?
Yes, where we started, the front of the mansion.
He seems to be headed to the back garden!
I would ask you to head around that side of the mansion!
I believe this time we can trap him for sure!
Got it!
Damn! This mansion's too big!
He is headed for you!
Catch him!
Conan-kun, let's go!
Right.
Look out!
Isn't riding a bike against the rules?!
I guess...
This place is like a maze!
How can we tell where he went?
This way!
Ow, ow, ow...
Are you okay?
Yes. We nearly bumped into one another.
I just tripped out of surprise.
What about Kataoka-san?
He probably headed back to the mansion...
Only seven minutes left!
Yurie-san!
Did you hear that shout?!
Yes! What happened?
I only just got here too!
Don't tell me that something happened to the master!
Master!
Ran-neechan! Any luck?
No, this room's empty too!
Damn... Where is he hiding?!
Did something happen?
I heard this really loud yell...
Seiya-san? Where have you been?
Where? I've been in my room, listening to music.
Master!
Sada?
That came from the back garden!
Master, you must hold on! Master!
What is it? Did something happen?
W-Well...
Move!
No good... He's dead!
The deceased was Eisuke Kataoka-san, 54,
magnate and master of this mansion.
His back shows signs of being struck hard.
The most severe wound was on the back of his head, which we believe to be the fatal wound.
He died at 5:55, I think we can say for sure.
Everyone here heard Mr Kataoka scream out and the sound of a ladder falling.
Kataoka-san was in the middle of playing a game with you?
Yeah, we were playing tag.
We were chasing him.
Honestly, playground games at your age...
Well, it's not like that.
This was an accident, wasn't it?
The ladder has Kataoka-san's boot marks on it.
Kataoka-san probably lost his balance when climbing the ladder, and fell.
I expect that's how it happened.
The bruise on the cheek of the corpse probably happened when falling off the ladder too.
It's just what he deserved!
All he thinks about are those games!
That's Mr Kataoka's wife!
It seems he remarried three
years ago, after his first wife died.
Huh? You're not wearing your wedding ring, Yurie-san?
It gets in the way, so I haven't worn it for some time.
But then she wouldn't have that ring mark...
And he's the first wife's child?
Yes. Apparently he resented Kataoka-san, blaming his reckless father for his mother's death...
Well, he died the same way he lived.
Hey, Seiya-san, what happened to your hand?
Oh, I caught it on a guitar string earlier...
Huh? But back then, didn't he say...
Did something happen?
I heard this really loud yell...
Seiya-san? Where have you been?
Where? I've been in my room, listening to music.
I sincerely apologise for putting you through all of this trouble.
But was this really an accident?
Is there something worrying you, Mouri-kun?
Every time Mr Kataoka challenged me, he'd always set up lots of tricks.
But this time, all he did was run away from me...
Aren't you overthinking this?
He was an amateur. He wouldn't always have to have great tricks.
Well, you may be right.
So this really was an accident.
It seems so.
No, the old man's right.
There's too much that doesn't fit for this to be an accident.
First, the corpse hadn't been sweating.
Even though he should've been running until just before he died...
And...
It couldn't be...!
Here?!
Then how about over there!
It should be somewhere around here.
This too, huh?
Don't scream when you see me! I'm not a ghost!
Everyone's been shouting and looking for you!
Then how come back then—
The late Kataoka-san liked that track.
Someone must be playing it from the mansion.
To mourn his death.
Uncle, try and move this statue.
It's made out of bronze, it's not gonna move!
But there's something strange about it, don't you think?
Your mustache is connected into one piece, when it shouldn't be.
Almost like it's an impostor.
Is this it?!
Hey, there's nothing even in there...
That sound...
I get it!
Let me borrow this, okay?
I see, so that's what happened.
Huh?
What're you doing all the way over here, Conan-kun?
Oh, Detective Takagi!
Uncle Kogorō told me to ask you something...
But Mouri-san's just over there...
Don't worry, don't worry!
Uncle! I brought everyone back here, just like you asked!
What's going on here, Mouri-kun?
I finally figured it out.
I've worked out the truth behind this murder disguised as an accident!
But the crime scene has all the signs of an accident!
Why do you think it was murder?
His bruise.
His bruise? You mean the mark on his cheek?
But couldn't he have got that when he fell off the ladder?
That's what I thought at first.
But this statue told me what really happened.
Take a good look.
My nose is chipped, see?
It certainly is.
But how does that...?
The damage is new.
It's as if something struck it with a lot of force recently.
You can't mean...?!
Yes. If you check the shape of the mark, it should match.
The bruise on the corpse's cheek was made when he collided with my nose.
But the corpse was found over there!
Yes.
If Kataoka-san really did fall off the ladder, there's no way he would've collided with this distant statue.
That's right. Kataoka-san didn't fall from the ladder!
First, he was hit and knocked out by his killer over here.
Then they carried him over to where we found him,
and murdered him by hitting his head and his whole body against the stone paving.
Then, his killer left his boot marks on the ladder, and placed the ladder by the corpse,
to make us think Kataoka-san had fallen from the ladder.
But who would do that?!
Before I get to that, there's something I want to check.
Detective Takagi!
Was the corner of Kataoka-san's cape torn?
It wasn't torn at all.
Wouldn't you say that's strange, Ran?
I get it!
What do you mean?
Kataoka-san's cape should have a tear in it!
Look out!
But the cape on the corpse wasn't torn at all.
But how...?
The answer's simple.
It means the man you were chasing wasn't Kataoka-san.
Of course, the Kaitō K we were
originally chasing was Kataoka-san.
But along the way, someone else took over.
Kataoka-san was replaced by his killer.
Isn't that right?
Second Kaitō K and murderer of Kataoka-san...
Makoto Sada-san!
But no, Dad!
Sada-san was with us while we were chasing Kataoka-san, you know?
He didn't have any chance to be replaced...
No, you weren't always with him.
There was one time you parted ways.
When you were headed to the back garden.
I would ask you to head around that side of the mansion!
I believe this time we can trap him for sure!
Got it!
It was probably originally Kataoka-san's plan.
He must've prepared the replacement trick for our game.
But Sada-san decided to use this trick to murder Kataoka-san.
He saw Ran and Conan off, then took a shortcut through the mansion.
He put on a Kaitō K costume and mask that were readied for him,
then hit and knocked out Kataoka-san,
who was waiting to be replaced, from behind,
and hid him in the shade of the statue, then appeared in front of Ran and Conan as Kaitō K!
Then after that, the Kaitō K we were chasing...
...was Sada-san, not Kataoka-san.
I had the kid check earlier, and where Kaitō K's boots should be dirty from running through the tunnel,
the pedals on the bike Kaitō K rode were clean.
Then after finishing his display as Kaitō K, Sada-san removed his disguise, acting none the wiser.
Mouri-san! You're forgetting one important thing!
When I was with Ran-san and Conan-san-san-tachi'}, we all heard the master shouting and the sound of a ladder falling over.
Was that this?
Detective Takagi!
Right.
There's no mistaking that. That's the voice and noise we heard!
It was the sound of the stereo.
Sada-san recorded Kataoka-san's shout and the sound of a falling ladder onto a CD.
Then he used the timer to set it, so it would play at full volume when he needed it to.
But the truth is that Kataoka-san was still alive at the time.
Hidden in the shade of this statue...
But that means that while we were searching the mansion for Kataoka-san...!
Yes. Sada-san murdered Kataoka-san in the back garden, and disguised it as an accident while everyone was searching for him.
Even the reason he was holding Kataoka-san's corpse was to disguise the blood of his victim on his clothes.
Isn't that right?
Sada-san, where you failed is by setting the stereo's volume too high.
It even reached us, far from the mansion, and Seiya-kun, who was listening to music with headphones.
Shouts don't normally travel so far.
But what are you trying to imply?
That is not enough to prove my guilt.
Right.
So let me show you something.
The decisive evidence proving that you were his murderer!
After you had finished your act...
You had to hide your disguise somewhere at the crossroad with a bronze statue of me.
It turns out that the statue was hiding a hollow pedestal.
But it was empty.
Of course.
Yes. Since all you used it for was to hold an object in which you would hide your disguise.
Back then, you hid your disguise in the object you took out of the hollow!
Isn't this ball odd...?
It's a bit too big, and it's making a strange noise as well.
T-This is...!
A shard of marble...
And it's got a trace of blood on it.
The wig has grey hairs in it too.
How do you explain this, Sada-san?
Back then, you took the ball from the hollow pedestal, hid your disguise in it, and threw it out of Ran and Conan's sight.
You probably planned to come back and collect it later.
But there were two things you miscalculated.
The first was that a lost stray cat would move the ball.
And the second was that the marble shard you quickly shoved inside the ball led it to make a strange noise.
No, I'd say that my greatest miscalculation was underestimating your powers of deduction, Mouri-san.
You mean...
Yes. I am responsible for the master's murder.
But...
Why?
I couldn't forgive him.
The master lived such a wild life, as if he'd completely forgotten about his late wife.
I felt sorry for her.
You're wrong about that.
There's only two things he adored — detectives, and his late wife.
He married me to try and overcome his sadness.
But in the end, I just couldn't fill her place.
I only just realised the truth recently...
And that's why you took off your wedding ring?
I just intended it as a silent protest.
But he never even noticed!
Really? Then the master's feelings for her never faded...
So this is the prize that Kataoka-san planned to give you?
I guess he truly was a fool to make me something like this!
I just enjoyed our games together...
Dad...
So...
What do we do with this?
A dog walk hides an exceedingly skillful and puzzling trick.
Can you break the alibi, Detective Boys?!
Detective Conan: 'The Suspicious Walking Path'!
Airs at 6 PM on Saturday 3rd May!
Next Conan's Hint: A dog walk.
Hey, let's get a dog!
Dad's a good enough guard dog already.
Woof!
Good boy, good boy...
Get back in your kennel...