Here!
Nice catch!
That was great, Shimpei-san!
Shimpei Asakawa (21)
Okay, you're up next, Conan-kun.
Here it comes! Here!
H-Hey, come on, stop that...
M-Matsunosuke?!
Matsunosuke?!
That's enough, Matsunosuke...
Morning, Grandma.
Grandma?
Kanae Asakawa (65)
Matsunosuke's Owner
Shimpei! You're still playing games this early in the morning instead of getting a job?
No, I wasn't playing anything...
He wasn't playing!
He teaches us how to throw frisbees here every week!
He's very kind!
What's the difference? You should act your age.
Thanks to you, now even Matsunosuke wants to catch any frisbee he sees.
Is that dog called Matsunosuke? He's so cute!
Oh my, you're covered in dirt...
I'll get this cleaned...
...and give it back to you.
Oh, it's fine. Don't worry about it.
No, I have to make it up to you.
I wouldn't want your parents to come complaining to me later.
Grandma, you're about to have breakfast, right? Make some for me too.
Only once you find yourself a job and pay me back the money I lent you.
R-Right...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
Walking a dog along the same path every day...
The smallest difference is the start of a case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Are you there, ma'am?
We're here to get Conan's jacket!
She's probably not home.
Maybe she's walking her dog?
Right. Let's come back later.
But Matsunosuke's sleeping over there.
You're right.
He's sleeping so soundly.
He's not moving at all.
Oh, is Matsunosuke asleep?
I was going to give him some treats...
Oh, who are you, ma'am?
Tomoko Hirota (52)
Friend of Kanae and Fellow Dog Owner
A friend of Kanae-san's and fellow dog owner. I own Matsunosuke's brother.
Oh? Matsunosuke has a brother? Do they look alike?
Of course! They're identical.
H-Hey, don't tell me...
Conan-kun?
It's open?!
K-Kanae-san!
What's all the racket about?!
I can't concentrate when everyone's so noisy...
Like we said, we came here to get Conan's jacket, and Matsunosuke was asleep!
We called him but he wouldn't get up!
What? M-Matsunosuke?
He's a dog! He's asleep outside in his kennel.
Right. Forensics think that he was drugged to fall asleep.
Drugged?!
Hmm... You're her friend and fellow dog owner, Hirota-san, correct?
Yes.
I came here to share my dog treats with Matsunosuke.
But then...
And you're her neighbor, Kitazawa-san.
Sōkichi Kitazawa (52)
Kanae's Neighbor
Yes. I heard her doorbell being rung again and again, so I came over to check and saw this.
Did you already know each other before this case?
We did.
Hirota-san, you owed Kanae-san a lot of money, didn't you?
She was always complaining, saying you never paid her back.
You may not look like a killer, but it was you, wasn't it?
Oh, I've heard you were always complaining about her too!
You told everyone her dog's loud barking was annoying.
What?! Are you saying I killed her?! Don't give me that!
I could say the same thing!
Now, now, calm down...
Inspector Megure, various people at the shopping district and park report
seeing Asakawa-san walking her dog today between 8:00 and 8:15 this morning.
Right... Do you know Asakawa-san's dog-walking route?
After leaving her house, she goes to the shopping district then heads to the park, I believe.
Then she walks along the highway to get back home.
Yes, she said she likes to take walks an hour long.
Which means...
She left home just before 8 AM, and it would've been around 9 when she got back home after the walk.
She must've been murdered after that.
What were you both doing at that time?
I was playing shōgi at my house with a friend.
I was at my house too.
I had a florist deliver some flowers, and then asked her to help arrange my garden.
My jacket's back from the cleaners.
A beige spring coat...
Is that the coat she was wearing when she died?
A side dish pack... Is that from her breakfast?
Huh?! But didn't Shimpei-san say...
Inspector! Come over here!
What is it?
Look at this.
That's a bandanna...
Is that stain blood?!
Hey, isn't that...?
Yes...
Shimpei-san's bandana!
Shimpei-san?
Kanae-san's grandson.
Inspector Megure!
This woman says she saw a man fleeing this house...
What?!
I'm sorry, but could you repeat what you told me?
Sure.
I think it was after 9...
I saw a young man leave this house.
His face was white as he ran away...
I think he was Kanae-san's grandson...
Do you know where he lives?
I've heard that he lives alone in a nearby flat.
All right, let's bring him in for questioning right away.
R-Right!
No way!
Shimpei-san would never murder anyone!
It's some sort of mistake!
It's awful! I can't believe Shimpei-san would kill her...
He was so passionate about teaching us how to catch frisbees...
It can't be! No way they're right!
Oh, Genta-kun...!
What're you doing, at a time like this...
I-It wasn't me...
Shimpei-san?!
Huh?! Conan-kun...
Hey! The police are looking for you.
About grandma, right?
Yeah. They say you killed her.
No! I didn't do it!
But you were running from the scene, right?
T-That was because grandma e-mailed me and asked me to come over,
but when I got there, she was already...
I panicked and ran into someone as I was leaving.
Didn't know what to do after that.
Shimpei-san, you said your grandmother has breakfast after walking Matsunosuke, right?
Huh? Y-Yeah...
She says it's best to eat after having exercise...
There he is!
No! It wasn't me!
They caught Shimpei-san...
Hey, Conan-kun!
Why didn't you do anything?!
Don't blame me.
Shimpei-san's bandana was at the scene, and someone even saw him there.
No way!
Don't tell me you think Shimpei-san's guilty too, Conan-kun?
I thought better of you!
"But..."
You've got more to say, right, Edogawa-kun?
Well, yeah.
First, the bandana at the scene wasn't exactly anything special, so anyone could get one if they wanted to.
I see.
So maybe the real killer put it there to frame Shimpei-san.
But that won't be enough...
There was a plastic bag with a tag from the cleaners in the bin at the scene.
The tag was for a women's beige spring coat.
A beige spring coat...?
That's the coat she was wearing when she died!
Right...
And under that plastic bag was the pack from a breakfast side dish.
A breakfast pack under the plastic bag...
That means she threw away the breakfast pack first.
So she ate breakfast before walking Matsunosuke.
It's the wrong way round!
Right!
Shimpei-san said that she always had breakfast after walking Matsunosuke,
but the scene shows it the other way round...
In other words, the murder scene might've been manipulated!
But what if Shimpei-san's lying?
I doubt that.
We heard about her breakfast habits last week, right?
Grandma, you're about to have breakfast, right? Make some for me too.
If that was a lie too, then he must've had quite a plan.
And if he did, he wouldn't have left his blood-soaked bandana behind, right?
You might be right.
Then who could've done it?
The only suspects we have right now are her friend with the dog, Hirota-san, and her neighbor, Kitazawa-san.
But they both have alibis.
Then we've gotta break those alibis!
I get it! Then Shimpei-san might be able to come back!
This is a job for the Detective Boys!
Yeah!
I'll start with Kitazawa-san's house.
Then we'll go ask around the shopping district.
No do-overs, you know?
Quiet! I know that!
Here it comes, Conan! Here!
Excuse me!
Our frisbee went over your fence, can we come over and get it?
Oh dear...
Sorry!
I've got it. Come round to the front door.
Sorry about the frisbee, mister.
Oh, shōgi!
Huh, that's a good match.
How long have you been playing?
Since this morning.
Wow, that's amazing!
I've had 99 wins and 99 losses against him over the past 10 years. Today's is truly a decisive match.
I've been giving all I've got since 6 AM without a moment's rest.
But you're losing...
Quiet! You're disturbing our match!
S-Sorry!
Right, it was 8:30.
That's the time Hirota-san asked me to deliver the flowers.
Did you arrange her garden too?
Yes.
She has lots of flowers, so I was there until well after lunch.
Is that right...?
In the end, we couldn't break their alibis...
What do we do now, Conan?
Shimpei-san's gonna take the blame.
Maybe we got one of the initial conditions wrong.
Huh? Initial conditions?
We thought that she was murdered after coming back from walking Matsunosuke, but what if...
What do you mean?
She usually walks exactly the same route at almost exactly the same time every day.
So what if maybe...
I get it! Maybe the people who saw her just thought they saw must've seen her today!
Oh, a woman with a dog wearing a beige coat, right?
I saw her this morning too.
Was it really today you saw her?
Yeah. It must've been after 8...
I always pass her while walking this guy.
Her dog always marks the area over there,
but she must've been in a rush today since she pulled it away and rushed off...
Oh, you mean the woman who walks her dog every morning?
I saw her. And today sure was a sight to see.
A sight to see?
Her dog always fights with a cat in front of my shop.
And today it was even worse than usual...
She'd been trying to avoid the cat lately, but she must've forgotten today.
It takes 15 minutes to get here from her house.
Everyone says she passed by today...
That means they weren't just mistaken, doesn't it?
Ma'am!
My, what is it?
Did you see a woman walking a dog around here this morning?
Why, a police officer asked me the same thing.
I saw her, I'm sure of it.
Was she pulling her dog along when it didn't want to go?
Pulling it along?
Yes, it did seem like she was.
She always goes left after leaving the park.
But today, she pulled her dog along as she turned right.
She pulled it to the right?!
H-Hey, Conan-kun!
Her walking route's the other way!
We won't find any witnesses this way!
T-That's...!
Oh, it's you kids.
Are you still looking for witnesses?
Oh! It's the guy from earlier!
You didn't have your dog, so I didn't recognize you.
I see! So that's what happened!
Everybody was wrong!
The witnesses...
And the killer!
Then there's one place the killer will have to go...
To remove an important piece of evidence...!
Good evening.
Why're you here so late?
You kids...
Miss, we figured out who really killed Kanae-san.
They murdered Kanae-san before 8 AM this morning, after she'd finished preparing her breakfast.
Then, they cleaned away the breakfast she prepared
and dressed her in the coat that had just come back from the cleaners
to make it look like she'd been killed after walking her dog.
After that, they left Shimpei-san's bandana, which they'd prepared earlier, by the front door,
and went out for a walk with
Matsunosuke disguised as Kanae-san.
To create eyewitness reports that Kanae-san walked Matsunosuke today, and establish their alibi.
It was a simple disguise, so they might've been found out if someone paid attention,
but they fooled everyone by having Matsunosuke with them.
He marked the spots he always does, he fought with a cat where he always does...
So everyone thought "Oh, it's the lady who always walks Matsunosuke".
But the killer turned right after leaving the park.
Though she always turns left.
They had to. If they'd walked the whole route, they wouldn't be able to make an alibi.
After leaving the park, they went back to their own house with Matsunosuke,
then met with someone they'd called out to complete their alibi.
Hold on.
What about the dog? What about Matsunosuke?
Matsunosuke was sleeping here back then, wasn't he?
The killer couldn't have walked him...
That's a fake.
The dog we found drugged and sleeping was a fake Matsunosuke prepared by the killer.
Which means the killer has a dog
who looks just like Matsunosuke!
Miss, you said you owned Matsunosuke's brother, right?
A brother that looks just like him!
In other words, it has to be you...
Tomoko Hirota-san!
Conan-kun.
D-Detectives!
Please, help me! These children
keep saying such strange things...
Wasn't it Mouri-kun that told us to come out here...?
Yeah!
But something came up that Uncle Kogoro couldn't get out of, so he told us to come and tell you instead.
I see.
Then you have proof, right?
T-That's right! Proof! Show me some proof!
The proof is right by your side.
The dog you swapped...
The real Matsunosuke!
What do you have to say, Hirota-san?
N-No, they're wrong! This is my dog.
Matsunosuke is tied up over there...
Hey, Matsunosuke! Here it comes!
All right!
Say, ma'am...
You're thinking it's the dog's fault you were found out, right?
Of course it is! If only that dumb dog hadn't tried to catch that frisbee!
You're wrong.
After murdering Kanae-san, you cleaned up her breakfast and dressed her in her coat
to make it seem like she was murdered after walking her dog, but you made a big mistake in doing that.
Kanae-san always has breakfast after walking her dog.
If she'd been killed straight after coming back, she wouldn't have cleaned up after breakfast,
and if she'd been killed after breakfast, it'd be strange for her to still be wearing her dog-walking coat.
In other words, everything was out of place at the murder scene you made.
But I'm glad we found the real killer in the end.
Now Shimpei-san can keep teaching us how to catch frisbees.
That's right. I can't wait!
And you even got your jacket back all clean.
Yeah!
Not a single trace of Matsunosuke's pawprints lef—
Oh! Sorry, Conan-kun...
I'll get it cleaned again for you...
No, don't worry about it...
Next Conan's Hint: Champagne!
shampan
What's champagne?
pan
sham
It goes "shake-shake-pop!" at celebrations.
It's wasted on the old man...