My name's Kogorō Mouri... a detective.
Right... My job is to find people's faults.
Most all detectives have their own secret watering hole, for when they need to heal their work-weary hearts.
Awesome!
This bar filled with youngsters loudly playing billiards and darts...
is unfortunately not my preferred watering hole.
But my client happens to be the bartender here, so I must be here as well.
Here you go, detective. Why don't you give this a try?
Yuzuki Fukui (26)
Bartender
Her name is Yuzuki Fukui, 26. She's the bartender here.
And she's probably fallen in love with me.
Giving me this faint green gimlet on the house is proof of her feelings...
She must see that famous detective, Philip Marlowe in me.
This is just green tea!
I'm sorry! I thought you wouldn't be able to work if you were drunk...
Oh...
No, wait... Let's start this over again.
My name's Kogorō Mouri... a detective.
My client is the bartender of this billiard bar.
Here, my heart is soothed by lending my ear to this bar's off-beat jazz rhythms...
Hey, Uncle!
and this brat's voice...
Why are you here?!
Because Ran-neechan told me to hurry up and get you, dinner's getting cold!
Like I told her, I'm here for a job!
Which she said was probably just your excuse to have a drink.
You called me here to solve a difficult case, right?
Y-Yeah...
See?
What sort of case?
I've been hearing a strange sound while working.
A ‘pop', like a cork being pulled from a champagne bottle...
A sound like a cork being pulled from a champagne bottle...?
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
A case turns up over drinks at the Blue Parrot billiard bar!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
There you go, that sound.
Maybe it really was someone pulling a cork from a champagne bottle...?
But I heard it when nobody had a champagne bottle...
Maybe a patron secretly brought in a bottle?
And wine bottles have corks too...
I thought the same thing, so I made sure to pay attention to all the patrons,
but none of them were drinking champagne or wine...
And after I heard the pop, I also thought I heard something falling,
so I looked around when cleaning up after the bar had closed, but couldn't find any corks lying around...
But there was an odd scent...
An odd scent?
Don't tell me you could smell gunpowder, like something had exploded?!
No, nothing like that... I could smell yuzu.
It was very faint,
but my name even has ‘yuzu' in it, so it's a smell I've always been quick to recognise...
YUZU
KI
We don't use yuzu at this bar, so I thought it strange and decided to contact you, Mouri-san.
Maybe a patron had spilt a cocktail with a similar citrus fruit?
You know, gimlets use lime juice,
and there's cocktails like screwdrivers and white ladies too.
I was sure it was yuzu, though...
Have you heard that sound more than once?
Yes. Two or three times, all on separate days.
Were there any patrons that were always here when you heard it?
There were.
The four at the table behind you right now were always here at the time.
Okay, I'm going to take it!
Ready, say cheese!
Mompei Kogure (28)
Employee
Boss, this roll of film's full up.
Don't worry, it's fine. I've got two or three spare rolls somewhere here.
Chikafumi Usuda (51)
Department Head
And we've got plenty of extras now too.
Right?
Oh, right.
Here, Kogure-kun.
Right.
Kensaku Hatsumura (31)
Employee
But boss, don't you think analogue cameras are too much work these days?
I hate all that digital stuff!
You know... You remember that guy in our department?
That useless geek who always boasted that he was good with digital stuff.
You mean Yoshikuwa-kun?
Yeah, Yoshikuwa, Yoshikuwa... People like that get lost in their digital world and lose their grip on reality.
They become shut-ins and end up hanging themselves!
Speaking of which, weren't you close to him, Kishiura-kun?
Mika Kishiura (30)
Employee
If you're feeling lonely because you don't have a boyfriend, I could do something about that.
Oh, no, I'll be fine.
Come on, give it a try! We'd be perfect for—
Oh right, boss...
What is it, Hatsumura?!
I bought that billiard cue you asked for!
It's a top of the range cue with an ebony base, I found somewhere selling it at a discount.
Oh, I see. Thanks, Hatsumura-kun.
It's the best gift I could hope for.
G-G-Gift?!
This is my birthday present, right?
R-Right...
I got that personal darts set you wanted too.
You usually see soft darts with plastic tips everywhere, so these fully metal darts were pretty hard to find...
That so, huh?
You guys aren't so useless after all!
O-Obviously, they're a present for you too...
Kogure! You know why I wanted steel-tipped darts?
N-No.
Well...
Plastic ones just don't scare people like this!
Oh... Looks like a billiard table opened up.
I feel like trying out this new cue you gave me!
Anyway, hurry off home and tell Ran this:
‘Uncle Kogorō's working on a difficult case, so he won't be back for a while.'
So there we go, Yuzuki-chan! Gimme a gimlet!
But will you really be able to work if you're drinking?
I'll be fine, fine!
Don't blame me when this blows up in your face.
Hey, Uncle! Come home!
Ran-neechan's getting really mad!
Hmph, be quiet. You shouldn't have come back!
I told you, I'm working!
Looks more like you're just drinking...
Yuzuki-chan, one more gimlet please!
Come on, you should be thinking about the case!
I want to put the solution on my blog when you figure it out.
Don't worry. I've just about solved it already.
You mean it?
Seriously?
The culprit probably spilt some ponzu.
Made with yuzu.
Ponzu made with yuzu?
Hey...
Which means...
Which means...?
Which means there's ‘yuzu' and ‘pon'.
pon
Yuzu and a ‘pop'! Get it?
It's got the pop and all, see!
He's utterly hopeless.
In the end, the boss passed out.
Yeah. He just keeps drinking, even though he can't hold his liquor.
Still, it really stings...
That billiard cue cost me 100,000 yen...
The darts I bought cost 60,000 yen together with the case...
You got off lightly, Kishiura. You just had to get five or six rolls of film, right?
I told you, he made me buy that poster of an idol on an online auction for a birthday present!
Oh yeah, you gave it to him back at the office...
It's signed, so it cost me 30,000 yen...
Mind if I take a look?
Just don't damage it. I'll be taking the blame if you do...
I know!
Huh, it's Yōko Okino...
Then should we have one last round of drinks before we go?
Sounds good.
You were diluting and mixing up the whisky, and didn't end up drinking that much, right?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
I feel like this ice pick's hardly left my hands...
Then how about another bottle of champagne, finish like we started?
Good idea.
That was very nice. What do you think?
Fine with me.
Excuse me! A bottle of champagne, please!
Coming up!
Oh, and three glasses too.
Huh?! Isn't that Kogorō Mouri sitting at the counter there?!
No way! The great detective?
I feel like I'm being watched...
We should get a photo!
Isn't it just someone who looks like him?
Right. He wouldn't be such a drunkard.
I'm really no good at getting these things out...
Hey! Don't point it at me!
Kogure-kun, can you help?
Kogure's the best one to ask when you need some strength.
Right, leave it to me.
What's wrong with this? It's really tight...
Hey! Don't have it fly off at me!
I know!
It's spilling out!
You idiot! It's getting on the poster!
I'm sure that's the sound I heard...
But that was just champagne too, right?
The side of the poster's wet!
T-This is bad!
Excuse me! Three hand towels please!
Sure!
How about the sound of opening those hand towel packets?
Could that have been the sound you heard?
I think the sound of the cork from before was closer...
Hey! The boss got soaked too!
Oh no!
What's that?
There's a round, red mark on his neck...
You're right.
Wait... T-The boss isn't breathing!
N-No way...
Boss! Boss!
Boss!
Are you okay?!
Hey, what's happened?!
Our boss won't wake up, it's like he's dead!
What?!
No, he doesn't just look dead...
He really is dead.
My name's Kogorō Mouri... a detective.
I came to this billiard bar at the request of Yuzuki Fukui-chan, the bartender here who's fallen for me...
But it seems that murders love me even more than she does.
I can't be sure without a proper autopsy, but I believe the cause of death was suffocation by a neurotoxin.
P-Poison?!
Yes. From the wound at the back of his neck,
it seems he was stabbed with something sharp like an awl, that had been coated with poison.
But wouldn't you usually yell out and make a scene if you were stabbed by that?
I believe he died in his sleep.
The victim was dead drunk at the time.
Wait, you again?!
Right you are, Inspector!
Don't tell me you just happened to be at yet another murder scene?
Well, yeah... I just happened to be here.
Yes... A detective has a duty of confidentiality.
No matter what happens, he must never tell others about his clients.
To ensure suspicion never falls on Yuzuki-chan, he must never mention that she hired him.
His pride as a detective depends on it...!
I called him here!
There was a mystery I wanted him to solve.
A mystery?
I've been hearing a ‘pop' sound while working here. It's the sound of a cork being pulled from a champagne bottle.
Of course, there aren't any patrons with champagne when it happens, and I didn't find a cork while cleaning up after closing.
But I could smell the scent of yuzu...
By the way, just how much is she paying you for this...?
She said she'd clear off my tab...
Of course, you'll still have to pay for the gimlets you drank tonight.
What? R-Really?
So?
Those three were drinking with the victim, correct?
Yes.
I questioned each of them before you arrived.
From the right, they are...
Mika Kishiura-san, 30.
Kensaku Hatsumura-san, 31.
And Mompei Kogura-san, 28.
They all worked at the same company as the murdered Usuda-san, their boss,
and were apparently here tonight to celebrate his birthday.
So one of these three resented and poisoned their supervisor...
J-Just hold on a minute!
We just came here to celebrate his birthday...
We didn't poison him!
You all planned this together, didn't you?
You were glancing round at me and talking amongst yourselves.
We were talking about how you looked just like the famous Sleeping Kogorō.
Who would've thought you were the real thing...
And we don't even have any reason to kill him!
But, you know, after your boss passed out, you got talking, right?
You all said he forced you to get really expensive birthday presents and you were fed up with him!
Y-You heard all that, little boy?
Yeah! I've got good hearing.
I also heard him making fun of a guy named Yoshikuwa, who committed suicide, and that you and Yoshikuwa were lovers.
Is that true?
Well, he's right...
But if you're bringing that up, Hatsumura-san was his senior at university too,
and he joined the company together with Kogure-kun.
If we hated him enough to kill him, we wouldn't have played billiards and darts with him in the first place, would we?
You played games with the victim?
Yeah. We each took turns playing him until he passed out...
Hey, did their boss really play games with those three?
Oh, right, you went home several times, so you didn't see what happened.
Their boss was making a lot of trouble.
The dartboard here is designed for soft darts,
but he tried to use the steel-tipped darts he was given,
and ended up arguing with the other patrons...
Those three had to step in, and managed to cool him off.
It seemed like they told him to wait at the table until he sobered up.
Then what happened after that?
The three of them played billiards and darts amongst themselves for a while, winner-stays-on.
Then while two of them were playing, the other one of the three was all alone with their drunken boss, right?
In other words, all three of you were alone with your boss at some point...
Anyway, we'll need to perform body searches and check your belongings.
A billiard cue...?
It does look expensive...
Yeah. It was supposed to be 160,000 yen.
I got it because it was reduced to 100,000 yen.
O-Of course, just like that kid overheard, I was annoyed since I never intended for something so expensive to be a present...
But do you really think I'd kill him, just for that?
But... If you stuck a poisoned needle to the tip of the cue with some tape, then you'd even be able to stab him from a distance.
If I'd done something that weird, someone would've seen it!
And I didn't, did I?
No.
After their boss passed out, he put it straight in its case.
I see, so these are the dart tips that caused the argument...
I didn't buy them to cause an argument!
The boss told me to buy him steel-tipped darts.
My late grandfather left me an antique dartboard, so I gave it to our boss, and he told me to go buy darts to go with it.
I don't even play darts...
That's right, you got quite the fright when your boss feigned throwing a dart at you, didn't you?
Yeah, that was really scary...
Couldn't you have stuck poison on the end of one of the darts, and thrown it at him to stab him?
I just told you, I'm no good with darts!
And even if I wanted to, it'd be simpler and easier to just have stabbed him with them from up close...
Well, I guess.
If you suspect me, then just check out the tips of those darts, and you'll see!
Of course, we intend to.
You got him some rolls of film and a poster of an idol?
It does seem you got off easy compared to the other two.
Hold on! That poster's signed, it cost me 30,000 yen!
My desk's next to his desk, so I had to listen to him always telling me how much he wanted it and I had to buy it for him...
I can smell something from the wet part of the poster...
Is that... yuzu?!
W-What's this?!
So the old man realised it too!
It's a poster of Yōko-chan!
And it's the elusive western bikini shot!
Is that what he noticed...?
And you got it wet!
bijo
bijo-bijo
The pretty lady's pretty soaked because of you!
And he's making bad jokes too...!
The champagne spilt out when Kogure-kun pulled out the cork.
You seem to have taken quite a lot of photos too...
Did your boss like photos?
Yeah. They were for his blog.
Even so, we're the ones who have to choose and upload them...
The boss was hopeless with anything digital.
Yet he wanted to seem cool by having a blog...
Well, I guess at least after everything that's happened, we won't have to pick out photos to use too...
Oh! That's hardly a reason why we'd want to kill him, is it?
By the way, who was in charge of mixing up and diluting the whisky?
It was me, but why...?
Then we'll have to check this out too.
The ice pick is sharp and pointed too, just like the tips of the darts. It's very close to the shape of the murder weapon.
My name's Kogorō Mouri... a detective.
It seems my essence as a detective has brought disaster through the doors of this billiard bar, a place of refreshment...
Well, well...
I guess I'm going to have another sleepless night over a case...
fui ni furidasu haru no owaritsugeru ame
isogu machikado de kimi o mitsuketan da
ame ga suki na no hitotsu kasa ni kakurete
daremo ki ni sezu zutto yorisoeru kara...
amefuru machi de kimi to deatte
amefuru machi de kimi o ushinatta
aitakute aenakute afuredasu namida no ame
kaeritai modorenai tōi hi no omoide
nureru mama tachitsukusu machikado de kono kokoro wa
mada kimi no koto sagashite'ru
A baffling case at the Blue Parrot!
Kogorō takes to the bar like a fish to water?
Time for the old man's sleeping deduction show!
Detective Conan: ‘Kogorō in the Bar (Part II)'!
Airs on Saturday 17th May at 6 PM!
Next Conan's Hint: Clay!
Clay'll get you barred from the bar!
Mouri-kun, are you drunk?
You can just stay in the bar forever...