My name's Kogorō Mouri... a detective.
Just like you can always find fish in the sea,
I always seem to find myself at a murder scene.
The start of this mess was when I arrived at a billiard bar
at the request of Yuzuki Fukui-chan, a bartender who had fallen for me...
She had a peculiar mystery for me...
While working, she'd hear what sounded like a cork being pulled from a champagne bottle,
followed by smelling the scent of yuzu.
Yuzuki Fukui (26)
Bartender
I was pondering the solution to this riddle, when suddenly...
One of the four people sitting behind me was murdered.
Chikafumi Usuda (51)
Department Head
The victim was Chikafumi Usuda, 51.
A department head at some company.
He was killed by poison.
His killer had coated a neurotoxin onto the sharp end of something like an awl,
and stabbed it into the back of his neck.
There were three suspects, who had been celebrating the victim's birthday at this bar.
Kensaku Hatsumura, 31, who was forced to buy him a billiards cue as a birthday present.
Kensaku Hatsumura (31)
Employee
Mompei Kogure, 28, who was forced to buy him a darts set.
Mompei Kogure (28)
Employee
And Mika Kishiura, 30, who was forced to buy him a rare poster of Yōko Okino and several rolls of film.
Mika Kishiura (30)
Employee
The most suspicious of them were Kogure, who had brought the darts,
and Kishiura, who had been crushing the ice for their drinks with an ice pick...
Well then...
I guess tonight I'll be staying up to solve yet another case...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
A deduction show at the Blue Parrot...
Unveil the trick behind the hidden weapon!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
What?!
No trace of any poison?!
There wasn't anything on the darts or the ice pick?!
Right.
Forensics say there wasn't even any blood on them, let alone any poison.
You checked those three people too, right?
Yeah.
None of them had any weapon or anything containing poison.
I see.
Honestly... This is just like that pickpocket case before, we couldn't find the murder weapon there either...
Oh, speaking of that pickpocket case, did you tell Jodie-san about that peculiarity, Inspector?
No... She's an outsider. She has no reason to know.
Well, sure, but still...
Hey, Detective Takagi...
What peculiarity?
Oh, the truth is that—
Takagi-kun!
Oh, right!
Let's give the bar another search.
Yes, sir!
I wonder what that peculiarity Detective Takagi mentioned is...
The only peculiar thing in that case was that pregnant lady...
What's that?
Hey, Yuzuki-san...
What is it, Conan-kun?
What's that thing hanging from the ceiling?
Oh, it's a piece of tinsel.
A piece of tinsel?
Yeah. I stuck it to the ceiling with drawing pins, but that bit ripped off when I tried to pull it down.
It was for a private party here last week.
The ceiling's shaded here and it doesn't stand out, so I thought I'd leave it there for the moment,
but I guess it is obvious then?
Yeah! I'm always looking up when talking to adults.
I see.
Just make sure you don't keep looking up all the time and forget to look down, little detective!
Take a look!
Mouri-san's got gum stuck to the bottom of his shoe, see?
I wonder where he stepped on it, since it wasn't there when he was kneeling by the corpse earlier.
How's it going? Have you found anything?
No, nothing...
Don't move!
Uncle, you stepped on a piece of evidence!
What?!
Takagi-kun, take it!
Yes, sir!
This looks like clay, not gum...
There's something imprinted into it...
Four letters written backwards, EPDH,
and there's a bump sticking out above them...
If it's got EPDH imprinted into it backwards, then it was originally HDPE —
high-density polyethylene...
Plastic?
And if there's a bump above it, there must've been a depression where the clay was stuck...
Which means it was probably stuck to the bottom of that...
But why would someone stick clay to the bottom of that...?
Usually I'd be long gone and be humming to myself in the bath around now.
The bath?
I get it! So that's it!
The murder weapon didn't vanish.
The killer used that to make the weapon lift off...
out of sight of the adults!
I've figured it out, Inspector!
I know who murdered Chikafumi Usuda-san.
Is that true, Mouri-kun?
Yes.
He was murdered by the patrons he argued with.
It seems they've already left, but if they took the poisoned needle away with them after murdering him,
that explains why we can't find the murder weapon.
...is what you might think, but is not actually the case.
Just what are you trying to say?
Oh, no, that was just...
There he is! My inner self!
Most all detectives have an inner self that objectively reviews their own deductions,
but my inner self always tends to butt in at the worst possible moment...
Even the inspector hears what he says, so I must be speaking what he thinks out loud,
but I never even realise I've said anything...
It's like some enigmatic presence takes over my body.
No, the bigger problem is the faint pain that always runs through my neck straight afterward...
Yes, just like that!
And then the unstoppable drowsiness that suddenly races through me...!
It's probably the price I pay for my brain cells working at full power...
H-Hey, Mouri-kun?!
Is this it? Your usual thing?!
But lately, I've come to like this drowsiness... Because after all...
Mouri-san.
Mouri-san!
Mouri-san, are you awake?
Everyone else already left!
What about the case?
What do you mean?
You just finished your Sleeping Kogorō Deduction Show!
Right... When I come back to myself, the case is always solved.
I guess I must use my entire mental prowess to ascertain the truth and reveal it to everyone,
though can never remember doing so...
Then the patrons he argued with really did kill him...
Huh?!
You just told me that there's no way that they'd just happen to have a poisoned needle, didn't you?!
But then that must mean... One of those three working at the same company... must have killed him...
Huh? Yeah...
But that can't be right!
Sure, they had things that looked like the murder weapon, but there wasn't a trace of poison or blood on them!
Are you feeling all right?
...uh, so you realised that couldn't be right too, right?
Oh!
You were testing me to see if I understood your deduction, right, Mouri-san?
R-Right, yeah...
I understood it perfectly, you had me thinking 'Oh, I see!'!
I'd never have thought that the killer hid the murder weapon like that!
'Like that'?
The experiment that you had Conan-kun help conduct was great too!
First, take the film case that you had Detective Takagi buy and fill a third of it with some water,
then break off and add a sugar cube-sized piece of one of the bubble bath bars you also had him buy...
After that, just shut the lid and flip it over so the lid's at the bottom and wait,
then about two and a half to three minutes later...
...and that's how it happened.
Also known as a film case rocket.
The water and the bubble bath react upon contact and create carbon dioxide,
and the gas filling the case forces open the lid, making it take off like a rocket.
There's the scent of yuzu!
Right.
The killer must've used a yuzu-scented bubble bath bar.
Then those 'pop's I heard two or three times before...
The killer tested it here several times first.
They needed to know whether a film case with the weapon attached to it would embed itself into the ceiling.
W-With the weapon attached?!
But it was something like an ice pick!
There's no way it'd be strong enough to lift something that heavy...
The tips of steel-tipped darts are removable, and weigh roughly 18 grams. Easily light enough to lift.
Also, the killer stuck clay to the bottom of the film case to attach the dart tip,
and stuck the rolled-up poster over it to hide it and guide its flight.
With this setup, it would reach the ceiling even if it launched slightly off-centre.
Did I get anything wrong?
I'm asking you who bought a personal darts set as a birthday present for the culprit...
Mompei Kogure-san!
You would've been able to coat a dart tip in poison and place it in the case beforehand,
and only you could've pulled off the film case rocket trick, since you were sitting next to the poster.
After the victim passed out,
Kogure-san probably intentionally lost
while playing billiards or darts with his colleagues,
and then alone with the victim, he went round and helped cover him with his coat or so,
while really stabbing the tip of the poisoned dart into his neck.
Then, he pulled off and swapped the dart tip for a spare tip he had ready,
attaching the poisoned dart tip to a film case with clay.
He hid the film case rocket between his legs or so,
so all he had to do was distract his colleagues to put it on the table.
Right... Mentioning how another bar patron resembled a celebrity would do the trick.
Of course, after he'd ordered a bottle of champagne...
Now that you mention it, back then...
Then how about another bottle of champagne, finish like we started?
Good idea. That was very nice. What do you think?
Fine with me.
Excuse me! A bottle of champagne, please!
Coming up!
Oh, and three glasses too.
Huh? Isn't that Kogorō Mouri sitting at the counter there?!
No way! The great detective?
I feel like I'm being watched...
We should get a photo!
Isn't it just someone who looks like him?
Right. He wouldn't be such a drunkard.
Then as the final touch, he pulled out the cork of the champagne in time with the rocket's launch...
What's wrong with this?
It's really tight...
Hey! Don't have it fly off at me!
I know!
By aiming the champagne that came foaming out at the poster,
he got the chance to wipe the bubble bath off the table.
As proof of that, the wet side of the poster should smell of yuzu.
It certainly does.
But Kishiura-san's the one who bought this poster.
The victim had been doggedly urging her to get it back at their office.
He probably intended to get another poster if she hadn't bought that one.
He'd be able to guess the victim would ask him to get darts if he gave him a dartboard, too.
And if he knew the victim would want lots of photos for his birthday blog entry,
he'd be able to predict that she would be made to buy some rolls of film.
Though in the end, from up in the ceiling,
the weapon tells us all we need to know...
Only Kogure-san, who bought the darts, could have prepared an identical spare dart tip.
But if all that's stuck there is the dart tip,
then the film case that propelled it up there must've fallen off.
Of course. But at the time, everyone was panicking over champagne being spilt on the victim's dear poster.
Even if it fell on the floor, everyone would think it was just knocked off while wiping the table.
Incidentally, I ended up stepping on the clay, which had fell off the case when it hit the floor.
The reason that clay had HDPE imprinted into it backwards was because those letters appear on most film cases.
Then what about the piece of the bubble bath bar on the table?
He probably put it into his beer.
It would dissolve in the beer, where the foam wouldn't stand out.
Though even his perfect crime has now vanished along with the foam, due to crossing paths with me, Sleeping Kogorō.
I see. I wish I'd thought of that.
You did!
Honestly...
The inspector told me you never remember anything after solving a case. I guess he was right.
Then you don't even remember that the motive was revenge
for his boss harrassing his colleague so much that he committed suicide?
N-No, not at all...
But you were so cool!
No, hold on!
There's no way I can't remember it at all...
What if what I thought was my inner self was actually something else, sleeping deep within...
'The True Kogorō Mouri'
My true self!
So that's it! I'm usually in energy-saving mode, storing up my strength for 'Sleeping Kogorou'!
Well, I don't mind either way, so anything's fine for me!
Oh, by the way, do you think Conan-kun's okay?
Oh, that four-eyed brat left me here and went home?
Yes.
He was talking with Detective Takagi, then his expression suddenly changed and he ran out.
I wonder what they were talking about.
All I could hear was something about thefts by a pickpocket...
He probably rushed off because he heard Takagi talking about a thriller that he wanted to see being shown on TV tonight.
Why?
Because it's a pretty t-hefty thriller!
Just kidding!
Damn, I've outdone myself again!
There was something peculiar about one of the victims?
Yeah. Do you remember that man?
Tōhei Benzaki, a victim of theft by that pickpocket.
Yeah. I think he said he was held hostage with Jodie-sensei during that bank robbery?
Yeah, remember how his wife turned up afterward and said she was the one to tape up Jodie-san's eyes and mouth?
But at the time, the bank robbers told people who had no companions to do that,
to stop them from going easy on people they know.
Okay, now, everyone without any companions here, stand up.
Come here and take a roll of tape each.
Use it to tape the eyes and mouths of everyone with a companion, and tie their arms behind their backs!
Since you aren't acquainted with any of them,
I don't have to worry about you going soft on them.
Here.
Of course, we'll tape you up just the same afterwards.
Umm...
Sorry, I have to do this...
If that husband, Tōhei-san, was a hostage back then too, it just doesn't add up...
Why would his pregnant wife try and deceive the bank robbers and put them both in danger...?
So?! Did you try to contact that couple?!
Y-Yes.
We visited him quite a few times,
but he always turned us away, saying he doesn't remember being involved in the case of that pickpocket's murder.
Also, it seems Benzaki-san doesn't have a wife, but is actually single,
and doesn't even know any pregnant women.
I don't know what's going on anymore...
Could it be?
Could it be?!
Morning sickness is a condition that you
have in the first stages of pregnancy, right?
T-That's it! My eyesight is bad!
Then was that man with a burn scar next to you your boyfriend?
I saw him two or three days ago, that's all.
Could it be?!
I've gotta calm down. I'm fine. I'm still safe!
Now he'll be alone with Ran-kun.
If he's going to give himself away, it'll be now.
So all three of them could have done it.
No.
On the next Conan: 'The Bathroom Where Ran Blacks Out (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Spare Key!
That tomboy's showing up again?!
And you're needed less and less.
Hey, Ran-neechan...