If that couple really were Bourbon and Vermouth...
If they overheard me talking with Jodie-sensei, that means...
E-Either way, I have to meet up with Haibara and check with her!
Damn! Why didn't I realise any sooner?!
Since they said that the husband had been a hostage too, that doesn't fit.
They even made such an obvious blunder!
An obvious blunder?
Was that...
A trap?!
Have I felt their presence lately?
Y-Yeah.
You said they had a certain smell or something, didn't you?
I haven't felt anything, though I haven't been watching out for them.
You did say that they believe I'm dead.
I-Is that so? That's good then.
What is it? Don't tell me they found out that I'm still alive!
I-I was just checking! That's all!
Sorry for calling so late.
I've got to stay calm, stop panicking...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
Ran collapses while investigating
with Sera. Just what happened here?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
What?
Don't "what" me!
You haven't stopped glancing around since we got here.
Is there anyone suspicious here?
Oh, don't worry about it.
It's nothing like that.
Really?
This is a problem.
Ever since that happened, I feel like I'm being watched.
I've told Jodie-sensei that that couple may have been from the Black Organisation just in case...
But if they, by any chance, noticed that...
Gotta calm down. It'll be fine. I'm fine!
Aren't you feeling well, Conan-kun? You're drenched with sweat!
I know we were going to have lunch at a Chinese restaurant with my mum after this, but would you rather go home?
I-I'm fine! I was just thinking.
Really?
We were given some pretty hard homework, you see.
A shutter sound?
I wasn't imagining it!
I am being watched by someone after all!
But who? And why?!
Again! And closer than before!
Where? Where are they being taken from?!
Hey, guys! What are you doing here?
You too, Sera-san! Why are you here?
I'm here for work!
You know how there's a girl called Keiko Kitao over in Class A?
Oh, Kei-chan?
Her older sister hired me for a job.
See that girl sitting over there?
Rumi Kitao (21)
University Student
That's Rumi Kitao-san, a third-year university student.
And the guy sitting next to her is Ken'ya Settsu-san, a fourth-year university student.
Ken'ya Settsu (22)
University Student
Those two have been dating for half a year now.
She wants to introduce him to her parents as a possible husband, but rumour has it that he's a playboy.
And what's more, she suspects that he hasn't cut ties with his ex-girlfriend yet.
So I'm investigating him!
So basically, an adultery investigation.
And? How is it going?
Right now, he's in the grey.
Apparently he's still got a spare key to his ex-girlfriend's flat.
And this is the block of flats
where his ex-girlfriend lives!
Are you sure you should be telling us all that, though?
No problem! You guys know how to keep a secret, right?
So what are you guys doing here?
I didn't expect to see you in Kanagawa prefecture.
My mum's working for one of the residents here and is meeting with him right now.
We're going to have lunch together after that...
It's my mum.
What? You're kidding! You can't leave?!
But we're starving!
I'm sorry. This meeting's going to take a while yet.
If you're hungry, why don't you have a little snack with Conan-kun, and we'll meet in the lobby here tonight?
Okay.
I guess we better get some rice balls or something nearby...
In that case, how about having those two treat you to lunch?
They were planning to have lunch together with his ex-girlfriend today.
Stop joking around! I've never even seen them before.
It's an undercover investigation!
Undercover?!
Do it for Keiko-kun from Class A!
You're kidding, right? Your sister isn't coming?
That restaurant is pretty famous, it wasn't easy to get a reservation for all of us!
It's not like she has much of a choice! She said something suddenly came up with her friends!
What is it? Don't tell me you're aiming for her?
That ain't it! I just figured if your sister was there, she might be able to calm the air a bit!
I wanna make peace with Waka at lunch today, you know.
We haven't spoken to each other
since we broke up, after all.
That's true. Well, Kaga-san will probably liven things up when he arrives!
E-Excuse me...
Would you be Kei-chan's sister, by any chance?
Y-Yes.
I'm Ran Mouri. I was in her class last year.
She showed me your picture a few times, so I figured you might be her sister.
Oh, I see.
What a coincidence.
Actually, the plan was that I'd join them for lunch in Keiko-kun's place.
If that man really is a playboy like the rumours suggest, he'd probably make eyes at me when she isn't looking.
But since you're cuter and more stylish than me, how about you take my place?
If he's really that kind of guy, I think he'll definitely bite if we toss him some bait.
Okay then. First, I need to casually put out some bait...
Umm...
You said you were hungry, C-Conan-kun, but we haven't decided what to eat, have we?
Y-Yeah.
Casual as a fish out of water.
Then how about you eat with us?
I doubt they'll mind us bringing a kid with us.
T-Thank you.
Well, that didn't take much bait.
Perfect.
Waka sure is late.
It's already past noon.
It's inevitable.
She was out drinking until 5 this morning, so she's probably still fast asleep.
Mitsuaki Kaga (22)
University Student
There you are, Kaga!
Is there a toilet in this lobby?
Yeah, just past the lift.
Then I'll be back in a minute.
In that case, I'll go check on Waka.
If you're going to see Waka,
can you give her back this spare key?
I don't need it anymore.
Ken'ya...
Hey, don't drop it!
Sorry!
Now he'll be alone with Ran-kun.
If he's going to give himself away, it'll be now.
I'm sorry, but would you guys mind going with her?
If Waka hasn't sobered up yet, she might lay into her.
That's true.
I did steal her boyfriend, after all.
If there's a stranger around, Waka might be calmer.
I don't mind.
Then please come with me.
All right.
I get the feeling she might've suddenly decided she doesn't want to see me.
In that case, please tell her that I'd like to meet her face-to-face in order to apologise.
He's better than I thought.
She's not answering.
Maybe she is asleep after all?
Then let's use this!
Waka?
Are you sleeping?
Oh, sorry, it's my phone.
I'm sorry, but could you go ahead and wake Waka?
When she comes home drunk, Waka ends up sleeping in weird places.
So check in her wardrobe and stuff as well.
Oh, okay!
Sorry for making you wait.
You can't hear me?
I'll go out on the balcony...
Waka-san? Are you there?
Waka-san?
This is weird. She's nowhere to be found.
The bathroom?
I'm a friend of Rumi-san's sister.
I was asked to come and get you.
W-Waka-san?
Are you okay?
Waka-san?!
Hey, hold on! Waka-san! Waka-san!
Waka...
Ran-neechan!
Ran-neechan, wake up!
Ran-neechan! Ran-neechan!
C-Conan-kun...
Great, you're awake!
Are you okay?
Sorry about that.
Sera-san?
W-What happened to me?
You collapsed in the bathroom!
I-It's terrible! I found Waka-san collapsed and bleeding in the shower!
Yeah. See in there?
The police are already here and investigating right now.
What happened?
I heard the shower running from out here,
and when I went in, Waka-san was lying on the floor, surrounded by steam.
I went to wake her up, but
I suddenly started feeling faint.
Did you see anyone suspicious?
No...
I searched the wardrobe and everything, but there was nobody here.
Why did you check her wardrobe?
Waka-san has the habit of sleeping in weird places when she comes home drunk,
according to Rumi-san, who came with me to get her.
S-Speaking of which, where is Rumi-san?!
I'm fine!
Sorry for getting you involved in this.
Rumi-san!
I found you and Waka lying in the bathroom, but I ended up passing out too.
So I didn't see the culprit.
And since we never came back,
these two came after us, right?
Yeah.
We'd waited 30 minutes for you,
and you weren't answering your mobile phone.
We explained the situation to the block's manager, and had him open the door for us.
Right?
Yeah.
Then we found the three of them lying in the bathroom.
And quickly called the cops.
But I wonder what the hell was that smell was.
It made me kind of dizzy when I went into the shower room.
It's chloroform.
It's a form of anaesthetic —
if you breathe in a lot of it, you lose consciousness.
In some cases, you might even die.
It was turned to gas and this room was filled with it!
Well, this kid turned on the ventilating fan right away, so it's fine now.
Then, Waka was killed by this anaesthetic?
Come on now, can't you tell just by looking?!
She was beaten to death!
Someone beat her head in with a blunt weapon and killed her.
But then why did they use an anaesthetic?
And is it really Waka that died?
We can't see her face through that mask.
In that case, let's take a look.
Waka!
Hey! Don't come in here.
Still, this is a strange corpse. She's winking.
And something's trickling out of the corner of her eye.
Mascara?
At first glance, it seems that Waka-san was about to take a bath, when she was hit from behind and killed.
But could this be something else...?
Well then, according to your collective statements, the four of you had planned to have lunch together today,
and had agreed to meet here, in the lobby of the block of flats where the victim lives, shortly after noon.
But because the victim wasn't coming down, Rumi-san and Ran-san, who also happened to be present,
went to the victim's flat to check up on her.
And since she didn't answer when you rang the bell,
you used the spare key Settsu-san, who used to go out with the victim, had given you to open the door and entered.
Then Rumi-san received a call from Settsu-san and Ran-san had to search for the victim on her own.
She found the victim lying in the bathroom, but passed out due to the chloroform.
Rumi-san came in afterward, and fell asleep too.
And 30 minutes later, the two of you headed up here because you were concerned that the girls hadn't come back,
where you found the three of them lying in the bathroom.
Yes, that's about it.
The safety lock was on and it took some time to get it open, so it took some time to notify you.
I-I'm a bit paranoid, so I tend to lock doors straight after coming in.
By the way, is it true that the victim was drinking until 5 this morning?
Yes, I was drinking with her here.
We also invited Settsu and Rumi, but they didn't want to come since we were going to meet today anyway.
I had to listen to her badmouthing her ex-boyfriend Settsu quite a bit.
Right until she fell asleep dead drunk.
Then how did the door get locked?
O-Of course, when I left, I woke Waka up and made her lock the door!
Still, this is quite an amazing flat
for someone living on their own.
Waka's father is a top executive of a famous company.
The only person I've seen not be surprised by this flat was a first-year girl who joined our circle this year.
It turned out she was the daughter of the chairman of the whole business group.
Hey.
When you and Ran-neechan entered this flat with the spare key, you received a call from Settsu-san, right?
What was the call about?
He asked me to look for something.
He left something here when he was still going out with Waka.
So he asked me to look for it and bring it with me.
Well, he'd already asked me to find it, so I was going to look for it even if he hadn't called.
What did you forget here?
A wristwatch I really liked.
I thought it was probably still lying around somewhere in the living room.
And that if Waka happened to still be asleep, I could ask her to enter with the spare key and secretly get it back.
Since she couldn't find it, Waka might have found it and thrown it away.
The living room is that big room connected to the balcony, right?
Yes.
When I got the call I went out to the balcony, so it was the best time to search for it.
This is a tower block, so the reception is pretty bad everywhere else.
That's why I asked you to search for Waka, right?
Y-Yes.
Which means Rumi-san went left from the entrance into the living room.
And Ran searched the right side where the bedroom is located.
Speaking of the balcony, Waka fell asleep there once when she came home drunk, didn't she?
Yeah, I heard about that.
She called me in a drunk daze and said
'Feeling the wind sobers me up',
but ended up falling asleep during the phone call.
When I came here because I was worried, she was leaning against the balcony, fast asleep.
She also slept under the bed once.
But this time, she didn't sleep on the balcony or under the bed, but in the shower.
At eternal rest.
And the person who did that to her is someone who had a key to this flat.
One of you two.
Hey!
Wait a second!
Her ex-boyfriend Settsu had a spare key, but I didn't have one.
Maybe you made the victim drink until she blacked out
and sneakily took the key with you when you left?
Then when you came here earlier, you could have just tossed it somewhere to deceive us!
Or you could've just stayed up here until the meeting time just after midday.
R-Rumi might have a key too.
She was sharing the flat with Waka until Settsu and Waka started dating.
I-I returned that key a long time ago!
I see.
If all three of them might have had a key, that means all three could have performed the crime.
No.
The only ones who could have killed Waka-san before Ran-kun found her are...
Settsu-san and Kaga-san. I doubt it could've been anyone else.
What?!
Kaga-san only arrived shortly before Ran-kun and Rumi-san went to Waka-san's flat to check on her.
And about 30 minutes earlier, Settsu-san went to the toilet for a while.
If they had a key to Waka-san's flat and took the stairs, where no security cameras are installed,
they could have killed Waka-san without being seen.
In contrast, Rumi-san was with me the whole time until she came here.
And since she didn't even go to the toilet before she went to Waka-san's flat,
the crime would have been impossible for her.
You were with Rumi-san?
Or rather —
who the heck are you?
I'm a detective.
I was hired by Rumi-san.
In any case...
Sorry...
Thanks for picking them up!
Here you go.
Be careful not to drop them again.
But if that corpse wasn't Waka-san, then it's a different story.
What?!
On the next Conan: The Bathroom Where Ran Blacks Out (Part II)!
Next Conan's Hint: Wink!
It's nearly June!
May streams by in the blink of an eye!
Mascara's streaming out of your eye!