Ran and I made plans to have lunch with her mother, Kisaki-sensei.
We were going to meet her in a block of flats where she had a meeting.
There, we happened to meet Masumi Sera,
and Ran ended up helping her out in an investigation at her request.
During the investigation, she was looking for one of the residents of the block, when...
Waka-san?!
Hey, hold on! Waka-san! Waka-san!
Waka...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
Sera's deduction, and another mystery.
Don't blink, or you'll miss the ingenious trick!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A detective?
W-What's the meaning of this, Rumi?!
Rumi Kitao (20)
University Student
Ken'ya Settsu (22)
People were saying you hadn't cut ties with Waka, so I...
Damn it, Rumi...
I-I'm very sorry.
In any case...
As I was saying, given this situation, one of you must be the killer!
Mitsuaki Kaga (22)
University Student
It certainly looks that way.
But there's also another possibility.
Hey, Rumi-san...
I found this picture in the living room.
All four of you are wearing glasses here, so how come none of you wear them now?
That photo's from around two years ago.
We've all switched to contacts by now.
What?! You found the murder weapon?!
Yes!
We found traces of blood on a golf club in the living room.
We also found a bottle of chloroform and a syringe in the kitchen sink.
Furthermore, in the bathroom drain there was a liquid that looked like red paint.
R-Red paint?! Why would something like that be there?
The shower head just hanging there spouting water is also pretty strange.
If you were trying to hide the time of death without changing the core body temperature,
you'd normally turn it towards the corpse, right?
This case doesn't make any sense!
Ran-neechan, Rumi-san was the one who used the spare key to open the door, right?
Y-Yes.
Did she have any trouble opening it?
Not particularly...
It felt like she was used to opening it.
But when I take a key out of my pocket like this...
I'm sorry! Could you pick those up?
Geez.
Oh, well...
Sorry...
Thanks for picking them up!
Here you go.
Be careful not to drop them again.
So I was right, that explains it!
And if I noticed this, she probably did too.
A phone call?
With who?
Hey, is my deduction wrong?
In any case,
the only people who could have beaten Waka Hashitani-san to death in the bathroom are...
You, Settsu-san, who had been dating the victim until half a year ago and still had a spare key...
And Kaga-san, who was drinking here with the victim until 5 AM and could have taken a key with him —
you two are the only ones!
The two of you had planned to meet with the victim in the lobby here at noon in order to have lunch,
but Settsu-san, you went to the bathroom 30 minutes before the meeting time
and Kaga-san, you came to the lobby shortly after noon.
Your movements before that are unknown.
So, confess!
One of you two killed her, right?
H-Hold on!
Waka was lying in a bathroom filled with chloroform!
If one of us was the killer, why would we have filled the bathroom with chloroform?
You probably did it to put Rumi-san to sleep when she came to get the victim, in order to delay the discovery of the corpse.
Because the later the corpse is found, the greater the time span of the estimated time of death.
That goes for Rumi too.
She may have said that until she went to get Waka she was with that detective, but can we really be sure about that?
K-Ken'ya...
She used to share this flat with Waka, so she might still have a key.
She could be in cahoots with that detective and have arranged for their statements to match.
Anyway, isn't it too much of a coincidence?
You came out of nowhere and said you've been with Rumi this whole time, to give her an alibi or something.
No, I'm not saying Rumi-san has an alibi.
All I'm saying is that if Ran-kun, who went with her to get Waka-san, found her corpse,
then one of you two is the culprit.
But if that corpse wasn't Waka-san, then it's a different story.
W-What?!
But it really was Waka-san's corpse that I found.
Are you really sure about that?
You'd never met Waka-san before, right?
That's true, but...
And the corpse was lying face-down, wearing a facial pack and had a towel wrapped around her head.
On top of that, the bathroom was filled with steam from the shower, right?
If someone else was posing as her, I don't think you'd have noticed.
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
She... Could it be?
P-Pose as her?
Who are you saying impersonated her?!
She was lying there wearing nothing but a towel, right?
Y-Yes.
It was definitely a woman.
In that case, the only one who could have done this is the one who came to get Waka-san together with Ran-kun...
Rumi-san, right?
That means that when she came here with Ran-kun, she pretended to go to the living room
and made Ran-kun look for Waka-san in the opposite part of the flat, where the bedroom is.
Then, when an opening presented itself, she went into the bathroom,
put on a towel and a facial pack, wrapped another towel around her head...
And smeared some red paint where her head would lie, to make it look like she was dead.
Then she waited until Ran-kun came to the bathroom to look for Waka-san,
and released the chloroform she had inserted into a syringe, which vaporised...
Are you okay?
Waka-san!
...and knocked out Ran-kun, who had entered the bathroom.
Of course, she herself held her breath in the meantime.
Hold on! Where was the victim at that time?
She must have been asleep in the living room.
Remember, they said that Waka-san fell asleep on the living room balcony before when she was drunk, didn't they?
If Rumi-san knew that Waka-san and Kaga-san were drinking here until morning...
She could have waited until the time Kaga-san would have left, called her,
and made her go to the balcony by saying that it would help her sober up, making her fall asleep there.
Right.
After Ran-kun blacked out, Rumi-san left the bathroom, temporarily turned on the ventilating fan to dissipate the chloroform,
and washed away the red paint.
Then she changed back into her clothes, and woke up Waka-san who was asleep in the living room.
She made her go to the bathroom by telling her that a girl she didn't know was lying there or something similar.
And while Waka-san was taking in the sight of the unconscious Ran-kun, Rumi-san beat her to death with the golf club.
She then dressed her in a towel, applied a facial pack to her face,
wrapped a towel around her head and filled the bathroom with chloroform once more.
This time she actually breathed it in herself and blacked out, waiting for the two guys to find her!
After all, who'd think that somebody who went looking for the victim would suddenly be posing as her corpse?
Y-You're wrong! I wouldn't do anything like that!
A-And I went to the living room because I got a call from Ken'ya!
Still, even if he hadn't called, you were planning to go to the living room to look for Settsu-san's watch, weren't you?
Y-Yes.
And, even if you hadn't gotten the spare key from Settsu-san,
you probably intended to use the key you still had from the time you lived here,
saying you were planning to return it today, or something like that.
All the threads come together if the reason you hired me as a detective was so that I could see you posing as that corpse!
Though in this case, Ran-kun ended up playing that part instead.
Your sister, who was supposed to come to lunch today,
might have been made to play that part as well,
but you figured that, being your sister, she might recognise you, so you decided to make a stranger do it instead.
T-That's not true! I didn't—
Inspector!
We found fingerprints on the chloroform bottle!
Oh? Could those be Rumi Kitao-san's prints?
Y-Yes!
A splendid deduction! Not bad, young one!
Thanks.
Doesn't that deduction...
...seem a bit off?
O-Off?
W-What are you talking about?
Oh, it's not me.
Shin'ichi heard about the case from Conan,
and told me on the phone to say that.
I-I'll put him on speaker now!
Shin'ichi Kudō?
I don't know who the hell you are, but outsiders should stay out of this.
The problems are the following three points...
You said the victim was made to fall asleep in the living room, like she did once before,
but back then, that just happened by chance.
Even if you manage to make the person you're calling go to the living room,
I don't think you can make them fall asleep there so easily.
And even if you're lucky and they happen to fall asleep, you still can't be sure they'll still be asleep by the time you get there.
There's also the risk of the doorbell waking them up.
Then what if Rumi-san came here a while before she came here with me,
and put her to sleep in the living room using chloroform?
In that case, something like the
doorbell wouldn't have woken her.
That's the second problem.
If that was the case, why would she have locked the front door?
If Settsu-san hadn't, by chance, given her his spare key,
she would have had to use her own key, pretending she intended to return it,
and because she had that key, she would have been the main suspect, don't you think?
What's more, if she had put her to sleep beforehand, having the sleeping Waka-san pose as a corpse would have been safer.
There would have been no reason for her to go out of her way to hold her breath and pose as a corpse.
And the third problem is the fact that the body was lying there face-down wearing only a bath towel.
No-one can know how exactly how they look from behind.
There's a good possibility of there being a mole or birthmark you don't know about yourself on your back.
If Ran saw that and revealed that she'd seen someone else, it'd be all over.
It was the worst possible situation, and the worst possible posture to try and impersonate.
B-But the body had a facial pack applied!
Plus, the killer used steam to make it hard to see!
No matter how you look at it, that's—
That's just it.
Because the face was hidden and visibility was limited, people will suspect that it had been someone else.
As if that was the culprit's aim all along!
The reason that the body was dressed in a towel and lying face-down was to make the person who discovered the body
quickly see that the face was being hidden and that it was a woman's body.
This way the culprit himself would be removed from the list of suspects,
because only a woman could have posed as the corpse, and Rumi-san would be the scapegoat.
Isn't that right? You pretended to go to the toilet 30 minutes before the meeting time and came here,
killed Waka-san and put into motion the plan I just described.
Her ex-boyfriend...
Ken'ya Settsu-san!
W-What?!
That's right.
After sneaking in here, you waited for a chance, and put Waka-san to sleep by making her breathe in chloroform.
Then you carried her to the bathroom, took off her clothes and wrapped her in a towel.
And after applying a pack to her face and wrapping a towel around her head, you beat her with the golf club.
Afterwards all you had to do was pour some red paint down the drain and fill the bathroom with chloroform.
Later you called Rumi-san, who had gone to look for her, and made her go to the living room,
creating the time that makes people wonder whether she might have posed as the corpse.
And if, after it's all over, Rumi-san's fingerprints are found on the chloroform bottle,
it's likely the police will believe the corpse was a fake.
By the way, the bottle with Rumi-san's prints was probably one that Settsu-san made her touch before the incident.
Seeing how the two of them were dating,
he could have easily made her take it in her hand by putting it in the spice rack, for example.
H-Hey, I've no idea who you are, but Kaga could have done that trick, too!
That's why I had Conan-kun test you for me.
T-Test us?
Remember, I made you pick up some change for me, didn't I?
Back then, I held out my hand and asked you to give it to me, right?
Kaga-san put the coins into my hand, but Settsu-san put the coins into his own palm and held them out for me to take.
That's how I knew!
Settsu-san couldn't judge distance well,
so he couldn't put the coins into my palm.
So even though I had my hand held out, he made me pick the coins up from his own outstretched hand!
Well, Settsu-san had already missed Rumi-san's hand for the same reason
when he handed over the spare key, so it's not surprising that he did that!
W-What are you talking about?
Contacts.
One of Settsu-san's contact lenses is missing.
Most likely it fell out when he was making Waka-san breathe in the chloroform and she fought back.
Flustered, he searched the floor for the lens, but couldn't find it.
That's because Waka-san, who had fallen down after she had sniffed the chloroform,
picked it up and hid it even while her consciousness was slipping away.
She hid it?! But where? The victim was stripped of her clothes afterwards!
You agreed that the corpse was strange, didn't you, Inspector?
Oh, the winking!
The victim hid it inside her own eye!
Check the body immediately!
Yes, sir!
If the lens were to be found in the living room,
you were probably planning to shrug it off by saying that you lost it when the two of you were still dating.
But if it's in her eye and missing from yours, it's unshakeable proof.
And since it's a contact lens,
it should have your prints as well.
Hey, that's not true, is it, Settsu?
Why would you want to kill Waka anyway?
Didn't the two of you break up?
Yeah, so I could date the chairman's daughter.
T-The chairman's daughter? That first year?
I didn't have much of a choice, did I?
Waka's father is a managing director, while her father is the chairman of that company's business group!
If I did well and managed to marry her, it'd be quite the move up in society.
I'd gotten an informal offer for a job at said company as well, so I was moving up in life!
But if you'd broken up, there was
no reason to kill her, was there?
Waka threatened me.
If I got together with that girl, Waka was going to reveal to her all the bad things I'd done.
I made quite a number of girls cry before I started dating Waka.
Then what am I?! Why did you go out with me?!
If that woman was killed the moment I stopped going out with her, I'd be suspected immediately, wouldn't I?
By dating you and encouraging the rumour that I hadn't cut ties with Waka yet, you'd have a motive as well, due to jealousy.
Well, you were able to date someone as awesome as me for half a year.
You should cherish that memor—
Oh, sorry. When I'm having to listen to idiots blab on, sometimes my head starts itching, and my elbow just moves scratch it...
Keep it up, and this time my buttocks will probably start itching and my knee might lash out.
Anything more to say?
N-No.
You really surprised me!
It's impressive how you saw through that fake!
It wasn't me, but Shin'ichi-niichan!
No way! Shin'ichi just hung up on me.
T-That's right, Shin'ichi-niichan told me something!
He realised it was fake because of the mascara running out of the corner of Waka-san's eye.
Because if you put on a facial pack, you have to remove your make-up.
The culprit also realised that and removed the lipstick at least.
But if the culprit was a woman, she wouldn't have overlooked the mascara!
And he said that you probably didn't realise that because you've never put on mascara yourself!
I see.
But Shin'ichi's never put on mascara either!
You were involved in a murder case?!
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, I had a detective with me, Sera-san.
Though it was Kudō-kun who solved it in the end.
Anyway, I'm off now.
Oh, that girl...
Huh? Do you know Sera-san?
Yes. Actually, I came down here to the lobby before noon, to let you know that the meeting would take longer.
But you weren't here yet and that girl was on the phone.
On the phone? With whom?
No idea. But since she attached nii to their name, I imagine it was her brother?
So today you're watching the
football match with your girlfriend?
And so, Sanada...
Aiming another strong, straight shot at the upper left corner.
Don't worry about it, Sanada-kun!
That guy...
He's suspicious.
On the next Conan: The J-Leaguer's Promise!
Next Conan's Hint: Takahiro Sanada!
Kudō-kun sure knows his make-up, huh?
The knowledge is purely theoretical.
He's so annoying.