Wow!
What?!
Great!
Damn!
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
An impassioned shot by the mischievous Sanada unfolds into an unforeseen case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
THE J-LEAGUER'S PROMISE
So Big Ōsaka didn't score...
Huh? I thought you weren't Big supporters?
Well, you know... We are Spirits fans,
but we got to know Sanada when we took that football class.
So the three of us decided to cheer for Sanada-san as well.
But I guess Big Ōsaka's no good without Higo...
It's not his fault.
Higo was chosen to play in the World Cup, so he couldn't play in this tournament.
After all, he and Hide were the strikers
chosen to represent Japan!
So Sanada-san had to sub in for Higo-san, right?
Yes, because he's Higo's substitute.
And he even told us...
Hey, I'm not just a substitute!
Takahiro Sanada (18)
J-League Big Ōsaka player
I'm a super sub!
Remember that!{\i0]
...when we met him, right?
Still, that shot was a really close call!
He used his right foot, didn't he?
He must've done that to stop the defender from blocking his shot.
I'd say he made the right call there.
I'm not so sure...
In that situation, I'd say he didn't
need to stop and go for a feint.
If he kept going and took a shot at the left side of the goal with his left foot, I'm sure he'd have scored.
Then why didn't he follow through?
I don't know. But that wasn't the first time.
What do you mean?
Earlier, when Sanada rushed toward the goal,
he got handed a perfect cross, remember?
I was sure he would volley it in with his left.
But you're right, he used his right instead, and it flew over the bar.
Ever since then, I've been wondering why he didn't use his dominant leg.
Maybe he was trying to impress the coach by showing him he could shoot, even with his right leg?
Though it ended up backfiring on him...
And there's one more thing about him today.
I've been wondering about it for quite a while.
Sanada seems to occasionally
look towards the stands on the...
Oh, he's doing it again!
See? He keeps looking that way.
I wonder who he's looking at...
Your guess is as good as mine...
I can't quite tell from here, but he's definitely worried about someone.
Don't tell me he's intentionally missing his shots because someone's threatening him.
Just kidding... Like that could ever happen.
What makes you think that?
Did a case like that happen before or something?
No, nothing like that!
Sorry, I was just overthinking things.
Let's just keep watching the match!
Still, that play just now was really strange.
There must be some reason behind it.
Ayumi-chan, Genta-kun, do you think Conan-kun's reasoning might actually be correct?
You mean someone's forcing Sanada-san to miss his shots on purpose?
Precisely.
It felt like Conan-kun had a reason
to bring it up, though he's not telling us.
If that's true...
We should help that guy out.
Yeah!
Conan-kun!
We're all going to the toilet real quick.
Sure.
Hey, look at that man!
He does look quite suspicious...
Let's go take a closer look!
Do your best, Sanada-kun!
Now, Sanada!
We're clear! Squeeze up!
Another miss...
Don't worry about it, Sanada-kun!
That guy...
It was like he was checking out Sanada-san and that lady cheering for him.
He's definitely suspicious.
If it isn't Conan-kun!
Oh, Kaoru-san!
Kaoru Kōda (27)
Nichiuri Shimbun Photographer — Local News Division
Here to watch the match with your girlfriend?
Well, that's...
Wrong.
Oh, I see. My bad!
You aren't here for work today then, Kaoru-san?
You're not wearing a press bib.
Yup, I'm off-duty today.
I made it back into the local news division with that scoop photo last time.
But I've become personally interested in Takahiro Sanada since those bombings.
And so I've kept supporting him.
By the way, don't you think there's something strange about him today?
Yeah, Sanada-kun is acting
a bit different from usual.
Two days ago, I took some photos of him doing early morning practice drills on a pitch
by the Nishishiba Hotel that Big always stays in when they have matches in Tōkyō.
Was he practising shots with his right foot?
No...
He was practising penalty kicks, but using his left foot.
And he was doing fast, straight shots aimed at the top-left corner of the goal.
He didn't even practise any
other shot at all, just that one.
So I was on the mark...
Then why would he use his right foot today?
Oh! So close...
That pitch sure brings back memories though...
Why? Have you been there before?
Yeah, it's the Nishishiba Sports Park.
I went there for a football tourney back when I was in middle school.
And a few days before the tournament...
I went to check what the turf was like and tried practising a few shots on my own.
I tried a penalty kick to wrap things up, and just like Sanada, I went for a strong, straight shot at the top-left corner.
I ended up overshooting it, though.
So you're saying that you, a high-school football player, messed up the penalty kick even without a goalkeeper being there?
I said that was back in middle school!
Huh?! ‘Back in middle school'?
Did you just say ‘back in middle school'?
Oh, I was just repeating
what an older boy I know said.
Do your best, Sanada-kun!
Huh?! What's that near his knee?
I don't know... It looks like a black pipe.
It's a gun!
It's got to be a gun's muzzle!
Can gun muzzles be that thick?
That must be a silencer, something you add to a gun to dampen the noise it makes!
You see them used in spy movies all the time.
These are the facts...
That girl who's cheering on
Sanada must be his girlfriend,
and to prevent her from getting killed,
he was threatened into missing his shots!
And that's why he's been taking shots with his
right foot instead of his left on purpose!
What should we do then, Mitsuhiko?
Let's go warn that security guard!
Good job, Takahiro!
Oh no!
This can't be good!
He scored a goal...
Watch out!
Stop!
Hey... What in the world?!
Let go!
We're not letting you go!
You were threatening Sanada-niichan, weren't you?!
Quick, Ayumi-chan, the security guard!
Hey, guys...
This doesn't look like a gun.
Hey, you guys!
Hey, let go of me.
What'd you guys do?!
I was sure that was a gun silencer...
That's a video camera.
One used for covert photography...
W-What're you talking about?
That's nothing to do with me!
That man, he's the one who's been stalking Yuki!
So that lady wasn't Sanada-san's girlfriend after all.
It looks like she was just an ordinary fan.
Man, I'm glad that thing ended up
being just a video camera.
I don't know what would've happened to you if it had actually been a gun!
But it was thanks to you that I got some good pictures, so you've got my thanks.
I'll treat you to something from
the concession stands as a reward.
Half-time just started anyway.
Yay!
Good grief...
What's with that ‘good grief' of yours?
Those kids did that because of what you said.
Well, I guess you're right.
Still, I'm sure that there's something
strange going on with Sanada.
Kō Watanabe (10)
Nishishiba Primary
4th Year
Shingo Fukazawa (40)
Shopkeeper
I'm going to the toilet.
Are you sure you don't you want me to go with you?
I'll be fine.
So he was watching that boy...?
Hey...
Is there something wrong with that kid's right ankle?
Yeah, he twisted it when he fell off his bike.
Are you his dad?
Oh no, you've got it wrong.
You don't look like a football coach...
Is he a friend of Sanada's?
Why do you ask?
Sanada gave him some kind of signal.
Hey, is there some connection between Sanada and that boy falling off his bike?
What makes you think that?
Because whenever Sanada comes to Tōkyō, he always does individual practice at a park in Nishishiba.
And that kid had his training jacket on, which says ‘Nishishiba Soccer Club'.
I work at a corner shop in Nishishiba, but then two days ago, when I was walking through the Sports Park there...
Are you okay, kid?
My ankle...
My bad, my bad!
I was practisin' penalty kicks,
but the ball flew right over the goal.
Are you hurt?!
So I took them both to a nearby hospital.
I'll never be able to play in matches with my ankle like this...
Don't sweat it! You'll be able to run fine if you give it ten days!
But I still won't be able to shoot with it.
That's nothin'!
If your right foot's no good,
you can always kick with your left!
Does that mean you can really score just as well with your right foot as your left, Sanada-san?
Ya bet! I'm a J-Leaguer, after all.
I'm just as great with my right!
Then promise you'll score a goal with your right foot in your next match.
If you do that, I'll try my best as well.
And so, Sanada...
Sanada later sent us tickets to today's match.
But Kō-kun's parents were both
busy, so I came instead.
Thanks.
I'm in shock.
No matter how much he blames himself for that boy getting injured,
where else could you find a J-Leaguer that would make such a stupid promise?
Well, I guess you could say
that's the way Sanada is.
Or maybe that it's one of his good points?
I wanna see Sanada make
a goal in the second half, too!
Not one of those hack shots like he made before!
Yeah, a really exciting goal!
The thing I'm more worried about is...
Yes, this is the Nishishiba Sports Park Manager's Office.
What? Mouri?!
You mean the famous detective Mouri?!
I heard what happened from Fukazawa-san.
Why don't you just forgive Sanada?
No way! A promise is a promise.
But you getting hurt wasn't Sanada's fault.
What are you talking about?!
He kicked the ball that...
Can you tell me where you fell off your bike?
Sure...
I think it was around here.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
Because it was right after I passed the zebra crossing.
And what direction did the ball fly towards you from?
It came from behind me, diagonally.
Sanada was standing here, kicking fast, straight balls towards the goal's upper-left corner.
However, he put too much force into one, and sent the ball flying past the goal.
That ball flew over Fukazawa-san's head
and assuming it continued flying toward the street in that direction...
See? A ball aimed at the upper-left corner of the goal...
...couldn't possibly have hit you diagonally from behind, Kō-kun, on the other side of the crossing.
Then why...?
There's only one possibility I can think of.
First, the ball that Sanada kicked didn't fly over Fukazawa-san's head...
It hit him.
And in his face of all places.
Fukazawa-san, it looks like
your glasses are in bad shape.
If you look closely, one of the arms is slightly bent.
The ball hit them, didn't it?
No... Nothing like that.
Hey, wait a sec!
If the ball hit Fukazawa-san like
you say, then how did it hit me...?
Right. The ball shouldn't have
headed towards you at all, Kō-kun.
Unless Fukazawa-san got angry from having a ball hit him in the face, and threw it in the opposite direction.
Y-You're wrong! I was further ahead when I saw the ball, and I'm sure it flew over my head.
You must be wrong about the path Sanada kicked the ball in the first place.
Think back, and remember.
The ball didn't come at you diagonally,
but straight from the side, right?
Fukazawa-san...
Did you know that park has
a surveillance camera here?
I called the sports park manager's office and had him check the video from the other day.
Damn it!
Why would you go that far...?
It's not that I really wanted to
expose your guilt, Fukazawa-san.
I realise you're not a bad person, Fukazawa-san.
I just needed to reveal the truth.
Both for Sanada and for Kō-kun.
A foul?!
He gets a penalty kick!
We're counting on you, Nobu!
Bring it on!
If I kicked it in that corner
with my left leg like I practiced,
I'm sure I could score.
But if I did that, I'd break the
promise I made to that boy...
Ow!
Unbelievable.
I knew it. Another hack shot.
Damn...
Don't worry 'bout it! There's no time
to feel down 'bout it, me!
Are you a moron?! Don't talk to yourself!
Thanks, guys!
Well, it's just like Sanada to do that.
fui ni furidasu haru no owaritsugeru ame
isogu machikado de kimi o mitsuketan da
ame ga suki na no hitotsu kasa ni kakurete
daremo ki ni sezu zutto yorisoeru kara...
amefuru machi de kimi to deatte
amefuru machi de kimi o ushinatta
aitakute aenakute afuredasu namida no ame
kaeritai modorenai tōi hi no omoide
nureru mama tachitsukusu machikado de kono kokoro wa
mada kimi no koto sagashite'ru
Ya mean, the ball ya threw...
I'm so sorry for lying...
Sanada-san, Kō-kun.
Please accept my apologies.
Enough, mister.
I'm gonna do my best in the next match.
W-Wait a second, Sanada-kun.
I'm very sorry!
Even if you're the one who threw that ball...
It doesn't change the fact that Kō was injured with the ball I kicked.
And it even hit you in the face, as well.
Please forgive me!
Sanada-san...
But you can normally make that penalty kick, right...?
‘Chain of Robberies Underway'
You found a girl's corpse near
the crime scene from before?
H-Hey, don't tell me...
No way...!
How could this happen?!
The pain has finally awoken me to the truth.
This case is not settled yet!
Not settled, Mouri-san...?
On the next Conan: ‘Two Overlapping Coincidences'!
TWO OVERLAPPING COINCIDENCES
Next Conan's Hint: A brand new skirt!
Take it away, Makino, who plays for the Reds...
Let's go, Japan!