Argh... They said it wasn't going to rain today!
"Chain of Robberies Underway"
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun! Dad!
Oh, you came out to meet me! Thank you.
Geez! It's already past 9 PM.
Sorry... My club ended up staying late...
Here's an umbrella.
Thanks, Conan-kun.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
A chain of robberies —
A coincidental trick has surprising consequences!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Be careful though. There's some dangerous guy creeping around here lately.
Oh, you mean the hooded robber?
What was it...?
He's known as the hoodman.
He attacks women with an extendable baton and steals their bags, right?
Yeah. So far, everyone got off with light injuries, but if he's not caught soon, his crimes might start escalating—
Hey! Are you okay?
The man in a hood went that way!
Got it!
Say, mister...
Huh?
Conan-kun?
Why aren't your clothes wet?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
If we don't hurry, he'll get away!
The rain started without warning.
Your shoes are dirty, and your trousers are wet.
But isn't it strange that you don't have an umbrella, but your clothes are dry?
Hmm, he's right...
You were wearing something else on top of them, weren't you?
Something like...
...a hoodie.
Damn!
Stop!
Move!
Well, that's the way it goes...
Hey, you okay?
I'm fine!
I wasn't talking to you.
Right, what about that scream from before?!
In here!
Miss! Are you okay?!
Well, you've been a great help, Mouri-kun!
We didn't know what to do about the hoodman.
Oh, it was nothing special, Inspector.
This is a hospital!
Shush, I know that.
Well then, feel free to call if you ever need anything, Inspector!
Right!
Thank you.
We'll be leaving now.
How was it?
She'll be fine.
Her CT scan and brainwaves show nothing wrong. The doctor said she could go home.
That's great.
Mizuki Tachibana (25)
Victim of the hoodman
Thank you so much.
It's all because of you.
Oh, right. I should call my roommate...
She must be worried about me.
But I'm glad you got off with light injuries.
A small relief hidden in misfortune, I guess.
Oh, sorry. Excuse me for a minute.
Yes, Sato here.
That's strange...
Is something wrong?
Yoko—my roommate, she's not answering the phone.
She should've finished work long ago by now...
You found a girl's corpse near the crime scene from before?
Right...
Right!
Mizuki-san, do you know what Yoko-san was wearing?
She was wearing a white jacket and a beige skirt...
Tachibana-san, is that true?
Y-Yeah.
H-Hey, don't tell me...
No way...!
How could this happen?!
Yōko Katsuragi (25)
Mizuki's roommate
There's no mistake! That's Yoko!
She was so happy when we said goodbye this morning...
I never thought that would be the last time I'd see her alive!
Yoko...!
Mizuki-san...
Ran, you stay with her.
From looking at her corpse, I'd say she died about one or two hours ago.
Yeah.
She worked at a clothing store nearby, and was probably attacked as she was heading home.
She was hit on the back of the head with some sort of rod.
The method, area, and time frame all match with the other hoodman victims.
The cash in her purse had been taken too.
He probably intended to just give her light injuries like with the others, but something made him end up killing Yoko-san instead.
And then he attacked Mizuki-san without even taking a break.
Who would have thought two roommates would be attacked one after another?
But that led to us catching the culprit.
Maybe their bond together brought about a miracle.
What's that?
It smells like coffee...
What's this...?
Damn brat, always wandering off...
Huh? Where's everybody going?
We're taking Tachibana-san back to HQ to hear her story, just to be sure.
We should take her statement about the case too.
I was thinking I should go with Mizuki-san.
I wanna come too!
Okay, Uncle?
Just to check, that's definitely the man who attacked you, right?
Yes. It was definitely him.
Understood.
Hey, doesn't he seem angry about something?
Oh, he confessed that he was
behind the chain of robberies, but...
He's completely refusing to admit
that he murdered Yoko-san.
Even when attacking you, Tachibana-san, he says that he didn't know what to do because you saw his face,
but he had no intention of killing you.
Hey, what's going on?!
You've gotta tell us!
We're counting on you, Detective!
Still, we haven't finished our investigation...
What is it, Detective Takagi?
Oh, Conan-kun, well...
You've caught the hoodman, right?
Does that mean you ladies are...?
Yeah! Victims of the hoodman!
And you'll give us back what he stole, right?!
Our purses!
I had my driver's license in there!
Have you really been looking for them?!
We have been looking...
Wait a sec!
All of you ladies had your purses stolen?
Yeah, that's right!
What does this mean?
The murdered Yoko-san only had her money stolen, and her purse was left at the scene!
Well then, Takagi-kun, I'll leave them with you.
Right, I'll drive them back safely.
Hold on, Detective Sato!
You've got a thread on your skirt.
No way! Oh no!
I forgot to take out the tacking stitch!
The tacking stitch?
Threads called tacking stitches are attached to slits and pleats on new skirts.
To make the fabric keep its shape, the ends are tied together with a knot.
The skirt I was supposed to wear today broke, so I rushed and bought this one.
So that's it!
Hi, Mouri here.
Inspector!
Are you sure?
Right, understood!
Did something happen?
The blood on the hoodman's extendable baton was found to be Yoko-san's blood.
What?!
Then that means...
Yeah! Now we've even got evidence.
We can be sure that Yoko-san was killed by the hoodman!
You must be glad to hear that, Mizuki-san.
Yes. It'll make Yoko happy from up in heaven too.
I'm stuffed!
Oh, waitress! I'll have another beer and some kara'age!
Oh, you've had enough!
Don't worry! I just solved a case!
I'm telling you this isn't the proper time and place!
Mizuki-san just lost a close friend!
Let's not argue, both of you...
Sorry.
Yoko and I used to argue and talk here a lot, so you brought back some memories.
Mizuki-san...
But I'm glad her killer was caught.
It really is all thanks to you!
Stop, Dad!
That's my hand towel!
That one's yours!
Really?
Geez, I can't believe you...
Sorry, sorry. Here, you can have it back.
No way! I'm not using that now!
What's it matter? They're all the same!
It's not the same!
I see... So that's it...
Oh, I've got it, Tachibana-san!
No, let me. I want to show my gratitude.
No, I wouldn't want it to cause problems for you later, you know?
Is that so? I'm sorry...
Well then, I'll let you...
The total is ¥10,250.
Huh? That's quite a lot. I-I hope I have enough...
It was a real feast.
Sorry, Takagi.
Really, thank you so much.
Oh, and I know this is a tough time, but don't give up, okay?
If you get lonely, call me anytime...
I'll be right over!
Sorry about that, just ignore him.
Well then, I should say goodbye.
Dad?
Mouri-san?
The pain has finally awoken me to the truth.
This case is not settled yet!
Not settled, Mouri-san...?
I mean that the hoodman wasn't Yoko-san's murderer.
What do you mean? You even said there was evidence earlier...
No, there's too much that doesn't fit, if he was her murderer.
Doesn't fit?
Yoko-san had the cash taken from her purse, and her purse left behind at the scene.
But wasn't he after her money?
No. In the previous three thefts,
he stole the victims' purses too.
So why would this time be different?
I did think it was odd. But that's hardly enough...
Next, the wound on the corpse.
It was on the left side of Yoko-san's head.
Yoko-san was attacked from behind.
Which means the culprit hit Yoko-san with the baton in their left hand.
In other words, her killer was left-handed. But the hoodman was...
Right-handed!
Incidentally, Mizuki-san, you called her with the phone in your left hand, and used your left hand when you went to pay.
I-I certainly am left-handed.
But so are a lot of other people, right?
I'm not finished yet. Yoko-san had a fresh coffee stain on her white inner shirt.
But the stain ended where it met her skirt, and there was no stain on her skirt.
And her skirt had the tacking stitch attached.
The tacking stitch?
Yes.
Tacking stitches are put in new skirts so they keep their shape.
I had an idea, and decided to check with the manager of the shop Yoko-san worked at.
Right when Yoko-san was leaving the clothing store for the day, she spilled coffee on her top and skirt.
Because of that, she bought a new jacket and skirt there, and changed into them before leaving.
That's why the coffee stain on her shirt cuts off, and why her skirt still had the tacking stitch on it.
What are you trying to say?
You said this about the dead Yoko-san...
She was so happy when we said goodbye this morning!
I never thought that would be the last time I'd see her alive!
Yoko...!
You hadn't seen Yoko-san since you said goodbye to her this morning, so how did you know?
How did you know about the clothes she wore after work?!
Mizuki-san?
S-She was probably wearing similar clothes this morning...
So I just mistook them...
Mizuki-san! Uncle wanted you to see this.
What's that?
But that's...
I had her manager send it over.
That's a photo of Yoko-san today, before she changed.
Now please tell me, Mizuki-san?
How does that look like a white jacket and beige skirt?
You did see Yoko-san.
After she left work.
But Mouri-san, that's not enough to say for sure that Mizuki-san murdered Yoko-san...
Yes. It is all circumstancial evidence. Nothing decisive.
How cruel! You're treating me like a killer just because of that?
Yoko was a close friend of mine!
She's right, Dad! If you're going to accuse someone, you should have good evidence!
Good evidence, huh?
Oh, the evidence exists.
It's right here.
Mizuki-san...
At the restaurant, for some reason you put your purse into your pocket, when you had taken it out of your bag.
Why didn't you put it back into your bag...?
You were afraid.
Afraid of me seeing inside your bag when you put it away...
There's something that you don't want us to see in your bag.
Right. I thought it was strange when we first met.
It's cold enough tonight that anyone would wear a coat.
But your clothes are far too light.
But if I assume that you had to take off your coat for some reason, then that would explain your light clothes.
That bag probably contains your coat, with Yoko-san's blood on it.
No, that's not all...
The hoodman's original extendable baton should be in your bag as well.
T-Then what was the baton the hoodman had?
The murder weapon Mizuki-san used to kill Yoko-san!
Isn't that right?
First, to make it look like the work of the hoodman, you researched the extendable baton he always used.
Then you bought another baton just like it, and used that extendable baton to kill Yoko-san.
But ironically, as you were leaving the scene, you were attacked by the real hoodman.
What a stroke of bad luck.
But the chance came to transform that luck from bad to good...
Hey! Are you okay?
The man in a hood went that way!
That was when you came up with a plan.
The way to use your accident with the hoodman to great advantage!
I see! So she swapped the hoodman's
extendable baton with her own!
That's why we found Yoko-san's blood on the hoodman's extendable baton.
Yeah. She even almost deceived me.
But the fuss about the hand towels made me realise...
That perhaps the murder weapon was swapped sometime, just like the hand towels.
Mizuki-san...
Ran hasn't left your side since we rescued you.
You haven't had time to dispose of your coat and baton.
Now, show us... Show us what's in your bag!
Mizuki-san...
Yoko...
yōko = "child of the sun"
She really was like the sun.
So bright, so selfish, and everything had to revolve around her...
mizuki = "beautiful moon"
She was the sun, and I was just like the powerless moon...
And that was Yoko's excuse to steal everything from me...
She took my clothes, my money, and my boyfriend, all like it was the natural thing to do.
But I still held back.
Until I heard her say that...
Oh, sorry, Mizuki will be back soon.
Oh, I wish the hoodman would just do her in.
She's such a nuisance.
That's why I attacked her instead and made it look like it was the hoodman!
Hey, Dad!
You ate my cake as a snack again, didn't you!
I-It wasn't me! I may have eaten your cakes before, but this time it was really that darn cat!
Trying to pin the blame on Goro-chan again, are we?
You really got away with the perfect crime.
Oh, you heard that call?
The collar's extended, and I can see your bra.
This is an off-shoulder, and that's the whole point of it!
Death by drowning, huh?
I'm taking you into custody for murder!
On the next Conan: Suspect: Makoto Kyōgoku? (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Bowling Alley
At a bowling alley...
Karate vs. Jeet Kune Do!
Why there?!