Karuizawa
Yes! Strike!
That's just like Ran!
Way to go!
Too bad about the tennis,
but bowling's also fun, right?
Well, there's also one guy who is drinking in desperation
because he can't watch tennis girls in miniskirts...
Hey, you're up next, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Go for it, Conan-kun.
Hang in there, brat.
And? Who is it? The person
you wanted me to meet?
Ah, that's...
Someone who was waiting in the pouring rain at the tennis court for 4 hours!
That person is changing into dry clothes
right now and will then come here.
Stop beating around the bush and just spit it out.
That person is coming here on a bike in this rain!
What the hell's with you?
You want to go at it, huh?
Jeet Kune Do...
He dodged it!
Interesting!
I'll knock you down!
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
A man Sonoko'll be pleased to see,
and an explosive situation at a bowling alley!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Jun'ichi Higashi
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Urakami
Keiko Urakami
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Shigenobu Kaihoko
Executive Producer
Seiko Terajima
Planning Support
Hiroshi Torimitsu
Kazumasa Ogura
Masakazu Hakuya
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Presented by
Interesting!
I'll knock you down!
Ah, no, Sera-san!
It's that person! The one
Sonoko wanted you to meet!
My boyfriend, Makoto Kyogoku-san!
This girl is my classmate, Masumi Sera-san!
Y-You're a girl...
Please forgive me...
I thought you were some insolent guy
who was getting overly friendly with Sonoko-san.
Don't worry about it! I'm always being mistaken for a guy!
Really, Sonoko! You should have stopped them earlier!
But I wanted to see those two fight!
Geez, what would you've done if one of them got hurt?
Kyogoku-san!
Here's your glasses!
So sorry...
I'm much obliged.
Oh, it's no biggie.
I wanted to try fighting him a little more too.
Sheesh...
Jeet Kune Do... Who taught you that?
My older brother! Well, my brother was
three times stronger than me, though.
B-But...
Didn't you say your older brother was dead?
Yeah, that's what I heard.
B-But weren't you talking on the phone
with your brother the other day?
Ah, you overheard that?
I have another one!
My smart second-oldest brother...
He takes after our father,
unlike my late brother and me,
so he doesn't look like me.
But it seems that he's in the middle
of an important job right now,
and he won't even tell me where he is.
But he sometimes advises me
on a case on the phone!
During the case the other day he also told me
that my deduction was unreliable,
but since you were there to
come to the rescue if I was wrong...
Ah, not me, but Shinichi-niichan!
Could it be that she knows I'm Shin'ichi Kudo?
By the way, Sonoko-san...
Did something go wrong
when you washed that shirt?
Eh? Go wrong?
The collar is so wide, your underwear is visible.
I-It's called off-shoulder and it's done on purpose!
I'm showing it off!
S-Showing it off?
That underwear is meant to be shown off?
T-That's right.
Sonoko got all dressed up for you, Kyogoku-san!
More importantly, Kyogoku-san, there's blood
coming from the back of your right hand.
Could it be that when you
fought Sera-san earlier...
Ah, no, this is from outside...
Excuse me...
I'm sorry about earlier! Are you all right?
Michiko Mon'na (30)
Middle School Math Teacher
It's nothing. My wounds are very shallow.
More importantly, how is he?
He's fine. He's simply suffering
the consequences of his actions.
An acquaintance is taking him home in the car.
Did something happen?
When I went to buy some
clothes to change into earlier,
I became entangled with an
acquaintance of this woman,
and he punched me in the solar plexus.
He may not look it, but he
teaches PE at a middle school!
Sunami Masaki (29)
Middle School Science Teacher
Usually Tamba-sensei is an
earnest, steady teacher,
but when he drinks, he
becomes a different person.
How is he?
He fell asleep in the car.
In his sleep, he whispered,
"I'm going to kill that bastard."
More importantly, what are
we going to do now?
That's right.
We were going to have him
teach us how to bowl, but...
Teachers!
Looks like you could use a hand.
Why not let a guy like me
show you how to do it?
Use your hips! The hips!
Move your hips this way!
Y-Yes...
When you hold the ball, the pivot leg, ball,
and head all need to be in a straight line, see?
Yes...
Now, you try!
Wow! Amazing!
That's it, magnificent!
Really, to be able to instruct a couple
of teachers. It's the highest honour, ladies!
Ah, yes...
That guy... He'll be brought in
for sexual harassment one day...
Makoto-san, good luck!
And it seems like this guy will be
arrested for property damage some day...
It would appear that this sort of
fashionable game doesn't suit me.
S-So it seems...
I only returned to Japan today,
so I also have a bit of jet lag.
In that case, why don't you
take a nap in Dad's rental car?
Seeing how I have the key...
Well, I'll take you up on that offer then.
Just when I was finally
on a date with Makoto-san...
Come on, we're going out
to dinner afterwards as well!
Oh, where are you going, Michiko?
I'm going to see how Tamba-sensei is doing.
I'm a bit worried about him.
I see...
He'll be back once he sobers up.
Huh? He isn't there?!
Tamba-sensei wasn't in the car?
No, seems like he got out of
the car and went somewhere.
Then why didn't he come here?
Who knows? Maybe he's sleeping
in the shade of some car.
Stop joking! It's been raining
this whole time, hasn't it?
T-That's true...
Excuse me...
If you're looking for someone, why
don't you leave it to me, Kogoro Mouri?
My father is a detective.
K-Kogoro Mouri?
That famous detective?!
Sensei!
Tamba-sensei!
Are you there?
It's no use! He isn't anywhere between the cars!
Could it be that he's in some bar, drinking again?
He isn't drunkenly bothering
someone else again, is he?
Let's look for him in nearby bars, then!
Yeah.
Hey! You guys go looking
around drinking places as well!
But how?
We don't even know what he looks like.
This is a picture of him.
Shall I send it to you?
Yeah.
Say, our rental car was also parked here, right?
Yes.
Ah, Kyogoku-san...
Yeah... Well, I don't think if Makoto-san were to get in a fight,
he'd fight back until they were beaten to a pulp...
I wouldn't say "beaten to a pulp", at any rate...
Damn! He's nowhere to be found.
Same here.
He didn't return to the car either!
He also turned off his mobile phone, it seems.
Really, where did he disappear to?
What's that? What's that sound?
I also looked underneath the cars,
but it really seems like he isn't
anywhere in this parking lot.
Then should we ask the police
to look for him after all?
W-What happened?
The door of the toilet was
unlocked, so I opened it...
A-And inside...
There's petechiae on the eyelid and conjunctiva.
And foam is coming from his mouth.
No facial edema.
And no sign of strangulation on the neck.
Death by drowning?!
There's also no sign of his having
been restrained on his arms and legs,
and since his clothes are soaking wet...
What?
He was carried here after
being drowned somewhere?
Yes, given the state of the livor mortis and
rigor mortis, he was killed about an hour ago.
Just about the time when we starting looking
for him and went to various drinking places.
Which means that the killer tossed the corpse
into this toilet and escaped before we returned.
N-No way...
Who on earth...
This teacher's pretty strongly built,
so it was either a repeat offender,
or someone really strong.
Umm...
Did something happen?
So, the person who was killed...
was Masahiro Tamba-san, 32,
who taught PE at a middle school.
And the one who found the body
was a science teacher from the same
middle school, Masaki Sunami-san, right?
Yes.
Well then, could you please tell me
how you found him in more detail, ma'am?
Y-Yes...
Today Tamba-sensei and I had planned to go
bowling together with our colleague, Michiko,
but drunk from the beer he had drunk on the car ride here,
he started to act violently
downtown. It was quite stressful.
We thought it might be best to let him sleep it off, so I brought him to Michiko's car.
Colleague, you say... Does that mean
you're also a middle school teacher?
Ah, yes. I teach math.
I see.
And then? What happened next?
After Sunami and I had been
bowling for about an hour,
I went to the car to check up on him.
He had a lot of things going on,
so I didn't want to leave him on his own.
But when I came to the car, he wasn't there.
Flustered by his disappearance,
all of us started looking for him.
When you say all of you...
At the bowling alley,
we happened to meet...
None other than me, Kogoro Mouri!
Ahh, Mouri-san, what a pleasant surprise!
So we searched the parking lot,
but didn't find him.
And thinking that he might be getting drunk again in a bar somewhere,
we divided the area between ourselves,
with my daughter and her friends helping out as well,
and searched in the bars around here for about an hour,
but we didn't find him anywhere,
so we came back to this parking lot,
thinking that he might have returned to the car.
And just as we had thought, he had returned.
Into this toilet stall on the parking lot,
as a cold, drowned corpse, that is!
D-Drowned?
Is that true?
Yes. Without an autopsy we can't be 100% sure,
but going from the state of the body,
that is most likely the case.
What is the estimated time of death?
It should be around 5 PM.
I see, 5 PM, huh?
That's around the time when we left this parking lot
to look around the various bars, right?
Yeah.
But why did you not look inside the toilet
the first time you searched the parking lot?
It was locked with a padlock, and an
"out of order" sign was stuck to the door.
Stuck to the door, you say?
Ah, I saw that too!
But when we came to look here for the
second time that sign had been removed,
and since the padlock was
also nowhere to be seen...
A-And when I opened the door...
T-Tamba-sensei was...
Which means... Between the time when
Sunami-san accompanied the victim to the car,
and the time when Michiko-san checked up on him
an hour later, someone got him away from here.
Then they drowned him while Mouri-san
and the others were going around the bars.
They brought the corpse back here and placed it
inside the stall before Mouri-san returned.
Yes, that's right.
By the way, what was that about
keeping watch on Tamba-san?
Well, he becomes like a different person when drunk,
easily picking fights with strangers.
That's why he said he wouldn't drink
even one today, but in the end...
Inspector Yamamura!
There's a bruise on the victim's abdomen.
A bruise?
Oh, you're right.
Ah, my bad, Inspector.
He was drunk and starting an argument
over nothing, swung his fist at me,
so I hit him in the solar plexus without thinking.
Over nothing?
He screamed that our eyes
had met, or something similar.
You are a very good-natured person, are you not?
You helped Mr. Mouri-san and the
others looking for that drunk, right?
No, I was taking a nap in Mouri-san's car,
which was parked here, at the time.
I am taking you into custody for murder!
H-Hey, wait a moment, Yamamura.
Would he really murder someone
just because they picked a fight with him?
What're you saying?
What are you saying, Mouri-san?!
He clearly just confessed with
a cleverness that could rival my own!
Saying that he has a motive and no alibi!
T-That's not enough to immediately
arrest him though, is it?
He's fumbling along as always.
What are you saying?!
There's no way Makoto-san is guilty!
Then you can prove his innocence?
Yes, I can!
Because... Because Makoto-san is...
Makoto-san is...?
Absolutely fantastic and nice and a good person!
That's no proof at all...
Inspector Yamamura, please look at this.
There's a burn mark at the tip of his left shoulder.
This means the victim was probably
knocked out with a stun gun.
S-Stun gun?
If the killer used a stun gun,
this guy here should be innocent.
Huh? W-Why?
Because he can knock someone out with
nothing but a punch to the stomach,
and since the victim was already bruised
there from the first time he punched him...
But what if he used a stun gun
on purpose to make us think that?
I can't believe that he would walk around with a stun
gun for protection, seeing how he's a karate master.
K-Karate master?
He's been winning championships all over!
Yeah! Undefeated in 400 matches,
he's the prince of kicks!
If that's the case, you should've said so earli—
Please say so earlier, Mouri-san.
You already met during
the red handkerchief case, you know.
Yamamura, are you feeling unwell?
You sound so formal all of a sudden.
You were usually so casual all the time.
I-I did that on purpose so people
would let their guard down around me.
But as an Inspector I should
preserve a certain dignity!
Ah, I see...
So, if you were here the whole time,
did you see anything?
A suspicious person for example?
I was fast asleep, so...
I see, you were fast asleep...
S-Stop!
I said stop...
That was close.
Could it be that the ground
is inclined downwards here?
Yes, there's a slight inclination
due to land subsidence.
It seems like they're planning to work
on the road surface here next month.
I see.
Land subsidence...
Wait a sec! In that case...
The slanted dirt marks on this wall...
Could it be?
R-Rain...
No way! It's raining again.
Let us go inside the bowling alley for now.
We can continue our talk there.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
If you don't go soon...
Say.
Isn't it a bit strange around the vents there?
It's the only place where the raindrops don't
run down, but form a sort of ring, right?
It's a bit sticky.
Maybe something was affixed there.
Hey, you guys should also quickly go inside!
Yes!
The raindrops are similarly repelled around the door.
Almost like it had been weatherized with duct tape.
But this was a drowning, not a suffocation, right?
Yeah.
But the same is not true for the
vents at the bottom of the door.
If it's weatherstripping,
it makes no sense...
Yeah...
And also, didn't you smell something
when we first entered the toilet?
Yeah...
The smell of kerosene!
You guys!
Didn't you hear me earlier?
Yes, yes.
We're going now!
He definitely drowned?
Really?
Yes!
The coroner just informed me that water had
accumulated in his respiratory tracts.
But, even assuming that he
was knocked out with a stun gun,
drowning such a fit man
without tying him up somehow...
Wouldn't you need two
or three people for that?
That is true.
Well, if it were a karate master,
one would be more than enough.
What's that? Are you still
suspecting Makoto-san?
N-Not particularly...
I was also informed that there's pressure marks
in the form of a line on the corpse's lower abdomen...
On the lower abdomen?
Yes... There were no such marks on the back.
So maybe the killer carried the corpse by the belt.
I see...
You would need to have quite powerful arms for that.
Like a karate master, for example.
I-I said for example. For example.
That reminds me, you said that the victim had a lot of
things going on earlier. What did you mean by that?
Well...
Sunami Masaki (29)
Middle School Science Teacher
Michiko Mon'na (30)
Middle School Math Teacher
Tamba-sensei and my little
sister were planning to marry,
but his father was against it.
It seems his parents had already
arranged for him to marry another girl.
When they found out,
the two of them were shocked.
I think they had considered
eloping at one point.
But in the end, only my sister killed herself
by jumping into the ocean to drown...
Did they talk to you about eloping?
Yes. I got an e-mail from my sister...
"The two of us are going away together", it said...
I got that mail as well.
Since she and I were classmates and best friends...
It was from that point on, wasn't it? That Tamba-sensei
would start getting violent when drunk...
Yes... That's why, when he
woke up while we were bowling...
He probably got into a fight
with someone and then...
Say. Do you come often to this bowling alley?
Yes. Since the girl who passed away loved bowling...
Speaking of which, it rained the last
few times we came here as well...
Inspector Yamamura!
We found a wet towel and four strange empty cans
in the bin next to the toilet!
Empty cans?
Yes...
All four are burned around the opening.
Maybe it is because someone
used them as an ashtray?
B-But the smell of kerosene comes from inside...
Kerosene?
Ah, wait... Conan-kun?!
Mr. Forensics Guy!
Can't you check it out? That shelf over there...
No, no! Kids should be over there!
But Uncle Kogoro said that there might be
something in the spare toilet paper roll(s)...
Geez, what an obstinate boy... But, well, if you say
that Sleeping Kogoro asked you to check it out...
Burn marks on the ceiling?
Hey! Take some pictures!
R-Right!
So it's like that after all...
That explains why the lower part of the wall
inside the toilet was curiously wet like that...
There's no doubt about it!
That person was the killer!
"It seems like he has
also arrived at the truth..."
"But whether or not our deductions are the same...
Lately I've been losing confidence in that regard..."
Oh! That was quick!
"Who is he?", is it?
I guess that was to be expected...
Oh! It came!
"If it's him there's no problem", you say?
A fight! It was a fight!
The drunken victim who was sleeping in the car
woke up, went to some bar to start drinking again
and there it came to a fight with someone...
He was taken somewhere and killed!
But Mouri-san, when you and your companions
went around the bars to look for the victim,
did not everyone say they had not seen him?
They were probably just playing dumb!
Since the bar's reputation would suffer if it came out
that customers had been brawling there!
But why was the killer carrying a stun gun?
Furthermore, where and why
did he drown the victim?
And there's absolutely no reason for the killer
to leave the corpse in the toilet on the parking lot
where the victim had been sleeping in the car.
How should I know?!
In any case, the victim, Tamba-sensei,
was brought to the car on this
parking lot by Masaki-sensei here
in order to sleep off his inebriation.
And before Mon'na-sensei went
to check on him about an hour later,
he must have woken up and left the car.
And while we went looking for
Tamba-sensei in various bars
after hearing that he had disappeared...
After getting into an argument with someone somewhere,
he was drowned, and before we
came back to the parking lot again,
he was placed inside the toilet on the
parking lot. There's no doubt about it!
Well, you could say that the person who was taking a nap
in the car on that same parking lot the whole time...
this karate guy is suspicious as well...
But considering the fact that
the killer used a stun gun,
he's completely innocent.
That's why I'm saying you should
hurry up and go around the bars,
to properly question people!
I-I suppose you're right.
Inspector Yamamura!
The preparations for the experiment are finished!
Experiment?
Ah, yes...
One of the forensics people said that
Detective Mouri needed it to solve the case...
And that you had given your permission, Inspector...
Huh? What're you saying?!
I don't remember saying anything like that!
B-But according to the forensic scientist, this boy...
A-Anyway, let's go take a look! I love experiments!
Would some shrimp who's in the first year of grade
school even have done an experiment before?
Ah, but he might have done so at Doc's...
Well, let's go and find out what's going on!
Good idea.
"If it's him there's no problem"?
Why?
Why does my brother...
know this kid?
Hey, now! What's this?
The area around the toilet is totally flooded!
Ah, but... You ordered us to do so, didn't you?
You said we should put a towel over the drain
to hold back the rain water and let it accumulate...
I see, since the ground is inclined
here due to land subsidence...
The rain that fell until a little
while ago has accumulated...
But like this, the valuable
crime scene is completely ruined.
We transferred the toilet box with the corpse
somewhere else and are in the process of examining it.
This is a different toilet box.
This was also done on Detective Mouri's order.
As I've said before, I didn't say any such—
D-Dad?! There's water gathered there!
What does it matter if my pants get wet?
If it helps me verify this trick, that is!
W=When you say trick...
Could it be... that the victim was drowned
using this accumulated rain water?
But it takes quite a while
for this much rain water to gather.
Furthermore, even if the victim
was knocked out by a stun gun,
you would need quite a bit of force to drown
a grown man in this water without binding him up.
That means the killer must have been
someone rather strong after all, no?
I told you Makoto-san
isn't like that, didn't I?
Right, Makoto-san?
Ah, Makoto-san?!
He ran away!
Let him be!
He probably went to the toilet.
He has nothing to do with this.
But...
That's because you don't need to be
strong in order to use this trick.
The killer locked up the victim in the toilet.
And the victim was drowned
without being touched.
Just like magic...
Magic...
But seeing is believing,
so why don't we try it out?
Whether we can actually drown
someone inside that toilet...
Of course, Inspector Yamamura,
you'll be the guinea pig!
M-Me?!
Don't worry... I asked the forensics people
to prepare some oxygen for you...
Is that an oxygen flask?!
Hey, tomboy!
You can help set up the trick!
You also understood the trick that was used, right?
Yeah... I guess...
First the victim is placed in the toilet.
Then the vents at the back of the box are sealed with tape.
After that, we fill four cans with kerosene
and stuff some paper into the opening.
After lighting the paper up,
we place the cans on the rack inside the toilet.
Afterwards, we only need to close the door
and seal the openings with tape...
A-And how does he drown?
Just wait!
Geez...
The water doesn't reach farther than my ankles...
How could someone drown like this?
But it's getting rather hot...
It went out...
W-What was that?!
What just happened inside?!
Well then... Why don't you take a look?
Are you all right?
Have you any idea what you
put me through, Mouri-san?!
I could've drowned, you know?!
B-But why was there so much water inside the toilet?
Because the pressure inside the toilet fell.
Have you never seen that science experiment?
The one where you place a burning
candle in a bowl filled with water,
and put a beaker over the candle...
And when the flame goes out, more and
more water gets sucked into the beaker...
The same thing happened here!
The cans burn on the rack inside the airtight toilet,
the air becomes warmer and expands...
The amount of oxygen is reduced,
and when the flames go out the air
becomes cooler and contracts.
And to fill that space, the rain water that accumulated is
sucked into the toilet through the lower vents. That's all.
Is that about right?
Science teacher...
Masaki Sunami-san?
First you brought Tamba-sensei to the
toilet box while walking him to the car,
saying something like "I forgot my keys,
so please shelter from the rain inside the toilet."
Once he was inside, you knocked
him out with a stun gun,
and passed a piece of string through his belt,
which you then tied to the joints of the toilet seat,
preventing Tamba-sensei from standing up...
Then you placed the four cans filled with
kerosene on the rack inside the toilet...
and locked the door using a padlock,
putting up the "out of order" sign at the same time.
Afterwards you only had to seal
the vents on the back with tape,
and close off the drain with a towel,
so the rain water would
start to accumulate, and that's it.
You told Mon'na-sensei that he had
fallen asleep in the car, an easy lie,
and waited for the rain water to gather...
And after a while, Mon'na-sensei, who worries easily,
went to go look after Tamba-sensei, all according to plan...
Well, even if she hadn't done
so out of her own volition,
you probably intended go check on him
yourself while inviting her along...
Just like you had thought, she came back and
announced that Tamba-sensei wasn't in the car.
And once everyone started
searching the parking lot,
you confirmed that enough
rain water had gathered,
removed the sign stuck to the door,
lit the cans that were placed on the rack,
and sealed the door with tape.
Afterwards the rain water
was sucked into the toilet,
just like it happened in the experiment,
drowning Tamba-sensei.
While you were going around the bars with Mon'na-sensei, effectively giving you an alibi,
then you returned to the parking lot again,
removed the towel from the drain
so the accumulated water could drain off,
peeled off all of the tape,
threw the cans into the bin and cut the string
that had been fastened to Tamba-sensei's belt...
And in order to hide the fact that
the toilet had been filled with water,
you placed new toilet paper rolls on the rack,
before giving off a scream, as though
you had just discovered the body!
For this trick to work it is important
to find the body as soon as possible.
If the discovery is delayed, the time span
for the estimated time of death widens,
nullifying the painstakingly created alibi.
That's why the murderer must be the person
who discovered the body — in other words, you!
You are also the only one who could have created
the time for the rain water to accumulate!
The forensics people are probably retrieving
the tape with your fingerprints right about now.
Since it wasn't in the rubbish bin,
you must have flushed it down the toilet.
And peeling off tape is rather
difficult with gloves on.
Is that about right?
Sleeping Kogoro-san?
Y-Yes...
T-This must be some sort of mistake!
Because Sunami has no reason
at all to kill Tamba-sensei...
I do.
That man let my best friend die without doing anything.
What better motive could there be?
W-When you say best friend...
Are you talking about my sister?
Yes, your sister, who had
planned to marry that man!
But my sister threw herself
off a cliff by the ocean...
There was even a suicide note...
She wrote a mail beforehand, didn't she?
Saying "The two of us are going away together"...
That mail wasn't about eloping...
It was a double suicide note, saying the two of them
were going away to the next world together!
However, that man suddenly
became afraid of death,
and without trying to help your
drowning sister, he left that cliff...
I-Is that true?!
Yes...
When he was drunk that man
told me so without inhibition...
Saying "I'm a hopeless coward" while crying...
Well, even though he's like that...
My best friend loved him to death...
That's why I helped him get there...
Into the water where she was waiting for him...
You went to look for the killer?!
Yeah.
But I thought you didn't know who did it?
So how did you...
Since it appeared that the
killer was exceptionally strong,
I figured I would be able to
feel his killing intent if I saw him...
And if possible you wanted to
have a fight with him, is that it?
W-Well, that might have been...
He was simply looking for a fight...
As I've come to expect of you, Sleeping Kogoro!
Solving the case so superbly...
I-It was nothing, really...
As expected of the true me...
But, but, that experiment...
That fumbler, he's completely fallen
back to his old way of talking...
Well, she took all the good parts though...
Oh, that reminds me, Dad...
You've gotta change your pants
quickly or you'll catch cold!
After all, you were just doing your
deductions while sitting in a puddle.
W-What's this? I'm soaking wet!
Well, Uncle, you did say "What does
it matter if my pants get wet?"
Did I... say that?
You did, you did!
You were super cool!
Super cool?
A message... From my brother...
Ah, I see... So that's how it is...
A PS...
"PS: Have you already met the wizard?"
You could say so...