Karuizawa
Yes! Strike!
That's just like Ran!
Way to go!
Too bad about the tennis,
but bowling's also fun, right?
Well, there's also one guy who is drinking in desperation
because he can't watch tennis girls in miniskirts...
Hey, you're up next, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Go for it, Conan-kun.
Hang in there, brat.
And? Who is it? The person
you wanted me to meet?
Ah, that's...
Someone who was waiting in the pouring rain at the tennis court for 4 hours!
That person is changing into dry clothes
right now and will then come here.
Stop beating around the bush and just spit it out.
That person is coming here on a bike in this rain!
What the hell's with you?
You want to go at it, huh?
Jeet Kune Do...
He dodged it!
Interesting!
I'll knock you down!
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
A man Sonoko'll be pleased to see,
and an explosive situation at a bowling alley!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The Suspect is Makoto Kyogoku
(Part One)
Interesting!
I'll knock you down!
Ah, no, Sera-san!
It's that person! The one
Sonoko wanted you to meet!
My boyfriend, Makoto Kyogoku-san!
This girl is my classmate, Masumi Sera-san!
Y-You're a girl...
Please forgive me...
I thought you were some insolent guy
who was getting overly friendly with Sonoko-san.
Don't worry about it! I'm always being mistaken for a guy!
Really, Sonoko! You should have stopped them earlier!
But I wanted to see those two fight!
Geez, what would you've done if one of them got hurt?
Kyogoku-san!
Here's your glasses!
So sorry...
I'm much obliged.
Oh, it's no biggie.
I wanted to try fighting him a little more too.
Sheesh...
Jeet Kune Do... Who taught you that?
My older brother! Well, my brother was
three times stronger than me, though.
B-But...
Didn't you say your older brother was dead?
Yeah, that's what I heard.
B-But weren't you talking on the phone
with your brother the other day?
Ah, you overheard that?
I have another one!
My smart second-oldest brother...
He takes after our father,
unlike my late brother and me,
so he doesn't look like me.
But it seems that he's in the middle
of an important job right now,
and he won't even tell me where he is.
But he sometimes advises me
on a case on the phone!
During the case the other day he also told me
that my deduction was unreliable,
but since you were there to
come to the rescue if I was wrong...
Ah, not me, but Shinichi-niichan!
Could it be that she knows I'm Shin'ichi Kudo?
By the way, Sonoko-san...
Did something go wrong
when you washed that shirt?
Eh? Go wrong?
The collar is so wide, your underwear is visible.
I-It's called off-shoulder and it's done on purpose!
I'm showing it off!
S-Showing it off?
That underwear is meant to be shown off?
T-That's right.
Sonoko got all dressed up for you, Kyogoku-san!
More importantly, Kyogoku-san, there's blood
coming from the back of your right hand.
Could it be that when you
fought Sera-san earlier...
Ah, no, this is from outside...
Excuse me...
I'm sorry about earlier! Are you all right?
Michiko Mon'na (30)
Middle School Math Teacher
It's nothing. My wounds are very shallow.
More importantly, how is he?
He's fine. He's simply suffering
the consequences of his actions.
An acquaintance is taking him home in the car.
Did something happen?
When I went to buy some
clothes to change into earlier,
I became entangled with an
acquaintance of this woman,
and he punched me in the solar plexus.
He may not look it, but he
teaches PE at a middle school!
Sunami Masaki (29)
Middle School Science Teacher
Usually Tamba-sensei is an
earnest, steady teacher,
but when he drinks, he
becomes a different person.
How is he?
He fell asleep in the car.
In his sleep, he whispered,
"I'm going to kill that bastard."
More importantly, what are
we going to do now?
That's right.
We were going to have him
teach us how to bowl, but...
Teachers!
Looks like you could use a hand.
Why not let a guy like me
show you how to do it?
Use your hips! The hips!
Move your hips this way!
Y-Yes...
When you hold the ball, the pivot leg, ball,
and head all need to be in a straight line, see?
Yes...
Now, you try!
Wow! Amazing!
That's it, magnificent!
Really, to be able to instruct a couple
of teachers. It's the highest honour, ladies!
Ah, yes...
That guy... He'll be brought in
for sexual harassment one day...
Makoto-san, good luck!
And it seems like this guy will be
arrested for property damage some day...
It would appear that this sort of
fashionable game doesn't suit me.
S-So it seems...
I only returned to Japan today,
so I also have a bit of jet lag.
In that case, why don't you
take a nap in Dad's rental car?
Seeing how I have the key...
Well, I'll take you up on that offer then.
Just when I was finally
on a date with Makoto-san...
Come on, we're going out
to dinner afterwards as well!
Oh, where are you going, Michiko?
I'm going to see how Tamba-sensei is doing.
I'm a bit worried about him.
I see...
He'll be back once he sobers up.
Huh? He isn't there?!
Tamba-sensei wasn't in the car?
No, seems like he got out of
the car and went somewhere.
Then why didn't he come here?
Who knows? Maybe he's sleeping
in the shade of some car.
Stop joking! It's been raining
this whole time, hasn't it?
T-That's true...
Excuse me...
If you're looking for someone, why
don't you leave it to me, Kogoro Mouri?
My father is a detective.
K-Kogoro Mouri?
That famous detective?!
Sensei!
Tamba-sensei!
Are you there?
It's no use! He isn't anywhere between the cars!
Could it be that he's in some bar, drinking again?
He isn't drunkenly bothering
someone else again, is he?
Let's look for him in nearby bars, then!
Yeah.
Hey! You guys go looking
around drinking places as well!
But how?
We don't even know what he looks like.
This is a picture of him.
Shall I send it to you?
Yeah.
Say, our rental car was also parked here, right?
Yes.
Ah, Kyogoku-san...
Yeah... Well, I don't think if Makoto-san were to get in a fight,
he'd fight back until they were beaten to a pulp...
I wouldn't say "beaten to a pulp", at any rate...
Damn! He's nowhere to be found.
Same here.
He didn't return to the car either!
He also turned off his mobile phone, it seems.
Really, where did he disappear to?
What's that? What's that sound?
I also looked underneath the cars,
but it really seems like he isn't
anywhere in this parking lot.
Then should we ask the police
to look for him after all?
W-What happened?
The door of the toilet was
unlocked, so I opened it...
A-And inside...
There's petechiae on the eyelid and conjunctiva.
And foam is coming from his mouth.
No facial edema.
And no sign of strangulation on the neck.
Death by drowning?!
There's also no sign of his having
been restrained on his arms and legs,
and since his clothes are soaking wet...
What?
He was carried here after
being drowned somewhere?
Yes, given the state of the livor mortis and
rigor mortis, he was killed about an hour ago.
Just about the time when we starting looking
for him and went to various drinking places.
Which means that the killer tossed the corpse
into this toilet and escaped before we returned.
N-No way...
Who on earth...
This teacher's pretty strongly built,
so it was either a repeat offender,
or someone really strong.
Umm...
Did something happen?
So, the person who was killed...
was Masahiro Tamba-san, 32,
who taught PE at a middle school.
And the one who found the body
was a science teacher from the same
middle school, Masaki Sunami-san, right?
Yes.
Well then, could you please tell me
how you found him in more detail, ma'am?
Y-Yes...
Today Tamba-sensei and I had planned to go
bowling together with our colleague, Michiko,
but drunk from the beer he had drunk on the car ride here,
he started to act violently
downtown. It was quite stressful.
We thought it might be best to let him sleep it off, so I brought him to Michiko's car.
Colleague, you say... Does that mean
you're also a middle school teacher?
Ah, yes. I teach math.
I see.
And then? What happened next?
After Sunami and I had been
bowling for about an hour,
I went to the car to check up on him.
He had a lot of things going on,
so I didn't want to leave him on his own.
But when I came to the car, he wasn't there.
Flustered by his disappearance,
all of us started looking for him.
When you say all of you...
At the bowling alley,
we happened to meet...
None other than me, Kogoro Mouri!
Ahh, Mouri-san, what a pleasant surprise!
So we searched the parking lot,
but didn't find him.
And thinking that he might be getting drunk again in a bar somewhere,
we divided the area between ourselves,
with my daughter and her friends helping out as well,
and searched in the bars around here for about an hour,
but we didn't find him anywhere,
so we came back to this parking lot,
thinking that he might have returned to the car.
And just as we had thought, he had returned.
Into this toilet stall on the parking lot,
as a cold, drowned corpse, that is!
D-Drowned?
Is that true?
Yes. Without an autopsy we can't be 100% sure,
but going from the state of the body,
that is most likely the case.
What is the estimated time of death?
It should be around 5 PM.
I see, 5 PM, huh?
That's around the time when we left this parking lot
to look around the various bars, right?
Yeah.
But why did you not look inside the toilet
the first time you searched the parking lot?
It was locked with a padlock, and an
"out of order" sign was stuck to the door.
Stuck to the door, you say?
Ah, I saw that too!
But when we came to look here for the
second time that sign had been removed,
and since the padlock was
also nowhere to be seen...
A-And when I opened the door...
T-Tamba-sensei was...
Which means... Between the time when
Sunami-san accompanied the victim to the car,
and the time when Michiko-san checked up on him
an hour later, someone got him away from here.
Then they drowned him while Mouri-san
and the others were going around the bars.
They brought the corpse back here and placed it
inside the stall before Mouri-san returned.
Yes, that's right.
By the way, what was that about
keeping watch on Tamba-san?
Well, he becomes like a different person when drunk,
easily picking fights with strangers.
That's why he said he wouldn't drink
even one today, but in the end...
Inspector Yamamura!
There's a bruise on the victim's abdomen.
A bruise?
Oh, you're right.
Ah, my bad, Inspector.
He was drunk and starting an argument
over nothing, swung his fist at me,
so I hit him in the solar plexus without thinking.
Over nothing?
He screamed that our eyes
had met, or something similar.
You are a very good-natured person, are you not?
You helped Mr. Mouri-san and the
others looking for that drunk, right?
No, I was taking a nap in Mouri-san's car,
which was parked here, at the time.
I am taking you into custody for murder!
H-Hey, wait a moment, Yamamura.
Would he really murder someone
just because they picked a fight with him?
What're you saying?
What are you saying, Mouri-san?!
He clearly just confessed with
a cleverness that could rival my own!
Saying that he has a motive and no alibi!
T-That's not enough to immediately
arrest him though, is it?
He's fumbling along as always.
What are you saying?!
There's no way Makoto-san is guilty!
Then you can prove his innocence?
Yes, I can!
Because... Because Makoto-san is...
Makoto-san is...?
Absolutely fantastic and nice and a good person!
That's no proof at all...
Inspector Yamamura, please look at this.
There's a burn mark at the tip of his left shoulder.
This means the victim was probably
knocked out with a stun gun.
S-Stun gun?
If the killer used a stun gun,
this guy here should be innocent.
Huh? W-Why?
Because he can knock someone out with
nothing but a punch to the stomach,
and since the victim was already bruised
there from the first time he punched him...
But what if he used a stun gun
on purpose to make us think that?
I can't believe that he would walk around with a stun
gun for protection, seeing how he's a karate master.
K-Karate master?
He's been winning championships all over!
Yeah! Undefeated in 400 matches,
he's the prince of kicks!
If that's the case, you should've said so earli—
Please say so earlier, Mouri-san.
You already met during
the red handkerchief case, you know.
Yamamura, are you feeling unwell?
You sound so formal all of a sudden.
You were usually so casual all the time.
I-I did that on purpose so people
would let their guard down around me.
But as an Inspector I should
preserve a certain dignity!
Ah, I see...
So, if you were here the whole time,
did you see anything?
A suspicious person for example?
I was fast asleep, so...
I see, you were fast asleep...
S-Stop!
I said stop...
That was close.
Could it be that the ground
is inclined downwards here?
Yes, there's a slight inclination
due to land subsidence.
It seems like they're planning to work
on the road surface here next month.
I see.
Land subsidence...
Wait a sec! In that case...
The slanted dirt marks on this wall...
Could it be?
R-Rain...
No way! It's raining again.
Let us go inside the bowling alley for now.
We can continue our talk there.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
If you don't go soon...
Say.
Isn't it a bit strange around the vents there?
It's the only place where the raindrops don't
run down, but form a sort of ring, right?
It's a bit sticky.
Maybe something was affixed there.
Hey, you guys should also quickly go inside!
Yes!
The raindrops are similarly repelled around the door.
Almost like it had been weatherized with duct tape.
But this was a drowning, not a suffocation, right?
Yeah.
But the same is not true for the
vents at the bottom of the door.
If it's weatherstripping,
it makes no sense...
Yeah...
And also, didn't you smell something
when we first entered the toilet?
Yeah...
The smell of kerosene!
You guys!
Didn't you hear me earlier?
Yes, yes.
We're going now!