We were going to play tennis in Karuizawa, but it was canceled due to rain.
So we decided to go bowling.
And? Who is it?
The person you wanted me to meet?
Ah, that's...
Someone who was waiting in the pouring rain at the tennis court for 4 hours!
That person is changing into dry clothes
right now and will then come here.
Stop beating around the bush and just spit it out.
That person is coming here on a bike in this rain!
What the hell's with you?
Jeet Kune Do...
He dodged it!
Interesting!
I'll knock you down!
Ah, no, Sera-san!
It's that person! The one
Sonoko wanted you to meet!
As Sera and Kyogoku were about to start a fight, they got introduced to each other.
And we went to play bowling with
the teachers group we met there.
However, the PE teacher who was supposedly sleeping in the car went missing,
So we ended up searching for him.
W-What happened?
The door of the toilet was
unlocked, so I opened it...
A-And inside...
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
Sera receives a suspicious e-mail!
We'll find out the truth about Kyogoku today!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The Suspect is Makoto Kyogoku
(Part Two)
He definitely drowned?
Really?
Yes!
The coroner just informed me that water had
accumulated in his respiratory tracts.
But, even assuming that he
was knocked out with a stun gun,
drowning such a fit man
without tying him up somehow...
Wouldn't you need two
or three people for that?
That is true.
Well, if it were a karate master,
one would be more than enough.
What's that? Are you still
suspecting Makoto-san?
N-Not particularly...
I was also informed that there's pressure marks
in the form of a line on the corpse's lower abdomen...
On the lower abdomen?
Yes... There were no such marks on the back.
So maybe the killer carried the corpse by the belt.
I see...
You would need to have quite powerful arms for that.
Like a karate master, for example.
I-I said for example. For example.
That reminds me, you said that the victim had a lot of
things going on earlier. What did you mean by that?
Well...
Sunami Masaki (29)
Middle School Science Teacher
Michiko Mon'na (30)
Middle School Math Teacher
Tamba-sensei and my little
sister were planning to marry,
but his father was against it.
It seems his parents had already
arranged for him to marry another girl.
When they found out,
the two of them were shocked.
I think they had considered
eloping at one point.
But in the end, only my sister killed herself
by jumping into the ocean to drown...
Did they talk to you about eloping?
Yes. I got an e-mail from my sister...
"The two of us are going away together", it said...
I got that mail as well.
Since she and I were classmates and best friends...
It was from that point on, wasn't it? That Tamba-sensei
would start getting violent when drunk...
Yes... That's why, when he
woke up while we were bowling...
He probably got into a fight
with someone and then...
Say. Do you come often to this bowling alley?
Yes. Since the girl who passed away loved bowling...
Speaking of which, it rained the last
few times we came here as well...
Inspector Yamamura!
We found a wet towel and four strange empty cans
in the bin next to the toilet!
Empty cans?
Yes...
All four are burned around the opening.
Maybe it is because someone
used them as an ashtray?
B-But the smell of kerosene comes from inside...
Kerosene?
Ah, wait... Conan-kun?!
Mr. Forensics Guy!
Can't you check it out? That shelf over there...
No, no! Kids should be over there!
But Uncle Kogoro said that there might be
something in the spare toilet paper roll(s)...
Geez, what an obstinate boy... But, well, if you say
that Sleeping Kogoro asked you to check it out...
Burn marks on the ceiling?
Hey! Take some pictures!
R-Right!
So it's like that after all...
That explains why the lower part of the wall
inside the toilet was curiously wet like that...
There's no doubt about it!
That person was the killer!
"It seems like he has
also arrived at the truth..."
"But whether or not our deductions are the same...
Lately I've been losing confidence in that regard..."
Oh! That was quick!
"Who is he?", is it?
I guess that was to be expected...
Oh! It came!
"If it's him there's no problem", you say?
A fight! It was a fight!
The drunken victim who was sleeping in the car
woke up, went to some bar to start drinking again
and there it came to a fight with someone...
He was taken somewhere and killed!
But Mouri-san, when you and your companions
went around the bars to look for the victim,
did not everyone say they had not seen him?
They were probably just playing dumb!
Since the bar's reputation would suffer if it came out
that customers had been brawling there!
But why was the killer carrying a stun gun?
Furthermore, where and why
did he drown the victim?
And there's absolutely no reason for the killer
to leave the corpse in the toilet on the parking lot
where the victim had been sleeping in the car.
How should I know?!
In any case, the victim, Tamba-sensei,
was brought to the car on this
parking lot by Masaki-sensei here
in order to sleep off his inebriation.
And before Mon'na-sensei went
to check on him about an hour later,
he must have woken up and left the car.
And while we went looking for
Tamba-sensei in various bars
after hearing that he had disappeared...
After getting into an argument with someone somewhere,
he was drowned, and before we
came back to the parking lot again,
he was placed inside the toilet on the
parking lot. There's no doubt about it!
Well, you could say that the person who was taking a nap
in the car on that same parking lot the whole time...
this karate guy is suspicious as well...
But considering the fact that
the killer used a stun gun,
he's completely innocent.
That's why I'm saying you should
hurry up and go around the bars,
to properly question people!
I-I suppose you're right.
Inspector Yamamura!
The preparations for the experiment are finished!
Experiment?
Ah, yes...
One of the forensics people said that
Detective Mouri needed it to solve the case...
And that you had given your permission, Inspector...
Huh? What're you saying?!
I don't remember saying anything like that!
B-But according to the forensic scientist, this boy...
A-Anyway, let's go take a look! I love experiments!
Would some shrimp who's in the first year of grade
school even have done an experiment before?
Ah, but he might have done so at Doc's...
Well, let's go and find out what's going on!
Good idea.
"If it's him there's no problem"?
Why?
Why does my brother...
know this kid?
Hey, now! What's this?
The area around the toilet is totally flooded!
Ah, but... You ordered us to do so, didn't you?
You said we should put a towel over the drain
to hold back the rain water and let it accumulate...
I see, since the ground is inclined
here due to land subsidence...
The rain that fell until a little
while ago has accumulated...
But like this, the valuable
crime scene is completely ruined.
We transferred the toilet box with the corpse
somewhere else and are in the process of examining it.
This is a different toilet box.
This was also done on Detective Mouri's order.
As I've said before, I didn't say any such—
D-Dad?! There's water gathered there!
What does it matter if my pants get wet?
If it helps me verify this trick, that is!
W=When you say trick...
Could it be... that the victim was drowned
using this accumulated rain water?
But it takes quite a while
for this much rain water to gather.
Furthermore, even if the victim
was knocked out by a stun gun,
you would need quite a bit of force to drown
a grown man in this water without binding him up.
That means the killer must have been
someone rather strong after all, no?
I told you Makoto-san
isn't like that, didn't I?
Right, Makoto-san?
Ah, Makoto-san?!
He ran away!
Let him be!
He probably went to the toilet.
He has nothing to do with this.
But...
That's because you don't need to be
strong in order to use this trick.
The killer locked up the victim in the toilet.
And the victim was drowned
without being touched.
Just like magic...
Magic...
But seeing is believing,
so why don't we try it out?
Whether we can actually drown
someone inside that toilet...
Of course, Inspector Yamamura,
you'll be the guinea pig!
M-Me?!
Don't worry... I asked the forensics people
to prepare some oxygen for you...
Is that an oxygen flask?!
Hey, tomboy!
You can help set up the trick!
You also understood the trick that was used, right?
Yeah... I guess...
First the victim is placed in the toilet.
Then the vents at the back of the box are sealed with tape.
After that, we fill four cans with kerosene
and stuff some paper into the opening.
After lighting the paper up,
we place the cans on the rack inside the toilet.
Afterwards, we only need to close the door
and seal the openings with tape...
A-And how does he drown?
Just wait!
Geez...
The water doesn't reach farther than my ankles...
How could someone drown like this?
But it's getting rather hot...
It went out...
W-What was that?!
What just happened inside?!
Well then... Why don't you take a look?
Are you all right?
Have you any idea what you
put me through, Mouri-san?!
I could've drowned, you know?!
B-But why was there so much water inside the toilet?
Because the pressure inside the toilet fell.
Have you never seen that science experiment?
The one where you place a burning
candle in a bowl filled with water,
and put a beaker over the candle...
And when the flame goes out, more and
more water gets sucked into the beaker...
The same thing happened here!
The cans burn on the rack inside the airtight toilet,
the air becomes warmer and expands...
The amount of oxygen is reduced,
and when the flames go out the air
becomes cooler and contracts.
And to fill that space, the rain water that accumulated is
sucked into the toilet through the lower vents. That's all.
Is that about right?
Science teacher...
Masaki Sunami-san?
First you brought Tamba-sensei to the
toilet box while walking him to the car,
saying something like "I forgot my keys,
so please shelter from the rain inside the toilet."
Once he was inside, you knocked
him out with a stun gun,
and passed a piece of string through his belt,
which you then tied to the joints of the toilet seat,
preventing Tamba-sensei from standing up...
Then you placed the four cans filled with
kerosene on the rack inside the toilet...
and locked the door using a padlock,
putting up the "out of order" sign at the same time.
Afterwards you only had to seal
the vents on the back with tape,
and close off the drain with a towel,
so the rain water would
start to accumulate, and that's it.
You told Mon'na-sensei that he had
fallen asleep in the car, an easy lie,
and waited for the rain water to gather...
And after a while, Mon'na-sensei, who worries easily,
went to go look after Tamba-sensei, all according to plan...
Well, even if she hadn't done
so out of her own volition,
you probably intended go check on him
yourself while inviting her along...
Just like you had thought, she came back and
announced that Tamba-sensei wasn't in the car.
And once everyone started
searching the parking lot,
you confirmed that enough
rain water had gathered,
removed the sign stuck to the door,
lit the cans that were placed on the rack,
and sealed the door with tape.
Afterwards the rain water
was sucked into the toilet,
just like it happened in the experiment,
drowning Tamba-sensei.
While you were going around the bars with Mon'na-sensei, effectively giving you an alibi,
then you returned to the parking lot again,
removed the towel from the drain
so the accumulated water could drain off,
peeled off all of the tape,
threw the cans into the bin and cut the string
that had been fastened to Tamba-sensei's belt...
And in order to hide the fact that
the toilet had been filled with water,
you placed new toilet paper rolls on the rack,
before giving off a scream, as though
you had just discovered the body!
For this trick to work it is important
to find the body as soon as possible.
If the discovery is delayed, the time span
for the estimated time of death widens,
nullifying the painstakingly created alibi.
That's why the murderer must be the person
who discovered the body —
in other words, you!
You are also the only one who could have created
the time for the rain water to accumulate!
The forensics people are probably retrieving
the tape with your fingerprints right about now.
Since it wasn't in the rubbish bin,
you must have flushed it down the toilet.
And peeling off tape is rather
difficult with gloves on.
Is that about right?
Sleeping Kogoro-san?
Y-Yes...
T-This must be some sort of mistake!
Because Sunami has no reason
at all to kill Tamba-sensei...
I do.
That man let my best friend die without doing anything.
What better motive could there be?
W-When you say best friend...
Are you talking about my sister?
Yes, your sister, who had
planned to marry that man!
But my sister threw herself
off a cliff by the ocean...
There was even a suicide note...
She wrote a mail beforehand, didn't she?
Saying "The two of us are going away together"...
That mail wasn't about eloping...
It was a double suicide note, saying the two of them
were going away to the next world together!
However, that man suddenly
became afraid of death,
and without trying to help your
drowning sister, he left that cliff...
I-Is that true?!
Yes...
When he was drunk that man
told me so without inhibition...
Saying "I'm a hopeless coward" while crying...
Well, even though he's like that...
My best friend loved him to death...
That's why I helped him get there...
Into the water where she was waiting for him...
You went to look for the killer?!
Yeah.
But I thought you didn't know who did it?
So how did you...
Since it appeared that the
killer was exceptionally strong,
I figured I would be able to
feel his killing intent if I saw him...
And if possible you wanted to
have a fight with him, is that it?
W-Well, that might have been...
He was simply looking for a fight...
As I've come to expect of you, Sleeping Kogoro!
Solving the case so superbly...
I-It was nothing, really...
As expected of the true me...
But, but, that experiment...
That fumbler, he's completely fallen
back to his old way of talking...
Well, she took all the good parts though...
Oh, that reminds me, Dad...
You've gotta change your pants
quickly or you'll catch cold!
After all, you were just doing your
deductions while sitting in a puddle.
W-What's this? I'm soaking wet!
Well, Uncle, you did say "What does
it matter if my pants get wet?"
Did I... say that?
You did, you did!
You were super cool!
Super cool?
A message... From my brother...
Ah, I see... So that's how it is...
A PS...
"PS: Have you already met the wizard?"
You could say so...
I've already heard! Kid-sama is coming again, isn't he?
"Kid-sama"?
There'll be a showdown between Kyogoku-san and Kaitō Kid?!
Well, you'll see when we get there!
Yes. I will protect it until the end.
You may bet on this fist without fear.