Undefeated in 400 matches?
In karate tournaments all over the world?
I'll look forward to seeing how much further you can take that record, then!
Ah, well...
Unfortunately, I was unable to participate in the most recent tournament,
and lost by default...
He ditched the tournament for my sake and came here!
Er...
If it weren't for that, his epic undefeated streak would still continue!
However, physical prowess is of no use for the Suzuki family.
You! Are you prepared to shoulder the weight of the Suzuki Financial Group?
Now, Tomoko!
Don't you think it's too early for that sort of thing? After all, the two of them are still in high school.
Not at all.
Shiro Suzuki (51)
Sonoko's Father
(Chairman, Suzuki Financial Group)
Tomoko Suzuki (43)
Sonoko's Mother
Given the fact that our eldest daughter Ayako married into the Tomizawa family,
we are left with no choice
but to make Sonoko's future husband a part of our family and have him succeed you!
I had thought that we would choose someone adequate to take over the Suzuki family...
And now you tell me you've been dating some hobo who travels abroad while still in high school
to advance his combat skills like some wandering knight?!
What were you thinking, Sonoko?!
That's none of your business, is it?
I have no intention of succeeding the family name...
Now look here...
Now, now...
Makoto-kun... It's almost time for your flight home.
Shall I drive you to the airport?
We can continue this talk next time.
Ah, yes...
Please tell me how the next tournament turns out for you!
I may not look like it, but I'm actually a huge martial arts fan.
I will...
A call from Ran...
Excuse me! I'm still talking...
Hello?
Eh? Kaitō Kid?!
Early this morning, under the supervision of Suzuki Financial Group's advisor Jirokichi Suzuki...
Yes, that's right!
Kid has once more announced that he'll steal one of Jirokichi Suzuki's jewels...
They're bringing the advance notice on the news right now!
You're kidding! Seriously?!
I'll have to give Uncle Jirokichi a call immediately!
W-Wait a...
Really! Even though I called to tell her not to do anything silly since Kyogoku-san is around...
That seems to have backfired.
Hello? Uncle?
I've already heard! Kid-sama is coming again, isn't he?
"Kid-sama"?
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
A fight between the two people Sonoko loves?!
The final weapon of Jirokichi's fighting spirit!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Kaito Kid VS Makoto Kyogoku
(Part One)
O-One hundred losses in a row?!
Are you saying that it was completely beaten?!
The state-of-the-art security system
that was only finished a few days ago?!
Y-Yes.
Of course, it was merely a computer simulation, but...
The result of inputting all of Kaitō
Kid's movement patterns up to now
and starting a simulation run is...
H-He perfectly...
What shall I do? The heist is tomorrow!
At this rate, that guy'll have no trouble
taking it from right under my nose...
The alexandrite that I finally got my hands on
after searching the whole world for it...
The Green Emperor...
B-But considering Kid's disguise technique
that allows him to impersonate anyone,
as well as his sharp mind that lets him
react to any change in circumstances,
and adding in his almost inhuman physical abilities...
Any security system would give the same results...
In that case, should we decrease Kid's numbers
by 20 percent and try the simulation again?
He's human after all... and everyone
has a bad day once in a while...
As if!
That guy is a quick-witted great thief!
And what's more, he improves every time...
He's someone you can't beat even by
reducing his numbers to 20 percent!
But seeing how it's a streak of 100 losses,
putting the jewel on display when
I know it's going to be stolen is a bit...
This wasn't my intention, but it seems like
I'll have to postpone the exhibition this time...
Advisor Suzuki!
R-Right now, in the hall... there's a
strange man who wants to meet you!
What?!
Continuing this contest is futile.
I implore you to grant me an audience
with Advisor Jirokichi Suzuki!
What's going on?!
A-Advisor!
My name is Makoto Kyogoku.
I have the honor of going out with Sonoko-san.
Ah, you're Sonoko's boyfriend.
And, what's your business?
It has reached my ears that you hold onto a jewel
that a certain thief intends to take possession of, sir.
In that case, if you would graciously allow...
My humble self, Makoto Kyogoku...
To have the honor of joining the security detail...
I refuse!
I-I implore you to reconsider...
Young one...
You're probably don't understand
why Sonoko has a crush on him, right?
But don't you worry!
That's like the measles...
T-The measles?
Once I've caught that guy, she'll forget all about him!
A-Advisor?!
Well then, go home!
Oh, Sonoko? Good timi—
Say, could it be that Makoto is with you?
Advisor! Just another word!
We're at Haneda Airport right now.
But when his plane started boarding,
Makoto-san had disappeared...
It seems that he asked our driver for your address...
So I thought he might have gone to your place...
What kind of man is he?
I heard that he did karate, but...
He doesn't just do karate! He was undefeated in 400
matches in a row in tournaments all over the world!
He is without equal in a fight —
the prince of kicks!
U-Undefeated... in 400 matches?
Huh? Please don't place guards inside the room where the jewel will be on display?
Why on earth?
Kaitō Kid is going to try to steal it!
Advisor Suzuki just called and told me
that people would get in the way
of his state-of-the-art security system.
That old man again... What is he thinking?!
And I received this video just after the phone call.
V-Video?
O-One man is... Surrounded by a
bunch of men pointing guns at him?!
Of course, the bullets are BBs, but with this
number of people at point-blank range...
And taking into account that the field of vision of the man in the middle is obstructed by the gas mask,
you'd think he had no chance of
avoiding the bullets, wouldn't you?
Please allow me to defeat you all at once.
His name is Makoto Kyogoku. According to the advisor,
it seems like he's the world's strongest security system.
T-The world's strongest?!
You know her as well right?
The advisor's niece, Miss Sonoko...
Looks like he's her boyfriend.
B-Boyfriend?!
Interesting...
Oh my...
Don't tell me. You intend to stay in the museum like this all night?
Yes. I desire to imprint the room's dimensions onto my mind.
As fortune would have it, I happened to have a sleeping bag...
And some provisions on my person as well...
Say...
Won't you make a bet with me?
A... bet?
There'll be a showdown between Kyogoku-san and Kaitō Kid?!
Really?!
Yes!
It seems like Makoto-san had a talk with Uncle Jirokichi!
Hearing me mention Kid-sama got him all hot-blooded!
To think that sparks will fly between
the two hot guys that surround me...
That's so awesome!
That surround you, you say...
Even though Kid has never paid attention to Sonoko...
And? Who would you like to win,
between Kid and Kyogoku-san?
Well, of course I want Makoto-san to win.
But you could say I don't want Kid-sama to lose either...
What's that supposed to be? At least have an opinion!
Because Makoto-san is... my... important... darling...
Hello? Sonoko? The connection seems...
Hello? Ran? Ran!
No way?! No signal...
A phone jammer...
Good evening, milady.
K-Kaitō Kid?!
W-Why are you here?
I merely stopped by to stretch my tired wings.
And, though it would be no more than the icing on the cake...
Might I also persuade you to make a bet with me?
A bet?
Kaitō Kid came last night?
To your room?
That's right!
He stood by the window as though he was Peter Pan!
Although he had to leave almost
immediately since our guard saw him...
Haven't you heard about it?
How would I have heard about it?!
And? What did Kid want?
Well, you see...
Might I persuade you to make a bet with me? he said...
As a reward for managing to take the jewel...
allow me to take your lips as well?
That's obviously a lie.
What did he really say?
A-Ah, in reality...
He asked me to tell Uncle Jirokichi
that if he successfully steals the alexandrite
Green Emperor that is being put on public display,
fe would like one work of art of his choice
from those held by the Suzuki Financial Group
in exchange for the stolen jewel.
Which item does he want?
Who knows? He said he'd tell us after stealing the jewel.
So? What did you answer?
Naturally, I told him, Go jump in a lake!
We will never accept any terms by a villain like you, I said!
Really?
Well, I might have said it a bit more softly than that...
That's strange.
Kaitō Kid only targets so-called Big Jewels.
And such jewels, if they were in
the hands of the Suzuki Financial Group,
should already have been used
by Advisor Suzuki to lure Kid out.
And why would he ask Sonoko for something that important?
Speaking of which, what's Kyogoku-san
doing to protect the jewel?
Ah, Makoto-san is...
...already with the jewel!
A-Already, you say?
That jewel is on public display as of today, isn't it?
Yes, at the Grand Suzuki Museum
where we're headed right now!
Don't tell me he's standing beside the display case
with a stern expression or something like that?
Well, you'll see when we get there!
Huh? Why's the jewel hanging from such a boring place?
Isn't that weird?
It's fine, it's fine.
See?
I-Indeed...
He's with the jewel alright...
Well done, Sonoko!
Just like my niece to choose a warrior like him as your partner!
Uncle Jirokichi!
But the time announced by Kid
is 10 PM, after the public has left.
There's no need to do something like this already...
It was his own wish!
To prevent Kid from stealthily exchanging
the jewel before the announced time,
and then pretending to steal it at the correct time!
However, even if he's a karate master,
he's still a high school student, right?
Leaving the protection of the jewel to him alone is...
Didn't you see it?
The video which I sent to the MPD?
Where he utterly defeated eleven men with lightning speed?
But still... if he's plunged into darkness
by Kid's specialty, the blackout...
No worries.
He's the prince of kicks, who possesses the mind's eye!
If we're plunged into darkness,
he's the one who'll have an advantage!
And what is more...
I also have a secret plan.
S-Secret plan?
Kid's favorite stunt is posing as someone close to us,
using his disguise technique to approach the targeted jewel.
Like when he impersonated my husband...
That was only because I fell for that fake phone call.
The two of you have also experienced that
quite often, have you not, Inspector Nakamori?
Y-Yes... That's why...
We pinch people's cheeks like this from time to time...
That may be acceptable for you gentlemen. However...
Ouch...
Doing something so boorish to a woman
is rather a different matter, in my opinion...
That is why I prepared...
This western dress, the only one of its kind in the world,
specially ordered from a Parisian designer,
and it only arrived today!
B-But this dress... If Kid put you to sleep and took it off...
That only applies to you gentlemen.
As far as I know, Kid has never impersonated
a woman with all her possessions.
Which means, as long as I wear this dress,
you can confirm at one glance that it is truly me!
I-I see...
Sera doesn't count, huh?
Of course, I also prepared western
dresses for Sonoko and her friend.
F-For me as well? Even though we only
dropped by on the way home from school...
Please change into them later.
Only after pinching each other's cheek like this, of course...
Y-Yes...
And...
Well, I'm sure the advisor doesn't want to
let this boy, the Kid Killer, go home, right?
Ah, that reminds me!
When I checked the mailbox this morning,
this letter from Kid-sama was in it!
What?!
Addressed to Makoto-san...
What on earth... Could he...?
B-Blank?
Could he be meaning to turn this time's
advance notice back to a blank slate?
That guy... Is he afraid of the karate master?
I don't think it's blank.
This is invisible writing, isn't it?
It smells fruity...
I-Invisible writing?!
Let's use my lighter to find out.
Some letters seem to appear...
Let's fight fair and square. —Kaitō Kid.
Eh? Just that?
Yes. There is nothing on the backside either.
It is probably meant as a foolish challenge, along the lines of...
If you think you can reveal me this easily, then come and try it...
Sonoko, Ran-chan,
let's go get you changed...
Ah, yes...
But before that...
When you're grown up.
Good luck, Makoto-san!
Ah, thanks...
I...
believe in you!
Yes. I will protect it until the end.
You may bet on this fist without fear.
Let's go, Sonoko.
I also believe...
that you will keep that promise you made.
Yes...
Of course.