Sonoko brought Makoto along to her family house, but...
Sonoko's mother, Tomoko, hates him.
And when he sees Sonoko's excitement at the mention of Kaitō Kid...
"Kid-sama"?
What's going on?!
A-Advisor!
My name is Makoto Kyogoku.
I have the honor of going out with Sonoko-san.
Ah, you're Sonoko's boyfriend.
And, what's your business?
It has reached my ears that you hold onto a jewel
that a certain thief intends to take possession of, sir.
In that case, if you would graciously allow...
My humble self, Makoto Kyogoku...
To have the honor of joining the security detail...
What kind of man is he?
I heard that he did karate, but...
He doesn't just do karate! He was undefeated in 400
matches in a row in tournaments all over the world!
He is without equal in a fight —
the prince of kicks!
U-Undefeated... in 400 matches?
Huh? Please don't place guards inside the room where the jewel will be on display?
Kaitō Kid is going to try to steal it!
Advisor Suzuki just called and told me
that people would get in the way
of his state-of-the-art security system.
O-One man is... Surrounded by a
bunch of men pointing guns at him?!
Of course, the bullets are BBs, but with this
number of people at point-blank range...
And taking into account that the field of vision of the man in the middle is obstructed by the gas mask,
you'd think he had no chance of
avoiding the bullets, wouldn't you?
He's the world's strongest security system.
But, Tomoko paid a visit to Makoto,
and so did Kid with Sonoko.
Each offered some kind of bet.
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
Kaitō Kid's surprise strategy.
The battle of the security systems is on.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Kaito Kid VS Makoto Kyogoku
(Part Two)
Good luck, Makoto-san!
Ah, thanks...
I...
believe in you!
Yes. I will protect it until the end.
You may bet on this fist without fear.
Let's go, Sonoko.
I also believe...
that you will keep that promise you made.
Yes...
Of course.
Right. I'll be counting on you.
Won't you make a bet with me?
A... bet?
If you manage to protect the jewel,
I shall consider that a sign of heaven
and accept you as Sonoko's partner.
However, should, on the other hand,
that thief manage to beat you,
you will give up on Sonoko once and for all.
Do we have a deal?
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid!
What?! Letters from Kid arrived here at the museum?
And addressed to this man again?
Y-Yes, about 100 letters, all at once...
O-One hundred?!
It would seem that the writing is invisible again...
Oh geez, we can't go through
100 letters one by one with a lighter!
In that case, might you be so good
as to prepare a candle and a candle stick?
If we use those to heat the letters,
we can save a lot of time and effort.
Hey! Somebody bring a candle and a candlestick!
W-What is this?
"The greatest thief in the whole world never lets his prey escape."
"Nothing is impossible for the moonlight magician."
"The opponent is the world's strongest security system? Challenge accepted!"
They're all completely pointless!
Move away, move away! Move a bit further away please!
What the hey?
We can't have you coming near it anymore!
You can't really call that a public display anymore...
But what is it? This huge number of letters...
Is it meant to unsettle Kyogoku-san...
Or...?
Kid! Kid! Kid!
The museum is now closing.
Visitors are asked to leave the premises in a timely fashion.
Thank you for visiting today.
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Now, fall as always, Kaitō Kid!
Today I'll show you something you won't forget so easily!
You, that is!
I have a bad feeling...
As though we've been had by him...
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
You look a bit grim...
Ran-neechan!
What do you think of my outfit?
I chose the most conservative one, but...
I-I think it suits you very well...
You do? That's good...
C-Conservative? It shows way too much cleavage!
Makoto-san!
I'm dressed like this now, so don't you forget it!
Yes!
Now, only five minutes until
the announced time arrives...
I would like to ask everyone
to leave this exhibition room...
From now on, until this is over,
I shall consider anyone who enters this room an enemy,
and aim to defeat them with all my might.
Y-Yes, got it...
I'm counting on you!
Alright! Us as well, we won't let anyone pass!
Yes, sir!
I'll go to the bathroom for a second!
Say.
Those are the letters from Kid, right?
Yeah.
Since there are so many of them,
did the mailman deliver them directly
to the back office of the museum?
No... Miss Sonoko said earlier that
she received them from the mailman.
Sonoko did?
Was she wearing that dress at the time?
Good work, everyone!
Yes... She said that when she went to look
around outside after changing into the dress,
she happened to meet the mailman,
whom she knew by sight.
Let me see those letters for a sec!
I don't intend to take them out of the bag!
H-Hey!
As I thought, it doesn't react to black light!
Which means... Could it be that Sonoko...
B-Blackout?!
I'm sorry... Makoto-san...
Kid! Kid! Kid!
B-Blackout?!
There's something glowing up there...
Quite a lot of things...
Fluorescent paint?
Huh? There are some strange things rolling towards us...
No! Ran-neechan, get away from them!
Nobody panic! It's the usual sleeping gas!
If you've got your gas mask on, this is nothing!
Damn!
Damn you, Kid...!
This is Sonoko-san's voice...
Makoto-san! Can I come in?
Makoto-san!
Sonoko-san, what on earth happened to you?
Kaitō Kid's cut all the power and filled
the whole mansion with sleeping gas!
I wasn't knocked out because I'd been given
this mask by one of the squad members...
All the other squad members had their
gas masks cut off by Kid's card gun...
My word...
There was something like fluorescent paint on the gas masks,
so using the light from those, Kid in the dark...
In which case, he's still around here somewhere...
I think he would've run away already.
And apparently before the power cut
there was a card from Kid,
saying, "I have helped myself to the jewel"...
That can't be right! The jewel's been around
my neck the whole time, just like so!
Anyway, let's check that somewhere with better light,
whether it's the real jewel or not!
You can't really tell with the moonlight from the window...
Then perhaps...
with a candle...
Oh yeah!
The one for revealing invisible ink!
The real jewel was green wasn't it?
R-Red! It's shining red!
I knew it! Kid's switched it with a fake!
B-But...
When? How?!
In any case, I'll go and hand this fake over to the police!
Ah, okay...
Makoto-san, you should go and
help the sleeping squad members!
You...
You are not Sonoko-san, are you?
Wha... what are you saying? I'm the real one,
of course! Although this jewel's a fake...
Actually, that jewel's the real thing.
C-Conan-kun?!
Alexandrite is a dark green under lights,
such as sunlight or the museum's fluorescent lights,
that are strong in the blue-green part
of the visible light spectrum.
But under incandescent or candle lights, that are
stronger in the red part of the visible light spectrum,
it shines a vivid red instead.
In other words,
those hundreds of meaningless invisible ink letters were sent
in order to ensure that candles would be kept here!
Those were letters you had hidden
somewhere in advance in the museum,
and then, disguised as Sonoko,
gave to a squad member, weren't they?
After all, if they'd gone through the post office
and ended up coming into contact with some heat,
then the letters wouldn't be invisible any more.
As proof of this, there were no barcodes used by the
post office for area demarcation on any of the letters.
No trace of the invisible ink
that usually shows up under black light!
So are you saying that Kid stripped off
my clothes and disguised himself as me?
No...
Sonoko took off her clothes and
handed them over to Kid herself!
In order to set things up for the bet she made with Kid!
A bet?
That's right! A bet on whether Kyogoku-san could tell
the difference between a Kid disguised
as Sonoko and the real Sonoko!
Damn it! He dodged!
O-Oh no!
Where... Where is he?!
The Green Emperor is mine!
But for now, why don't curse your
own flightless self's incompetence...
Mr. World's Strongest Security System?
Why, that...
Give me some space.
T-The pillar... with karate?
He can't be knocking down all the
pillars to bring down the ceiling?!
Okay, I'm scared! I'd better make myself scarce quickly...
No way!
H-He flew?!
As expected of the World's Strongest...
Now then... I would like to have them back...
Both the jewel... and Sonoko-san's heart!
Of course... it wasn't what I was looking for,
so I will be able to return the jewel.
But the young lady's heart
is a different matter entirely.
What?!
You say return, but it wasn't even stolen in the first place.
Not at the point when I offered the terms of this bet...
O-Okay! I'll take that bet, but...
Don't hurt him, alright?
Makoto-san's got... a really big
tournament coming up next week...
Who's there?!
K-Kaitō Kid!
Oh, geez...
It seems as though you won't be able
to keep this visit of mine a secret,
so make up some reasonable lies for your friends.
Especially for that little boy with glasses...
But unfortunately,
and even though I've still ended up
giving you a few scrapes and bruises,
this bet was won completely and utterly...
by that young lady!
What?!
He took off all her clothes and left her locked in the toilet?!
Is that true, Sonoko?!
Well, kind of...
He's merciless even to the girls!
Kid told her to say that, right?
Otherwise she'd be accused of being his accomplice.
Then the moment he put the fluorescent
paint on the gas masks must have been...
Good work, everyone!
...then!
Damn! That rotten Kid...
But, young man, you did an
excellent job protecting the jewel!
I can't say I did. He got away, after all...
Please forgive me...
Eh, don't worry about it.
Next time, our battle will continue, and then...
Yes. Then, without fail...
You've spoken well.
Now, you're the world's strongest security system!
He's quite the strapping young man!
Indeed...
he's a focused, simple, well-mannered, and very strong...
he would definitely be fun to tease...
She scares me...
I'm really sorry, Makoto-san... testing you like this...
Ah... it's okay...
One more thing...
How did you realize that it was Kid in disguise?
Was it something like, because the real me is even prettier?
Right? Something like that, right?
Well...
Actually...
Unlike me, Kid's ring finger is longer than his index finger?!
Y-You actually noticed that?
Yes... I've got into the habit of assessing all
my opponent's physical features in a glance...
Was there really nothing else at all?
Like the real me seems more pure or something...
P-Pure?
You know, pure, innocent...
Oh, forget it!
S-Sorry...
Geez!
Well, they say that girls usually have
longer index fingers than ring fingers
and guys vice versa because of the
relationship between fingers and hormones.
Although there are plenty of exceptions to that...
Hey, my ring finger's really long!