Um... Sato-san?
W-What's this important matter you wanted to talk about?
Just get in.
Uh... Okay.
Hey, wait a minute. This seems awfully familiar.
As I recall, when I opened the door that time...
You fell for it! You fell for it!
She thought it was the most hilarious thing ever.
Okay, I'll fall for it again today, hook, line and sinker.
Come on, give the pranks a rest!
Huh?
What are you doing?
Oh, um... I assumed you were playing another practical joke.
I said this was important, didn't I?
That's what you said last time,
and then you pulled a prank on me.
Listen...
Yes?
Can't you tell what it is?
C-Can't I tell what what is?
All I can tell is that you're as lovely as ever—
Quit being an idiot!
Come on, just tell me what it is!
I'm missing my you-know-what.
Oh? You missed it?
Missed?! You don't mean—
It's embarrassing, so don't tell anyone, got it?
O-Of course not!
What am I going to do? Someone's
going to have to take responsibility.
I-I'll do right by you.
Takagi-kun...
Hang on... In cases of marriage between police officers,
to say nothing of two officers in the same precinct,
given the possibility of issues arising
from a married couple working together,
one of them is supposed to transfer out.
Sato-san is the belle of Division 1,
so if I cause her to transfer out...
there's no telling what hell the senior
detectives will put me through.
So I'll have to transfer to some other precinct.
No, I could resign and be a stay-at-home dad.
Understood!
We're on our way.
We got a tip that a suspect we're after
was spotted in Beika Town.
We're going to check it out.
S-Sure!
M-Miwako is having a baby?
What happy news!
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
Will Sato finally profess her feelings to Takagi?
A perfect alibi! A mystery written in the language of flowers!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Come on, all three of you are yawning?
What are you, Haibara?
Well, excuse me for yawning a lot.
We can't help it!
Titan Hunter just came out, and it's too much fun!
We all got sucked into it.
Geez, you're wasting your precious summer
vacation playing some video game?
Oh, right! I got my daddy to help me and I made it to Rank 5!
Seriously?
I keep getting eaten by the Blue Titan!
What kind of game is this?
From what I hear, it's a role-playing game
where you protect your castle from a race of attacking titans.
Now that you mention it, the strategy
guide goes on sale today, doesn't it?
Oh, you're right!
Hey, do you think they have it in
that convenience store over there?
Let's go see!
Hey, you guys!
I thought we were going to go play soccer in the park!
I guess not.
Oh, for crying out loud.
Was there an accident there?
And those flowers...
I think those are called false dragonheads.
They signify...
Hey, Edogawa-kun.
What are you doing? Keep up.
R-Right.
That sure was a surprise.
I can't believe a total stranger
looked so much like our suspect.
That's for sure.
It's a little late, but do you want to
grab lunch somewhere around here?
Oh, sure!
How about pickles and ice cream or something?
Huh? Why would I want that?
Whoa, awesome!
This says it's called the Haouken!
It's so cool!
It says its attack stat is over 10,000
and is the only blade feared by the titans!
It's black-and-white, so you can't
tell what it really looks like, though.
It says here that you can only get it if you're Rank 8
and defeat a big-ass Red Titan!
I won't be getting it anytime soon...
Oh, I have that sword.
Its hilt is shiny and gold, and the design on the blade is red!
Noriya Makabe (7)
1st-year Grade School Student
It seems like you still need to get a bunch of buff items
to level up the sword afterwards, though.
Oh, wow! You made Rank 8, then?
Yep!
Hang on, aren't you in the class next to ours?
You aren't lying to make yourself sound cool, are you?
I'm not lying!
Right, Toshinari-niichan?
That's right.
You worked hard for it.
Huh? That's the guy I just saw...
If you really got the Haouken, I'd sure love to see it!
Me, too!
Want to come over to Toshinari-niichan's place, then?
It's okay, isn't it, Toshinari-niichan?
Toshinari Shiga (25)
Graduate Student
Wait for me in the car, then. I'll go pay our bill.
That comes to 1,350 yen.
Put it on my card, please.
Of course. Number of payments?
One-time charge.
Of course.
He drives an import and has a platinum card...
Maybe he's a trust fund kid.
Whoa!
This place is a dump!
Hush, Genta-kun!
It may not look like much, but home is where you make it.
I'll park the car, so you go on inside.
Okay!
Apartment #3
Shiga
Whoa, it's really the Haouken!
The grip really is shiny and gold!
- It's so pretty...
- Awesome!
Sheesh...
It's full of junk food, instant noodles
and convenience-store bento boxes.
Their diet is on display here.
Hey, Haibara.
What?
Did you smell something?
Not really.
I don't think there's any kitchen garbage in here.
No, in the hall before we came in.
No, I didn't notice anything.
You didn't?
Hey, where do you get off poking around someone's home?
Tell me something, Noriya-kun...
Did your brother just move here?
No, it was about a month ago.
Before summer vacation, he lived in the
same apartment building as my folks.
And Toshinari-niichan isn't my brother. He's my cousin.
He's the son of my mom's older sister.
My dad is on an overseas business trip right now,
and Mom left for a week to take care of him,
so I'm staying here with Toshinari-niichan while she's away.
You're staying here for a week?
Yeah. Plus, Mom asked me to do something for her.
Toshinari-niichan's big sister died
in a traffic accident six months ago.
He's been really sad ever since,
so Mom asked me to stay with him and cheer him up.
Then he was laying those flowers at the spot where she died...
Oh, right! I got him to show me some pictures of her earlier!
She was really nice. She used to take me camping all the time.
Huh? Were there this many pictures before?
Say. Can I see?
Sure.
That's strange. She isn't looking into
the camera in any of these last ones.
And what are these? There are little
holes in the tops of the pictures.
T-That was Toshinari-niichan's voice!
The hallway... Don't tell me...
It was coming from apartment #4?
I knew it, that smell was...
C-Conan-kun?
What is it?
The rest of you, stay back!
Haibara, call the police. Tell them someone has died here.
On it.
What's that?
The pictures pinned up on this cork board...
The pictures and the sun-bleached areas don't quite line up.
And it's not just one or two of them.
What could cause that?
She isn't looking into the camera...
There are little holes in the tops of the pictures...
I don't believe it.
The culprit who did this is...
It can't be...
I have to say, I had no idea things
had progressed so far with those two.
They're gonna get hitched for sure now.
Things are gonna get dangerous for Takagi-kun, though.
Hm? Dangerous how?
Imagine what'll happen when the other detectives find out.
Oh, you have a point.
Sato-san has a big fan club.
He's in trouble. Seriously.
He sure is.
In serious trouble.
Um... Yumi-san?
Your mouth is saying one thing,
but your face is saying another.
The victim is Hiroto Yasutomi-san. Age 31, job hopper.
Forensics puts estimated time of death
sometime between 7:00 and 9:00 last night.
Repeated stabs to the chest and abdomen...
Then you were the first person to find the body?
You're Toshinari Shiga-san, the next-door neighbor?
Yes.
I had parked my car in the lot,
and when I was going to my own apartment,
I noticed a strange smell coming from this one.
The door was unlocked, so I let myself in.
That's when I found him like this.
I shouted in surprise, and that's when this boy,
a friend of my cousin Noriya's, barged in.
Isn't that Conan-kun?
Then the girl who reported the body was...
Me.
We all came over to hang out
at Noriya-kun's cousin's place today.
I have to say, you're every bit
the angel of death that Mouri-san is.
I keep finding you at murder scenes.
G-Gosh, you two sure arrived at the scene quickly.
We got a tip that an employee at a nearby
florist's looked like a wanted suspect.
It turned out to be a false alarm, though.
We happened to be in the neighborhood,
so we caught the case.
If Takagi-kun hadn't been whispering
with that employee about flowers,
we could have gone straight back.
We were still in the area because we were eating lunch!
You were talking about flowers?
Are you gonna give some to somebody?
If it was to Detective Sato, he wouldn't
have been whispering about it!
He must be cheating.
You think so, too?
I-I am not!
To get back on track...
If he died between 7:00 and 9:00 last night,
why don't you ask Noriya-kun and Toshinari-san about it?
They were next door, so they might have
heard strange sounds or something.
During those hours last night,
I was watching TV with Toshinari-niichan!
The Kamen Yaiba movie was on.
I watched that, too!
Me, too! Wasn't it awesome?!
It was on from 7:00 to 9:00 for its TV premiere!
You didn't hear any strange sounds
or moaning while it was on?
Yeah! During the movie, our neighbor banged on the door
and yelled at us to turn it down.
Around what time was that?
I think it must have been around 7:30.
I apologized through the door and turned down the volume.
Which means that Yasutomi-san was still alive at that time.
Did you hear anything strange after that?
Well... Kamen Yaiba is one of those superhero shows,
so there was a lot of screaming and explosions.
Even if there had been any strange
noises, I might not have noticed.
Besides, his body was found by his kitchen sink,
which is two rooms away from where we were watching TV.
Come to think of it, I saw him at the
convenience store yesterday evening.
Around what time?
Well, it was when we were buying bento boxes for dinner.
I remember being worried about their expiration date
and asking Noriya what day it was.
You asked a child what the date was?
Yeah! I was holding the shopping basket.
It had a newspaper in it that we were going to buy.
I told him that August 13th was written on it.
I said that was the day that the
Kamen Yaiba movie was gonna be on TV.
If it was the 13th, that means it was yesterday.
When you saw him, was Yasutomi-san with anyone?
No, I think he was by himself.
Say, Noriya-kun. Did Toshinari-san
get up to go to the bathroom or anything
while you were watching the movie?
No, I was sitting beside him the whole time.
What did you do after it was over?
It ended before 9:00, right?
Yeah! I went to pee right after it ended,
and then I went back to playing my game.
Went back to? You were playing it before the movie, too?
Yeah, I played from the time we got back
from the store until the movie started.
Toshinari-niichan looked at his watch and said,
Oh, no! It's already 7:00!
The movie's starting, so we'd better save our game.
We saved it real fast and switched it back to cable.
We did it just in time,
because the movie had just started!
While you were in the bathroom after the movie ended,
Toshinari-san didn't leave the apartment?
Nope, he asked me what kind of snacks
I wanted from outside the bathroom door.
Then you played your game together all evening after that?
That's right! We played until pretty late,
and then after I got up early and played some more,
I went to the store with Toshinari-niichan to go buy breakfast.
After that, I played until around noon or so.
Then I got tired, so I took a nap.
After I woke up, I played some more,
and then I got hungry, so we went to the store.
And that's when I ran into you guys!
T-Talk about gaming night and day...
That's why your rank was so high!
I'm jealous!
What about lunch, then?
Oh, I'd been snacking all day, so I wasn't hungry at all.
Snacking and gaming all day!
That's so great!
I'd call that heaven!
Don't follow his example.
So you were with Toshinari-san all day again today?
After we ate breakfast, he said he had an errand to run,
so I should play my game while he was out.
He didn't want the man next door to get mad at us again,
so he said to play with headphones on.
When was that?
Let me think...
It was around 6 o'clock when we went
to the store to buy breakfast,
and that was right after we came home and ate it,
so I guess that was around 7:00.
The clock behind the cashier at the
store said it was just after 6:00.
What? Do you suspect him?
E-Excuse me...
Would you mind if we went back to my apartment?
I'd rather not make these kids hang around a dead body.
Good point.
Just to rule you out, I'd like to go
through your garbage and things.
Is that all right?
Sure, that's fine.
Hey, I know you!
You weren't at the florist's earlier, were you?
Yes, I bought some flowers.
I thought so!
When I asked what kind of flowers
to give someone when a wish comes true,
the guy there said, How about a
bouquet of false dragonheads
like that man just bought?
I caught a glimpse of you just as you were leaving.
So you just got some good news, Detective Takagi?
Did you win a prize on your ice cream stick?
C'mon, tell us!
Uh, well... Help me out here!
Huh? Why?
I said I'd do right by you, didn't I?
Oh, that.
Well, you're partly to blame for my little situation.
I'd say it's only natural that you
man up and do the right thing.
Y-You have a point.
That's the flower you bought?
Yes.
In that case,
did you also have some kind of wish come true?
Y-Yes... I suppose.
Shiga-san. Shall we go to your apartment, then?
S-Sure...
Say, Detective Takagi.
What is it, Conan-kun?
There's something I'd like you to find out for me.
Toshinari-san placed those flowers
by the road in front of that florist's,
so I was wondering if there had been an accident there.
Oh, he did?
Come on. Quit dawdling, Takagi-kun.
S-Sure...
Get a move on!
Should you be exerting yourself, Sato-san?
You should be taking it easy!
He's probably the one who murdered Yasutomi-san.
It was Toshinari Shiga-san, I'm sure of it.
And the murder weapon is probably in...
But the problem is his alibi.
At the time of the murder, 7:00 to 9:00
on the evening of August 13th,
he was right next to Noriya-kun the whole time.
Damn it...
How the hell did he murder Yasutomi-san?
Well?
Takagi-kun? Did you get some good news today, then?
Beg pardon?
W-What's with this ominous vibe I'm getting?
Well, you see...
S-Sato-san's maternal instincts are kicking in!
Hey, about that Yaiba movie you watched last night.
Yeah, that's right. I held it in so long
I thought I was going to burst.
Just as I thought!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Newspaper
Summer break is great for...
Video games!
Sweets!
Naps!
Go play outside!