Three of the Detective Boys have spent their
summer vacation enthralled by a new video game.
After talking to a fellow Teitan Elementary student
that we bumped into at a convenience store,
we ended up going over to his
relative’s place to play the game.
I sensed something suspicious about the apartment.
But just then, Toshinari-san made a grisly
discovery in the apartment next door.
Elsewhere, there was another surprise
between Detectives Sato and Takagi...
I’m missing my you-know-what.
Missed?! You don’t mean—
It’s embarrassing, so don’t tell anyone, got it?
M-Miwako is having a baby?
What happy news!
We won’t give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
Detective Takagi’s gonna be a daddy?
A shocking trick that startles the two of them!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
“Detective Conan”
Serialized in Shogakukan’s
‘Weekly Shonen Sunday’
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Jun'ichi Higashi
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Urakami
Keiko Urakami
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Shigenobu Kaihoko
Executive Producer
Masataka Todo
Planning Support
Hiroshi Torimitsu
Kazumasa Ogura
Masakazu Hakuya
Associate Producer
Shuho Kondo
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Presented by
MPD Detectives’ Love Story
(The Truth)
I’m back...
W-What’s with this ominous vibe I’m getting?
Well, you see, Chiba-kun...
Okay, found it!
A bento lunch made on August 13th,
and a newspaper from August 13th.
Well, I do buy a newspaper every day.
Look, even if you’re only taking care of him for a week,
you can’t feed a child nothing but snacks,
convenience-store bento boxes and instant noodles.
Shouldn’t you give a little more thought to what he’s eating?
You’ll stunt his growth.
S-Sato-san’s maternal instincts are kicking in!
And... And I’m the father!
Hey, Takagi-kun.
Did you go to the convenience store and confirm his story?
Yes. The store’s security camera caught everything.
Around 6:00 PM yesterday, August 13th,
Yasutomi-san was there shopping.
It also showed Toshinari-san and
Noriya-kun there at the same time.
Ah.
Oh, and there was apparently an accident six months ago
in front of the florist’s next door to the convenience store.
An accident?
Yes.
Apparently, a woman ran into the street.
The driver swerved to avoid her, but it was too late.
After he hit her,
he slammed into the guard rail in the
oncoming lane and lost consciousness.
A bystander called an ambulance,
and that saved the driver’s life,
but his car had snagged the woman’s clothes,
and no one noticed her underneath the car.
They say the delay in treatment cost her her life.
The driver’s statement said that
it looked like she ran into the street
because she was being chased by someone.
So? What does that have to do with this murder?
The thing is, the cashier at the convenience
store apparently saw the whole thing.
He saw Yasutomi-san running from the scene.
And as for the woman who was run over, she—
Yes.
It was my sister, Mika, who died in that accident.
Ever since then, I’ve made a point of
laying flowers at the scene every day.
O-Oh, is that right?
That flower seems like a bit of a
gaudy choice to set out, though...
My sister loved pink,
so I thought it would be nice to set out
flowers like that every once in a while.
I see...
Say, mister...
Was your sister having any problems?
For instance...
A stalker or something, maybe?
Was there one?
No.
She never mentioned anything about that to me.
I knew it. The man who killed Yasutomi-san...
...was this man. Toshinari Shiga-san.
But he has an alibi.
For the two hours between 7:00 and 9:00
on August 13th, the time of the murder,
he was with Noriya-kun the entire time.
I’m going to let some fresh air in.
No way! The sun is going down already! I have to get home!
Seriously? I just opened this big of chips!
Genta-kun, you’re getting them everywhere!
Do you have a bowl or something?
I think he has paper ones.
What happened to your leg?
It looks like bruises from pinching.
I-I guess I was bitten by mosquitoes
and scratched too hard.
Hey, about that Yaiba movie
you watched last night, was it...
Yeah, that’s right. I held it in so long
I thought I was going to burst.
That means that that newspaper is...
It can’t be.
C-Conan-kun?
Just as I thought!
The only one missing is from August 12th.
No doubt about it...
This man is the killer.
He manipulated the passage of time to give himself an alibi.
He even manipulated Noriya-kun’s feelings.
At any rate, if Toshinari-san and Noriya-kun
were next door to the crime scene
from 7:00 to 9:00 PM last night,
the window the murder was committed in,
but didn’t hear any strange sounds
because of the movie they were watching,
our only choice is to question
the other residents of the building.
This building is scheduled to be
demolished next year, though.
The only other residents are an
old couple on the second floor.
They say they spent last night at their grandchildren’s.
Really?
Haibara, get rid of the others.
Sure.
Come on, everyone. Let’s have a sleepover
at the Doctor’s place and game all night!
Let’s play Titan Hunter, then!
Good idea!
I’ll go grab the disc from my house, then!
Care to join us, Noriya-kun? We’ll want
to pick your brain over the game.
Besides, you don’t want to sleep
next to a murder scene, do you?
You’re not going?
I will. But first...
Why would you move into a building
that’s going to be demolished next year?
I wanted to distract myself with a change of scenery.
I used to live with my sister, and she died in that accident...
But you moved in a month ago, right?
You’d think that you would have bought
at least a pot or a frying pan.
But there’s nothing here at all.
I’m a terrible cook, so I never
bothered to get any cooking utensils.
But there isn’t any detergent or
a sponge or scrub brush by the sink.
Doesn’t that mean that you also
don’t have any dishes or glasses?
Yes. I’d planned to get some soon.
Oh, really? I assumed it was
because you planned to move out
just as soon as you had murdered
your neighbor, Yasutomi-san.
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?
Toshinari-san was watching TV during the crime window,
from 7:00 to 9:00 last night.
Noriya-kun was with him.
Didn’t you hear Noriya-kun?
He said he held it in as he watched the whole movie.
Doesn’t that suggest that there were
no commercials for the whole two hours?
Oh...
O-Oh, right! A rental DVD!
Rental DVD?
Yes, if it’s being aired on TV,
then the movie’s also available for rent now.
It should also be available for purchase.
I follow you. If he bought the DVD
and put it in the player ahead of time,
and then hit “play” at exactly the right time,
it would look to a child like it was airing on TV.
But Toshinari-san...
Didn’t you say that on the 13th,
the night of the murder,
you played that game with Noriya-kun
in addition to watching the movie with him?
Yes. Both before and after the movie.
He couldn’t have committed it, then.
Was that really the 13th?
Yes,
he said he had Noriya-kun check the date on that
paper they bought at the convenience store.
I-Isn’t that right?
Yes.
See?
That day was definitely August 13th.
Oh, I see. I had it all wrong?
Convenience stores don’t sell papers
from a day in the future, now do they?
Tabloids!
Those so-called “evening edition” papers
have the next day’s date printed on them!
If he bought that and had Noriya-kun check the date for him,
he could make him think that it was a different day.
Now that you mention it, August 12th
was the only day there’s no paper for.
I get it.
He got rid of the paper dated the 13th
that he bought on the 12th.
In other words, it was actually the night of August 12th
that you watched that movie with Noriya-kun,
giving you ample opportunity to commit
the murder on the night of the 13th.
N-Now wait just a minute!
Didn’t you hear Noriya? He said that
we watched the movie yesterday!
Even a child can tell the difference
between yesterday and two days ago!
If you think I’m lying, call Noriya back here and ask him!
He knows that today is the day after we saw that movie!
Actually, Noriya-kun said something about that, too.
On the evening of August 13th,
after you came back from the store,
he played that game until the movie started.
And after it ended, he went back
to playing it until late at night.
He then got up early, and after
playing the game some more,
Noriya-kun went to the store with you
to buy breakfast around 6:00 AM.
After playing the game again until lunch, he took a nap.
He then got up and played the game some more.
He was hungry by then, so you two went
to the store earlier and ran into us.
And he said he was with me the entire
time he was playing the game, remember?
Yes. But he also said that you went out for a bit
after you went to the store and ate breakfast.
You told him to wear headphones while you were gone.
You went out. Where?
I-I just stepped out for a smoke.
Besides, that was this morning.
Timing-wise, it has nothing to do with the murder.
Speaking of time...
There isn’t a single clock in this whole apartment, is there?
The only person who knows what
time it is is you, with your watch.
Plus, there are these heavy curtains on all the windows.
And if you’re eating snacks the whole time you’re gaming,
you won’t get hungry, either.
That would make it really easy to
lose track of time, now wouldn’t it?
I really think you should buy a clock.
S-Sure...
Oh, I see. So this is how it went down...
On the 12th, the day before the murder,
you bought an evening edition at the store
and made Noriya-kun think that it was actually the 13th.
That night, you let him play his game until after 10:00 or so
and then told him it was time for the movie.
Then, assuming you let him play
until early morning after having him
watch the movie on DVD until about midnight,
it was really the afternoon of the 13th
when you woke him up and said it was morning.
You let him play until evening,
and when you said “Let’s buy breakfast”
and went to the store, that was actually 6:00 PM on the 13th.
Oh, I get it! The sun is out at both
6:00 AM and 6:00 PM this time of year!
And then, when you stepped out
to run an errand after “breakfast”,
you had plenty of time to murder Yasutomi-san.
Noriya-kun was wearing headphones then,
so he wouldn’t have heard a thing.
Afterwards, you came back to your apartment
and had Noriya-kun keep playing until early morning.
If you told him to take a nap and
let him sleep until noon today, the 14th,
it would have seemed to Noriya-kun
that the 13th and 14th were only one day.
Well? Did I get anything wrong?
H-How do you expect me to answer that?
What possible motive would I have?
Your sister sure is pretty!
Hey! Kid!
It’s strange. She isn’t looking into the
camera in any of these at the end.
And there’s some kinda hole at the tops.
You sure must love your sister!
I bet you had a bunch of pictures
of your sister pinned up somewhere
that you’d taken without her knowing!
Are those from—
The stalker?!
Come to think of it, Forensics mentioned something about that.
There was a cork board in Yasutomi-san’s apartment with lots of photos pinned to it,
but they didn’t line up with the sun-bleached areas on the board.
So these are the pictures that were really pinned up there.
After the murder, you took them down
to remove any connection to you,
and you replaced them with pictures you
found in Yasutomi-san’s apartment, right?
If that’s the case, the camera
files these were made from
might still be on the laptop
that was on Yasutomi-san’s desk.
Check it out right away. They’re
probably already deleted, though.
On it!
I think they’re still there.
I didn’t think that far ahead.
Anyway, the only reason I took her pictures down
was because I didn’t want them hanging
in that stalker bastard’s apartment.
Then Yasutomi-san really was stalking your sister?
Yes. I found out two months ago.
I was placing flowers at the spot she died like I always do,
and he came up to me.
He asked me if I was also a “fan”.
I was curious, so I followed him.
That’s when I saw it through the window.
Dozens of pictures of her were pinned up,
and he was muttering that it was her fault for running away.
Hang on, that report that it looked like she was being
chased when she ran into the street, that was...
Yes. She ran into the street when he was chasing her
and she got hit by that car.
I know because I got him to confess before I killed him.
“Why did you run away?” I asked.
“Why didn’t you tell the EMTs
that my sister was under the car?!”
If he’d said something, she might still be alive!
He said... He said it was because he was scared!
And so you moved next to Yasutomi-san
and put your plan into motion?
Yes, I was asked a while ago
to look after Noriya for a week.
I never expected that I would be
able to fool him so easily, though.
What are you talking about?
It worked because Noriya-kun pinched his own leg
to stay awake and play that game for so long.
Because he’d been asked by his mother
to stay with you and cheer you up.
This crazy plan of yours never would have worked otherwise.
Now I get it...
He was the one who was looking after me...
So, what’s going to happen with Noriya-kun?
Until his mother comes back,
he’s going to stay at Dr. Agasa’s house.
Apparently, his mother called him and told him
that Toshinari-san had to go on a trip for a while.
Oh?
So, are you ever going to tell me?
Who were you going to give those flowers to?
To you, obviously!
It was going to be a surprise!
I was going to give you the false
dragonheads along with the ring!
Flowers and a ring?
Instead of all that, give me your red lapel pin instead.
Red pin?
The ones given out to members of
the Criminal Investigations Division?
Why would you want mine?
You said you were going to do right by me, didn’t you?
For the love of...
I tackled that suspect you had cuffed when
he almost got away from you, remember?
The impact must have knocked my pin off.
I noticed it was missing afterwards
and went back and searched everywhere,
but I couldn’t find it!
O-Oh, I picked that up and put it in my left pants pocket.
Sorry, I should have told you!
No way! Seriously?!
Hey! Sato-san!
Got it!
My red pin! What a relief!
Everyone wears them, but it’s not like it’s mandatory.
If you’d gone to the bosses, I’m sure
they would have given you a new one.
Oh, really?
I assumed I’d have to file an apology,
so I was too embarrassed to bring it up.
Boy, I’ve been a moody wreck ever since!
Uh... When you said you were missing
something earlier, you meant—
Yep! This red pin!
Look out! Watch it!
Hey, what are you moping about?
We nabbed the culprit in no time flat,
so let’s see some spring in your step!
Yeah...
Is it just me, or is everybody...
They’re looking at us, aren’t they?
Miwako!
Yumi? And Chiba-kun?
Hey, Yumi... Everybody’s staring at us.
You know better than anyone.
Miwako, I hear you missed a little something?
Oh, that! Don’t worry, I found it!
- Found it?
Look, Takagi-kun said he found it for me.
If he’d told me earlier, I wouldn’t have
been in the dumps this whole time.
D-Do they think that she’s...
Huh? Think what?
Time, 2126 hours! Wataru Takagi taken into custody!
Now taking him to interrogation room!
Roger that!
Hey!
Takagi-kun did something stupid again, didn’t he?
I’m sorry! There’s been a mistake!
It’s a little misunderstanding!
Er, I was the one who got it wrong!
Sato-san!
Wow! This is amazing!
Yep! We’re very close.
All right!
Oh no! He’s drowning!
Is there something important in that video?
Next Conan:
Next Conan’s Hint: Necklace