Wow! This is amazing!
Look at all the yachts!
I wonder how far we could go on that one of those?
I bet we could even go to another country!
Because this place opens out into the ocean.
Oh, I wanna ride on one!
I know, me too...
More importantly...
I'm gettin' kinda hungry, so let's hurry back and grab some lunch!
I should've known Genta-kun only cared about his stomach.
Huh?
Whoa, that looks so good!
Hey, where are you taking that?
It must be this one.
Takiguchi-sama.
I'm from the Shirakabe Hotel.
I brought the food you ordered.
He said he's from a hotel!
So of course it would look delicious, right?
Hey! I'm not going to give you some just for looking. Go away.
You shouldn't say something so unkind.
Nao Takiguchi (34)
Wife of the Company President
Thank you for all your effort. That was quite fast.
Oh, what a cute doggie!
His name is Coro.
And that's a really pretty necklace, too!
Thanks.
But this is just a cheap thing, made of acrylic.
Excuse me, ma'am, but where should I put your food?
Oh, I'm sorry. Could I have you carry it on to the ship for me?
And you guys are also welcome to come aboard.
Oh, but...
We shouldn't go with a stranger...
The food from this hotel is very delicious. Don't you want some?
But if we eat some, you won't have enough.
You children don't need to be so hesitant.
You could probably even have dinner too with all the food we ordered!
Kōtarō Takiguchi (55)
Company President
Wow!
Then we can really eat with you?!
Yes. We were thinking it would be lonely with just the two of us.
So it's our pleasure to invite you.
In that case, we'll gladly...
Accept your treat!
We won't give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
All of us become eyewitnesses...
...to the rich man who dove straight into the sea!
He sees the single truth for what it is
and looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Oh, geez. Where did those guys run off to?
Your fault for sleeping ever since we got here.
If we still can't find them after looking a little longer, I'm eating their lunches.
You'll be sorry if you do that.
Grudges over food can be pretty scary.
Well, I guess...
It's too bad Conan-kun and Haibara-san can't eat any of this delicious food.
Don't worry about it.
It's their fault for coming out to the beach and just sleeping.
You have other friends here with you?
Yep!
We're very close, but Haibara-san said she didn't want to get sunburnt today.
If she worries about her skin that much as a primary schooler...
I'm looking forward to seeing what a beauty she'll become in the future.
And even though Conan-kun's in primary school,
he stays up all night reading mystery novels.
He's a kid, but he really doesn't act like one.
It's really annoying.
Well, sorry for being annoying.
Conan-kun!
So that cute girl down there is Haibara-san?
Yes. Though I apologise for not being a "beauty" yet.
You're very beautiful, even now.
For a primary school student, anyway.
What're you two doing here?
That's what I should be asking you!
We came looking for you because we thought we should eat our lunches soon, you know!
I apologise to your mothers who took the time to make them for you.
But it's fine as long as you can eat them before going home, right?
You two, come on up and eat with us.
Yeah, come on! This roast beef's really good!
And this spiny lobster's the best!
Yeah!
Mitsuhiko, you're eating too much lobster!
I told you this is spiny lobster.
Is there a difference?
Dear...
The children will laugh at you.
You're almost like newlyweds!
Well...
We only got married six months ago.
I say that, but this is also my first marriage.
I was so busy expanding my company...
I completely forgot about getting married until I was this old.
It'd be so wonderful if we could take this ship out,
and swim around in the pretty ocean!
That's not possible.
You can't swim very well on your own yet, can you, Ayumi-chan?
If I had a boat like this at home, I'd learn to swim super fast!
That's the spirit, Ayumi-chan!
Don't let it get you down.
I couldn't swim either, until I was this age.
But after some practice, I finally learnt how.
If a person puts their mind to it,
they can accomplish anything!
So you went to a sports club?
No. Our house was just built, so I seized the opportunity and had a pool built.
Oh, I'll show you something nice.
Huh?
You were recording me?
Please stop. It's embarrassing.
But in the end... See?!
You're right!
You really did learn how to swim.
All right!
Then let's race and see who gets to that bank first!
You can use a swim ring, Ayumi-chan.
Okay! Let's do this.
Wait, you can't.
You just had wine.
And even if you hadn't, your blood pressure's high.
You should have a rest before swimming.
Aww, and I was sure I'd win, too!
How old is Coro?
He just turned one.
Huh?
The buckle on his collar is rusty.
Oh. Maybe that's because we take him on walks, even on rainy days.
Hey, we should head back soon.
Ah, I forgot.
Going off and having a feast all by themselves...
If that's what they were doing, why didn't someone come let me know?
I was really worried, and was thinking of calling the police.
Eating while angry is bad for your digestion.
All right!
Heads up!
Nice shot!
Huh?
Isn't that Nao-san and her husband's ship heading out?
You're right!
Yep! Nao-san came out, too.
Are they planning on swimming?
Mister! Thanks for the food earlier!
Let's go swimming, too!
Okay.
Then I'll go get a swim ring.
What is this?! This isn't right.
Someone... Anyone!
Oh no! He's drowning!
Dear!
I'm worried now.
I kinda don't feel like playing anymore.
Yeah.
The day's still young, but let's head home.
The fire station will want to question us about Takiguchi-san by phone later.
You five. Aren't you the kids who were with Takiguchi-sama earlier?
I went to pick up the dishes, but it didn't look like there was anyone on the ship.
Do you know anything about that?
Oh, then we'll go get the dishes for you.
I see. So you couldn't ride in the ambulance.
Should we bring Nao-san and her husband their clothes and things?
Ah, yeah.
You're sure this was an accident?!
Emergency Medical Centre
There hasn't been a thorough investigation yet.
But according to the witnesses' statements, there appears to be no doubt that he dove into the water on his own.
Ryōichi Katagiri (48)
Takaguchi's Secretary
I can't believe it.
Couldn't someone have pushed him off or something?
Detective Nagai (38)
He and his wife were the only ones on board the ship at the time.
Are you saying his wife pushed him overboard?
I'm not going to go that far.
But the president told me this himself!
When he was a child, he almost drowned in a river.
He's been afraid of water ever since, and couldn't swim.
He recently practised and learnt how to swim!
What?!
Who are you guys?
Oh, pardon the intrusion.
They're kids who met the Takiguchis at the beach.
We came because they say they're very grateful to those two.
We brought their clothes, too!
And Coro had been left behind.
How is Takiguchi-san doing right now?
Uh...
This is a hard thing to say,
but his death was confirmed just a while ago.
No way! To think that such a good man could die...
I can't believe it.
For now, Detective...
Please look into it and find out whether or not this was really an accident.
"Even before we got married, I'm certain people were after our fortune."
The president told me that more times than I can count!
Even so, the president was completely deceived by that woman.
And to think that it would end like this...
You're saying that Nao-san's a bad person?!
There's no way someone so nice would ever do something bad!
H-Hey, don't.
Please excuse them.
Are you from Takiguchi-san's company?
Yes. I'm Katagiri, the head secretary.
You all witnessed the accident, correct?
Yeah, we saw it.
We saw Takiguchi-san drown right before our eyes.
Takiguchi-san waved at us, and then dove into the sea.
I see.
In that case, while it may be difficult on you,
can I have you come to the police station and give us the details of what happened then?
Sure.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
So, when Takiguchi-san dove in,
do you know where his wife was?
She was standing not too far from him, doing something.
She was probably cleaning up the dishes from lunch.
I see.
So that would explain why she took a while to notice he was drowning.
Come in.
Nao-san...
Ayumi-chan...
Thank you for bringing me my clothes.
Nao-san, your necklace...
Oh, I bet that when I rescued him,
the chain snapped, and it sunk into the ocean.
I heard the story from these kids.
But it's apparent that your husband dove into the sea by his own free will.
It seems we weren't mistaken in thinking that this was an unfortunate accident.
It's my own fault.
No matter how well he said he'd learnt to swim...
If I had only warned him a little harder...
I wanted to ask you just one more thing about that.
It seems Takiguchi-san told people at his company that he couldn't swim...
So did he really learn how to?
Hey! Why not show him that practice video?
Oh, you're right.
I recorded this when he first started practising in the pool.
That's it! That's it!
The parts where I'm in the video were filmed by our maid.
Keep moving towards me!
Great!
And then this was recorded last week.
That's it! Keep it up!
Don't stop, try a flip turn!
I see.
He really was learning to swim.
Come with me a second.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Can I see your video camera?
Yes, that's fine.
Is there something important in that video?
You're right!
Yep! Nao-san came out, too.
Good. It picked up the audio, too.
The problem is what happens next...
Let's go swimming, too!
Okay.
Then I'll go get a swim ring.
What is this?! This isn't right.
Someone... Anyone!
Here, right here!
Can this zoom in more?
Yes, though the picture gets blurry.
Someone... Anyone!
Dear!
What does this mean?
There's a brief period between when Nao-san realised Kōtarō-san was drowning,
and when she jumped in to rescue him.
Besides, that cruiser had a life preserver.
So why didn't she use it?
And one more thing...
What was that thing I saw in the background of his swimming practice video?
Was Kōtarō-san actually...?
What are you two whispering about?
Ah, coming.
Huh?
The buckle on his collar is rusty.
Oh. Maybe that's because we take him on walks, even on rainy days.
So that's it!
Well then, everyone...
I'm sorry for having inconvenienced you,
but you're all free to leave now.
I'll take you to the hospital, ma'am.
Thank you for your help.
Can I have you wait on that a second?
What?
Do you have something you wish to say?
Um... No, no...
This is no mere accident.
It is a meticulously planned murder.
What?! What did you say?!
But Takiguchi-san dove into the sea on his own.
Indeed. However, if he knew that he couldn't swim,
Takiguchi-san probably wouldn't have dove in.
Though Takiguchi-san couldn't swim, he had been put under the impression that he could,
and suddenly led out into the open sea in his cruiser, where his feet couldn't touch the ground.
Isn't it a perfect murder?
Don't you think so, Nao Takiguchi-san?
My husband really could swim.
You saw that too, correct?
So are you saying that that video was manipulated somehow?
No, that video is perfectly genuine.
Takiguchi-san could swim...
W-What are you saying?
...but only in his own pool.
Conan-kun.
Here I am!
Lemme borrow this a sec.
Look at Nao-san's necklace here, when her husband was practising his flutter kick.
Huh?
There. You see how it's submerged in the water?
But on the last day...
See? It floats on the water.
What?! L-Let me see that...
Y-You're right. The necklace wasn't floating, but now it is...
Can I have you explain, in simpler terms, what this means?
Why did the necklace float?
I learnt that from Coro.
Though Coro only just turned one year old,
for some reason, the buckle on his collar is rusty.
That's because the victim's wife put a large quantity of bath salts into the pool water,
in order to make his body float more easily.
The necklace in the video is made of acrylic.
The specific gravity of acrylic is about 1.17 to 1.2.
Meaning the water in the pool last week had a higher specific gravity than that.
Isn't that right, ma'am?
You're wrong. If I'd put that much bath salts in the water,
even my thickheaded husband would have realised it.
Then what did you put in the water?
The necklace that was submerged in the sea was floating in the video.
In any case, your own video proves that the specific gravity of the pool water was higher than normal.
Should we go to your home and check?
Even if you did go, there's no water in it.
Unfortunately, we already drained the pool water.
You mustn't underestimate the police.
As long as there's the slightest bit of residue in the pool,
they'll find out right away what was dissolved in the water.
Ma'am, is what this man is saying true?
Well, is it?!
Nao-san! It's not true, is it?
It's... true.
Just as he said...
I put bath salts in the water at first.
But when I started adding more, he figured it out.
Ever since then, I switched to a water-soluble polymer.
A non-toxic one, used in medicines and foods.
The specific gravity of the pool water last week was probably over 1.3.
For reference, 1.3 is about the same as the Dead Sea, where it's said that you can float on the surface and read a book.
So it wouldn't be unreasonable for Takiguchi-san to believe he could swim.
You probably recorded that video,
thinking you could use it when the police questioned you.
But on the contrary, that video became your undoing.
Up until now, that man's head had been filled with nothing but thoughts of expanding his company.
He was fine with using any dirty means necessary to do so,
and didn't care how many people he made unhappy as a result.
That's why this time, I wanted to teach him how it felt to suffer.
But the agony of living with that unrefined man who lacked any common decency
was just too much to bear.
I was at the limits of what I could handle...
While it may be true that Takiguchi-san was obsessed with earning money,
and lacked common decency and refinement,
don't you think he's still a much better person than you, who killed someone out of revenge?!
I believed that she was a kind person, too...
I know. I thought she was a good person when she treated us to lunch.
I'm never trusting a grown-up ever again!
There are all kinds of adults. All kinds.
That's right. Even now, I still have a pure, untainted heart.
What? Did you just laugh because I said it's pure?
Oh, right. Didn't we still have the lunches we brought?
That's right! Thanks to us being treated this afternoon, we still have our lunches!
Let's hurry up and eat 'em!
Now that you mention it, I'm pretty hungry.
I wonder what the side dish is today!
Eel, eel!
Come on, you guys...
Weren't you guys just feeling down in the dumps?
Right! She's even holding Tai-chan!
This cat is my granddaughter's cat!
These two men turned up claiming to be his owners too...
No, I'm his real owner.
You're wrong! I'm telling you, he's mine!
He's not that ordinary.
...with a mystery solving specialist at my side.
On the next Conan: The Case of the Beckoning Calico Cat (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Taii!