Wow, awesome! Poirot's really in there!
That's right.
A reporter came here a while back and said he was going to publish a piece about us,
but I never expected that it'd be an article this big!
You're even in there, Azusa-san!
See, over here!
"Taii-kun, a calico cat who frequents the café, and Azusa-san, a beautiful Poirot employee."
Right! She's even holding Tai-chan!
Wow! Maybe calling me beautiful is a bit much...
Newspaper articles usually do exaggerate the facts, after all...
W-Well, I guess...
But there's nothing about you, Amuro-niichan?
Oh, I happened to be off work that day, because I wasn't feeling well.
It's a pity that you missed out.
Especially since you're so handsome!
Well, one of the men in black wouldn't exactly want his face showing up in a random gourmet food magazine like this...
Oh, right, wasn't there another kid in your group?
Ai-chan went home already.
We did ask her if she wanted to come to Poirot to see Taii...
But apparently she suddenly remembered something she had to do...
T-Talking about Taii!! Where is he?! Is he already here?!
Well, the truth is...
Taii-kun's been staying at my house since last week!
Are you sure that's the right thing to do?
Taii may be a stray cat, but he has a collar, so he must belong to someone, right?
Still... He's turned up covered in scratches from getting into fights with other cats around here...
I couldn't help but worry about him.
And there's a photo of him in that magazine now.
If Taii's owner is really searching for him, I'm sure they'll see the article and turn up here.
But it's not fair to keep Tai-chan all to yourself!
And there's no way his owner would find such a tiny photo!
Maybe if it was on the Internet, but like this...?
That's what you'd think, right? But we've got a surprise...!
Excuse me...
Is this the Café Poirot from the magazine?
Oh, yes...
I read in that article... Apparently a cat turns up in the evenings to beg for food? There was a photo and all.
Yeah...
Shōgo Amesawa (36)
Part-Time Worker
That's actually my cat!
I've been looking for him for the last six months.
H-Hey!
What're you trying to pull?!
Teishi Masuko (54)
Company President
That's my family's cat, I know it is!
You shouldn't just say something like that!
Wow! The owners really did turn up!
And not just one, but two!
T-They're not the only two.
There's another one waiting inside...
Let the refreshing autumn breeze blow away your summer fatigue!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
Three people claiming to be his owner?!
Time for a Kogorō and Bourbon deduction tag-team!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey! How many times do I have to tell you?!
This cat is my granddaughter's cat, Mugi-chan!
Mutsumi Shagawa (61)
Housewife
Where's my Mugi-chan?
Weren't you bringing her here now?
Oh, right...
When I left to go and get him, I bumped into these kids and we got talking...
And then these two men turned up
claiming to be his owners too...
No, I'm his real owner.
You're wrong! I'm telling you, he's mine!
Are you trying to steal my granddaughter's cat?!
Wow! Tai-chan's really popular!
But why do three people want him?
He's just an ordinary calico cat, like you'd see anywhere...
He's not that ordinary.
Well, he's certainly a brilliant cat...
He even took your message to this café, back when we were all trapped in that nasty delivery van!
Tai-chan was really helpful back then!
But in the end, that message just got blown away by the wind when he brought it here...
Y-Yeah...
Anyway, Azusa-san, if you would, go home and bring Taii here.
Oh, sure.
While we're waiting, I'll hear
what each of them have to say...
...with a mystery-solving specialist at my side.
A mystery-solving specialist?
Don't tell me he means...
What?! Looking for a cat's owner?!
Go ask someone else! I'm busy today.
Honestly...
It's Goro-chan!
Why is he here?
He's that scary old hag's cat, right?
Scary old hag...?
My mother had to go to Fukuoka for work,
so she asked me to look after him for tonight.
Off you go, leave! It's not like I'd
even be getting paid for it, right?
Then I'll hire you.
For payment, I'll give you a ticket to a premium seat at Yōko Okino's summer concert.
Now, let's see, the first cat owner...
Shagawa-san, I hear you're a housewife?
Right.
Just how simple-minded are you, old man?
So when did your cat go missing?
About two months ago.
I asked a friend to take care of him since we were going on a family holiday,
but apparently he vanished the moment she took her eyes off him...
This is a photo of the cat's owner, my granddaughter.
Though it's a photo from five years ago...
I see. He's just a kitten in the photo,
but the markings on his body do look similar.
See! Even this nice detective agrees with me.
Right...
Then you like cats too, miss?
Yes, of course.
Come on, come on up.
Come on up.
Oh my, your cat does seem to be quite shy.
Though he certainly loves his owner.
This cat isn't even mine...
The calico cat from the café had been neutered, do you know anything about that?
Oh, that was a rough time for him.
He was kept in overnight, and when he came out, he had to keep his bandages on for some time,
and it was a week or so before they took the stitches out.
Masuko-san, president of an IT company.
So you're the second candidate for this cat's owner... When did your cat go missing?
When I moved, four months ago now.
My wife of thirty years passed away, so I decided to sell our house and move into a flat...
I was sure he was in his carrier when he was put into the moving company's van,
but when we came to empty the van, he'd vanished...
Huh...
Do you have any photos of him?
I've got a photo taken on my phone...
It's just the cat and my wife in the photo, but I took it.
This looks just like the Poirot cat too...
Of course it does.
It's the same cat, after all.
Then you like cats, mister?
Yeah.
Would you like to hold him?
Have you got a cold?
I-I suppose I must have...
By the way, was your cat neutered?
Yes.
But my wife handled everything like that, so I don't know the details...
I do remember that despite having surgery, he didn't have any bandages,
but just what looked like a parabolic antenna around his neck though.
Like I said... Just bring the cat
here, you'll know soon enough!
I'm his owner!
Still, I'd like to hear what happened, part-time worker Amesawa-san.
When did your cat go missing?
About six months ago.
I value freedom, so I let him roam free.
Then one day, he suddenly didn't come back.
Do you have any photos of him?
'Course I don't. I value his freedom too.
Then you like cats, right, mister?
Yeah, of course!
Come on, come on up.
No way! Goro's usually so wary of strangers...
I've always got along well with animals.
Then do you remember whether he had been neutered?
Who knows... He was fully grown when I got him.
Oh, and by the way... We've been calling Taii-kun "him", but she's actually a girl, you know?
Huh?!
Oh, well...
Then maybe she's not my cat after all...
What're you saying?
Taii's a tom cat!
You can even see his balls!
Oh, is that right?
D-Don't scare me like that...
Of course he's male!
So which of those three is his owner?
It's gotta be that young guy, right? Even Goro really liked him.
But the photo the other man had looked just like Taii.
But he wasn't even in it.
Then how about the old woman's photo?
But that's from when he was a kitten...
Have you figured anything out, Conan-kun?
Not quite yet.
Oh! That's it! Go!
Hey! Turn that down! It's hard to think with that noise!
Noise...?
Oh, right. I should tell Ai-chan.
Three owners for Tai-chan turned up?
So how's it going?
Everyone's at their wits' end trying to figure out who's the real owner...
I'm not asking about everyone, just Edogawa-kun.
Huh?
What expression's on his face?
He's got a big, beaming, mischievous smile.
Then everything'll be fine.
It seems he's found the owner.
Hey, what's going on here?
Didn't you call us all here because you figured out who his owner was?
Well, as for that, Azusa-chan from Poirot should be arriving with the cat any moment now...
Oh, well you should've just said that.
With him here, we can easily tell who the owner is.
But my cat's owner is my granddaughter...
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Tai-chan!
See? He's obviously my cat!
Well then, we'll be leaving now.
But didn't you know that when some cats see three people,
they're drawn to the one in the middle?
You never know, he could've just leapt to you because you were standing in the middle.
What?!
Is that true, Conan-kun?!
Yeah! I saw it on TV.
That must be it.
My cat would've never jumped into the arms of someone as shady as him otherwise!
Then let's try it again, you'll see!
I can stand on the left or the right, it won't change a thing.
There's an even better method we can use.
It's an experiment that'll let us
identify the owner right away.
Azusa-san, are you ready?
Yeah.
Taii-kun's calmly eating in front of the door to the agency.
Then try coming here and opening the door one by one.
One-on-one, he'll be able to identify his owner for sure.
Let's start with Shagawa-san.
S-Sure...
See, Mugi-chan, it's me. Don't you recognise me?
Mugi-chan!
I guess it won't work unless it's
his owner, my granddaughter...
No, he'd do the same thing with your granddaughter.
After all, this cat is male, and the
one you're looking for is female.
Ah!
Isn't that right, Amuro-niichan?
Yes.
Shagawa-san, you said that when your cat was neutered, it was hospitalised overnight,
then it was a week until the stitches were removed.
R-Right...
You weren't describing a male cat being castrated, but a female cat being spayed.
Spaying is an invasive procedure involving opening up the abdomen and removing the ovaries,
where castration is a simple procedure that just needs the scrotum to be cut open and the testicles removed,
so it generally doesn't need a cat to stay overnight.
All that's needed to be done post-operation is to make the cat wear a collar so he doesn't lick the wound, like Masuko-san described.
And you made it sound like you and your granddaughter lived with the cat,
but the truth is that she just brought
it to visit occasionally, right?
You don't seem to know how to act around cats.
Cats don't like being stared at
by anyone but their owners.
That's why when you were calling Goro to come to you,
he went to Uncle Kogorō instead, even though he was just ignoring him.
I'm guessing that what really happened is that your granddaughter had to go away somewhere,
and left her cat with you, but she disappeared, right?
You're right, little boy.
My granddaughter went on a school trip, and her parents decided to go abroad while she was away.
I was asked to take care of her cat, but I couldn't seem to make friends with her...
And then she vanished when I took my eyes off her...
I didn't know what to do, but then the picture of the cat in the magazine leapt out at me.
So you thought the Poirot cat could replace the cat you were missing...
But male and female cats even have different body shapes...
B-But my granddaughter gets back from her trip tonight!
I won't be able to face up to her
if I don't figure something out...
When did she go missing?
Last night, after eating dinner.
I checked everywhere a cat could hide, inbetween the furniture and anything with an opened door,
but I couldn't find her anywhere.
Then you should try searching places behind closed doors.
Places like toilets, cupboards, and inside washing machines.
Cats can sneak in through doors unnoticed the moment they're opened.
I-I'll go and have another look!
Geez! What a crazy old woman.
Then why don't you try next, Amesawa-san?
Just do what Shagawa-san did earlier.
Sure! I've been waiting for this!
Though you know how this is going to go already...
He's right, Conan-kun. It'll be just like before...
He'll jump up and start purring, won't he?
H-Hey, what's wrong? Jump up here, like before...
Come on, jump!
Oh, didn't you know?
Catnip's effects only last for five to ten minutes.
And with that gone, you're nothing more than a random stranger who's yelling at him.
Just look at Goro if you want proof. He was happily playing with you before, but now he's scared and won't even come near you.
Well, if you were really his owner, you wouldn't need to cover yourself in catnip dust when coming to meet him.
Oh, well, I can explain...
And when Conan-kun told you that he was female, you backed off straight away, didn't you?
If you'd really seen him in the magazine and were convinced enough that he was yours to come all the way here to get him,
there's no way you'd back down so easily.
You knew, didn't you?
If he was female, he wouldn't have any value at all.
Value? Isn't he just an ordinary moggy?
You're thinking of female calico cats...
But due to chromosomal abnormalities, only one in a thousand calico cats are male.
That rarity is why manekineko beckoning cats were modelled on them...
They're worth at least a million yen each...
And I've heard some have sold
for twenty million yen or more.
T-Twenty million yen?!
No way!
You're amazing, Tai-chan!
As rare as a white lion!
J-Just how many eel lunches is that, let's see...
Obviously, someone like you who knows how rare they are wouldn't let such a rare cat run wild in such a big city, right?
I-I-I'm sorry for wasting your time!
Now finally, why don't you try, Masuko-san?
S-Sure...
But it's been four months... And my wife usually gave him his food...
It'll probably go just like with those other two...
S-Sōseki...
So you do remember me, Sōseki...
But how?
He was waiting there even before the door was opened...
It's the sound.
I saw on TV that cats have great hearing, and they always remember the sound of their owner's footsteps.
Say, you said he vanished when you were moving...
Did you have the Cheetah Moving Centre handle your move?
Y-Yes. But how did you know that...?
He's climbed into the back of a delivery van belonging to that company before.
I get it! That means...
He wanted to be reunited with his owner!
He must've thought he could get home if he went in a van with the same logo...
I'm happy for you, Tai-chan.
Thank you very much for your help!
Bye-bye, Tai-chan!
Take care of yourself!
Don't run away again!
This has my address and e-mail on it.
If we can arrange a time, I'd be happy for you to come and visit him.
Really?! Thank you!
Still, I never knew cats were drawn to the person standing in the middle of a group...
That was a lie.
If he hadn't said that, he wouldn't have had a chance to do the experiment with the footsteps, so he had to tell that little fib.
He's got sharp claws hiding under that innocent smile.
Oh, since we were talking about cats...
That was a pun, huh...?
One Week Later
I never thought that old man would be the one to contact us.
The e-mail he sent to the detective agency said we could come today if we wanted to see him, right?
Yeah.
It's only been a few days since then.
I wonder why...?
Maybe he decided to get rid of his cat after all?
He seemed to be allergic to cats...
A-Allergic to cats...?
Even though he owns one?
Well, some people get cats without ever knowing they're allergic to them,
and some people develop allergies
to them while owning them.
But then that means he's gonna sell it, right?
Twenty million yen is hard to refuse...
Isn't that Masuko-san's flat?
Anyway, please open the door!
I heard a strange noise from in there.
Masuko-san! It's the caretaker! Are you okay in there?
Huh? What's this cat...?
Hey! Has something happened?
Oh, this cat doesn't look injured at all, but there's blood on its paws...
But then that must mean that Masuko-san...!
It couldn't be!
There's blood on his paws!
Something must've happened inside!
Do any of you have a string or something?
Is it the room at the end?
So you two don't have time to be fooling around.
There's tape and scissors here, but the bin is empty.
Why isn't it anywhere here?
On the next Conan: The Case of the Beckoning Calico Cat (Part II)!
Next Conan's Hint: Wrapping!
Next week, yo, part two, yeah!
That's rapping...
It's wrapping!