Having solved the question of the owner of Taii, the calico cat,
we went to visit him at the flat of his real owner, Masuko-san, when...
Huh? What's with this cat...?
Hey! Has something happened?
Oh, this cat doesn't look injured at all, but there's blood on its paws...
But then that must mean that Masuko-san...!
It couldn't be!
Let the refreshing autumn breeze blow away your summer fatigue!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
The Detective Boys and a locked-room trick!
What's the secret behind this cute calico cat?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Oh! Again?! Elaborate gimmicks and intrigue on a Saturday night
But, oh! The summer's gettin' to me, the heat and this situation
Even so—Oh oh oh—Here's a case again—Oh oh oh—Get a new viewpoint?
Oh! No! I'm no Holmes, so why oh why oh why oh God why...
Hey! I'll burst out like a summer sweat, today it's time to take another ride
You can fall asleep now, I'll solve this — I melt slowly, I melt slowly
Hey! Solving mysteries with tricks you won't beat with a novel
I get tired of thinking when I overwork my mind in this puzzling town
Ah, when things don't go well, I stand by the wharf a while
Yearning for my passion, I'll solve this — I melt slowly
Hey! I'll burst out like a summer sweat, today it's time to take another ride
You can fall asleep now, I'll solve this — I melt slowly, I melt slowly
Hey! Solving mysteries with tricks you won't beat with a novel
I get tired of thinking when I overwork my mind in this puzzling town
Masuko-san! If you're okay, please say something!
Masuko-san!
K-Kid...
He might just be sleeping, you know? The door is locked.
But his neighbour heard a strange noise, right?
Y-Yeah. There was this loud thud that sounded like something being hit.
And there's blood on the paws of Masuko-san's cat...
Something must have happened inside!
Haibara, quickly, call an ambulance!
Got it!
Do any of you have a string or something?
Also, some sort of tape, and some sort of wire.
I've got some wool!
I've got plasters...
Here's a paper clip!
But what are you going to do with these?
Unlock the door.
First, you tie the string to the U-shaped bar on the lock, then fix the loop to the bottom of the U with a plaster.
Then, if you thread some wool through the paper clip,
and stick it to the inside of the door, you're ready!
You just have to shut the door, and give the string a big tug...
It opened!
Which flat is yours?
T-That one over there...
So it'll be the closest room to his neighbour... which means on the left!
H-Hey, Conan?!
Is it the room at the end?
Looks like an accident...
Yeah.
He put the chair on his bed and tried to change the light,
but lost his balance and hit himself on his side table.
I do the same myself sometimes, but it's hard to balance on a bed, so it can be dangerous.
Please don't do that!
Your mattress is very expensive, and it's so soft and fluffy!
How come you know so much about Detective Satō's bed?
Have you slept in it?
Ah, no—
I wanna have a sleepover at Detective Satō's house too!
Gossiping aside, what's the situation? What's the guy from this flat doing?
O-O-Oh. He's had surgery, but he's still
unconscious and in a critical state.
Anyway, once he's conscious,
I'm sure he'll be very thankful to you!
After all, it's thanks to Conan-kun opening the lock so quickly that he was saved!
Actually, before that...
Once he regains consciousness, I think he'll tell us who tried to murder him.
M-Murder?
So, this isn't an accident?
Just look, the chair's on top of the bedcover.
If you were going to stand a chair on a bed, you'd pull back the cover at least, wouldn't you?
And look at this, Masuko-san's still wearing one of his slippers!
If he was going to get on a chair on the bed, don't you think he would have taken off his slippers?
T-That's true...
And, you know, the shattered light on the floor is probably the old light he took out to change,
but none of the edges are blackened, are they?
It looks brand new!
So, in other words, somebody pushed Masuko-san over here in his bedroom, got him seriously injured,
and then set up the room afterwards to make it look like an accident.
And there was about an hour between the neighbour hearing the strange noise and the caretaker arriving.
There would've been plenty of time to set the place up.
B-But there's apparently only one spare key for the front door, and both of the keys were on the living room shelf.
And how would they have set the door's safety lock?
That's all been figured out already!
Right, Conan-kun?
If you can open a lock from the outside, then I bet you know how to lock one too...
Oh, no, not exactly...
Hey, look! There's somebody on the screen!
It's true!
Wait, what are you guys doing messing around here?
It's the intercom!
The intercom's set up to record videos of whoever rings the doorbell at the ground floor entrance.
And here they are. Three people came within the hour before we arrived.
The audio gets recorded too, and they all introduced themselves,
so we should be able to identify them using Masuko-san's address book.
So you two don't have time to be fooling around.
Geez! You just had to open your big mouth, Takagi-kun!
S-Sorry!
There's an old cat carrier on the table with some wrapping paper.
So he really was going to give that calico to someone as a gift.
There's tape and fold marks on the wrapping paper, and some tears here and there,
so did somebody unwrap it after it had already been wrapped?
There's tape and scissors here...
But the bin is empty...
Why can't I see it anywhere?
We managed to find the three people recorded by the intercom pretty quickly.
Yes, but his first visitor was the only one invited into the flat.
He dealt with his second visitor at the door,
and the third one rang the doorbell on his door, but didn't get a reply, and went home.
All three of them are suspicious.
You're right.
If we consider that the first visitor was still there when the second one turned up,
then even the first visitor could have tried to kill him after the second left.
Come to think of it, what did Masuko-san do when you lot rang the intercom at the entrance?
We didn't ring it!
We thought about ringing it, but then one of the residents was going out, so we went in while the door was open.
We thought we'd rush in and give him a surprise!
We had arranged to meet him.
And we knew his flat number.
I see.
Furuyo Tsuyuguchi (41)
Pub Landlord
Yes. I did indeed meet Masuko-san today and we had tea in his living room.
I stayed for about the length of one track on a record, so it must have been for 10 minutes or so.
A record?
Oh yes, I collect vintage jazz records and Masuko-san said that he'd found a record I'd been searching for,
so since I was going along to pick it up,
I asked him to play a track to me.
Did the bell ring while you were here?
No idea... I was listening to it through headphones.
Excuse me, but would you mind if I used the toilet?
Not at all.
Then if you don't mind...
Hey, kid!
Why didn't you turn off the light when you were done?!
I'm really sorry!
Oh, er, I just can't stand wasting power like that.
As I said,
I spoke to him at his door,
but I didn't come into his flat.
Mari Asō (28)
Former Employee of Masuko's Company
I had turned up without an appointment, and it seemed like he already had a visitor with him.
Why did you come to see Masuko-san?
Well, you see,
I was fired by Masuko-san's company,
so I thought I'd drop by to see him one last time...
You weren't coming to complain were you?
Oh no, quite the opposite!
I was fired because of a huge mistake on my part,
and he really helped me get a new job, so I thought I'd come to thank him.
Hey, that's a really cute kitty! Can I hold him?
He's so cute!
Tai-chan's really happy, he's wagging his tail!
You're right.
Do you have a cat?
No. My parents aren't big fans of pets, though I like them...
Don't make me repeat myself.
Rimpei Urushiya (53)
Novelist
Yes, I came up here to the front door,
but no matter how many times I rang the bell, he wouldn't answer, so I gave up and went home!
So, how did you get inside the building in the first place?
He let me in when I pressed the button on the intercom on the ground floor.
Though, he didn't say anything, so I can't say for sure that he was the one who opened the door.
What was your relationship with Masuko-san?
We've known each other since university,
and even debuted as writers in the same year.
Though his novels didn't sell so well, so he gave up very quickly.
That said, only my first novel sold well.
Looking back on it, he probably did the right thing, changing jobs.
And you came here to...?
Go over some ideas for novels with him.
He's always helped me out like that when I had writer's block.
Can someone take that cat away? It's so annoying...
Do you not like cats?
That's right! I got scratched by one of the neighbourhood strays this morning!
If you need a plaster, I've got one!
Don't worry. I've already seen to it myself.
Thanks.
Though if that cat was a great detective like in those famous novels, I'd be glad to have him around...
The order in which they rang the intercom was Tsuyuguchi-san followed by Asō-san, then Urushiya-san, so that fits,
but that neighbour wasn't sure what time exactly he heard the strange noise, so we can't narrow down our suspects.
I guess we'll just have to wait for Masuko-san to wake up.
No, I don't think we'll have to wait.
See!
It's that mischievous smile!
So those are the three people that came here around the time the neighbour heard the suspicious noise?
Yeah.
But the door was locked and bolted, wasn't it?
Are you sure this was a crime?
Ah, yes. The crime scene indicated that it wasn't an accident, a-according to Conan-kun...
Is Conan-kun inside the flat?
No, he said there was something he needed to buy.
We're back!
Conan-kun!
What did you buy?
We bought the thing that disappeared from Masuko-san's flat!
The thing that disappeared?
This.
A decorative ribbon!
You usually cut off the excess ribbon with scissors after tying up a present.
So, seeing how there weren't any bits of ribbon in the bin,
I guess the ribbon just happened to be the right length, even though Masuko-san had scissors ready to cut it.
The present itself was a used carrier, and he had tape there too,
so he must've wrapped it himself instead of having it wrapped at a store.
B-But... What does that tell us?
Are you still half asleep?
The fact that it disappeared from the crime scene means that the culprit must have used it for something!
H-Half asleep...?
For example, to lock the room to make it look like an accident.
In any case, let's try it out and see whether or not that's actually possible!
First up, how the safety lock was latched!
We pass the ribbon between the door and the bolt, so it catches on it,
then go outside holding onto both ends of the ribbon and close the door,
And finally, we only have to pull tight on both ends.
All right, Mitsuhiko!
Roger!
Start pulling.
All right!
I-It worked?!
Next up, locking the door!
After opening the door and checking that it's bolted,
we remove the ribbon, and make a knot in the middle of it.
I've knotted it!
Then we loop the ribbon around the dial to lock the door, so that the knot catches on it,
then we pull one end of the ribbon out and close the door.
After that, if we then pull on it from outside at an upward angle...
T-That's great!
The ribbon really locked the door!
But unlike with the safety lock,
you can't pull the ribbon out this time...
Hey, pull as hard as you can on the ribbon!
Right.
But since the door is closed, the knot's stuck...
That's weird. It should have worked perfectly.
Guess that's what happens when we rely on a kid.
When you guys came here, there wasn't a ribbon there, right?
No.
There wasn't anything there.
Well, it seems like locking the door with the ribbon is impossible.
Yeah... The ribbon gets left behind...
If only someone could pull out the ribbon from inside and take it somewhere else...
Someone, you say? The victim was the only one here.
And he's unconscious even now.
Guess there's no other choice.
Look, over there!
Good luck!
Move the ribbon around.
All right!
T-The cat grabbed the ribbon and took it?!
Follow that cat!
S-Sure!
Behind the bookshelf?
That's where the cat hides his treasures, I suppose.
I found it!
There's a second ribbon that's different from the one we just used!
It has a knot too, so there's no doubt about it!
The question is who used the ribbon for this trick?
I think it'd be someone who knows a lot about cats.
Yeah, they'd have to know that the cat would not only carry the ribbon somewhere, but also that it would hide it.
Then could it be the girl with the glasses?
Tai-chan was wagging his tail when she was holding him!
No, unlike dogs, cats wag their tail when they're agitated.
Asō-san, who didn't know that, doesn't seem to know a lot about cats.
Well, in that case, maybe he was agitated because she was the one who hurt his owner?
But in that case, she wouldn't happily ask to hold the cat!
She'd worry about it scratching her.
But the remaining two are Tsuyuguchi-san, who seemed to be very concerned about conserving electricity,
and Urushiya-san, who picked up the things that fell from Genta-kun's pocket.
Both of those actions seemed almost unconscious, like habits they had.
Yeah.
But, you know, when Genta dropped his plasters, tissues and a bottle cap, he only picked up the bottle cap, right?
Now that you mention it, that's true. But why would he do that?
Why don't we try it out?
See!
I see! The cat loves bottle caps too!
I see.
If the cat had taken the bottle cap and brought it to the rest of its treasures,
we might have found the ribbon that was used in the trick.
Well, it seems to have been a non-premediated crime using objects that were lying around.
If he wasn't wearing gloves, we should be able to get fingerprints from the ribbon.
All right, question Urushiya-san again!
Hey, when did you start thinking that author was suspicious?
Was it because Tai-chan raised his tail when he approached him?
As cats only do that around people to whom they are close and when they are very happy.
Well, there was that, but I suspected that he was the culprit
when he said that someone was kind enough to open the door when he rang the bell on the intercom for the ground floor.
If the one who opened had been the culprit,
he would still have been in the flat at that point.
It made no sense that the culprit would invite someone up
when he still had to use his trick at the door
in order to create the locked room.
Indeed. I was the one who attacked and injured him.
Coming up with that trick on the spot is quite something...
I once wrote a mystery novel with a trick like that.
Actually, I came today to borrow some money from him.
We had originally planned to meet up tomorrow, but this
morning, he called to tell me he had a great present for me.
Since I was curious, I couldn't help coming by today.
But the present turned out to be
a hastily wrapped used cat carrier!
And all that was in there was that calico cat!
On top of that, he told me that he couldn't give it to me yet, with a stupid grin...
That cat was just a stray that I rescued in the past...
So you were its owner before?
Yes. I had it for about half a year, while it was still a kitten.
I gave it to him when his wife was suffering from losing a pet...
Well, giving it to him turned out to be the right thing to do.
Right after that, my books completely stopped selling and I couldn't have cared for a pet cat.
But on the other hand, his company started to really take off...
Despite that, he had the gall to try and push that stray cat onto me!
That's right. When that cat came into the bedroom holding the ribbon I'd unwrapped, he picked it up and said...
You'll be fine if you have this cat!
And it was yours in the first place.
It's only fitting for you to be its owner.
But Tai-chan's an amazing cat, you know!
Male calico cats are a rare breed, and hardly ever found.
And they're worth loads!
But I suppose the reason why Masuko-san wanted to give the cat back to you wasn't money,
but because it was a lucky,
Beckoning Cat.
itsushika jibun miushinatte'ta ‘daijōbu'-tte hontō wa uso
iiwake nante mō dō ni mo naranai
kokoro ga odoru yō ja nakya ne
kokoro ni hitotsuzutsu hi o tomoshitekita kedo
gomen tameiki tsuichatta kono mama ja kiesō
muteki na heart sawagidashite
saa kokoro hodoite respect yourself
hontō no jibun de ireba muchū de yume mite'ta watashi ni (be back)
invincible heart mezamesasete
osoreru koto nai revives my heart
namida o nagashita ato ni wa muteki na watashi to ashita ni cheers!
Isn't that great news?
Tai-chan's owner was released from hospital!
Yeah, it seems like there weren't any after-effects, either...
So? What happened to the cat?
It ended up with Azusa-san from Poirot, it seems.
Huh? Tai-chan?
No way! You strayed off again?
And doesn't he look smaller, too...
His fur pattern's exactly the same, though...
Come on! Let's go home, Mugi!
Really, Grandma, you can't just open the carrier like that!
I'm sorry. But it seemed so tight in there...
That old lady...!
All's well that ends well, I guess?
Are you sure about that? I'm the 'peeping tom', you know.
You're still here, Suzuki-san?
Didn't the landlady tell you to hurry up and leave?
Hey, we have a guest, you know.
That's enough, Katsuko-san.
I-In there... K-Katsuko-san...
On the next Conan: ‘The Blind Spot in the Shared House'!
Next Conan's Hint: Fridge!
Leave the fridge to me!
I don't get it.
Must be the autumn appetite.