Really?! You're the strongest one in the karate club, Ran-chan?
That's right, Yasuko-san!
Her kicks can easily send even the guys flying!
W-Wait a second, Yayoi-san. You're exaggerating!
Yasuko Kawakami (25)
Office Lady and Resident of the Shared House
That's amazing! You must be a karate master!
No, I'm not that great...
Yayoi Yajima (21)
College Student and Resident of the Shared House
Well, as a senior in the same karate club, I'm very proud...
Shoot! It's this late, already...?
I've gotta take a bath.
In that case, I should be heading home soon, too...
Huh? You came all this way to hang out, so stick around a little longer.
Someone's coming to pick you up, too, right?
Yes, well...
In that case, you'll be fine!
I've just started getting to know you, too.
Yeah!
I'm back.
Oh. Welcome back, Suzuki-san.
Good to be back.
This girl here is Ran Mouri-san, my junior.
Hidehisa Suzuki (26)
Businessman and Resident of the Shared House
Sorry for intruding.
Nice to meet you. I'm Suzuki.
Oh, would you like some cake too, Suzuki-san?
Can I? I'm a peeping tom, after all.
Nobody believes that.
You're supposed to eat it about 15 minutes after taking it out of the fridge...
So hold on a little while.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Oh? You're still here, Suzuki-san?
Katsuko Kanō (25)
Dancer and Resident of the Shared House
Didn't the landlady tell you to hurry up and get out?
I bet you're the one who was lying about me, saying I was peeping on you!
But it's so easy to do this and that when there's only girls living here.
Don't give me that crap!
Hey, stop. We have a guest.
Please stop this, Katsuko-san.
Oh, Yayoi-chan. You can actually tell
me that with a straight face?
Whatever. I've gotta get in some tap dance practice before taking my bath.
Umm, Katsuko-san.
What?
I've asked you before, but can you please go easy on your tap dancing practice?
You know my room is right below yours, right?
So...
Umm... I have cake. Don't you like that, Katsuko-san?
Oh, being a brown noser, are we?
No, that's...
Then I'll have some later.
Okay, I'm gonna go take my bath now.
Alright.
Ran-chan, sorry for letting you see our dirty laundry like that...
Ah, it's not that...
Don't worry. Suzuki-san isn't spying on anyone.
Katsuko-san's just spreading false rumours of her own accord.
Let's not talk about that anymore.
Because I'm going to have a good, hard talk with that woman later.
Thanks for the cake. I'll eat it in my room.
Okay, you ladies take it easy.
Oh, thank you.
Let the refreshing autumn breeze blow away your summer fatigue!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
A shocking incident takes place in a shared house.
What alibi trick was on the schedule?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
You have all kind of things, even in a shared house.
When I first came here, I thought how attractive the place is.
How even the doors in this shared space work to make it feel really open...
And how there's a decorative potted plant.
This place was remodelled so that nobody would feel reluctant to walk right in.
Well, you're living with total strangers after all, so there are a lot of things to worry about.
There are a lot of rules, too.
Rules?
Yeah. Take a look at the back of your chair.
'Guest'
Oh!
'Yayoi'
'Yasuko'
And putting a sticker with your name on your belongings.
'Guest'
You're right!
Ah, that bath felt so nice.
Then I'll go take mine.
Okay.
So? What were you talking about?
We were gossiping about you, Yayoi-san.
About how you often forget to take out the garbage and such...
I can be kind of careless.
It looks like you have a set order for cleaning duties and a bathing schedule, too.
And even a message board. It seems really hard.
Yeah. But compared to a normal place, the rent's way cheaper here.
That's why no one wants to leave.
Oh, Yasuko-san?
Katsuko-san's cake?
Sure...
Okay. I'll put it back if she doesn't come in 15 minutes.
I'll help you with those, Yayoi-sempai!
No, I can handle the dishes. You're a guest after all.
Huh?
Is something the matter?
No, it's nothing...
Umm...
Did something happen with Katsuko-san?
Katsuko-san didn't even come down to eat it.
'Katsuko'
I'm borrowing money from her.
Money?
I see.
Because your father suddenly passed away.
And taking care of my younger brother, who's still in middle school, costs money too...
So I can't have remittance money sent to me, either.
But I'm fine. I manage to make ends meet between my part-time job and my scholarships.
Oh, Katsuko-san didn't come.
Is that right?
She really does whatever she feels like, doesn't she?
Could that be...
The people picking you up.
Come on in!
Oh, sorry I couldn't get here any earlier.
Let's go home, Ran-neechan.
Thank you for having me over, Yayoi-sempai, Yasuko-san.
Come back anytime.
Sure.
What's wrong? What happened?
Suzuki-san!
Inside... Katsuko-san's...
The victim is Katsuko Kanō-san, age 25.
It appears certain that the weapon was the knife found at the crime scene...
But there weren't any fingerprints on it.
The time of death is estimated to be between 7:15 and 7:45 PM.
The contents of the plastic bottle on the floor of the crime scene were examined,
and sleeping medication was detected inside.
I see. So she was drugged to sleep, and then stabbed to death.
Then, since you were the first to discover the body, Suzuki-san, please give us the details.
Ah, okay...
This morning, there was a message from Katsuko-san written on the message board, directed at me.
It said, 'I'll be stopping by your room tonight before 8 PM. Let's talk this out.'
I don't see that written anywhere.
Did anyone else see that message?
It also said 'Keep this a secret'!
So I erased it myself.
Also, I'm always the last one to leave the house, so Katsuko-san probably chose to write it at a time when I'd be alone.
Then what?
I waited in my room the whole time, just as the message said to.
But...
Katsuko-san never showed, even after 8 PM, and when I went to her room to check, Katsuko-san was lying on her bed...
I get it.
It's true! Please believe me!
No!
I didn't do it!
Isn't that right, Yayoi-chan, Yasuko-san?!
Huh?
Do the two of you happen to know something about this?
Actually, Katsuko-san and Suzuki-san having been fighting non-stop lately.
They had a bit of a quarrel before going back to their rooms tonight, too...
Ran, is that true?
Yeah...
It's not just me!
Even you two hated Katsuko-san!
Right, Yasuko-san and Yayoi-chan?
Wait a sec!
I don't think those two have anything to do with this case.
What makes you think that, Ran-kun?
Because between 7 PM and 8 PM those two were either taking a bath, as scheduled...
...or here with me.
As scheduled?
They're scheduled, right?
Bathing times, I mean.
'Cause it's a shared house.
That's right...
Also, except for one time I went to use the toilet,
I've been sitting here the whole time.
And I can see the hallway through the glass doors.
Sliding glass doors, huh...?
You can certainly see all the way around.
And to go from the bath upstairs,
you'd have to come through this hallway.
I'm sure no-one came through here while Yasuko-san was taking her bath.
I see... So that establishes these two's alibis.
So, Suzuki-san...
I'm sorry, but can I have you explain what happened when you found her at the scene upstairs one more time?
Yes, sir...
'Write your name on your personal belongings', huh?
Come to think of it, her name was written on the bottle at the scene of the crime, too.
You want something to drink?
Oh, no. I'm fine.
No need to be reserved.
Hey, is that Katsuko-san's cake?
Yeah... I pulled it out of the fridge and had it ready for her.
Since you called me from the bathroom, Yasuko-san.
I did that because I wasn't wearing anything.
But in the end, Katsuko-san never came down to eat it.
That's why I put it back in the fridge.
You're supposed to eat it about 15 minutes after taking it out of the fridge...
I wanted to have her eat it when it tasted the best.
So that's it.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Oh, nothing.
Did anything else odd happen while you were here?
Odd?
Now that you mention it, Yayoi-san!
When you were washing the dishes, you tilted your head to the side, like you were puzzled.
I'll help you with those, Yayoi-sempai!
No, I can handle the dishes. You're a guest after all.
Huh?
Oh, that...!
When someone's taking a bath,
the amount of hot water coming from the tap usually slows down.
But at the time, it was running fine.
The bath was that way, right?
Wait, Conan-kun!
It's here, too.
Traces of something being wiped up, and stepped on.
What's the matter?
Hey...
What is that stuff?
Oh no!
It's shampoo.
I spilled some when I opened a new refill.
I tried wiping it up, but it looks like I missed a spot.
The window...
It's a clear view of the dining room.
Which means that if I do this...
Why is this the only white spot on the wall?
Oh, that. A picture used to be hanging there, but the landlady removed it and took it with her yesterday.
Isn't that...
Inspector Megure!
Please, come quickly!
This towel was discovered in Suzuki-san's shoe box.
I see. So that's it.
Just as I thought, you're the killer, Suzuki-san!
You were on bad terms with Katsuko-san from the beginning.
And tonight's argument pushed you over the edge, so you murdered Katsuko-san upstairs,
during which you wrapped the handle of the knife in this towel, in order to not leave any fingerprints on it.
You then hid it, probably planning to dispose of it later.
That settles it! Right, Inspector?
Yes.
Hidehisa Suzuki-san, as our top suspect, will you accompany us to the station?
It's not me! I didn't do it!
No... That man isn't the killer.
The killer is one of those two...
So that's it!
Please wait, everyone.
M-Mouri-san? Is this...
It appears it's too soon to decide that Suzuki-san is the murderer.
B-But Mouri-kun. Didn't you just say...?
What I did was truly embarrassing.
After all, take one look at Suzuki-san and it's clear as day.
Think back to the scene of the murder.
Since Katsuko-san died due to having her artery cut, blood had flown out and landed all around her.
However, take a look.
Suzuki-san's sweatshirt is completely white.
How could the murderer have avoided coming in contact with blood?
Couldn't he have changed his clothes before pretending to find the body?
If that was the case, those clothes should have already been found,
because there was no time for him to go and throw them away.
T-That's true...
In that case, who on Earth did it...?
This is what the killer did:
First, pretending to be Katsuko-san, she wrote a message to Suzuki-san on the message board,
so that Suzuki-san would stay in his room while the crime occurred, and lose his alibi.
Then, at the time of the crime, the killer snuck out of the bath and went upstairs.
Hold on a minute, Mouri-kun.
According to Ran-kun's testimony, no one came through the hallway at the time of the crime.
Conan!
Here I am!
Detective Takagi!
There's a big potted plant in front of that door, right?
Look under it.
Do you see the marks left when it was moved?
Yes.
Can you move it a little closer to the door, following those marks?
L-Like this?
Now can you go out in the hall and close the door?
Got it.
Now, Ran-neechan. Go stand by the fridge, and when Uncle gives you the sign, open the fridge door.
Oh, okay.
Everyone come here.
Now take a good look at Detective Takagi.
Alright, Ran! Open the refrigerator door for me.
Okay.
T-This...
Do you understand now?
You can no longer see Detective Takagi from where Ran had been sitting.
I heard this from Conan, but it seems that before and after the crime, the refrigerator door had been opened twice.
In order to take out Katsuko-san's cake, and put it back in.
Before committing the crime, the killer slid that potted plant over in the short time Ran went to use the toilet.
Then she snuck out of the bath.
There's proof of this, too.
In the changing room, the killer stepped on some shampoo that had been spilled on the floor.
There were traces of that left in the hallway.
And in the instant the refrigerator door was opened,
she dashed off to Katsuko-san's room.
There, the killer snuck in, found Katsuko-san sound asleep from being drugged, and...
After the crime, she put the bloodied towel in Suzuki-san's shoe box...
And like before, the instant the cake was being put back in the refrigerator...
The rest was just looking for a chance to move that potted plant back.
Wait, Dad!
That means I was...
Ran, you were being used to create her alibi.
'Guest'
After all, that's the seat guests use.
But wait! I'm the one who opened the fridge.
Which means the killer is...
Yasuko-san?!
I did it?! That's absurd! You're wrong!
Oh? Hey, Miss. Did you hurt your shoulder?
It's bleeding.
And that is the very proof that you went upstairs.
Take a look at the window that looks out onto the stairs.
Although it's in a high place, she didn't want to risk having someone see her while going to commit the crime.
So she crouched down, but when she went to stand back up after passing the window...
That's right.
There was a nail sticking out of the wall next to the window, at the exact location for it to hit her shoulder.
Now hold on a second!
You said that Suzuki-san didn't have blood splattered back on him, right?
But Katsuko-san's blood isn't on my clothes, either, is it?
I realised this as soon as I saw that cut.
You received a cut on your body due to the nail, yet that T-shirt isn't torn.
The clothes you were wearing earlier probably aren't either.
So what does this mean?
After going to the bath, you took off all of your clothes and proceeded to murder Katsuko-san while completely naked.
That way, you could easily wipe off the blood that was splattered on you with the towel you used to hold the knife.
And as you made your way back to the bath,
you were careful not to let any drip onto the floor, before washing the rest off in the shower.
You're wrong! I...!
In that case, shall we have the drainage pipe from the shower examined?
Because I guarantee that they'll find Katsuko-san's blood in it!
Yasuko-san, why did you do it?
Tap, tap, tap, tap... It echoed through the ceiling.
Every single night, the sound of that woman's tap dancing shoes was right above me!
And no matter how many times I asked, she wouldn't stop!
I couldn't take it anymore!
You did it because of that...?
And she told me this.
To tell you the truth, it feels so good!
It's almost like I'm stepping right on top of your head.
So just deal with it.
'Cause I have no other use for a third-rate, half-assed woman like you.
Hey, Dad!
I just thought of a great idea!
Let's make this place a shared house, too!
It'll help with our household expenses, too!
What? Don't talk nonsense.
I see...
We could've had a beautiful, hard-working businesswoman living with us...
Oh, what a shame.
Well, I suppose if it will help us with our expenses a bit...
Really?! Yay!
'Eri Kisaki'
Then I'll go stick this on one of our empty rooms, okay?!
Now we'll be able to live together as a family again!
I've gotta let Mum know.
Hey, Ran! Stop!
Give me that!
Hello? Mum?
Hey, wait...
That means we'd have to eat Kisaki-sensei's cooking...
Hey, wait! Wait, Ran-neechan! Please wait!
These are the printed photos.
Do your best.
It happened fifteen years ago.
At another rental villa near this one.
By the time the police heard the noise and got there...
Red...
Red?
Red.
...in the bathtub...
On the next Conan:
'Tragedy of the Red Woman (Steam)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Tomatoes!
Greengrocer!
ya-o-ya
Woodpecker!
ki-tsu-tsu-ki
Newspaper!
shi-n-bu-n-shi
Conan's a weird kid!
ko-na-n he-n na ko