Detective Conan Episode 756 Tragedy
of the Red Woman (Revenge)
Invited by Sera,
we came to a rental villa in the mountains
to solve a series of mysteries
related to the Red Woman.
However, the body of villa guest
Masaie Hakuya-san was discovered,
and Sumika Kawana-san was attacked
by a mysterious woman with a knife.
A refreshing autumn breeze
blows through the gaiety
of summer for a stylish and
dashing display of deduction.
Sera's actions grow curious,
but the mystery of the Red
Woman is finally revealed.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Tragedy of the Red Woman
(Revenge)
In any case, I called a car to pick us up.
Everyone wait in the living room until then.
I'll inspect the other rooms.
You guard those five.
Um, but...
What about them?
Oh, yeah.
I want to ask this high school
detective some questions,
and Inspector Yamato just called to tell me
to bring this boy on any investigations.
I'm counting on you.
Why isn't Inspector Yamato
coming to this crime scene?
Aren't you in the same squad?
There was something he had to confirm
before tomorrow's Red
Woman media announcement.
He's out investigating something
with Inspector Morofushi.
Those two were stuck on the
Red Woman case for a while.
We can't find them anywhere.
No long-haired wig, no knife.
Not even wet clothes.
There isn't any moisture or
mud left around the window.
Sumika-san probably wasn't attacked by
Tamami-san dressed as the Red Woman.
Ninda-san's room on the second floor
was the same when we inspected it.
There weren't any wet marks in
the entryway or hallway, either.
Yeah.
I was sure one of those two did this, though.
It's possible Sumika-san made up
her story about being attacked.
In order to avoid suspicion,
she cut herself with a knife and
pretended she was attacked.
I don't think that's likely.
The cut on Sumika-san's back was a
single clean horizontal cut, right?
You couldn't do that yourself.
Then who attacked Sumika-san?
Maybe...
...the culprit isn't inside the villa.
Maybe there really is
something in the forest...
...hiding out there
and coming to get us.
I'm joking.
You're a cop, aren't you?
Anyway, what did you want to ask me?
Oh, right.
It's about the strange incidents that
previously happened at this rental villa.
If you were brought here as a detective,
I thought you might have heard the details.
You have pictures that were
taken then, don't you?
Yeah.
I see.
These incidents certainly are strange.
Red apples, red rose petals, and red paint.
And in this incident, a ton of tomatoes
were found floating in the bathtub, right?
They're all things that
remind you of the Red Woman.
Oh?
Just this photo looks old.
Yeah.
Apparently they took that twelve years ago,
on the afternoon their
classmate went missing.
The person in the middle is Imoto
Satoko-san, the girl found in the swamp.
That's odd.
She's wearing a beige cardigan, isn't she?
Yeah.
When her body was discovered,
she was wearing a long red coat.
What?
The ones who found the
knife next to the swamp
were Inspector Yamato
and Inspector Morofushi.
They were still in training
at the police academy.
Since then, they haven't
stopped arguing about it.
Inspector Yamato insists the skeleton
found with the girl isn't the Red Woman's,
but Inspector Morofushi says it
most likely is the Red Woman.
Inspector Morofushi seemed smug when we
learned the skeleton was the Red Woman's,
but Kan-chan wouldn't accept it.
Kan-chan?
Huh?
Oh! I mean Inspector Kansuke Yamato!
I-I call him that because
we're childhood friends.
Apparently, he went to talk
to the now retired policeman,
currently working at a
pachinko parlor, who showed up
at the crime scene fifteen years ago.
Pachinko
It doesn't make sense!
After the incident, you thoroughly searched
the forest for the Red Woman, right?
If you couldn't find the weapon then,
how did we find the knife three years later?
It must have been hidden under some leaves.
It was hidden when we discovered it, too.
But three years had passed
since the incident.
Normally you'd expect the
knife to have rusted more.
The knife was made from a special
rust resistant material.
But you chased after the Red Woman
immediately after she attacked you, right?
You should've known the Red Woman
was running into quicksand!
Why didn't you search the swamp then?
I-I couldn't follow her immediately.
M-My knees gave out...
What?
She threw the knife at me,
with a terrifying face covered in blood!
What?
I-I quit the police force
because it traumatized me.
Hey.
That means...
Yes. Most likely...
What?
A reporting error?
Yeah, that's right.
The uniformed officer who arrived
at the scene of the crime
was terrified and wrote
the wrong thing down.
In any case, Komei and I are on our way,
but you should be careful, Uehara.
C-Careful of what?
You idiot!
You don't understand?
She's still in the forest!
Oh, no. The battery's dead.
What did Inspector Yamato say?
It was about the police report on
the murder fifteen years ago.
The policeman wrote he was attacked
by the Red Woman and she escaped,
but she actually threw her
knife at him and ran away.
I see. So that's how it is.
In that case, just as I originally deduced...
That person killed Hakuya-san.
I knew evil spirits...
...don't exist!
Good work, ma'am.
Did you figure something out?
What?
Jinsuke Ninda (29)
Rental Villa Guest
I'm asking if you figured out who put
Hakuya in the tub and attacked Sumika!
N-Not yet...
What are you doing?
Aren't you cops?
It...
Sumika Kawana (28)
Rental Villa Guest
It was an evil spirit.
The ghost of the Red Woman is...
We don't know that's true.
Tamami Minegishi (28)
Rental Villa Guest
But if you don't know,
isn't that what that means?
Th-Then...
We shouldn't stay here any longer.
One by one, every one of us...
Like Satoko and Hakuya-kun...
We'll be killed by the Red Woman's ghost.
Can we even run from a—
No one's going to be killed.
The ghost of the Red
Woman you keep mentioning...
...doesn't exist.
B-But you don't know who attacked
Hakuya and Sumika, right?
No, but I do know who killed
Hakuya-san in the bathroom.
What?
B-But...
Isn't that the same person
who attacked Sumika-san?
Is the culprit among us?
Yes.
But Ran-chan didn't notice anything unusual
when she checked the
temperature of the water.
When they went to take a bath
after they finished cleaning,
they found a ton of tomatoes
floating in the tub,
and Hakuya-san's body in
the bottom of the bath.
The murder must have occurred while
the three of them were cleaning.
That means the people who could have
killed Hakuya-san are either Tamami-san,
who was prepping for dinner
in the kitchen, or Ninda-san,
who was out shopping at a
store one kilometer away.
Didn't you say it was impossible for
either of them to commit the crime?
Yes.
During that time,
Sumika-san and the others were cleaning
the first floor where the bathroom is.
I don't think it would have been possible
to kill someone without them noticing.
Besides, it must've taken more than
one trip to bring enough tomatoes
to cover the water's surface and the
dumbbells that kept the body from floating.
Then it wasn't possible for the
three of them to commit the crime.
No.
If Hakuya-san's body was already in the water
when Ran-kun and the others went
to check the water's temperature,
then there's one person
who could have done it.
Yes.
Before you went to check
the water's temperature,
the person cleaning the second floor alone,
Sumika Kawana-san.
You could have murdered him.
S-Sumika killed Hakuya-kun?
What are you talking about?
That's not possible!
That's right. It's true that Sumika-san was
cleaning the second floor the whole time.
We heard the vacuum running and
the nozzle bumping into walls.
The knocking sound was created by
sticking cardboard to Ninda-san's bat,
hanging it from a column, and
pointing a rotating fan at the pillar.
This causes the bat to sway each
time its struck by the wind.
On its way back, it strikes the column,
creating a regular knocking sound.
As proof, there were traces of
something sticky left on the bat,
Ninda-san's room is directly above the
living room you were cleaning at the time,
and there was a hook on a pillar
in his room for hanging the bat.
B-But there wasn't a corpse
when we checked the water...
The bath was green with bath salts,
and you couldn't see the bottom, right?
Yeah, but there wasn't a single
tomato floating in there.
They just weren't floating.
What?
The tomatoes just weren't floating.
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Sera-no-neechan stole this
tomato from the crime scene.
When you put it in water...
Look! It sinks!
They sometimes do this in the produce
sections at supermarkets, right?
Yeah.
Unlike normal tomatoes,
tomatoes high in sugar sink.
Maybe the tomatoes had sunk
to the bottom of the tub
so you couldn't see them.
Then how did she make the tomatoes float?
With salt.
Salt?
Yeah.
If you pour in just enough salt to
barely keep them from floating,
then by adding a little more...
It's floating!
Increasing the salinity of the
water caused its relative weight
to exceed that of the high sugar
content tomatoes, making them float.
Though she probably used bath
salts to avoid suspicion later.
Sumika-san pretended to be
cleaning the second floor,
and sneaked up on Hakuya-san
cleaning the bathroom.
She knocked him unconscious by striking
him with a dumbbell from behind.
After putting his body in the water,
she placed dumbbells on him so
he wouldn't float, used bath salts
to increase the salinity of the water
so the tomatoes barely wouldn't float,
and covered the tub.
Under the guise of checking
the water's temperature,
she had the girls confirm there
was nothing floating in the tub.
Then she entered the bathroom first,
added bath salts to the water,
and made the tomatoes float.
As proof, just like my sleeves when
I pulled the body from the water,
your sleeves should be covered in them, too.
Your sleeves that were soaked in incredibly
salty water have dried, leaving behind...
...salt crystals.
They probably got wet when
you first dumped bath salts
in the water and stirred them
around, but it was obvious.
Your sleeves were down when we first met,
but you've had them up
since after the incident.
I thought you were suspicious
since we first met, though.
Since we first met?
Everyone else thought
Sera-no-neechan was a boy,
but you handed her the photos
without asking her anything.
That means you knew Sera-no-neechan
was a high school girl detective, right?
I thought you might be the Red
Woman we saw in the forest,
and you were eavesdropping
on our conversation then.
No way!
That was Sumika-san?
Sumika killed Hakuya?
Is it true?
Yes, it's true.
I put on a long-haired wig, a
red raincoat and red boots
to become the Red Woman,
in order to draw out the coward
who left Satoko to die.
L-Left her to die?
A few years ago,
when I heard from a policeman, I knew.
When Satoko's body was
discovered in the swamp,
she was wearing a red coat.
W-Wait.
I thought Satoko was wearing
a beige cardigan then.
Satoko had been playing
the Red Woman, too.
B-But wasn't it Satoko who said she
saw the Red Woman in the forest?
That's right.
After saying that,
she pretended to get separated
while we were searching,
and planned to become the
Red Woman to surprise us.
If that's true, she must have
had an accomplice for her prank.
A partner to lead us to Satoko
disguised as the Red Woman.
It was Hakuya?
Yes, that's right.
That's why I reminded him of the Red
Woman by scaring him with apples,
rose petals and paint, but
he wouldn't show himself.
When I dressed as the Red
Woman, he finally let it slip.
He only mistook the
Red Woman for Satoko
because he was her accomplice.
When he was in the bathroom, he told me.
Satoko wasn't where they planned to meet,
but he got scared and couldn't say anything.
They probably got lost and couldn't
find where they agreed to meet,
but if he had told us about the prank...
Satoko...
Satoko wouldn't have died!
H-Hold on.
Then who was the woman who attacked you?
It was probably either Ninda-kun or Tamami,
once they realized what I had done.
W-We would never do that!
That's right!
Th-Then...
Wh-Who was it?
There's one more person
closely related to the case
whose fate is still unknown.
I found you.
What?
That's enough!
There's no Red Woman here!
Your revenge ended fifteen years ago.
It's never too late to make amends.
Once you make a mistake, you
must immediately make amends.
There's no need to hold back.
We, the Nagano Prefectural Police,
intend to reveal the reporting officer's
mistake at the press conference
on the murder that happened
fifteen years ago.
So please lay down your
knife, Shinobu Kagawa-san.
You're another victim
of the Red Woman case.
itsushika jibun miushinatte'ta ‘daijōbu'-tte hontō wa uso
iiwake nante mō dō ni mo naranai
kokoro ga odoru yō ja nakya ne
kokoro ni hitotsuzutsu hi o tomoshitekita kedo
gomen tameiki tsuichatta kono mama ja kiesō
muteki na heart sawagidashite
saa kokoro hodoite respect yourself
hontō no jibun de ireba muchū de yume mite'ta watashi ni (be back)
invincible heart mezamesasete
osoreru koto nai revives my heart
namida o nagashita ato ni wa muteki na watashi to ashita ni cheers!
H-His mistress?
She was the mistress of the
murdered company employee?
It may have been an affair,
but after seeing her beloved
brutally murdered before her eyes,
the shock and rage probably been
drove her to find an opportunity
to get revenge on the
Red Woman for fifteen years.
Then the person who attacked Sumika-san...
Because she was wearing
red clothes in the forest,
she assumed she was the Red Woman.
Satoko-san probably wasn't
at the meeting spot
because she was attacked
by her and ran away.
I'm impressed you noticed that.
It's because I heard about the error in the
police report from fifteen years ago.
What?
If she threw the knife and ran away,
she couldn't have had time to pick it up.
But the knife was found beside
the swamp three years later.
If the Red Woman herself fell into
the swamp immediately after she ran,
the only person who could
have taken the knife away
was the mistress who
witnessed the murder.
Hey.
Don't you need to report to your
brother about the incident?
I thought I would, but I lost my phone.
Could you call it with yours?
We can probably find it
by following the sound.
Sure.
It's under the cupboard?
How did it get here?
Who is this?
Thank you for finding it.
Sure.
Is that you, brother?
It was terrible.
In order for that image to
display after receiving a call,
the phone had to been left
showing that picture.
Does that mean she showed
it to me on purpose?
Why?
Episode Preview
It's true, everyone!
DoDonPa never lies.
Episode Preview
It's different?
Yes.
What's different, Inspector?
It's me! I did it!
All of Japan understands
how you feel, DoDonPa-san.
Episode Preview
Who released that information?
The Comedian Who Turned Himself In
(Part 1)
The next episode of Conan is The Comedian
Who Turned Himself In (Part 1)!"
Press Conference
Next episode's hint!
Press conference!
The festival is coming up!
Don't miss the next episode.
After the Red Woman come yellow pumpkins!
Happy Halloween!