Sheesh.
Beika Station         Police Box
Hey!
Four eyes, did you get in trouble
for doing something bad?
What?
It's not like that, Mouri-san.
He was delivering a wallet
he found in the street.
What? That's no fun.
Ouch.
I thought you were playing pachinko, Mister.
All the good machines were taken
while I overslept a little.
11:30...
You overslept more than just a little.
Why you...
U-U-U-Uh, um...
Huh? Isn't this guy...?
Are you the comedian...?
Yes. I'm DoDonPa Rokusuke.
Oh, the lying stand-up
comedian DoDonPa-san.
It's true, everyone!
DoDonPa, DoDonPa never lies!
Can I help you with something, DoDonPa-san?
My talent agency's office
is right down the street.
DoDonPa Rokusuke (30)
Comedian
There, I...
I killed the president!
What?!
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
The comedian who turned himself in
receives a surprisingly evaluation.
Is he hiding something with laughter?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Comedian Who Turned Himself In
(Part One)
Inspector Megure.
I had the housekeeper Ueki-san
prepare an open room for us.
Thank you.
The Beika Station seems to be a
mess with all the other cases.
Why don't you give us a detailed account?
Yes, sir.
I'll join you.
You don't have to.
No, I know I can help you solve this case.
You are the best detective around.
You must have a lot of time on your hands.
DoDonPa Rokusuke.
His real name is Rokusuke Tanigaki-san.
He lives in Akebono City, 3-chome.
The late Hideki Tendo-san operated
a talent agency out of that room,
which also served as his home,
but his only client was DoDonPa-san.
He worked closely with me as
my president and manager.
He was my dearest partner.
And you killed your dearest partner?
Yes.
I was coming up with new material this week,
and today we were going to meet
so I could show him what I had.
I came to the office around 11:10.
There!
It's true, everyone!
DoDonPa, DoDonPa never lies!
Hideki Tendo (42)
Talent Agency President
Your jokes are immature!
Wh-What do you mean?
Those aren't jokes!
You don't understand!
What the audience wants is...
The difference in our senses
of humor led to an argument,
and I became furious.
I went to the corner of the room,
picked up the bat lying there,
and I...
I'm sorry!
Based on the deep remorse you're feeling,
you don't seem to be lying.
But...
Where is he?! Is he in that room?!
Is it true DoDonPa Rokusuke-san
murdered the president of his talent
agency and turned himself in?
No, no!
Stay out of here!
We're still talking to him.
We'll release a statement later.
Please!
Let's go home.
We'd just be wasting our
time if we stayed here.
But no matter how angry you got,
would someone strike their
partner with a metal bat?
What?
I'm stuck on that, too, DoDonPa-san.
Go see if his story checks out.
Yes, sir.
You heard him.
Let's stay until they're finished checking.
There might be an opportunity
for a great detective.
Yeah!
He arrived at Beika Station at 11:00.
It's a ten minute walk from the
station to the crime scene,
so he arrived at the office around 11:10.
They immediately got in an
argument, and he killed him.
He returned to the police
box near the station
and turned himself in around 11:30, so...
The timeline of his story is consistent, huh?
Yes.
I'm going to hit up his
entertainer friends next,
and ask if there was any trouble
between him and the victim.
Do that.
I'll attend the autopsy.
Okay.
I see. Good work.
That was forensics.
The blood and hair on the metal
bat are victim Hideki Tendo's.
They got his fingerprints off the bat, too.
That means it's the murder weapon, then.
I told you I hit him with that bat.
Beika Theater
What?
So DoDonPa-san had a grudge
against Tendo-san over that?
Of course I resented him!
I was invited to be a regular
on a famous variety program,
but he turned the offer down
because he didn't like the program!
In other words, there had been friction
between you and Tendo since then.
I think I got angry because of that, too.
Otherwise I wouldn't have
suddenly hit him with a bat.
With everything lining up like this,
there isn't any room for doubt, is there?
Am I making too much of this?
Tendo Talent Agency
Could he be...
Is something wrong, Mister Housekeeper?
Huh?
This wasn't here when I was tidying up
around the rear entrance this morning.
A metal pipe?
They use these kinds of things
at construction sites, right?
I wonder who brought it here.
What time were you tidying up this morning?
Detective Takagi?
It's different?
Yes.
What's different, Inspector?
The weapon.
Apparently it's not the metal bat.
What?
When comparing the weapon to the victim's
head injury during the autopsy,
the shape doesn't quite match up.
The weapon is a blunt cylinder, though.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Got it.
Well done, Conan-kun.
That's it, then?
Yeah.
In addition to the shape,
the fragments of concrete in the wound on
Tendo's head match those stuck to the pipe.
They found Tendo's blood on the pipe, too.
In other words,
the metal pipe at the rear entrance was
the actual weapon used to kill Tendo.
Huh? What was that metal bat about, then?
I know, right?
Tendo's blood and hair were stuck to it,
even though it's not the murder weapon.
How do you explain this, DoDonPa-san?
Uh, I...
I-In any case...
In any case, I killed him!
I killed the president with these hands!
It's me! I'm the one who did it!
Things are finally starting to get interesting.
It seems this person is determined
to be the murderer
in a crime he didn't commit.
Does that mean he knows who the real
murderer is and is protecting them?
Mister Housekeeper, Inspector Megure
wanted me to ask you something.
There should be someone coming and going
around the time DoDonPa-san arrived.
Around 11:00, right?
I don't remember anyone.
There's been hardly any traffic
over the long holiday.
I'd remember if there had been anyone.
Did DoDonPa-san not see
the real murderer in person?
The only people coming
and going this morning
were the Mori-san couple
leaving for their trip,
Tendo-san when he went to buy lunch, and...
What time was that?
When did Tendo-san go to buy lunch?
7:58.
What about the time?
Can you tell what kind of
lunch you heated up for him?
Let's see...
It's a hamburger lunch.
Did he put hot water in his cup noodles?
Yes.
Tendo-san always gets his
hot water at the store.
Thank you.
What?
What is it this time?
By the way, DoDonPa-san,
where were you around 9:00 this morning?
Is there some significance to that time?
It's for reference.
Um...
Oh, right. Around 9:00, I
was at Suda-sensei's studio.
9:00? You mean...
Yeah. That's right.
The autopsy results revealed that,
based on the digestion
of his stomach contents,
Tendo-san was killed about
an hour after he ate.
He ate a hamburger lunch and cup noodles.
He bought both of those at the
convenience store at 7:58.
He had his lunch heated up,
and he put hot water in his
cup noodles at the store,
so he must have eaten them
as soon as he got back.
That's right.
Around 8:00 AM, Tendo-san ate
his lunch and cup noodles.
What?
If he was killed one hour later, then...
Yeah.
DoDonPa-san, Tendo-san wasn't
killed after 11:00 like you said,
but two hours earlier around 9:00 AM.
But at that time, DoDonPa-san...
Who is this Suda-sensei you visited?
A quick investigation should tell us.
She's an artist who lives in
Akebono City in my neighborhood.
Takagi-kun, meet up with
Chiba-kun and head there.
Yes, sir.
Looks like you didn't get
your chance to shine, Mister.
Studio
Suda-san! Are you in there?!
Coming!
Izumi Suda (68)
Artist
Who are you?
Were you sleeping? I'm sorry.
We met about six months ago.
He said he was a comedian,
but I don't know any performers.
After all, I don't have a
TV, radio, or cell phone.
I'm free from the rest of the world.
We want to know if DoDonPa-san
visited you this morning.
He did.
He came to return the art books
he had borrowed to help
him come up with ideas.
He called last night to say he
would be by at 9:00 the next day.
He was right on time.
You're sure he came this morning at 9:00?
Yeah. I looked at that clock.
I'm sure.
Here are the art books I
borrowed and some cake you like.
Huh? Did I come at the wrong time?
What?
No, you're right on time.
Come on in.
Yeah. DoDonPa-san came right at 9:00.
It wasn't possible for him to kill Tendo.
Yeah.
That clock wasn't broken, and it's over
an hour's drive to the crime scene.
He's got an alibi.
I wanted to be the murderer.
Does that mean you know
who the real murderer is
and tried to protect that person?
No, it's not like that.
What do you mean?
I wanted to protect...
I wanted to protect Tendo-san's reputation.
His reputation?
I owe Tendo-san for developing my talent,
but he was two-faced!
You should think hard about
which would be better for you.
He had dirt on people in the industry
and was extorting them for money.
Blackmail, huh?
When I arrived after 11:00 today,
Tendo-san was already dead on the ground.
I can only imagine someone he was
extorting killed him to silence him.
I couldn't just contact the police.
If they looked for the murderer,
Tendo-san's foul other face would be revealed.
I didn't want to let that happen.
I decided to say I did it because of the difference
in our approach to entertainment.
I could tell he had died to a blow to
the head, but the weapon was gone.
In order to make the weapon seem like
the bat that happened to be in the room,
I stuck my fingerprints on it,
and turned myself in at the
police box near the station.
I'm sorry!
I've caused you so much trouble!
Who was Tendo extorting,
and what was he using?
I have no idea.
I understand you did it for Tendo-san,
but you can't interfere with a crime scene.
Yeah.
It's a crime.
They're right.
I'm sorry!
However, right now the murder
investigation comes first.
We'll investigate your actions
after the case is solved.
You can leave for today.
What?!
B-But...
We understand how you feel.
Make sure we can get in touch with you.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry for the trouble I've caused...
It's time to start the investigation over.
But who actually killed Hideki Tendo?
Like he said,
the most obvious suspect is the
person Tendo-san was extorting.
Yeah.
Do everything you can to figure out who it is.
Yes, sir!
There was never any opportunity
for a great detective to shine.
But I wonder why the murderer took the
real murder weapon out of the room.
Their fingerprints must've been on it.
Then they should have
taken it all the way home,
but it was left at the storage
area by the rear entrance.
That's why the housekeeper
found it right away.
They didn't want to leave
it at the crime scene,
but it was left at the rear entrance of the
apartment where the crime took place,
right in plain sight.
Have they been waiting this whole time?
DoDonPa-san is surrounded.
I'm sorry, everyone.
In order to protect the
reputation of Hideki Tendo,
I, DoDonPa Rokusuke, wanted
to be called his murderer.
What that intent,
I falsely turned myself in.
I'm terribly sorry!
All of Japan understands
how you feel, DoDonPa-san.
I'm so grateful to hear that.
Take this to the station.
Hey, how did you guys know
DoDonPa-san turned himself in?
Huh?
Oh.
Every station received an
anonymous tip by phone.
Who had that information?
The people who knew were...
There, I killed the president!
What?!
I can't imagine that policeman
leaked the information,
and it wasn't me or the old guy.
The only one left is...
Maybe his goal wasn't to become the
culprit of a murder he didn't commit,
but to make us think that...
Around 9:00, when Tendo-san was killed,
he was visiting someone named Suda-san,
after saying the previous
night he would stop by at 9:00.
9:00 AM, the exact same time
Tendo-san was murdered.
Isn't it too much of a coincidence?
(Mai Kuraki)
itsushika jibun miushinatte'ta ‘daijōbu’-tte hontō wa uso
iiwake nante mō dō ni mo naranai
kokoro ga odoru yō ja nakya ne
kokoro ni hitotsuzutsu hi o tomoshitekita kedo
gomen tameiki tsuichatta kono mama ja kiesō
muteki na heart sawagidashite
saa kokoro hodoite respect yourself
hontō no jibun de ireba muchū de yume mite'ta watashi ni (be back)
invincible heart mezamesasete
osoreru koto nai revives my heart
namida o nagashita ato ni wa muteki na watashi to ashita ni cheers!
Episode Preview
The metal pipe that was used as
the murder weapon is on his mind.
Episode Preview
There was a construction site
on the way from Beika Station.
Apparently it was brought from there.
Episode Preview
You were contacted by the murderer?
I thought it might help
you find the murderer.
Episode Preview
At this rate, I won't be
able to protect Tendo-san.
The Comedian who Turned Himself In
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is “The
Comedian Who Turned Himself In, Part Two!"
Pocket Tissues
Next Conan's hint, twinkle!
Pocket tissues!
Hey, Conan! DoDonPa was on Obakyu, right?
Don't miss the next episode.
That's Doronpa! This guy's DoDonPa!