OSAKA OKONOMIYAKI ODYSSEY
This happened the day after the airship hijacking incident.
Our story took place from 10:00 AM to 2:30 PM.
You're finally awake.
You were sleeping like a baby, so I didn't wanna wake you.
What time is it?
A little past 10:00.
My mom said she was going to cook up a good breakfast just for you.
But I refused.
Why'd you do that!?
Didn't I tell you?
I'm taking you to an awesome okonomiyaki place for lunch.
You better leave plenty of space for it!
Kazuha, it's me.
I'm headed to that okonomiyaki restaurant now.
Why all of a sudden?
Let's meet at the usual place at 11:00.
Don't be late.
Wait!
That's settled.
Say, Hattori...
I appreciate you taking me out to eat, but...
I have to be at Shin-Osaka Station at 2:40...
I know.
You're taking the Nozomi train departing at 2:47 right?
Yeah.
Don't worry then.
It only takes 20 minutes to get to the station from the restaurant.
Even if we start eating at 12:00, you'd
still have 2 hours and 20 minutes.
Just enjoy your okonomiyaki, maybe try some ice coffee...
Oh, and buy some souvenirs, too.
I don't need any souvenirs.
Thanks for letting me stay!
Let's hurry a little.
If we're late, that girl's going to chew us out.
Damn, worst timing ever.
Oh, Hei-chan!
Hello.
I read the newspaper!
You did it again, didn't you?
Thanks...
Uhm, we're in a...
Oh my, Hei-chan, you're really the pride of our Neyagawa City!
They say it's either Goueidou or Hei-chan!
Goueidou is a famous sumo-wrestler in Neyagawa, Osaka.
Unlike my stupid son who only knows how to play
and can't even concentrate on his studies!
Well, his parents aren't geniuses either,
so I guess the blame rests on us.
Unlike us, Hei-chan's father is the chief
of the Osaka Metropolitan Police.
And your mother Shizuka-san is a
beauty with a green thumb in cooking.
As for me, I can't even handle cooking a yam...
My mother-in-law always criticizes me about it.
I guess I really need to retrain myself at my mother's place.
Then again, they say, "Like mother, like daughter."
My mother's cooking is almost as bad as mine,
and together we'll win the worst cooking award!
Speaking of which, my mother and I went
to visit my grandmother's place recently.
It was there that I realized that our bad cooking runs in the family.
I guess heredity is a frightening thing!
Well, I've been trying my best lately, but nothing has improved.
Well, I don't want to bother you, so see you!
Pardon us!
Damn, we wasted 10 minutes!
Let's run!
Hey!
Neyagawa City Station
Great!
She's not here yet.
We'll pretend we've been waiting for a long time and scold her!
Such a rotten heart you have.
Why hasn't she come?
I'm so pissed off.
HOW LONG'DYA WANT ME TO WAIT!?
That's supposed to be my line!
Where the hell are you!?
Where am I?
In Tomorogi Greenfield of course!
At the Octopus Park as usual!
You octopus-head!
We're not meeting in the greenfield!
At the station, the station!
We're taking the MRT?
You bet we are!
How could we go by bike with both you and the brat?
It's not like yesterday —
that was a special exception.
By "brat," do you mean you're with Conan-kun right now?
Yeah, I am.
He was staying at my place last night.
He stayed over?
Did you forget what you said to me when I said I wanted
to meet with Ran-chan and Sonoko-chan last night?
"Everyone's exhausted after that whole incident, so let's call it off."
Despite that, you secretly invited Conan-kun to your place, didn't you!?
No harm done...
I've agreed to treat him to the most delicious okonomiyaki...
There IS harm done, you black octopus!
BLACK OCTOPUS, HUH!?
Say, Hattori...
Any chance you can just ask her to come to the station?
We're wasting our time.
You're right.
We'll talk later.
Don't make us wait, hurry over.
So basically, you guys have two places where you usually meet up...
If you're taking the MRT, you meet at Neyagawa Station.
If by motorbike, you'll meet at...
Tomorogi Greenfield.
And, she thought you two were going by bike...
So she waited at the greenfield.
Yeah, it's always the same pattern when we go to eat okonomiyaki.
Yo!
You're finally here.
What do you mean, "You're finally here"!?
You make it sound like I was the one who was late!
It's all your...
Hello, Kazuha-neechan.
Hello.
I've been looking forward to seeing you again!
You're going to eat okonomiyaki with us, aren't you?
I've been looking forward to seeing Conan-kun, too.
Let's get going, Heiji.
What a huge change of attitude.
It's your fault, you know.
So we lost 30 minutes...
Well, I guess it's no biggie.
Nichi Sports
Airship Hijack!?
ROBBER GROUP ARRESTED!
High-School Detective
HATTORI HEIJI
Protecting the national treasure
Buddhist statuary
OUTSTANDING ACHIEVEMENT!
I bet he's pretty disappointed, that old man...
Yodoyabashi Station
Let's take the elevator.
Why not just take the stairs?
It's Hattori Heiji!
It really is!
And that kid...
Conan-kun, isn't it?
How cute!
I saw the news!
Please shake my hand!
Ah, fine.
Can I have your autograph?
I don't mind, but it's kinda embarrassing...
Geez, what a fluttery guy.
Now, Conan-kun, smile!
We need to stay close to get a good shot!
Breasts...
You're a bunch of fools!
Can't believe you'd fall for that guy.
It's a big fat lie that this guy solved the case.
His father was actually the one pulling the strings!
What was that?
Calm down, Heiji.
They're just jealous.
He's just a dirty scammer.
I'll prove it to you right now.
Listen.
A package out of nowhere has this written on it.
What's in the package?
See?
Is it too hard to figure it out?
No, it's so stupid, I can't even say anything about it.
What was that?
"Fruit" would be a hint, right?
I don't even need a hint!
It's a FIG-ure, so the answer is a "fig".
Oh, so that's what it is.
It's cheesier than the Professor's riddles...
In that case, tell me how these numbers relate to each other!
How's that!?
That's simple.
Those are the places where the prefectural governments are.
Why?
"2" sounds like "Tsu."
"Big 2" is "Ootsu."
And "78" is "Naha."
They're prefectural governments located in the Mie,
Shiga, and Okinawa Prefectures, respectively.
I see.
There's more.
"758" sounds like "Nagoya."
"310" is "Mito."
"291" is "Fukui."
Pop quiz, what's "1008"?
It's 1000 and 8, so Chiba!
Awesome!
Answer this, what does October 10th make?
十月十日
It makes the kanji for "morning."
朝
What about a silent woman?
ムロ女
Makes the kanji for "beginning."
始
What's an instrument that makes nets?
創
網
A clarinet!
倉リ網
Damn...
My turn.
A woman died in front of a mirrored dresser,
holding an English dictionary upside-down.
The suspects are two women —
Koide Keiko and Miyata Mayumi.
Who's the culprit?
The keywords are "mirror" and "English dictionary."
And, obviously, "upside-down."
The culprit is Miyata Mayumi.
Why?
Try spelling out Koide Keiko in romaji.
Romaji?
Then try to read that through a mirror.
Ah, I can read it.
Koide Keiko.
However, if you turn the page upside-down, you can't read it, right?
You're right.
Now try...
Miyata Mayumi, got it.
There we go.
Now I turn it upside-down and use the mirror...
I can still read it, but the order is...
That's the trick to this question.
Normally we would spell out letters horizontally.
However, we are to write vertically in this case.
Vertically?
I can read it!
It's legible, Heiji.
That's because letters having left-right symmetry can
be turned upside-down and still be read in a mirror.
Left-right symmetry?
In Miyata Mayumi, that's the case for M, Y, A, T, and U.
And "I" has perfect left-right and up-down symmetry.
In contrast, although the letters O and I in Koide Keiko are symmetric...
K, D, and E only have up-down symmetry.
Furthermore, U and W have left-right symmetry...
B and C have up-down symmetry...
And H and X have both left-right and up-down symmetry.
Hattori Heiji is awesome, but...
This kid is a genius, too!
How's that?
Still think he's just a scammer?
Well then, let's go.
Yeah.
12:11...
We lost 20 minutes?
We wasted 30 minutes earlier...
Leaving us just an hour and a half for lunch.
Well, that's more than enough for okonomiyaki.
Can't say for iced coffee, though.
Umeda Station
Are you all right, sir?
Hurry up here!
Heiji-niichan, what are you doing!?
We did it!
But why did we have to spend 10 minutes crossing a single street?
It's in the residential block if we go past this mall.
It's a small restaurant that's not even in the guidebook.
How did you find it if it's so small?
I've scoured all of Osaka on my bike.
Hattori Heiji, spending 17 years searching
for the most delicious okonomiyaki!
Leave it to the pro!
Right?
You're just an idiot.
Oh, excuse me, I would like to go to the bathroom...
Could I ask you to watch my kid for a short while?
I'm terribly sorry, but we're in a hu—
Sure, we'll watch your baby.
Thank you!
Kaoru, be good and wait here.
We only have an hour and 20 minutes left for lunch ya know...
Geez.
One should help those who are in need.
So you're called Kaoru-chan?
You're a girl, right?
That's obvious.
Just look at her clothes.
There, there.
You're pretty good with babies.
When Satoshi-kun from yesterday was still
a baby, he often came to my house to play.
You're really cute.
Say, Heiji, I want a baby.
D-Don't be stupid!
Don't laugh!
Isn't she pretty late?
I agree...
Perhaps she wasn't feeling well?
I'll go check it out.
Hey...
Don't let her cry, all right?
Geez...
Looks like you're not good at this.
Damn right I'm not!
Ah, no, no, no, no...
I'm the one who wants to cry...
Didn't I say not to let her cry?
I can't help it!
Regardless, where's her mom?
There, there, there...
Well, she's not there.
Not there?
What do you mean not there...
Don't tell me, she abandoned her?
Abandoned?
That mother looked like she was only 20 years old...
Could it be she got tired of the baby and left it in our care?
Don't be silly!
Normally one wouldn't abandon their kid to some teenagers like us!
But...
What if she knew who Heiji-niichan was?
If she knew that Heiji-niichan was a famous high school
detective, she might have felt content trusting in him.
There, there.
There you go, even that kid noticed that she's been abandoned.
What're you talking about?
She just had an accident.
I'll change her diaper, so take out the diapers and wet tissue!
Oh, roger that, roger that.
Here.
Thanks.
Huh?
"The Tale of Genji"?
What a deep book she's reading.
She's not abandoning her kid.
The restroom must've been occupied so she simply went elsewhere.
Huh?
What's wrong?
This kid... is a boy!
What'd you say?
And his bib is on inside-out.
Inside-out?
But isn't the seam supposed to be on the inside?
Normally yes, but in baby clothes the seam is always on the outside.
That way it doesn't irritate the skin.
I see.
Say, could this be...
Yeah, maybe she wasn't this kid's mom.
What do you mean?
This kid may have been kidnapped.
Kidnapped!?
That's right.
That woman may be a kidnapper or a kidnapper's accomplice.
Perhaps they've already gotten their ransom money...
But they didn't know how to return
the baby, so they gave him to us.
Or maybe the deal was off...
And they decided they couldn't handle the
baby, and wanted to leave him with others.
The reason why the baby boy is wearing girl's clothes...
Would be precisely because they wanted people
to mistake him as a girl when they saw him.
And as for his inside-out bib...
It's just like Kazuha-neechan said, they
didn't know how to dress him properly.
Let's confirm it with the guard.
Oh, that lady—she ran out about 20 minutes ago.
What's that!?
As I thought.
But... I still can't believe it...
Well, I'll ask for evidence.
Osaka Prefecture Police Dept.
Oh, Hei-chan; it's been a while.
A kidnapping?
How'd you know that, Hei-chan?
As I thought.
A young male was taken, wasn't he?
Right, an investor in Tezukayama had his
male puppy taken—its name is Kotarou.
Kotarou?
So that's the kid's name...
Puppy?
See, I knew you were wrong!
Ah, maybe the victim hasn't informed the police yet...
Out! Out! Out of my way!
There, over there!
That lady!
Thank goodness, you're all right!
Where have you been?
Owww...
So it's you?
You're the kidnapper!?
What are you guys talking about?
That man is my husband, Kaoru's father.
The restroom on the first floor was crowded,
so I went to the one on the second floor.
As I thought.
Upon looking out the restroom window, I saw
Hikaru riding his bike across the street.
I hurried and chased him.
So why did you...
But I ended up losing him.
And I've got a poor sense of direction, so I
returned to the wrong side of this building.
Listen here, why did you...
Over there, I spotted Hikaru and his bike again.
Then she told me about where Kaoru
was, and that's why I rushed here.
I'm asking why you simply ran off and left your baby alone!
It's Hikaru's fault!
You've been cold to Kaoru and me for no reason lately...
You haven't returned to our apartment either.
That's why I tried to find you.
Why didn't you go home?
None of your business.
What'dya mean none of my business!?
You're the father!
How could you leave your baby alone!?
He's not my child, anyway.
Kashiwa...
Kashiwa?
Kashiwa is...
What do you mean he's not your child?
Don't play dumb.
I know everything.
What do you know?
Hey, Hikaru!
Hikaru...
Kaoru...
Kashiwa!
Miss, do you like "The Tale of Genji"?
I started it half a year ago, and I'm totally hooked.
So you named your baby...
After "The Tale of Genji"?
Because Hikaru Genji's son is called Kaoru.
Right, and this man's name also happens to be Hikaru.
However...
Kaoru in "The Tale of Genji" was not actually Hikaru Genji's son.
He was born by a nobleman named Kashiwagi and
the Third Princess, Hikaru Genji's lawful wife.
So that's how it is...
I learned that recently, too.
Before that, all I knew was that Hikaru Genji's son was called Kaoru.
Say, did you talk about that to anyone else lately?
Yeah, I spoke with my mother about it when she came to visit.
Do you still remember what was said between you and your mom?
It was...
Is it true that Kaoru wasn't Hikaru's son?
Yeah.
His dad was actually Kashiwagi.
Right, and that conversation went into the ears
of your husband who had just returned home.
So that means...
It was all a big misunderstanding.
But, why did you dress him in girl's clothes?
My mom was pretty careless.
She thought we were having a girl...
So all she bought was girl's clothes.
And why is his bib worn inside-out?
Was it inside-out?
It's true!
I guess my mom wasn't the only careless one...
I've caused enough trouble for you three.
No, not at all.
I hope you guys get along well.
Please take good care of Kaoru-chan, all right?
Please excuse us.
Well, nothing beats a happy ending.
I guess this time I sorta read too much into what happened.
"Sorta" my foot!
You crime maniac!
What'd you say!?
It was your fault in the first place!
If you hadn't agreed to watch the baby...
But would anyone normally abbreviate "Hikaru Genji" to "Hikaru"?
No good!
Look at the time!
There's only 30 minutes left to eat okonomiyaki!
It's all right!
We'll make it if you eat as fast as you can!
The restaurant is just around the corner!
Wait up a second!
Hello?
Conan-kun, where are you?
What's wrong?
Can you get back to the Shin-Osaka station in 30 minutes?
The restaurant is just a corner away!
Sonoko misread the bullet train's departure time by 20 minutes!
What happened?
We've got less than 30 minutes!
It's fine.
Looks like it only takes 20 minutes from here to Shin-Osaka.
That's great!
Send my regards to Hattori-kun then.
Shin-Osaka Station
Just like that, Kudo's Osaka visit came to an abrupt end.
Hello Mr. my yesterday itteokure yo
Hello Mr. my yesterday, please say to me:
"yume kanau sono toki ni mata aeru" to
"We'll meet again the instant your dream is fulfilled."
zenpou no ikuta zentotanan no michi kouhou no michi koukai mo shitta
Ahead of me lies a road I've passed with regrets
Behind me there's a road I've passed with regrets
keiken to kachi yume nakaba ippon no michi kekka da ga
Experiences and values, a halfway dream
- it's a one-way road, but the result is...
kibou to yuu utsu to no baransu nakushite kara mou dore kurai darou
Ever since I lost my balance between hope and
depression, I don't know how long it's been
demo hokoreru mono mo nashi ni ima sara kaeru beki basho mo
But I have nothing to be proud of, and now I can't figure out
asu no riyuu mo mi idasenai yo boku ha...
Neither the place I should return to nor
the reason to stay for tomorrow...
Hello Mr. my yesterday taimumashin de
Hello Mr. my yesterday, use your time machine
ano hi no boku he ima tsutaetakute yume wo kataru mono yo
I'd like you to ask the me from the past, who always spoke of dreams:
"anata no me ni asu no boku no koto ha utsuttemasu ka?"
"In those eyes of yours, do you see the me from tomorrow?"
You're so cunning, Conan!
Leaving us to go somewhere all by yourself.
Going solo has always been his style, after all.
Say, Conan-kun, what did you have for lunch?
We ate a bellyful for lunch!
Octopus dumplings, pork buns...
Fried pork skewers, fried-tofu udon!
And omelet rice!
I didn't know that omelet rice actually originated from Osaka.
And don't forget, the most delicious dish was...
Okonomiyaki!
I'm stuffed, too.
Is it all right to eat dinner a little bit later, Conan-kun?
This is heaven!
So true!
The okonomi here is the best in Japan!
I really wanted that brat to try this.
Speaking of which...
Shouldn't Conan-kun be starving by now?
Don't worry about him, I bet he's chowing
down on train lunchboxes by now.
I guess you're right.
This is traumatizing.