Two years ago during the summer.
Riding a winning streak all the way to the Tokyo Championship...
Was our Teitan Middle School soccer club.
Shin'ichi-kun's got swag!
Yes!
Shin'ichi!
Awesome!
He's awesome, Ran!
Here he comes!
At the last moment, we caught their two-point
lead and moved on to the penalty shoot-out.
However...
In the end, I missed...
And lost our chance of victory and the chance
to participate in the National Championship.
You were so close.
About your last penalty shoot-out,
I think you did well on the decisive kick.
Thank you.
It's Higo!
Higo Ryuusuke
Endou Rikuo
Noir Tokyo Player
They're Noir Tokyo's Higo Ryuusuke and Endou Rikuo!
How about it?
Will you considering joining our brothers
in Noir Tokyo as we aim for the top?
Oh, no, that's just...
Please excuse me.
Hey...
Hold it, Kudo...
Geez...
Hey.
You.
Yes?
What's his name?
It's Kudo!
Kudo Shin'ichi!
Kudo...
Shin'ichi-kun, huh?
FLOWER OF FANTASISTA
1 Week Later
Good morning!
Everyone showed up!
Good.
3-7-5-5...
Everyone go-go.
What's this!?
"Teitan Middle Soccer Club: the regular players' flaws"?
What's that, what's that?
Lemme see, lemme see!
"Number 1, Goalkeeper: Kikukawa."
"Unreliable catching."
Mind your own business!
"Number 2, Defense: Inoue."
"Bad at positioning."
Well, my bad...
"Number 3, Defense: Shinohara."
"Overwhelmed when tackled."
I did lose out a lot...
"Number 4, Defense: Hiramatsu."
"Lack of persistence."
I guess I don't have it.
Everything here is right on the mark!
"Number 5, Defense: Tonooka."
"Amateurish marking."
"Weak in man-to-man defense."
"Unable to predict the flow of the game."
Why is it that only I have as many as three flaws!?
'Cause you're the captain!
"Number 6, Midfielder—bracketed substitute: Sugimura."
"Not enough workout."
The "substitute" is unnecessary!
"Number 7, Midfielder: Shouji."
"Carrying the ball too often."
True indeed...
"Number 8, Midfielder: Hama."
"Lacking precision at kicking."
"Number 9, Midfielder: Yamaichi."
"Chasing the ball too often."
Is it bad to chase it?
It means instead of chasing down the ball, pay
attention to the direction of the pass, see?
Oh, I see.
"Number 10, Midfielder: Kudo."
"Not enough malicia."
What does "malicia" mean?
In Portuguese, it means "sneakiness".
The former Brazil football captain Dunga...
Once commented that Japanese players are not sneaky enough.
It's true Kudo, your play is honest to a fault.
As far as soccer is concerned, that is.
What do you mean "as far as soccer is concerned"?
"Number 11, Forward: Oshihara."
"Underperformed in decisive shots."
Well said, well said!
"Number 13, Forward: Mizushima."
Underperformed in decisive shots!
Hey, Mizushima!
"Does not defend at all," isn't that right?
Who was the one that did all this scribbling?
Answer me truthfully!
I know who you are!
The culprit, barring Mizushima who's the
only second-year playing as a regular...
Is one of you first and second-year guys!
All right?
Our club room has its windows and door locked.
And the only ones who know about the
four-digit code to the padlock on the door...
Are club members.
All of us know that.
That means the culprit is an insider.
No doubt it's someone among you!
Very well.
Until the culprit comes forward, each one of you...
Is banned from participating in our practice!
This scribbling...
Is not the work of any of them.
Take a look at this.
What is that?
Chalk?
Yeah, probably a chalk print from someone's left thumb.
Someone's left...
Thumb?
And, this one here is likely from their left index finger.
Their left index finger?
What does that mean?
In short...
Initially the culprit, at a height where their
hand could reach, wrote down the title.
Then they kept writing from number 1 and onwards.
But when they reached the bottom of the board...
The space for writing numbers 10, 11,
and 13 wasn't available anymore.
As such, without a choice, they brought a chair here...
And stood on it to continue writing.
That's why they left their fingerprints on the chair.
In other words, the culprit has a small build...
And was holding a piece of chalk in their
left hand—a southpaw, so to speak.
In that case, the culprit is...
Hold on.
There's a first-year kid out there who's a shortie.
Hey, first-year shortie!
Me?
Oh, but he's...
There!
See?
Right-handed.
So it wasn't him?
As for someone else who's short and left-handed...
It wasn't me who wrote those!
But, if the culprit isn't one of us club members...
Then is the culprit an outsider?
No way that's possible!
How did they sneak into the room?
Say, it's been bothering me for a while...
Whenever you unlock, you always chant...
3-7-5-5...
Everyone go-go.
Not to mention you leave the unlocked
padlock hanging outside just like that.
If someone heard or saw what you were
doing, they'd know the number, no?
Well, but...
That reminds me, you...
At the end of one practice before summer vacation, you came
back yourself to retrieve something you'd forgotten, right?
At that time, did you chant 3-7-5-5?
I did...
Maybe.
And did you leave the padlock hanging outside?
Maybe...
Might have.
Well!
In that case, I'll leave the culprit investigation to Kudo...
Everyone, get changed and go practice!
Everyone, go-go!
Oh, Kudo.
Done with your practice?
Yes, sir.
That final match the other day was a close one.
Who knew in the end you would...
Sensei...
I have something I would like to ask you.
Let's go home!
Let's go, let's go!
Wait up!
Hey.
The one who scribbled on the blackboard
in our club room was you, right?
Sawamura Naomi (13)
Teitan Middle School First-Year
How'd you know it was me who did the scribbling?
There were chalk marks on the chair.
From a left thumb and a left index finger.
Then, I deduced that the culprit was
left-handed and had a small build.
Plus, the club room was neatly cleaned, unlike the way it had been.
Almost as if...
Hey, hey!
A cleanup, a cleanup!
There!
Wake up, wake up!
I didn't even ask you, so don't go around
cleaning people's rooms as you please!
What's wrong with that?
You really made a big mess!
This is just like my dad!
You're a lot like...
Someone.
Huh?
Oh, nothing...
Anyway, I suspected that a girl was behind it.
Not to mention what was written all hit the nail on the head.
That means it was no doubt someone knowledgeable
about soccer and is even actively playing it herself.
That's why I asked Sakuragi whether there was any girl who came
and said she wanted to join the soccer club before summer vacation.
And then, as I expected...
Yeah, there was one.
A first-year girl of small physique.
So, I asked for the girl's name...
And from a first-year boy who's a member and
your classmate, I got your approximate address...
Hence my visit.
My apologies.
I was the one who wrote it.
As I thought.
At the end of June, I transferred here
from a middle school in Yokohama.
I've been playing soccer since I was in kindergarten,
and at the middle school there, I was a regular.
Awesome!
A regular already since first-year?
In that middle school...
Three tenths of the club members are girls.
So I assumed Teitan Middle would be more or less
the same, but it turned out there are no girls here.
Our school team is one of the toughest, that's why.
Girls would chicken out and refuse to join.
I was a bit hesitant, but I really do want to play soccer.
That's why I went to see Sakuragi-sensei.
And then...
Here to apply for Manager, right?
Good timing with the Tokyo Championship coming up next month!
You'll be welcomed!
I...
Was quite shocked after hearing sensei's words.
"Oh... so girls are not expected to be part of this
school's soccer club members?" was on my mind.
I already realized that Sakuragi mistook your intention.
Since he said...
I told her she's welcome to be our manager,
but that was the last time we spoke.
I...
Without much of a choice, decided to
watch your soccer club practice from afar.
And, what were your thoughts?
Yes.
I was thinking, "While this team is indeed at a high
level, it isn't a challenge that I can't take on."
But the fact that there are no girls was a huge limiting factor.
So while I was being indecisive about whether
I should join or not, summer vacation came around.
And the Tokyo Championship started.
I had been watching since the preliminary matches.
Thanks to your fine play, Kudo-senpai, Teitan
Middle was able to stay on a winning streak.
But, I was also starting to see the
weaknesses of your team little by little.
And at the final match, our team lost.
I went to school the next day...
And wrote everything I observed on your club's blackboard.
Now that I think back, why did I do such a thing?
Perhaps it's because I wanted to join the
soccer club but couldn't make up my mind.
Maybe part of the reason was to vent my frustration?
What about the combination lock?
Before summer vacation started...
I saw the number on the lock Captain Tonooka left
hanging outside when he went in the club room.
As I thought.
He must have mumbled this when he was opening the lock:
"Everyone, go-go!"
But your scribbling was sort of harsh.
Some of our guys took it real hard.
I'm sorry.
You're such a brat, aren't ya?
The type who likes to bully someone she loves?
Well, how do you really feel?
About our final match earlier.
I was extremely hyped!
Kudo-senpai, each time you dribbled
and passed through your opponents...
My body would move simultaneously.
When you scored a goal, I was super excited!
That's why, at the end...
I was so frustrated and mortified.
Well, do you still have that feeling
of wanting to join our soccer club?
Yes!
But, since I did something like that...
Got it.
While there may be one guy who'd be hard to deal with...
Just leave it to me.
All right?
Days Later
And with that said...
This is our new teammate starting from today—Sawamura.
I'm Sawamura Naomi.
Pleased to be friends with all of you.
And, about my blackboard scribbling...
Please forgive me.
It's all right, all right.
What you wrote about us was all true, anyway.
Right, the bit about Tonooka was especially epic!
"Amateurish marking."
"Weak in man-to-man defense."
"Unable to predict the flow of the game."
In other words, you mean he's an idiot!
Hey, you!
She didn't say anything like that!
First and second-years, you shouldn't be laughing!
What's wrong, Mizushima?
Something you want to let out?
Kudo-senpai...
Next year, when you and the others leave the team...
It'll be up to us to aim for a win in the Tokyo Championship.
Yeah, so?
And yet a girl member?
She'll only slow us down!
Hey, don't say that!
If you think she'll slow you down, why
don't you just show her the ropes?
But...
Like Mizushima said, we truly want you to
triumph in the Tokyo Championship next year.
As such, we third-years will be having a practice match today
against some of you second-years who are would-be regulars.
The match will last for thirty minutes.
First-years will be observing!
Yes!
Let's go, boys!
Yeah!
Mizushima, they're gonna steal!
First point secured!
Second point!
Third point!
This is our fourth point!
Damn!
Kudo, a hat-trick already?
Your skill is unparalleled, indeed.
You'll be a badass in next year's Tokyo Championship!
Ow, ow, oww!
My leg's cramping up!
I probably pulled a muscle!
Hey, hey...
Geez, you're giving us trouble...
Oww, can't go on!
Sorry, but I gotta quit!
Tonooka!
Ow, ow, oww!
What do we do?
There are only eleven of us third-years!
No choice here, we'll have to play as ten.
No, just pick someone from the first-years.
That's it, Sawamura!
Yes?
Take the position in my stead.
You're Forward!
There, it's your debut match.
Give it all you've got!
Yes!
Oh, there she is!
It's that girl over there who was with Shin'ichi-kun!
Isn't she a cute girl?
Go for it, Sawamura!
Beat those second-years!
Sawamura!
Since you wrote those things about me...
I've brushed up on my defense!
Mizushima-kun...
Don't you think he's too much?
Yeah, really...
Again!?
She stood up!
Go!
Go for it, Sawamura!
Do your best.
Sawamura, nice assist!
Thanks!
She did well, that girl.
Mark that Sawamura!
Oh dear, she's so small we can't see her!
Shin'ichi-kun will probably just work with another guy, right?
I wonder...
Awesome!
Great job, Sawamura!
Nice first goal!
You're fantastic!
You guys, if you don't get a grip, that shortie
will steal away your regular positions!
Looks like we can look forward to the
Tokyo Championship next year!
Yeah.
All right, let's go home.
Aren't you going to confirm it with Shin'ichi-kun?
Confirm what?
What do you mean, "what"?
Hey, Ran...
Isn't it about time you come of age?
"Come of age"?
I'm—telling—you...
Never mind.
Hey, what is it?
Thank you very much!
And then, the second term started.
Ever since then, that Mizushima guy
has gotten along well with Sawamura.
But, I gotta say about Sawamura's play of jumping on the
Defense to serve as her foothold in order to reach higher...
It's against the rules, strictly speaking.
But well, you can say it's within bounds of legal physical contact.
Perhaps that's one of those so-called "malicia" moves.
That sort of cunningness is something I lack...
And I feel like I learned a lot from Sawamura.
You've been talking about that Sawamura girl this entire time.
Could it be that you maybe like that girl?
Idiot!
The one I like is...
White...
Oh, no...
Hold it, Shin'ichi!
I didn't see anything!
What was I doing, I wonder?