Riichi
Beika Mahjong
As expected, it's tiring, isn't it?
We've been at this for nearly twelve hours, after all.
This is the last round.
Let's finish this quickly.
Yes!
Finally! Just one more tile to win this!
Only a single 1-Pin tile left, huh?
The probability of it appearing is fifty-fifty.
If I can get that 1-Pin...
This'll be my walk-off home run!
Come to Papa, 1-Pin!
1-Pin...
I've won!
Four concealed triplets, one pair to-be, all
ones and nines—a triple yakuman bonus!
Uncle?
Mouri-chan, this...
Isn't a win, is it?
Oh!
It's a grape peel.
A white tile!?
Could it be that you thought it was a 1-Pin?
Unfortunately, a goof up.
That means you automatically finish in last place.
No... No way!
SHINICHI & RAN
MEMORIES OF MAHJONG TILES & TANABATA
He thought a white was a 1-Pin because of a grape peel?
What a blunder!
Uncle hasn't eaten any grapes since.
Seems he was put off by that experience.
What's a "White"?
What's a "1-pin"?
I'm not sure either, but...
They appear to be mahjong terms.
That's right...
You guys aren't familiar with mahjong.
Let's see, it should be around here somewhere...
Yeah, this is the one.
They're pretty!
These are mahjong tiles.
Man, Sou, and Pin are suits of numbered tiles...
And these are the Dragon and Wind tiles.
Ayumi can read these kanji!
Higashi, minami, nishi, kita...
east
west
south
north
That's how they're written, right?
That's right, but...
In mahjong, we use faux-Chinese pronunciation.
This way, they're read ton, nan, sha, pei.
Similarly, the numbers 1 through 9 are read as...
I, ryan, san, su, wu, rou, chi, pa, kyu.
Some pronounce kyu as chu, like me.
These are the kanji for the numbers, right?
But, why is five written as 伍 instead of 五?
This special kanji for five is used in currency writing.
And the kanji "man" is a motif of the
currency unit used in ancient China.
The same goes for Pin's and Sou's, right?
The circular Pin's represent coins...
While the rod-like Sou's represent bamboo sticks
that were used to string coins together in the past.
Those are numbers, too?
I see, so that's it!
For Pin's, you can count the number of circles...
And for Sou's, you can count the amount of rods, right?
And this bird?
That's the "one" in the Sou suit.
As for why it's a bird, I'm not sure either, but...
Let's take the Pin's suit for instance.
This is a 1-Pin, read as ipin...
7-Pin, or chipin...
And 9-Pin, or chupin.
I see!
This is interesting!
I don't really get it...
Professor, what was the "White" you mentioned just now?
Just look at these.
White, Green, and Red tiles.
These three are also called Dragon tiles.
White is for skin color...
Dark Green is for hair color...
And Red is for lip color, representing the three features of a beauty.
Hey, hey...
And when he saw this White with a round grape peel on top of it...
Mouri-kun mistook it as a 1-Pin.
They don't look alike at all.
Even though the 1-Pin does look purplish, it has a bright red center...
How stupid.
They finally understand why you and the professor laughed.
Yeah.
But...
Was it necessary to go through all
that just to explain White and 1-Pin's?
Riichi
Beika Mahjong
W-What?
You're discarding that tile?
It's such a waste.
I agree.
It's better to keep...
Shut up!
I can think for myself!
Discarding your bonus tile, Mouri-chan?
The bonus tile is determined prior to each round.
In this particular round, the bonus tile is 1-pin.
As Ran-chan said, it's such a waste.
I said it's fine!
Outsiders should shut up!
You're Kouda-kun, aren't you?
What's your occupation?
Just an ordinary office worker.
But his wife is amazing.
She's a best-selling illustrator.
Heard of her?
"Kouda Jun," that is.
Yes, I have.
She's a beauty with great drawing ability, right?
Is she really that beautiful?
But, poor Kouda-chan here...
He's been apart from his wife for three months.
Why?
His wife's currently confining herself to a mountain villa in Izu.
It seems she can't concentrate on her work unless she stays there.
Right, Kouda-chan?
Then, you're living alone at the moment?
Yeah, I guess.
I told you so!
I just hate these 1-Pin's!
Just because of the blunder you made that time...
Well, you should use this opportunity to
enjoy your bachelorhood once more.
Yep.
Your wife could be having the time of her life over there as well.
What do you mean by that?
Are you insinuating that she's having an affair?
No...
Why would I say that?
I was just joking.
My bad.
Really, that's just wrong, Okano.
C'mon, let's continue the game.
That's risky.
I don't think you should discard that either.
My win!
All sequence tiles, junchan, three same
sequence tiles, and double bonus tiles!
Junchan refers to any five of the 11, 99, 111, 123, 789, and 999 combinations of the Man, Pin, and
Sou suits. Adding the discarded 1-Sou, his 789-Man, 123789-Sou, 11789-Pin, 123-Sou would qualify.
Double yakuman bonus!?
See, isn't that exactly what I said?
You can tell from the tiles Hasegawa-san discarded.
Shut up!
It's all because you two were so noisy!
Get lost!
Conan-kun!
Are you all right?
I'm used to it.
What's with you?
We were only trying to offer our advice.
This is much better.
This set of tiles...
Do these tiles exist?
Those are flower tiles.
Flower tiles?
I've heard they use those when they
play Hong Kong or Taiwan mahjong.
This is my first time seeing them.
So pretty.
Spring...
Summer...
Autumn...
Winter.
Plum blossom, orchid, chrysanthemum, and bamboo, right?
"Orchid" is Ran-neechan's tile, right?
Ran means orchid in Japanese.
Yep.
For Conan-kun...
It'd be "south," right?
The "nan" in Conan means "south."
For Shin'ichi, it should be...
This one.
"Shin'ichi, when are you coming back?"
The kanji for "ichi" is on the face of the tile.
"Sorry, sorry..."
"I'm busy investigating a case right now."
"You always say that."
"Case this, case that—isn't that right, Conan-kun?"
"Yeah, you're right."
"And as we speak..."
"Spring..."
"Summer..."
"Autumn..."
"Winter..."
"All those excuses later, a year will go by in a flash."
"I know."
Just kidding.
Are you aiming for junchan again?
Kouda-chan, someone is eyeing your wife Jun-chan—get it?
I'm just kidding!
Okano!
They're still at it?
Huh?
Bamboo...
Yeah.
Tanabata's just around the corner, so I'm preparing
the bamboo for hanging the decorative wish cards.
Tanabata is a star festival held in summer.
Mahjong club and bamboo...
A surprising combination indeed.
It's not that surprising.
The relationship between a mahjong
club and bamboo runs pretty deep.
See, the Sou's are bamboos themselves.
There's also bamboo on the flower tiles.
Ah, I see.
Speaking of which...
Has Conan-kun's class started hanging
up wish cards on the bamboo?
Not yet...
Well, it should be soon.
At Teitan Elementary, the 1st and 2nd years always hang
wish cards on the bamboo at the start of July, every year.
Really?
Come to think of it, I guess that's true...
Shin'ichi and I did it before as well.
And...
During our second year, there was a small incident...
All right, everyone.
Write your wish on the paper card.
Yes!
What would you wish for?
Even if you talk about wishes...
I want to become prettier
Mom...
I hope Mom comes home soon
Had quarreled with Dad a year before...
And left home.
Mouri!
I heard your mom left home and
hasn't been back since—that true?
What!?
What about it!?
And all your dad does is drink and play mahjong!
That's what they call a dysfunctional family.
Shut up!
It's got nothing to do with you!
That rascal!
That Daisuke guy, so annoying!
Never mind.
It's true, anyway.
Hey, why aren't you saying anything?
If you're a guy, you should give him a punch!
This has nothing to do with me.
That idiot!
Poor Ran-chan...
That Shin'ichi was in the wrong, too.
Boys should help girls.
But still...
Writing such a wish on the paper card...
Makes me want to tear up.
Nevertheless, the wish came true.
A few days later, on the day of Tanabata...
Mom came home for me.
Mommy...
Mommy!
At that time...
I thought God had heard and granted my wish.
I was so happy.
That is, even though Mom quarreled
with Dad again that night and left...
It seems they're talking about you, Mouri-chan.
Can't hear them, can't hear them...
And then, the next morning...
What now?
Mouri...
I'm sorry about what happened before...
Your mom...
Is a beauty.
What's up with that guy?
No idea...
That day...
Everyone took down their decorative wish notes from the bamboo...
I hope
Mom comes
home soon
Mouri Ran
And kept one decoration and their own note as souvenirs.
I took care of the note from that time, and still have it.
That's a great story.
But, this Daisuke...
Why did he suddenly apologize?
He must've been scolded by his Mom or Dad.
That's gotta be why he apologized.
I thought so too, but...
Much later, I discovered the real reason.
One day, when I was in middle school...
Mom told me what happened on July 6th, nine years ago.
What's something like this doing here?
I hope
Mom comes
home soon
Mouri Ran
Ran...
Shin'ichi-kun?
Good evening.
Hey...
This is Daisuke.
He's Ran's friend.
Really now?
I hope you'll remain friends with Ran.
Yes, ma'am...
Bye!
Mom, you mean...
You came home because you saw my wish on that paper card?
Right.
Shin'ichi-kun...
I think he wanted to show me that wish card...
And decided to bring the bamboo from the classroom to my place.
He probably enlisted Daisuke as his helper.
That kid—he mocked you, didn't he?
He did...
But the next day, he apologized.
He even said, "Your mom is a beauty."
I thought that was unbelievable...
All of that was Shin'ichi-kun's doing, just for you.
That kid has his good points too.
Shin'ichi...
Clear.
I didn't know anything about it until then.
Since Shin'ichi, of course, kept quiet...
And that Daisuke changed schools afterwards.
That Shin'ichi kid sure sounds like a gentleman.
Yeah, quite impressive.
Ah, no, you flatter me...
I mean, he really is, isn't he?
Are you laughing at me too, Mouri-san!?
I can't take this anymore!
I quit!
Hey!
Dad, what did you say to that man?
You said something about his wife, didn't you?
No, I didn't...
Right?
Yeah, only Okano poked fun at his wife...
But I stopped after that.
I figured I'd angered him.
Mouri-chan didn't say anything, really.
Then, why did he leave in such a fury?
Dunno.
Wait, this...
I see how it was.
Say, that man must've looked at Uncle's discard pile...
And thought he was being made fun of again.
See it?
3-Sou is...
Pronounced sansou, like "villa."
And the white, green, and red tiles...
Represent white skin, dark green hair, and red lips.
Even the professor said these were the characteristics of a beauty.
5-Man is pronounced wuman, similar to woman.
The kanji here can be read as "fujin," which
has the same pronunciation as "wife."
And, with 9-Man, 9-Pin, and 9-Sou...
Which is pronounced chu-man, chu-pin, and chu-sou...
We get "chu-chu-chu."
Put them together, and...
At the villa...
His beautiful wife...
Kiss-kiss-kiss.
How to put this...
I'm speechless.
I'll go get Kouda-chan back.
It was my fault for making fun of him in the first place.
I'll tell him his imagination was getting the better of him.
Jeez...
Sending a message using mahjong tiles?
No one would want to do something so stupid and troublesome.
In fact...
Someone did come up with something this elaborate.
What's worse, as a serial killer.
However, I only figured this out much later...
It's great that Kouda-san realized it was a misunderstanding.
But it does look like Uncle's going to play mahjong all night again.
Conan-kun!
What is it, you all?
Conan, let's go bug-catching tomorrow.
Bug-catching?
The professor said he'll take us to Beika Forest by car.
We're gonna meet at his house at 4:00 AM.
4:00 AM?
If we don't get there by dawn...
There won't be any beetles!
But, I have my own things to attend to...
What things?
Well, I mean...
Fine, I'll go!
Then we'll go buy some bug cages.
Ran-oneesan, bye-bye!
Let's go!
Yes!
Bye!
Be careful!
Damn...
They're pushy.
Say, about my story earlier...
There's one thing left I can't figure out.
Why did Daisuke-kun decide to
help Shin'ichi carry the bamboo?
Or, should I say, what did Shin'ichi say to make him help?
Well...
What is it you want from me?
Say, you love Mouri, right?
I do not!
What're you talking about?
I'll give you this.
Only if you do as I say.
Really?
Speaking of Tanabata...
During first grade, I went to the Star Festival at Mall Ave...
And took a photo with Shin'ichi.
It was my first time wearing a yukata...
That's right—where is that photo now?
Where is it...
Well...
Here.
Right...
As for that photo...
I cut myself out, and gave it to him.
And I'll never tell.