KUDOU SHINICHI
THE CASE OF THE MYSTERIOUS
WALL AND THE BLACK LAB
Wow!
Like Hide!
Awesome!
All right, want to see my special overhead shot?
This is a little advanced for you guys, so don't try this at home.
Hey, you!
Oh, sorry.
Actually, I was wondering if you
saw me at this park three days ago.
At around 10:30 in the morning, maybe?
Well now, at that time on a weekday, a middle
schooler wouldn't have been in the park.
I was in class, you know.
I see.
I guess that's true.
So why...
Thanks anyway.
Hey, were you guys here on Thursday, by any chance?
What was that all about?
Seventeen people.
The number of people you talked to in the last hour after me.
Looks like you've got a problem.
If you'd like, I might be able to advise you.
Advise me?
Aren't you in middle school?
I'm not an ordinary student.
I'm a detective on the side.
Detective?
Of course, I'm still an amateur.
My childhood friend and classmate's father is a real private eye.
Though that's not saying much, I might be better than him.
But...
For instance, aren't those two men
standing over there police detectives?
They are!
But how...
I can't say much on the younger man...
But I have a hunch on the other one.
Solid build—definitely has martial arts experience.
A long coat worn by wind and rain...
Dirty, scuffed shoes...
And intent—clear eyes that haven't left you for a second.
Everything tells me he's a detective, and
an old-fashioned type one at that.
Well? Maybe I can help you?
What's your name?
Kudo Shinichi.
Kudo-kun, huh?
I'm Akimoto Kouichi.
I work at Touto Sanpou.
Touto Sanpou?
That's a big company.
Actually, I've become a suspect in a recent murder case.
The incident was...
Three days ago, on Thursday, at about 10:30 in the morning.
How did you know that?
Don't worry about that.
Please continue.
My grandmother, who used to dote on me when I was younger...
Was murdered at her home in Kamakura.
About 2,000,000¥ was stolen from her dresser.
I heard about that case.
I think the police said the suspect was someone she knew.
That was actually me.
Is there any reason the police would suspect you?
I took a personal day on Thursday, intending to visit her.
But Wednesday night, I ended up going
out with a friend and drinking all night.
Drunk, I stumbled to this park near my
house and passed out over there.
I caught a cold, and canceled my trip to my grandmother's.
About what time did you fall asleep?
10:00 AM or so, for about an hour, I think.
I see.
The murder was at 10:30, and Kamakura is at least an hour away.
That means that if we can prove you were here
then, it would corroborate your alibi, right?
That's right.
Of course, you did tell the police?
Of course I told them!
But during the interrogation, I mixed up my schedule
and answered that I was at my apartment at the time...
I was just shaken up, you know.
I had just heard my dear grandmother had been murdered.
And to think, it was on the very day that I was supposed to visit her...
The police found in their investigation that I wasn't at my apartment.
Remembering that I had come to this
park, I changed my statement, but...
You become more suspicious in the eyes of the police?
Yeah.
Since the police suspect me, it's difficult
to get them to search for witnesses.
Not to mention, this is outside their jurisdiction.
Those two detectives are from Kamakura.
And so you set out to prove your own innocence.
I've been looking for witnesses all day today.
Understood.
First, instead of looking on a Sunday, come back on a weekday.
That way, people who walk and jog here during the week will come.
It would be ideal to do it on a Thursday.
Oh, you're right.
Do you remember anything else?
Anyone who might have seen you?
I've been thinking about that the whole
time, but I just can't remember...
Was anyone using the tennis or soccer walls?
I don't think so...
What about sounds? Like...
A black dog!
That's right!
When I fell asleep, I thought I heard a dog barking, so I looked...
And I saw a woman pass here with a black dog.
Do you remember her face?
No, I don't.
Was she young?
I think she was wearing white and a white hat...
And what about the dog?
You could see it from this brick terrace?
Yeah, I couldn't see its whole body, but...
I did see its head and rear.
Given that it must be at least 50cm tall...
It has to be a large breed.
A black labrador...
Or maybe a flat-coated retriever...
Possibly even a doberman...
Does that help?
That's plenty.
Let's meet here tomorrow morning at 10:00.
If we're lucky, we'll meet the same woman with her dog.
But don't you have to go to school?
Well, my "studies" here are more important to me.
So, I'll be skipping class tomorrow morning for an hour or two.
Well, don't come crying to me if teacher catches you.
I wonder if the black dog that man saw was Robin-kun.
Robin-kun?
In my neighborhood, there's a woman who always walks a black lab.
Since I like dogs, sometimes I'd stand around
and talk with her when she's with Robin-kun.
She goes every morning from 9:30 for about
an hour and walks him in Beika Park.
Really?
Who is she? Do you know where she lives?
I don't really know her name or address.
But since the back of that wall seems like it's the
end of the walking course, I think that's right.
Really? Well, today's looking pretty...
Wait, you don't mean the back of the wall but the front, right?
The back of the wall is where Akimoto-san was.
She was saying it was the back.
That road is Robin-kun's favorite.
That can't be right...
The wall would block her view and she couldn't see.
Oh, that's true. I wonder what it is...
Probably, that day, for a change...
I know!
That Akimoto guy must be clairvoyant!
That's how he could see behind the wall.
Yeah, that's it. Clairvoyance.
What's that supposed to mean?
Are you making fun of me?
No, why would you think that?
You have your own ideas, but ESP
and telepathy are real, you know?
You idiot!
If people really did have those powers, we'd be
living in a world without crime or detectives!
Stupid!
Stop calling me stupid!
This earth is full of mysteries you can never solve!
There are not!
Are too!
Are not!
Hey, Kudo-kun's ditching class!
Who cares about that jerk?
What? Fighting like a married couple?
Suzuki, pipe down!
Sorry, sir.
Why is it always me?
Black lab?
Yeah.
They should come down this path again today.
Until then, let's look for witnesses together.
Are you sure you can miss your classes?
I'll be back by third period.
Along with lunch, that gives me 45 minutes.
It's the boy from yesterday.
What should we do?
Let them be for now.
Excuse me.
Can I ask you something?
At around this time last Thursday, did you pass this way?
Yes, I did.
Then, did you see this man, by any chance?
No, I don't believe I did.
What's the matter?
He asked if we saw this gentleman last Thursday.
I'm not sure...
I did.
I did too!
I saw him too!
Did you all really?
I found a butterfly.
It's Mr. Butterfly!
All right, I'm gonna catch him!
I'll get him too!
No, don't be mean to him!
Is he dead?
He's alive!
Thank goodness!
Ayumi-chan! Genta-kun! Mitsuhiko-kun!
What are you all doing?
Come on back!
Yes!
Well?
This should confirm Akimoto-san's alibi.
It's just that the testimony of three year olds is a little...
That's true.
Understood.
So, if I can corroborate their story with
the witness that owns a black lab...
Will that be enough?
You must have heard us talking.
Well, I might think about it.
Thanks, you guys.
Hey, what's an "alibi"?
It must be about ants (ari).
Note: This is a simple pun on "arigatou" (thanks) and "ari ga tou" (10 ants)
They do say, "Thank goodness there are ten ants," right?
If only the teachers had seen me, and not just the kids...
But we did get something to go on.
All that's left is the woman with the black lab.
Hopefully, she'll come along soon.
That's the bark!
It can't be...
Please wait here!
What dreadful crows, right boy?
Excuse me, is this dog Robin?
That's right. This is my Robin-chan.
Did you take the path on the other side of this wall last Thursday?
At about this time of the day, maybe?
No, this boy is fussy about taking this road every day.
But don't you take a different path for a change sometimes?
Please think carefully.
It was four days ago, on Thursday.
I'm telling you, it was this road.
I remember it, last Thursday, it was quite chilly,
and Robin saw a crow on the wall just like today.
What's going on here?
This Robin is obviously the dog Akimoto-san heard.
But...
If the dog was walking on this side of the wall,
there's no way he could have seen him.
That Akimoto person must be clairvoyant!
It can't be!
I don't see any holes or cracks.
There's no way to see that road...
So how can it be?
Kudo-kun, you should get back to school.
Third period's about to start.
I'll have to make this my homework.
I'll see you tomorrow at the same time.
Actually, I don't think I can take any more work off.
It already looks bad to my manager that
I had to get questioned by the police.
Then, I'll go at it alone.
I do have my pride as a detective.
It's been four days since then.
I've asked everyone that's come by Beika Park.
But no one seems to have seen you.
That woman's dead sure she was on the other side of that wall...
And I checked out leads in case a different dog might
have been walking in the park at the same time.
But you couldn't find anything, huh?
Yeah.
Nothing at all.
I don't know if this is any help, but...
When I saw the black dog, I remember
thinking it was a seeing-eye dog.
A seeing-eye dog?
Yeah.
I've seen people with black lab seeing-eye dogs there before.
I think they might have been trainers.
Got it.
I'll check that lead out starting tomorrow.
And that's when I remembered!
That's just like you.
Oh, Shin-chan, here you are!
Yeah, I find it's easy to calm down and think in here somehow.
I see.
Well?
Did you discover the secret of the Case of
the Mysterious Wall and the Black Lab?
Well, I spent all of today checking out guide animal centers...
But don't have much to show for it.
Hey, Yusaku.
How about some fatherly advice?
If you go to Beika Park, you'll see all kinds of people, like...
No.
Don't give me any hints.
I want to solve this on my own.
Oh, they grow up so fast!
Why did Akimoto-san think it was a guide
animal when he saw the black dog?
It's true that there are a lot of black lab seeing-eye dogs...
But is that the only reason?
Maybe playing the violin will pull you over this sticking point?
My young Holmes-kun.
Like I'm in the mood for that.
Besides, Holmes didn't play the violin when he was
at an impasse, but to pass the time between cases.
I'm sure you know at least that much.
Too bad!
I wanted to hear you play again, Shin-chan.
Was it...
I spent all yesterday and finally found it:
The black dog that Akimoto-san saw.
Really?
Was it a guide dog?
Just wait and see.
Akimoto-san...
Could you lie down in the grass like you did that day?
And you as well, detective.
Me too?
Yes, if you would.
Now!
Please get up!
A guitar case?
Indeed.
The black dog's true identity is a guitar case.
In your groggy stupor, the guitar case
looked like a black lab out for a walk.
One that had a harness, like a guide dog.
It's true...
I thought I was looking at a dog, too...
Even though I wasn't drunk or sleepy.
That's because I put the suggestion in your mind
that you'd be seeing a black lab beforehand.
In the same way that Akimoto-san had
seen black seeing-eye dogs here before.
It made your mind predisposed to confusing the two things.
And on top of that, the silhouette does resemble the same shape.
I tested it out yesterday.
You can see the top of her guitar case...
And the rocking motion looks like a dog walking.
So that's what happened...
I see.
Let me ask you once more:
Last week, on Thursday, at 10:30, did you pass down this road?
Yes.
Usually I don't cut through the park, but I just happened to that day.
And I saw that man.
I believe we've established Akimoto-san's alibi.
Sure seems that way.
This is Genjiyama.
What?
Understood. On my way.
Call from HQ: They got the perp.
Apparently, it was the work of a home robber.
Sorry about all this trouble.
No...
Let's go!
Yes, sir!
Well, if you won't be needing me...
Thank you very much.
That's that.
You must be very relieved that the killer was caught.
I owe you a debt of gratitude.
Thank you.
No problem.
I learned a lot, too.
Well then, I'll see you.
Hey.
You'll be a great detective.
Well, this time, my father figured it out.
Maybe playing the violin will pull you over this sticking point?
My young Holmes-kun.
You didn't solve it?
No.
But he was a famous detective, too, once.
Attention!
Bow!
Take your seats.
Barely made it...
Oh, yeah...
There's still this problem.
What? It wasn't clairvoyance.
Who cares?
What a beautiful song.
Yeah.
It really is.
So? How did it go?
Your case.
Oh, it was a guitar case.
And so, Ran and I ended our week-long
fight in the spring of 8th grade.
I had no idea the song would figure
into a huge case three years later...