Conan-kun, breakfast is ready!
Here, Conan-kun, your rice.
Thank you...
It's gotta be in Japanese style if we're talkin' about breakfast!
Aw snaps, this miso soup has a great flavor!
The stock is made from kelp and dried bonito flakes, right?
Yeah, I had some time this morning, so I brewed some soup stock.
How thoughtful of ya!
As for my mom, she sometimes uses fish bones and shells as stock.
Ya gotta let your stock simmer and
add a dash of flavor with sweet miso!
Add a lesser amount of miso if you're makin' Kansai style.
And why the hell are you here!?
Oh, no...
Why is Heiji-niichan staying here?
Hattori-kun saw that incident on the news and rushed
over because he was worried about you, Conan-kun.
Grabbed the first bullet train in the mornin'!
And then, Ku—
Couth as I was, when I saw you sleepin' so soundly...
I chose not to wake you up, Conan-kun.
Geez!
Last night I missed Youko-chan's drama...
And since early in the morning I had to listen to
all of that yadda yadda in the Kansai dialect...
What a pain!
Right.
Before I forget...
May I?
My souvenirs, sou-ve-nirs!
I'd better get 'em while I still remember.
Nothing for you!
I mean we didn't buy yours...
Sorry...
I totally forgot about buying yours and Kazuha-chan's.
Geez, that's too bad.
Instead of souvenirs, I'll just have to settle for
hearing about all your brilliant exploits this time.
This grilled egg roll is sweet!
We call it a dashimaki in Kansai, and instead of adding
sugar, we mix beaten eggs in dashi and mirin...
Come to think of it, I wonder if those guys
gave Kobayashi-sensei her gift already?
NIIGATA~TOKYO SOUVENIR CAPRICCIO
This is for me?
Yes!
We think this suits you perfectly, Kobayashi-sensei.
We picked this out for you with Ai-chan!
Though the one who paid for it was the professor.
Thank you!
May I open it?
Of course!
Wow, how cute!
Thank you!
It's a snow lass, right?
Let me take a look, please!
Isn't this...
The doll Sonoko-oneesan bought?
Come to think of it...
Hey, Ran!
What do you think of this?
What do you mean "what"?
It's a souvenir for Makoto-san!
Why not, it's really cute!
And looks a little like Sonoko.
Really?
And what is it doing here?
Beats me...
Uhm, you guys...
If this thing is here with us, that must mean...
Here, for you.
What's this?
A present.
I was in Niigata yesterday, you know.
I'm honored.
Niigata, you say?
I want you to open it and see!
Oh, sorry...
Please think of it as me and carry with you all times.
I see.
Although I don't know which is you...
Among the two swans here, the female
one must represent Sonoko-san, right?
Yes, that female one represents me...
Female?
S-WHAAAAA—!?
Uhm...
Could there have been a mix-up?
Yeah, well...
I see.
The same wrappers from the lodge and the same-sized boxes...
And they weigh...
Almost the same.
Because of this, it's no wonder that you,
miss, and the kids here didn't notice it.
But...
Why were the two boxes swapped?
That is the question!
Oh, thanks.
The question is when, where, and
how the two boxes got confused.
If I had to hazard a guess...
Sorry, is it too hot?
This is indeed a mystery.
Mist?
You want water?
Mystery, mystery!
I see...
"Mystery"?
Don't exaggerate things.
Nah, you can't be too sure.
Some mysteries may appear trivial, but oftentimes
they connect to a colossal-scaled enigma!
Well...
Given that Conan-kun is still so little, there's
no way he could've comprehended that part.
Could it be...
This is the work of someone who'd
want me and Makoto-san separated?
Well, that's definitely possible.
Not.
On the other hand...
Someone might've wanted to interfere with
Kobayashi-sensei and Inspector Shiratori's feelings...
Causing them to play this kind of trick!
That possibility is quite high, too.
I said that's not it!
But, ladies and gentlemen!
As long as the famous Detective of the
West—Hattori Heiji—is in charge...
No mystery will be left unsolved!
Just leave it to the expert!
We're counting on you!
Oh, right, we've also bought senbei from Niigata!
You don't have to worry about gifts for me.
It's all right, because we've bought a lot.
But, I don't think hot cocoa and senbei go together...
So did you guys return from Kitanosawamura by car?
Yeah.
Everyone rode with Uncle Mouri in his rental car.
If that's the case, it's likely the presents got swapped in the car.
And?
Where were the two boxes placed?
Inside a bag?
Ayumi held it at all times.
I'd hate to see it break.
I also had mine placed on my lap the whole time.
Because it's a super-super important
souvenir for my awesome Makoto-san!
Well, anyway...
Go ahead and tell me where everyone was sitting in the car.
The boxes in question were...
Conan
Mouri
Ran
Sono
Agasa
Hai
Gen
Mitsu
Ayu
Beside the window of the second and fourth rows, I see.
And...
Did anything special happen in the car during your return?
Something did!
We met a deer, right?
And we were spinning round and round!
What do you mean?
It happened soon after we left the village...
Teitan...
Teitan Elementary School!
Can't those guys stop with that song already?
Agreed.
Wait for me, Youko-chan!
I'm gonna rush home just for you!
Don't speed and get into an accident.
Shut up!
I know that already!
Uncle, up ahead!
Oh deer!
That's it!
The truth is...
Just as he slammed on the brakes and the car started spinnin'...
Such idiocy.
Well, since this isn't a comedy show, I guess that's not it.
There anything that seemed outta place?
We later got on the highway and headed straight for Tokyo.
If that's true, this case must've happened on the highway.
"Case", huh?
You guys, think hard and lemme know
the details of your highway journey.
It couldn't be that you guys rode
nonstop without stoppin' somewhere.
Now that you mention it...
A little after we got on the highway,
Genta-kun said he had to use the restroom.
Right, right.
That's when we stopped at a parking area.
Can't hold it, can't hold it!
Gotta go!
Hey, why don't we take a breather?
Sure!
In that case, me too.
You're not coming, Ai-kun?
I'm all right.
Are you OK being alone?
I'll be fine.
I'm used to being alone anyway.
Well, to be safe, I'm locking the door.
That's it!
"That"?
When you guys left the car...
That lil girl took the chance to swap the boxes.
Why?
It was a prank, a prank!
Haibara-san did what?
Ai-chan would never do something like that!
Naïveté, my dear Watson!
Oftentimes the culprit is someone beyond your expectations.
For the sake of argument...
Suppose this naughty-lookin' young man was the culprit...
It wouldn't be interestin' at all!
You're flattering me!
That wasn't a compliment.
Havin' said that, Conan-kun...
Call her and check.
Me!?
Coz that lil girl and ya are like best buds forevah, Conan-kun!
I wonder why, though?
Geez...
Hey, you.
Who do you think you're asking?
Well, I did say that was nonsense but...
Wasn't her, as expected.
Really?
There's no doubt coz we're best buds forevah like ya said!
That so...
It woulda been fascinating if that lil girl were the culprit...
Was there anything else outta the ordi—
What is it?
You remember somethin'?
Look at the time!
Can we have the pork buns you brought us as souvenirs for lunch?
Sure, no problem...
I'll go microwave them now.
I want three of them!
Got it.
Pork buns, pork buns!
Didn't you already eat some senbei just now?
Keep in mind that Genta-kun is the
owner of a stomach made of steel.
Is that so?
Dinner...
It's still too early for dinner!
We're having lunch now, you know.
No, no.
I was wondering about how you guys took care of dinner that day.
You ate at a service area, right?
And what about the boxes?
I thought about bringing my box with me, but...
We decided to leave them in the car after all.
But I'm sure that everyone definitely got out.
Was there no one who returned to the car halfway?
I'll have eel rice!
You have to pay for whatever's over the budget.
Then, ramen...
I'll have curry rice.
Ayumi wants hamburger meat.
Professor?
What's wrong?
Looks like I forgot my cell phone in the car.
Let me go get it.
That's it!
What now?
It was that old man who swapped the boxes!
The professor?
Why?
Again with a prank?
That's right...
Isn't that old guy kinda mischievous in a way?
That's true.
He's a much more likely candidate than Haibara-san.
What's more, at that time, the professor...
PREMIERE!!
STEAK COMBO
Premiere steak combo, huh...
You can't.
You and I will have salad udon, Professor.
I see!
He got upset about it...
And played a prank to relieve stress.
Hey, hey...
Guilty as charged, it was I who swapped the boxes!
Not him as I thought.
How do you know?
Of course I'd know something like that!
The professor and I have been friends since my childhood.
Since your childhood?
How old do you think you are now?
Nah...
But, if it wasn't those two...
Then it couldn't have been someone's prank, no?
So you guys didn't go anywhere else after dinner?
I suppose not.
I fell asleep actually.
I fell asleep after that too.
My tummy was full and I was getting too comfortable...
I dreamed about having eel rice!
Good for you, I guess.
And you, miss?
I fell asleep as well.
I was awake, though.
It'd be bad if Uncle Kogorou were driving while drowsy.
And?
Were the old man and the lil girl asleep too?
Later, when we exited the Beika interchange, I woke everyone up.
So you mean durin' the course of action,
you were on the highway nonstop?
We did encounter a little traffic jam, though.
Traffic jam?
It happened soon after we passed Beika Tunnel.
That was the part where the road goes downhill for a while...
Followed by a continuous uphill slope,
leading to pretty frequent congestion.
That's it!
Not again...
Listen up.
First, the boxes fell to the floor from
the knees of the two sleeping people.
Sonoko
Ayumi
And, when the car went through the long downhill road...
The two boxes slid away.
Then...
When it climbed the hill...
Sonoko
Ayumi
Finally...
The two people woke up and picked
up the swapped boxes, you see!
How 'bout it?
But I never picked up any boxes.
Ayumi neither.
When I woke up, my box was still there on my knees.
Somethin' like that must've happened when someone
else picked them up and put them on your knees!
Right?
I didn't do anything like that.
I didn't pick up anything either.
I also dreamed about eating rice cake soup!
So that wasn't it either?
Well, at least it was better speculation than that deer nonsense.
Looks like you guys had already arrived at Beika City.
Hurry, hurry!
Only fifteen minutes left until Youko-chan's drama starts!
Stop rushing us already!
That was a good nap.
Let's go!
Wait for me, Genta-kun...
That's it!
When the two of you picked up the pair of boxes you dropped...
I see!
The boxes were swapped as a result.
While falling in love!
See, it was the one where De Niro and Meryl
Streep ran into each other in a bookstore...
And accidentally swapped bags.
It was a romance movie masterpiece from the year 1984!
Don't you guys know?
Looks that way...
Anyway, looks like we've found out what happened.
Yeah...
I hereby announce that the case is closed!
Wrong!
"Wrong"?
What do you mean?
It couldn't be that the boxes were swapped at that time.
Because I had already marked my own box.
Look!
It's true.
There's a kiss mark.
What's a kiss mark?
It's something you don't need to know, Genta-kun!
Allow me to reconfirm this again, but...
The box you had today...
Really was wrapped with this piece of paper?
I double-checked my mark before
bringing it out, so there's no doubt.
In that case, when you and the lil girl bumped into each other, you
were certain you had correctly picked up the respective boxes?
I've been saying that, haven't I?
Say, Sonoko-neechan...
When did you make that mark?
Right after I bought it.
As soon as I came out the lodge and was headed for the car.
What, is that it?
Why didn't you mention that earlier?
I know the reason why the boxes were swapped.
The culprit is...
Hello, thank you for holding.
Mizuta Kana speaking.
Conan-kun?
Yesterday was pretty tough, huh?
Souvenirs?
Yeah, I remember them.
I was in charge of the souvenir counter yesterday.
Then, do you still remember who bought what?
If I recall correctly, the two high school girls bought
a wooden owl sculpture and a mug with swans.
And the elementary school girl got the snow lass doll, right?
As I thought.
Thank you!
Bye!
Well, do you see what's wrong now?
By the time the two boxes reached the hands
of Sonoko-neechan and Ayumi-chan...
They had already been switched.
What the...
As expected of our awesome Conan-kun!
The Great Detective of the West totally lost face!
Hey, what on earth is a kiss mark?
Well, we should hurry up and hand over the correct souvenir!
Let's go and give it to Kobayashi-sensei now.
Then, let me rewrap it for you.
And I have to set up an appointment with Makoto-san again!
Oh, right!
Did you already give that souvenir to Shinichi-kun?
No...
All I get is his voice mail even when I call his cell phone.
Done.
Here you go.
Thank you very much!
That's why I figured I should do what Shinichi
suggested and drop it off at his house later.
See?
Perhaps that was also swapped with someone else's gift!
No need to worry.
Because the lady just now mentioned a wooden owl sculpture.
That's true!
What a pity.
You just lost your chance to regain your tarnished name!
REGAIN
ONE'S
REPUTATION
MEIYOBANKAI
RESTORE
ONE'S
TARNISHED
NAME
OMEIHENJOU
Why would I want to regain my tarnished name?
Later, Conan!
See you tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
All this dealin' with kids drained me of all my strength!
Oops!
TO YOUKO-CHAN
What's this?
Youko-chan?
That sneaky man kept it a secret from everyone
and bought a souvenir for Okino Youko.
What a sly old fox he is!
TO YOUKO-CHAN
Okiya-san went out?
There it is.
If I don't tell her that I've dropped by and opened it...
She's gonna phone me like crazy and it'll be a drag.
Huh?
Shouldn't it have been a wooden owl sculpture?
What's this?
What are the odds that this got mixed up too?
But if I recall correctly, no one other
than me was at the register back then.
Don't tell me...
OKINO
YOUKO
Is this for me?
Yes!
From the silvery-white world, I selected
this baby just for Youko-chan!
I'm so glad!
Wonder what it is?
It's my honor to have made you glad.
I hope someone resembling an elf like you...
Will enjoy putting those on your beautiful ears.
This, you mean?
Yeah.
If you will put them on your beautiful ears for me...
I presume that the owl will also be thrilled and go hoot-hoot...
Like this?
W-OOOOOT!?
How's it, Kudou?
Did you enjoy the lil memento I left ya?
Geez...
So it was you who messed with it.
Did you figure out what was inside the box?
Something like what the man was thinkin' can be easily figured out.
Judging from the size of the box, it's probably some accessories.
And lookin' at the shape, it's very unlikely for it to be a necklace...
Not to mention a ring would be too suggestive.
The most likely answer would be earrings.
Correct.
Well?
Don't you think it suits you perfectly?
Ms. Kudou?
How the hell does it suit me!?
And don't you dare think the wrong thing!